<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5756</id><name>Danger Girl</name><description>OverviewDanger Girl: The Video Game continues the adventures of Team Danger Girl, first seen in the Danger Girl Cliffhanger comic book series created by Andy Hartnell and J. Scott Campbell. The game is a 3rd Person Shooter, with stealth and cover elements. Over the course of the games 12 levels, the player takes control of Abbey Chase, Sydney Savage and newest Danger Girl JC, as they try to prevent The Hammer Empire from aquiring a powerful ancient artifact.CharactersAbbey ChaseTeam Danger Girl, from left to right: Sydney Savage, Abbey Chase and JCHeight: 5ft 8in.Eye Colour: HazelHair Colour: Golden SiennaAffiliation: Danger GirlSpeciality: Archeaology / Mystic StudiesSecondary: Foreign Languages, Small ArmsBirthplace: Boston, MassachusettsAbbey Chase made her debut in the 1997 comic Prelude to Danger. She is a champion marksman, a virtuoso of languages and a scholar in world history. Although spending most of her youth as a loner, Abbey is a natural team leader, and it's this, along with her skills, that helped her shepard Team Danger Girl to victory over the Hammer Empire in their first battle.Sydney SavageHeight: 5ft 9in. (5ft 11in. in heels)Eye Colour: BlueHair Colour: AuburnAffiliation: Danger GirlSpeciality: Surveillance / SniperSecondary: Helicopter PilotBirthplace: Sydney AustraliaThe striking, sassy and vivacious part of the Danger Girls, Sydney originates from the picturesque Australia. She's often reprimanded for her wild and unorthodox procedures, but Sydney more often than not justifies her ways. Of all the Danger Girls, Sydney takes the most advantage of her looks to distract the teams primarily male antagonists.JCHeight: 5ft 10in.Eye Colour: GreenHair Colour: ChesnutAffiliation: Danger GirlSpeciality: Engineering / InventorSecondary: ExplosivesBirthplace: Vancouver, CanadaAlthough yet to become an official member of Team Danger Girl, JC has proven herself to be a valuable asset to the team.JC was brought into the fold by Deuce, after the team's first encounter with The Hammer Empire, to help maintain and repair the teams specialised equipment and vehicles. With The Hammer Empire striking again before a third opperative could be chosen, JC was more than willing to step up to the challenge. JC was created especially for Danger Girl: The Video Game.DeuceHeight: 6ft 1in.Eye Colour: BrownHair Colour: Salt and PepperAffiliation: Danger GirlSpeciality: Mission StratergistSecondary: EspionageBirthplace: London, EnglandA former British Secret Agent, Deuce was lured out of retirement when invited to create and oversee the first all female espionage team, code name "Danger Girl".ValerieHeight: 5ft 7in.Eye Colour: GreenHair Colour: RedAffiliation: Danger GirlSpeciality: CommunicationsSecondary: All things digitalBirthplace: San Francisco, CaliforniaTeenager "Silicone" Valerie graduatedtop of her Oxford class years before she could obtain a driver's license. She could of easily landed a wealthy career in communications technology, but she had her eyes set on a more dangerouslife. A chance encounter with Deuce led her to becoming a Danger Girl in-trainingNatalia KassleHeight: 6ftEye Colour: Ice BlueHair Colour: BlondeAffiliation: The Hammer EmpireSpeciality: Edged Weapons / Hand to HandSecondary: Counter IntelligenceBirthplace: Bucharest, RussiaNatalia was chosen to join the Danger Girl team for her phenomenal combat and espionage talent, among other more obvious outstanding attributes. Unfortunately she was also a double agent, working for The Hammer Empire. She infiltrated the ranks of Team Danger Girl and nearly led them to their death. She's currently a commander in The Hammer Empire, continually trying to take over the world, but her ultimate passion is to take out Abbey Chase.Major MaximHeight: Estimated at 7ftEye Colour: RedHair Colour: UnknownAffiliation: The Hammer EmpireSpeciality: Rapid Assault CommanderSecondary: InterrogationBirthplace: UnknownRebirthplace: Hammer HeadquartersMajor Maxim is the monstrous mastermind behind The Hammer Empires military force. He was once but a wounded soldier in the ranks of those very forces, until he became an unwilling "volunteer" to Doctor Kharnov Von Kripplor's bizarre Hammer Ubermensch (Super Soldier) program. The only "success" of the program, Major Maxom soon became dependant on the fluid, which supplies and maintains his size and strength.Mission ArchiveAbbey Chase in Rumble in the JungleAbbey Chase in Finders KeepersJC In Rigged to BlowSydney Savage in Caution: Curves AheadAbbey Chase in Dangerous DiscoveryJC in Frozen AssetsSydney Savage in Museum MayhemSydney Savage in Crossing the LineJC in Bustin' OutJC in Maximum FirepowerSydney Savage in Countdown to DangerAbbey Chase in Catfight to the Finish</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1248">Syphon Filter</game><game id="18599">Syphon Filter 2</game><game id="18168">007: The World is Not Enough</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7504/811252-197037_41963_front.jpg</image></root>