<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5769</id><name>High School Musical: Sing It!</name><description>GameplayHigh School Musical: Sing It! features fairly standard karaoke gameplay. Lyrics are filled in from left to right with players trying to sing in time to this s well as match the approximate pitch of the original. Two players can sing at once for duets, for these, a second lyrics set is shown, as well as a separate pitch chart.Tracks FeaturedThere are 30 tracks total. 10 from High School Musical, 11 from High School Musical 2 and 9 other songs from Disney Channel stars like The Cheetah Girls and High School Musical's own Corbin Bleu. Of all the songs in the game, only 1 is an original recording (Everyday, performed by Troy (Zac Efron) and Gabriella (Vanessa Hudgens).High School MusicalStart of Something NewGet'cha Head in the GameWhat I've Been Looking For (Sharpay and Ryan Version)What I've Been Looking For (Troy and Gabriella Version)Stick to the Status QuoWhen There Was Me and YouBop to the TopBreaking FreeWe're All in This TogetherI Can't Take My Eyes Off of YouHigh School Musical 2What Time is It?Fabulous*Work This OutYou Are the Music in MeHumuhumunukunukuapua'aI Don't DanceYou Are the Music in Me (Sharpay Version)Gotta Go My Own WayBet on ItEverydayAll for OneFrom Outside the FranchiseAll Good NowBeautiful SoulCheetah SistersCounting On YouI Will Be AroundJump To The RythemNo OneOn the RidePush It To The LimitLocationsThe game features 12 locations in which players sing, all are taken from the movies but ae not necessarily settings for songs in the move they are from:New Years Eve Lodge (Opening of High School Musical, Start of Something New)Auditorium (In the school, High School Musical, various original uses)Cafeteria (In the school, High School Musical, Stick to the Status Quo)Corridors (In the school, various original uses)Gym (In the school, High School Musical, Get'cha Head in the Game)School Grounds (In the school, Primarily High School Musical 2, What Time is It?)Rooftop Garden (High School Musical)Science Class (High School Musical)Trophy Room (High School Musical)Golf Course (High School Musical 2, Bet On It)Summer Resort (High School Musical 2, various original uses)Swimming Pool (High School Musical 2, All For One)</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3738">Boogie</game><game id="15661">Karaoke Revolution</game><game id="21135">Naked Brothers Band</game><game id="32905">Singstar Guitar</game><game id="34233">SingStar Danske Hits</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7900/261533-high_school_musical.jpg</image></root>