<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5771</id><name>Buck Rogers: Countdown to Doomsday</name><description>OverviewBuck Rogers: Countdown to Doomsday is based on TSR's Buck Rogers XXVC setting created in the late eighties and based on the character whose exploits had been seen in nearly every medium and through several revivals since his debut in 1928. In this adventure, players must help Buck Rogers uncover and destroy a doomsday weapon that could spell the end of resistance to the empire that holds Earth within its grasp.SSI adapted the Buck Rogers setting (another TSR property using the same rules) using the Gold Box Engine that they had pioneered with its work within the Forgotten Realms campaign setting via such titles as Pool of Radiance and Curse of the Azure Bonds.Based as it was on the "Gold Box Engine", players interfaced with the game via a grid-based, 3D system wherein the world is viewed from a first-person perspective with 90° turns and movement spaces. Party members were displayed in the upper right hand corner along with hit points and armor class. Random enemy encounters would provide combat opportunities within the game against mixed groups of foes, providing experience.The console variant of the game eschewed the 3D exploration interface in favor of an isometric view instead, although the tactical combat view was still included.The game is a sci-fi role player, although it uses the same rules as ADD (which was the case with its tabletop original). Classes and weapons are analogous to certain aspects of the system, but it is firmly rooted within its high-tech setting.The packaging, as was typical of SSI's attention to detail as exemplified by their treatment of the Gold Box series of games, took this opportunity to immerse the player within the fiction of its world via an included booklet outlining its history and systems.Included were:The Rule Book (manual)A logbook containing the history leading up from 1990 to 2356 (the date the game takes place) and describing the systems that it uses as well as text paragraphs describing different areas of the gameAnd a data card (a quick-start card on how to get started with the game on specific machines)The main disks of the game could be freely copied, although players would be challenged to find certain words within one of the booklets that the game had come with in order to proceed as a test. This mechanic would also be used in a variety of other games within SSI's RPG lineup.The logbook doubled as a key part of the game as it contained dialogue, scene descriptions, and maps that it would reference. This technique was also used in several other RPGs such as Wasteland and Dragon Wars. As with those titles, Countdown to Doomsday's paragraphs also contained several red herrings designed to mislead players who chose to read ahead and potentially spoil the story for themselves.SettingOne of the restrictions of the creative credo governing the franchise is that the realism of Buck Rogers' world had to be based on what could be scientifically plausible and possible - hard science as opposed to more fantastic versions. As a result, the series was focused more on the Solar System and the problems associated with terraforming its planets as well as traveling among them.As another result, the history of game reflects this within its protagonists. In 1999, the United States and the Soviet Union engage in a final war, exchanging blows via nuclear weapons. As a result of this terrible conflict, conventional warfare is abandoned and the survivors band themselves into large alliances. The Russo-American Mercantile (RAM) forms out of an alliance between what is left of Russia and the United States, for example. The Indo-Asian Consortium (IAC) and the Euro-Bloc Faction (EBF) also form and become the pre-eminent superpowers of the day.Over the next few centuries, these superpowers form an alliance of their own to expand their efforts into space and colonize the planets. RAM colonizes Mars, the Moon (Luna) is colonized by the EBF, and Venus is colonized by the IAC. Fusion rockets transport men and materials to their destinations throughout the Solar System.In 2275, RAM revolts against an increasingly oppressive Earth government. Venus signs a nonaggression pact with Mars and ten years of war follow. Battered, broken, and cut off from its colonies, Earth starves allowing RAM's forces to dominate what is left. The colonized worlds continue to grow on their own, developing their own unique socieities thanks to the success of their terraforming efforts. for example, Mercury develops a thriving industry based on mining and solar power.Humanity has also changed with its expansion into the Solar System. Earth is still home to those now known as the Terrans. Mercury's people have become strong and powerful. The Martians have become prideful with their successes, and the Venusians have focused more on matters of study and of the mind.However, in the first half of the 25th century, the New Earth Organization is set up by Terrans (Earth natives) that seek to overthrow RAM and restore Earth to its former glory. With the revival of Buck Rogers from cryogenic sleep and with his daring leadership and heroic exploits across the Solar System, NEO manages to thwart RAM's attempts to stop them.High technology has also enabled the construction of robots and Digital Personalities, programs that emulate human thought and emotion but think at the speed of a computer. Genetic engineering on a vast scale has also created tailored creatures found on specific worlds, each made to fulfill either a specific purpose during terraforming or as part of a new product line. As another example, RAM makes use of Combat Gennies, disposable soldiers bred and equipped to fight their wars.This is the world that the player will be caught up within as they do their part to stop RAM and its allies.StoryThe player's party are new NEO recruits and arrive at Chicagorg (formerly Chicago, but far larger) to undergo their final training when it is attacked by RAM troops. If they manage to fend off the attack and save the base, they join efforts to salvage what is left and discover a RAM ship among the wreckage.Entering the ship, they discover a RAM science program named Scot.dos who joins them as he wishes to defect to NEO after having enough of RAM. Onboard, they discover a batch of ECGs (Experimental Combat Gennies), genetically enhanced soldiers, and find a way to stop them before they mature and create problems for Earth. Scot.dos tells them that the ECGs were created on an asteroid base which they go to investigate.At the research facility, they discover other projects that RAM is involved with, one of which happens to be a very powerful, laser-based weapon capable of demolishing entire cities at will. A series of satellite reflectors are also being used as a part of its aiming system, and the party is able to destroy these before heading out to Mars where the weapon is located and a test is scheduled.Unfortunately for them, space pirates under the employ of RAM capture them with the intention of selling them off to their enemies. But Buck Rogers, who has been following a rumor that the pirate leader, Talon, may be employed by RAM, intervenes and helps the party damage the ship to prevent pursuit while they escape.On Mars, they eventually discover the base where a smaller version of the weapon is being tested and destroy it. They also learn that one of the components for the real weapon is being manufactured on Venus and head there to learn more on what is going on, discovering that the Doomsday Laser is housed on a solar satellite (a Mercurian Mariposa) controlled by a Mercurian noble called the Sun King.Believing that the party are actually there to help the Sun King take over the Doomsday Laser for himself, the minions of the Sun King let them pass through security. There, the party discovers that the Laser is already targeting Earth and cause a power outage to delay the countdown. After setting it to self destruct and fighting their way from the core of the Mariposa, they manage to escape and watch as the Marisposa explodes taking the Doomsday Laser with it.GameplayThe game is a party-based RPG using the same engine that SSI had initially built for its Gold Box titles such as Pool of Radiance. As a result, it has many visual cues that make it appear very similar to its more fantastic cousins, but the differences lie mainly within its gameplay conventions.With the use of more conventional armaments, such as laser guns and plasma throwers, ranged attacks have a greater emphasis in this game. The use of grenades and other explosives are considered key to winning many battles quickly. As it is also space-based, the use of that medium has also opened the door on opportunities to attack and board enemy spaceships, often giving them a great deal of loot to recover and sell if need be.Limited dialogue with NPCs, puzzles, and the exploration of bases, secret laboratories, caves, and a variety of other venues are also found throughout the game.Gender is treated only as a cosmetic choice in the game as with many others, but race plays a major part in determining what career a character may be restricted in playing as.RacesThere are six races that players can choose from in order to build their party. Four of these are considered "human" types while two others are "gennies", those that have been bred to include certain other attributes that lie outside of the human gene pool.Terrans - These are unengineered humans. They can be a part of any career path and have no distinct weaknesses with fairly average statistics across the board.Venusians - Venus' civilization is a diverse mix of cultures and are often involved as traders, farmers, or herdsmen. They can also be a part of any career path.Martians - They are the oldest and most advanced civilization in the Solar System having benefited from RAM's continuing work there. Because of the lower gravity on Mars, they are slightly weaker than Terrans but equal to most everyone else. Any career path is open to them.Mercurians - Mercury is ruled by the Sun Kings, those descended from the original owners of the great Mariposa solar satellites that orbit the planet, holding court within their palaces. Three other cultures live on the surface of Mercury, descended from the refugees that had fled the chaos of the rest of the Solar System. They can be a part of any career path.Tinkerers - These were bioengineered with lemurs and gibbons to be able to work in small spaces and maintain machinery. As a result, they are very good with technology, but they are restricted to only to careers: Engineer and Medic.Desert Runners - One of the oldest bioengineered races, they were bred to survive on the harsh surface of Mars during its latter terraforming years. They bear feline features from the genetic stock they were mixed with, can run long distances, and fight with their own claws if need be. They are great fighters and good with their hands which help considering that they are restricted to the Rocketjock, Warrior, and Engineer career paths.AttributesEach character has a set of basic attributes that affect various abilities, such as combat prowess and how many spells a magic user can memorize before they must rest and re-acquire their spells once again. During character creation, the player may re-roll as many times as they want. Prime requisite attributes are those that are a requirement for certain classes. For example, Warriors must have a good Strength score in order to be effective in melee combat.The natural maximum for any attribute is an 18, although it can go higher depending on factors such as race. Throughout the game, unless it is due to an outside intervention such as with a piece of equipment, these attributes never change even when a character levels.Strength (STR) - determines physical power and damage with weapons; also affects encumbrance in combatDexterity (DEX) - reflexes and the ability to remain hard to hit in combat; affects ranged weapons such as laser rifles, bolt guns, and even their ability to pilot a rocketship without crashing.Constitution (CON) - a character's health is determined by this and hit points are derived from this score and a bonus calculated against it with every level. Sheer physical toughness.Charisma (CHA) - affects the perception that others have of a character, especially the leader. Helps with Intimidation and Acting.Intelligence (INT) - This is required for most of the careers in the game and reflects wit and memory. Still prized in the 25th Century.Wisdom (WIS) - Common sense and important to Medics in their practice, Rogues in keeping them from robbing the wrong people, and aids in certain skills.Tech (TCH) - Technical Knowhow that determines a character's affinity for machines and equipment. If a character has a high Tech skill, they have a better grasp on fixing things as well as people.Attributes, such as Strength and Dexterity, are also affected by the selection of race and certain bonuses and minuses are allotted across them as a result. For examples, Desert Runners are inherently stronger than the other races and, thus, have a bonus to their Strength and Constitution scores.AlignmentThis game does not use an alignment system. The party is expected to be on the side of "the good guys".CareersInstead of classes, Buck Rogers' uses a system based on careers instead with a series of skills associated with each one.Rocketjocks - They are the pilots of the Solar System, the daredevils that can drive anything as long as it can move.Warriors - These are seasoned fighters dedicated to the arts of combat. Every second level (2nd, 4th, etc..), warriors also earn a specialization bonus to their weapon of choice up to a maximum plus of 3 for each one.Medics - Advanced technology only means that medics can work their miracles even better than before. They can use onboard Medical Centers, cure poison, and otherwise bandage everyone back up.Rogues - No security system can stand in their way for long and they can also stay out of sight when someone comes looking for something they may be missing.Engineers - If it's broken, they can fix it. Not quite as much of a braggart as a Rocketjock, but they're close.SkillsThe also uses an extensive skill system based on what career a character has chosen along with a number of general skills that each can also develop, roughly similar to that used in Interplay's post-apocalyptic RPG, Wasteland.These represent a character's expertise with a particular field. Every new character gets an allotment of points to distribute among their career's skills and every level-up awards them with 40 points to distribute among their abilities. A maximum total of eighty points can be assigned to any one skill which translated as a percentage. Ability skills, such as those under the heading for Dexterity, also benefit from its score.For example, if the Pick Pocket skill has 20 points allocated to it and the character's Dexterity is 16, the end total for the skill would be 36 which translates into a success percentile of 36%.One unusual factor to consider is that among the skills offered to the player in this game, not all of them are actually used. The reason behind this is that they have been included in anticipation of the sequel, although this won't prevent a player from putting points into those skills.Dexterity SkillsAcrobatics - The skill of balanceClimb - The ability to scale over obstacles without equipmentDrive Groundcar - Anything on the ground is fair game. Not used in the game.Drive Jetcar - Ability to use a car powered by jets. Not used in the game.Hide in Shadows - The ability to stay out of sightManeuver in Zero-G - Important when fighting without gravity; characters will a low skill level will be penalized for every action they takeMove Silently - The ability to slip through terrain unnoticedPick Pocket - The five fingered discountPilot Fixed Wing Craft - The ability to fly jet or propeller powered machines; not used in the gamePilot Rocket - A rocketjock's bread and butterPlot Rotorwing Craft - Ability to fly a helicopter-type machine; not used in the gameUse Jet Pack - Ability to fly with a jet pack and not crashTech SkillsBypass Security - The ability to disable security systemsCommo Operation - Being able to repair and use communications equipment with easeDemolitions - Being able to place and defuse explosives without turning into little piecesFirst Aid - With this, you might not be able to fill in that hole in your leg, but you can bandage that cut next to itJury Rig - The skill to quickly patch fix equipment; requires Repair Mechanical and Repair Electrical skills at 10 each to useOpen Lock - Self explanatory, although electronic locks are covered by Bypass SecurityRepair Electrical - Can be used to make field repairs to a ship after combatRepair Life Support - A ship without an atmosphere is not a safe ship; requires Repair Mechanical at 25 and Repair Electrical at 30.Repair Mechanical - Anything mechanical can be fixed with a high enough skillRepair Nuclear Engine - Can be used to fix ships after combat; requires Repair Mechanical at 10Repair Rocket Hull - Another skill to help fix a ship after combat.Repair Weapon - Even the the future, weapons break. Useful to fix ships as well.Sensor Operation - The ability to use sensors and fix them; useful for getting an estimate on just how strong that rocket you attacked might beMedic SkillsDiagnose - Knowing what ails you is just as good as knowing how to cure itLife Suspension Tech - Allows you to use and fix life suspension equipment; not used in the gameTreat Critical Wounds - Severe injuries are treated with this; requires Treat Serious Wounds at 40Treat Disease - Allows you to treat diagnosed diseases; not used in the gameTreat Light Wounds - Field aidTreat Poisoning - Allows a character to heal poisoned party membersTreat Serious Wounds - Can only be used after combatTreat Stun / Paralysis - Can help members hit by sonic stunnersIntelligence SkillsAstrogation - Can be used to track and find places in space; requires Astronomy at 20 and Mathematics at 25Astronomy - Working knowledge of space; a prerequisiteBattle Tactics - Allows the party to become more efficient at combat in knowing what to expect; bestows bonusesDisguise - Need a new face on the fly? This is what you use.Library Search - Allows you to find whatever you want in a library, no matter how obscureMathematics - It's math. Prerequisite only.Mimic - Copy the voice of others. Great at parties.Navigation - Helps steering your rocketship; requires Astronomy at 15 and Mathematics at 25Planetology - Understanding of planetsProgramming - Ability to program both planetside and shipboard computersCharisma SkillsAct - The ability to perform as someone elseBefriend animal - Relate to animalsDistract - Determines how well you can divert someone's attentionEtiquette - Understanding of a culture's social norms without embarrassing anyoneFast Talk/Convince - The ability to make others see your idea as the best one before they can think twice about itIntimidate - How well you can scare others into believing that you're the only one they should be afraid ofLeadership - The ability to tell others what you need done and how to do it; with a high enough rating, you can take control of NPCs to help the partySing - How to sing without breaking glassWisdom SkillsNotice - Careful observation reveals many things and at higher levels, nothing stays hiddenPlanetary Survival - How to survive on a planetShadowing - Ability to follow others without being noticedTracking - Ability to follow tracks in the wildernessCombatThere are five different difficulty levels that determine the initial toughness of the combat encounters. They are, in the order of easiest to hardest:NoviceCadetTrooperVeteranAceThe game is preset at "Trooper" difficulty which is considered the average, or median, range of difficulty that is not too hard for newcomers yet not too easy as to present little challenge.The party-based Gold Box series of RPGs had standardized themselves on the engine that was pioneered with this game for both exploration and combat explaining the similarities between each one. Although each subsequent game would feature tweaks and modifications as a result of further gameplay enhancements, the basic structure and approach within this formula was always the same.Fighting in the game continues to be handled through random and set encounters wherein experience, items, and gold are earned. When combat begins, an isometric view (the combat map) is presented with every member and attacker shown as an icon.It is a turn based system with each side taking their turns to maneuver and issue commands. This tactical approach, in conjunction with the obstacles present onscreen such as walls and doorways, allowed the player to create their own strategies.Initiative played an important role in determining who goes first. Each round is divided into ten segments and every character and foe act on a specific segment determined by their initiative. Actions can be delayed and held until the end of round and the computer can fight for the player using the Quick command.Space CombatWith rocket ships and pilots, the game also involves space combat which is handled both from the pilot's perspective and that of the crew's. From the Pilot's Menu, the player can fire its weapons, target specific systems on the enemy ship, ram the enemy vessel, or even board it once they have pummeled it to the point where it can no longer move.This is not in real-time.During combat, the player can also give orders to the crew to help repair the ship, jury rig systems to get them working again, boost the engines, use sensors to probe the other vessel (thus revealing additional information), or administer aid to those injured.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16452">Pool of Radiance</game><game id="26463">Mines of Titan</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2369766-genesis_buckrogerscountdowntodoomsday.jpg</image></root>