<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5857</id><name>Dog's Life</name><description>Dog's Life was developed by Frontier Developments, published by Sony Computer Entertainment, and released for the Sony PlayStation 2 in 2003 in Europe, 2004 in North America, and 2005 in Japan.Kerry Shale voiced 32 characters in Dog's life -- enough to own the world record for the most characters voiced by a single voice actor in one game. GameplayThe player controls an average dog named Jake, with your main objective being to save another dog named Daisy whom Jake is keen to impress. She has been captured by the evil Miss Peaches and her two henchmen, Wayne and Dwayne, from a crooked cat food company. To advance through the game, Jake must find bones which can be obtained by digging them up, beating other dogs in a variety of challenges, completing challenges set by human characters or by collecting special smells.The game is divided into three different areas:Clarksville, a rural townLake Minniwahwah, a ski resort SmellovisionBoom CityThese locations are divided into even smaller areas such as farms and housing districts, each full of humans willing to give bones to you if you complete the desired mission. There are dangers in certain areas, with a dog catcher and a Doberman out to catch Jake.Certain smells can be collected using the game's "Smellovision", which can activate challenges against other dogs. These missions include races, obedience trials, tug-of-war games and a territorial game where the player must run around urinating in marked areas to obtain territory. Once this dog has been beaten, the player can take control of this dog and use his/her abilities to find bones that Jake cannot reach by himself. The other two challenges include scent collection challenges, and a minigame called the Doggy Do Challenge where you must copy the moves of the local dog.The player must also look after Jake by feeding him any of the food found around the area, or by begging from or growling at people in order to convince them to give him food, and cleaning him in the local salons, along with acquiring a new collar. After Jake has rescued all the other dogs, he proceeds to rescue Daisy from the deadly cat-food machinery, and it is implied that they intend to settle down and have puppies together.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3438">MediEvil II</game><game id="10148">Nintendogs</game><game id="43529">PlayStation Vita Pets</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2478652-box_dl.png</image></root>