<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5881</id><name>Forza Motorsport 2</name><description>Forza Motorsport 2 marks the first appearance of  Forza on the  Microsoft  Xbox 360. The game was developed by  Turn 10 Studios, an internal team at Microsoft, and was released on May 29, 2007.  Forza Motorsport 2 features lap-based races on several real-world circuits, including Sebring International Speedway, Road Atlanta, and Tsukuba Ciruit. The game features more than 300 cars, which are divided into four race classes and six production classes. Customizing your car with additional parts can improve its performance, and can also raise it up into a higher class. To keep things fair, some races have class restrictions. Car class is determined by performance index, or PI. The higher the PI the higher the class. PI can be raised by upgrading your car's Engine, Tires, Aero parts such as Wings and Bumpers, or Handling parts like Brakes, Springs, and Differential. Car Classes D-class carsThese are standard production cars that you would see most people driving around the streets in today like the Scion tC or a Volkswagen Beetle. Examples of competitive online cars in D-class would be the Volkswagen Golf or the Honda Civic VTi. D-class PI is 0 to 400.  C-class carsThese are sport production cars and have a highly competitive racing scene online due to C class races being more based on driver skill instead of the car. Examples of stock C-class cars would be a Nissan Fairlady Z the Audi S4. Examples of competitive online cars in C-class would be the Scion tC or the Honda Civic Type-R. C-class PI is 401 to 550.  B-class carsThese cars are performance production cars. Examples of stock B-class cars would be the Lotus Exige or the Porsche Cayman. Examples of competitive online cars in B-class would be the Chevy Cobalt SS or the Audi TT 07. B-class PI is 551 to 700. A-class cars These are high-performance production cars, and likely have the most competitive online scene. A-class races have the best balance between car performance and driver skill. Examples of stock A-class cars would be the Ferrari 360 Modena or the Audi Tuning Silverbullet S4. Examples of competitive online A-class cars would be the Volvo S60 or Nissan Fairlady Z version S. A-class PI is 701 to 850. S-class cars These are ultrahigh-performance production cars. The S-class online scene is more based on choosing the right car for the right track than driving skill. Examples of stock S-class cars would be the Dodge Hennesy Viper or the Pagani Zonda. Examples of competitive online S-class cars would be the Mitsubishi Lancer Evo X or the Subaru Impreza 22b STi. S-class PI is 851 to 998. U-class cars These are cars that have been upgraded beyond the PI of 998. U-class does not have much of a competitive online scene because U-class cars are very difficult to tune since they can easily get too powerful. Examples of stock U-class cars would be the Chrysler ME Four-Twelve concept car or the TVR Cerbera Speed 12. U-class PI is 999. CustomizationIn addition to customizing a car's parts for a performance boost, Forza Motorsport 2 also features a deep, layer-based livery editor that allows players to customize the paint color and apply vinyl shapes and lettering. Even though the game only provides basic shapes, some players have really taken this feature to extremes, re-creating famous real-world race cars or slapping corporate logos, anime characters, or classic video game characters all over the various cars. Another large mechanic (pun intended) of Forza 2 is car tuning. When players upgrade a car with parts, the cars class and performance index will increase. Upgraded parts can be tuned, improving the car's performance without changing its class. Players can tweak a variety of settings like tire pressure, ride height, gearing, and spring stiffness to make their cars perform better. The race class cars (R1, R2, etc.) cannot be upgraded but allow for tuning based on their class.Some players on the  www.forzamotorsport.net forums have taken tuning and painting to the next level. Users have formed tuning shops, which usually consist of painters, tuners, test drivers, and sellers. Painters will create an awesome paintjob for the car. Tuners meanwhile pick a class and a car, and try to tune it as well as possible for either short ,medium, or long tracks. After the tuner thinks they have done a good job, they will send the car over to the test driver, who will try the car out. Then the test driver sends the car back to the tuner with some feedback about the tuning. Usually the driver will let the tuner what needs to be done to improve it, for instance, if the car needs to accelerate faster, or if it has understeer or oversteer. After the tune has been tweaked and tested again, its ready for release. The car is sent to the sellers, who then stock the auction house with copies of the car so that everybody can enjoy it. A user-created Giant Bomb themed Lancer Evo VIII GSR The game features an innovative car auction system that lets players use in-game currency to bid on cars in real time. Players can choose how long the auction lasts, if it has a "buyout" option, and can have the car "featured" for an extra fee so the car sits at the top of the auction list. A few of the more rare autos called unicorn cars are only available via auction. Usually these unicorn cars are made by people that are on staff at Turn 10, like Fred Lowell, and will feature either the signatures of the Turn 10 team, or the signatures of other developers like their recent Too Human car featuring Dennis Dyack's signature. Tracks Real life tracks   Mazda Raceway Laguna Seca   Road Atlanta   Nürburgring Nordschleife   Mugello Autodromo Internazionale   Sebring International Raceway   Suzuka Circuit   Silverstone Circuit   Tsukuba Curcuit   Game tracks  New York Circuit  Nissan Speedway  Maple Valley Raceway  Sunset Peninsula Infield  Test Track Infield tracks  King Cobra BoomslangRussel's ViperDeath AdderCopperheadInland TaipanDiamondbackMalayan KraitBlack Mamba DLC tracks   Twin Ring Motegi (real)   Road America (real)Car ListAcura1997 Acura NSX 2000 Acura VIS Racing Integra Type-R 2002 Acura #42 Realtime Racing NSX   Aston Martin2001 Aston Martin V12 Vanquish 2005 Aston Martin DB9 Coupe  Audi2004 Audi TT Coupe 3.2 quattro 2000 Audi S4 2004 Audi S4 2003 Audi RS 6 2006 Audi RS 4 2000 Audi AWE Tuning SilverBullet S4 2001 Audi #4 Johansson Motorsport R8 2002 Audi #1 Infineon Audi R8 2004 Audi #5 Audi Sport Japan Team Goh R8 2004 Audi #88 Audi Sport UK Team Veloqx R8 2006 Audi #2 FSI Champion Racing R8 2004 Audi #8 Audi ABT TT-R 2002 Audi #1 Champion S4 Competition 2003 Audi #1 Champion RS 6    2006 Audi R10 #8 Audi Sport Team Joest (September Car Pack)2008 Audi R8 (December Car Pack)1983 Audi Sport Quattro (December Car Pack)2007 Audi S5 (March Car Pack)2007 Audi TT Coupe S-line (March Car Pack)  Bentley2004 Bentley Continental GT 2003 Bentley #7 Team Bentley Speed 8  BMW1997 BMW Motorsport M3 E36 2005 BMW Motorsport M3 E46 Coupe 2002 BMW Motorsport M3-GTR 1999 BMW Motorsport #15 BMW Motorsport V12 LMR 2005 BMW Motorsport #2 BMW Motorsport M3-GTR 1991 BMW M3 E30 (December Car Pack)2008 BMW Motorsport M3 E92 (March Car Pack)1971 BMW E9 Motorsport 3.0 CSL (March Car Pack)  Buick1987 Buick Regal GNX  Cadillac2004 Cadillac CTS-V 2002 Cadillac #6 Team Cadillac Northstar LMP-02 2004 Cadillac #16 Team Cadillac CTS-V  Chevrolet2005 Chevrolet Cobalt SS Coupe 2002 Chevrolet Camaro 35th Anniversary SS 2002 Chevrolet Camaro SS 1996 Chevrolet Corvette Grand Sport 2002 Chevrolet Corvette Z06 2006 Chevrolet Corvette Z06 1969 Chevrolet Camaro Z28 1969 Chevrolet Camaro SS Coupe 1970 Chevrolet Chevelle SS-454 1967 Chevrolet Corvette Stingray 427 1970 Chevrolet Corvette ZR-1 2003 Chevrolet Corvette Guldstrand Edition 2002 Chevrolet Lingenfelter 427 Corvette 2004 Chevrolet #3 Corvette Racing C5.R 2006 Chevrolet #4 Corvette Racing C6.R 2003 Chevrolet #73 3R-Racing Corvette Z06 2005 Chevrolet #31 Whelen Engineering Corvette Z06 2005 Chevrolet #99 Tiger Racing Corvette Z06  Chrysler2004 Chrysler PT Cruiser GT 1998 Chrysler Eagle Talon TSi Turbo 2006 Chrysler Crossfire SRT6 2005 Chrysler ME Four-Twelve Concept 1968 Chrysler Plymouth Barracuda Formula-S  Dodge2003 Dodge SRT4 1996 Dodge Stealth R/T Turbo 2006 Dodge Charger SRT8 1999 Dodge Viper GTS ACR 2003 Dodge Viper SRT10 2003 Dodge Viper Competition Coupe 1969 Dodge Charger R/T-SE 2000 Dodge Hennessey Viper 800TT 2000 Dodge #57 Carsport Holland Viper GTS-R 2001 Dodge #58 Larbre Compétition Viper GTS-R 2002 Dodge #1 Team Zakspeed Viper GTS-R 2003 Dodge #126 Team Zakspeed Viper GTS-R 2005 Dodge #77 Team Zakspeed Viper ACR 2003 Dodge #23 Magellan Financial Viper Competition Coupe 2004 Dodge #22 3R-Racing Viper Competition Coupe 1970 Dodge Challenger R/T Hemi (September Car Pack)2006 Dodge Challenger Concept (September Car Pack)  Ferrari2005 Ferrari 612 Scaglietti 1994 Ferrari F355 Berlinetta 1999 Ferrari 360 Modena 2002 Ferrari 575M Maranello 1991 Ferrari 512 TR 1998 Ferrari F355 Challenge 1984 Ferrari GTO 2004 Ferrari F430 2003 Ferrari Challenge Stradale 1987 Ferrari F40 1995 Ferrari F50 2002 Ferrari Enzo Ferrari 1969 Ferrari Dino 246 GT 1964 Ferrari 250 GTO 1967 Ferrari 330 P4 1998 Ferrari #12 Risi Competizione F333 SP 2003 Ferrari #72 Team Alphand Aventures 550 Maranello GTS 2003 Ferrari #88 Veloqx / Prodrive Racing 550 Maranello 2005 Ferrari #11 Larbre Competition 550 Maranello GTS 2006 Ferrari #62 Risi Competizione F430GT 2006 Ferrari FXX (December Car Pack)2007 Ferrari 599GTB (December Car Pack)1996 Ferrari F50 GT (March Car Pack)1989 Ferrari F40 Competizione (March Car Pack)2007 Ferrari 430 Scuderia (March Car Pack)  Ford2003 Ford Focus SVT 2006 Ford Focus ST 2005 Ford Mustang GT 2000 Ford Mustang Cobra R 2005 Ford Ford GT 1970 Ford Mustang Boss 429 1966 Ford GT40 MkII 2003 Ford FocusSport SVT Focus 2004 Ford #10 Tiger Racing Mustang  Honda1994 Honda Civic 1.5 VTi 1995 Honda CR-X Del Sol SiR 1999 Honda Civic Si Coupe 2000 Honda Prelude SiR 1991 Honda CR-X SiR 2000 Honda Integra Type-R 2004 Honda Civic Type-R 2002 Honda Integra Type-R 2003 Honda S2000 1992 Honda NSX-R 2005 Honda NSX-R 2005 Honda NSX-R GT 2004 Honda Wings West Civic Si 2000 Honda Aerogear Integra Type-R 2004 Honda Mugen Civic Type-R 2002 Honda Mugen Integra Type-R 2003 Honda Mugen S2000 1994 Honda Do-Luck NSX 2003 Honda #16 G'ZOX NSX 2005 Honda #18 TAKATA DOME NSX 2005 Honda #8 ARTA NSX 2006 Honda Civic Si Coupe (September Car Pack)2007 Honda Civic Type-R (EDM) (September Car Pack)  Hyundai2003 Hyundai Tuscani Elisa  Infiniti2003 Infiniti G35 Coupe  Jaguar2007 Jaguar XK Coupe 1993 Jaguar XJ220 1961 Jaguar E-type S1  Koenigsegg2002 Koenigsegg CC8S2008 Koenigsegg CCGT (December Car Pack)  Lamborghini2005 Lamborghini Gallardo 1988 Lamborghini Countach LP5000 QV 1997 Lamborghini Diablo SV 2005 Lamborghini Murcielago 1999 Lamborghini Diablo GTR1967 Lamborghini Miura P400 (September Car Pack)2006 Lamborghini Miura Concept (September Car Pack)2007 Lamborghini Gallardo Superleggera (December Car Pack)2007 Lamborghini Murcielago LP640 (March Car Pack) Lancia1992 Lancia Delta Integrale EVO 1974 Lancia Stratos HF Stradale  Lexus2003 Lexus IS300 2002 Lexus SC430 2006 Lexus IS350 2003 Lexus Foose Design IS430 Project Car  Lotus2003 Lotus Elise 135R 2005 Lotus Elise 111S 2005 Lotus Exige 2005 Lotus Exige Espionage 1989 Lotus Carlton 2005 Lotus Exige Cup 240 2002 Lotus Esprit V8 1972 Lotus Elan Sprint  Maserati2006 Maserati GranSport 2004 Maserati MC12 2005 Maserati #15 JMB Racing MC12 2005 Maserati #35 Risi Competizione MC12 2005 Maserati #9 Vitaphone Racing Team MC122006 Maserati MC12 Corsa (March Car Pack)2008 Maserati GranTurismo (March Car Pack) Mazda2005 Mazda Axela Sport 23S 2001 Mazda Mazdaspeed Familia 2001 Mazda Mazdaspeed Roadster 1990 Mazda Savanna RX-7 2004 Mazda RX-8 Mazdaspeed 1997 Mazda RX-7 2002 Mazda RX-7 Spirit R Type-A 1995 Mazda AB Flug RX-7 1995 Mazda INGS RX-7 1995 Mazda RE-Amemiya RX-7  McLaren1997 McLaren F1 GT 1997 McLaren #41 Gulf Team McLaren F1 GTR 1997 McLaren #43 Team BMW Motorsport McLaren F1 GTR  Mercedes2003 Mercedes CLK55 AMG Coupe 2004 Mercedes C32 AMG 2005 Mercedes SLR 1998 Mercedes AMG Mercedes CLK GTR 1954 Mercedes 300SL Gullwing Coupe  MINI2003 MINI Cooper-S  Mitsubishi2003 Mitsubishi Eclipse GTS 1995 Mitsubishi Eclipse GSX 2006 Mitsubishi Eclipse GT 1998 Mitsubishi FTO GP Version R 1997 Mitsubishi GTO 1999 Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution VI GSR 2004 Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution VIII GSR 2004 Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution VIII MR 2000 Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution VI TME 2006 Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution IX GT 1999 Mitsubishi MINE'S CP9A Lancer Evolution VI 2003 Mitsubishi Sparco Lancer Evolution VIII 2006 Mitsubishi HKS Time Attack Evolution2008 Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution X GSR (March Car Pack) Nissan1996 Nissan Silvia K's 1992 Nissan Silvia CLUB K's 2002 Nissan Skyline GT-R V-Spec II Nür 2003 Nissan Skyline Coupe 350GT 2000 Nissan Silvia Spec-R 2003 Nissan Fairlady Z 2002 Nissan Skyline GT-R V-Spec II 1993 Nissan Skyline GT-R V-Spec 1994 Nissan Fairlady Z Version S Twin Turbo 1998 Nissan R390 1969 Nissan Fairlady Z 432 1969 Nissan Fairlady Z 432R 2002 Nissan Tommy Kaira Skyline GT-R R34 2003 Nissan Fairlady Z Custom Edition 2000 Nissan Top Secret D1-Spec S15 2002 Nissan MINE'S R34 Skyline GT-R 1993 Nissan MINE'S R32 Skyline GT-R 1998 Nissan #32 NISSAN R390 GT1 2003 Nissan #12 CALSONIC SKYLINE 2003 Nissan #23 XANAVI NISMO GT-R 2003 Nissan #3 HASEMISPORT ENDLESS Z 2005 Nissan #46 Dream Cube's ADVAN Z2007 Nissan Altima (Nissan Car Pack)2007 Nissan Sentra SE-R Spec V (Nissan Car Pack)2007 Nissan 350Z (Nissan Car Pack) Opel2004 Opel Speedster Turbo 2003 Opel #5 OPC TEAM PHOENIX Astra V8  Pagani1999 Pagani Zonda C12 2003 Pagani #17 Carsport America Zonda GR  Panoz2005 Panoz Esperante GTLM 2003 Panoz #11 JML Team Panoz LMP-01 2005 Panoz #51 JML Team Panoz Esperante GTLM 2006 Panoz #81 Team LNT Panoz Esperante GTLM  Peugeot2007 Peugeot 207 RC 2004 Peugeot 206 RC 2007 Peugeot 207 Super 2000 1993 Peugeot #3 Peugeot Talbot Sport 905 EVO 1C 2007 #1 Peugeot 207 Super 2000 (March Car Pack / separate, free download) Pontiac2006 Pontiac Solstice 2004 Pontiac GTO 1968 Pontiac GTO Hardtop1973 Pontiac Firebird Trans Am (December Car Pack) Porsche2003 Porsche Boxster S 1989 Porsche 944 Turbo 1982 Porsche 911 Turbo 3.3 2006 Porsche Cayman S 2004 Porsche 911 GT3 (996) 2007 Porsche 911 Turbo (997) 1987 Porsche 959 2007 Porsche 911 GT3 (997) 1995 Porsche 911 GT2 2003 Porsche Carrera GT 1970 Porsche 914/6 1973 Porsche 911 Carrera RS 1987 Porsche #17 Racing Porsche AG 962c 1998 Porsche #26 Porsche AG 911 GT1-98 2004 Porsche #23 Alex Job Racing 911 GT3-RSR 2005 Porsche #31 Peterson-White Lightning 911 GT3-RSR 2005 Porsche #44 Flying Lizard 911 GT3-RSR 2005 Porsche #5 XBOX 360 911 GT3-RSR 2002 Porsche #57 Larbre McDonalds 996 GT3 Cup 2003 Porsche #22 3R-Racing 911 GT3 Cup 2005 Porsche #3 Lechner Racing School Team 1 911 GT3 Cup 2005 Porsche #55 Applied Materials 911 GT3 Cup 2005 Porsche #66 AXA Racing 911 GT3 Cup 2006 Porsche #81 Synergy Racing 911 GT3 Cup 2006 Porsche #82 Red Bull 911 GT3 Cup2007 Porsche 911 GT3 RS (997) (September Car Pack)1998 Porsche 911 GT1 (December Car Pack)2008 Porsche 911 GT2 (997) (March Car Pack) Proto2006 Proto Motors Spirra  Renault2003 Renault Sport Clio V6 RS1980 Renault 5 Turbo (December Car Pack)2007 Renault Renault-Sport Clio 197 (December Car Pack / separate, free download) Saab2002 Saab 9-3 Aero  Saleen2000 Saleen S281 2006 Saleen S281 E 2004 Saleen S7 2001 Saleen #26 Konrad Motorsports S7R 2002 Saleen #11 Graham Nash Motorsport S7R 2003 Saleen #2 Konrad Motorsports S7R  Saturn2006 Saturn ION Red Line2007 Saturn Sky Red Line (September Car Pack) Scion2005 Scion tC  SEAT2003 SEAT Leon Cupra R 2005 SEAT Cupra GT Prototype2007 SEAT Leon Cupra (September Car Pack / separate, free download)2007 SEAT  Leon Supercup (September Car Pack) Shelby2007 Shelby GT500 1999 Shelby Series 1 1968 Shelby Mustang GT-500KR 1965 Shelby Cobra 427 S/C  Subaru2005 Subaru Legacy B4 2.0 GT 2005 Subaru Impreza WRX STI 2004 Subaru Impreza WRX STi 1998 Subaru Impreza 22B STi 2006 Subaru Impreza S204 1998 Subaru Tommy Kaira Impreza M20b 2003 Subaru #77 CUSCO SUBARU ADVAN IMPREZA  Toyota1985 Toyota Sprinter Trueno GT Apex 2002 Toyota MR-S 1992 Toyota Supra 2.0 GT Twin Turbo 2004 Toyota Altezza RS200 2003 Toyota Celica SS-I 2002 Toyota Soarer 430SCV 1995 Toyota MR2 GT 1998 Toyota Supra RZ 1969 Toyota 2000GT 2002 Toyota Tom's W123 MR-S 1995 Toyota Border MR2 Turbo T-bar 1995 Toyota VIS Racing MR2 Turbo T-bar 2003 Toyota APR Performance Celica GTS 1995 Toyota Tom's T020 MR2 2002 Toyota Tom's Z382 Soarer 1992 Toyota Do-Luck Supra 1998 Toyota VeilSide Supra Fortune 03 1998 Toyota AB Flug S900 Supra Turbo 1998 Toyota VeilSide Supra Fortune 99 1998 Toyota Top Secret 0-300 Supra 1999 Toyota #3 Toyota Motorsports GT-ONE TS020 2004 Toyota #35 Yellow Hat YMS Supra 2005 Toyota #36 OPEN INTERFACE TOM'S SUPRA 2005 Toyota #6 EXXON Superflo Supra 2006 Toyota #25 ECLIPSE ADVAN SUPRA  TVR2001 TVR Tuscan S 2001 TVR Tuscan R 2005 TVR Sagaris 1998 TVR Cerbera Speed 12  Vauxhall2006 Vauxhall Astra VXR 2004 Vauxhall VX220 Turbo 2005 Vauxhall Monaro VXR  Volkswagen2004 Volkswagen Beetle 1995 Volkswagen Corrado VR6 1992 Volkswagen Golf GTi 16v Mk2 2003 Volkswagen Bora VR6 2006 Volkswagen Golf GTi 2003 Volkswagen Golf R32  Volvo2004 Volvo S60 R 2004 Volvo #24 At-Speed S60 R   Soundtrack Daft Punk is Playing at My House - LCD Soundsystem Come On - Andy Hunter Switch On (feat Ryan Tedder) - Paul Oakenfold Truckers Choice - DJ Mark Stinger - DJ Mark Rockstar (Jason Nevins remix) - N.E.R.D. Insomnia - Faithless Sonido Total - The Pinker Tones Look at What You get - Taxi Doll Put Your Hands Up - Ben Benassi Roboslut - The Crystal Method What you Want - Killing Bird and Jane Fontana Told You So - Tom Cloud Small Step on the Other Side - DJ Tiesto--Basic Perspectivce Body Language - Mandy Vs Brookashade Beautiful - Goldfrapp  Sink - Sister Machine Gun Lenny Penne - Underworld Elevate Myself - Grandaddy Break your Neck - Shy Child Witch in the Club - Quintron On Repeat (XFM Session) - LCD Sound System Off The Hook - CSS Lead Head - Beamish  Fly Slide In - Goldfrapp  Nothing Left - Orbital Positive Tension - Bloc Party Karma Hunters - The Pinker Tones Gone Daddy Gone - Gnarls Barkley Disco Infiltrator (FK's Infiltrated Vocal) - LCD Sound System Crash V8 - Kill Memory Crash Cobrastyle - TeddyBears Alala - CSS Rogue Rock - The Rogue Element BlackPowder - Motor Come Inside - The Chemical Brothers Solid Rock Razor Steele - Apollo 440 Rollin' Down the Highway - Apollo 440 If You're Gonna Jump (Paul Oakenfield Remix) - Natasha Bedingfield Lights Out - P.O.D. Spitfire - Prodigy Busy Child - The Crystal Method Weapons Of Mass Distortion - The Crystal Method Forza2 Theme - Junkie XL Remix Platinum Hits In August of 2008, Microsoft released Forza Motorsport 2 Platinum Collection. The disc contained all of the premium DLC car and track packs that Turn 10 had released including the March, September and December car packs and the Premium Track Pack, as well as several limited edition cars that were only available to people that pre-ordered the limited edition release of the original Forza 2 disc, all of these DLC packs have a retail price of around $20 USD. All of the extra content was placed on a second disc that has to copy itself to your hard drive. Forza Motorsport 2 Platinum Collection is available for $19.99 which makes it significantly cheaper than buying a stand-alone copy of Forza 2 and all the DLC. Xbox 360 Game InstallationForza Motorsport 2 requires 5.3GB of space to install on an Xbox 360  HDD.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20597">Gran Turismo 5 Prologue</game><game id="8844">Need for Speed: Carbon</game><game id="12976">Need for Speed: Most Wanted</game><game id="19809">Project Gotham Racing 3</game><game id="18095">Need for Speed: ProStreet</game><game id="20858">NASCAR 09</game><game id="6978">Enthusia Professional Racing</game><game id="21297">Gran Turismo HD</game><game id="11055">NASCAR 08</game><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="788">The Fast and the Furious</game><game id="3916">DiRT</game><game id="20936">Ferrari Challenge Trofeo Pirelli</game><game id="19522">Live for Speed</game><game id="16220">GTR: FIA GT Racing Game</game><game id="14858">GTR 2: FIA GT Racing Game</game><game id="6213">Race: The Official WTCC Game</game><game id="327">Race 07: The Official WTCC Game</game><game id="19563">Sports Car GT</game><game id="20038">NASCAR: Dirt to Daytona</game><game id="531">TOCA Race Driver 2</game><game id="22215">V8 Supercars 2</game><game id="9445">MotoGP '07</game><game id="15965">Sega GT</game><game id="8779">Sega GT 2002</game><game id="5869">TOCA Touring Car Championship</game><game id="8831">Need for Speed: Porsche Unleashed</game><game id="941">Project Gotham Racing</game><game id="6137">Driving Emotion Type-S</game><game id="8437">TOCA 2: Touring Car Challenge</game><game id="16276">Ford Bold Moves Street Racing</game><game id="5648">Burnout Paradise</game><game id="357">Burnout 3: Takedown</game><game id="16492">Burnout Revenge</game><game id="4970">Burnout Legends</game><game id="13514">Burnout 2: Point of Impact</game><game id="8459">Burnout Dominator</game><game id="10149">Burnout: Championship Drag Racing</game><game id="20919">Ford Racing: Off Road</game><game id="5977">Need for Speed III: Hot Pursuit</game><game id="7431">Ford Racing</game><game id="12950">Gran Turismo 3 A-Spec</game><game id="7777">Juiced</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="284">NASCAR 2005: Chase for the Cup</game><game id="8438">NASCAR 06: Total Team Control</game><game id="17274">MotoGP '06</game><game id="22693">RACE Pro</game><game id="17784">Gran Turismo 4</game><game id="20741">Need for Speed: Undercover</game><game id="1052">Super PickUps</game><game id="25226">Need for Speed World</game><game id="25225">Need for Speed: SHIFT</game><game id="8100">Gran Turismo 2</game><game id="26842">Gran Turismo</game><game id="20418">Midnight Club II</game><game id="5875">Midnight Club 3: DUB Edition</game><game id="20927">Midnight Club: Los Angeles</game><game id="21114">Midnight Club: Los Angeles Remix</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2213158-box_forza2.png</image></root>