<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>589</id><name>R:Racing Evolution</name><description>Overview R: Racing Evolution is what seems like an attempt by Namco to make a Ridge Racer game with more simulation like gameplay, with licensed real world cars such as the Audi TT and the Mazda RX-7, and a story based career mode called Racing Life.  Gameplay  The main mode of R: Racing Evolution was Racing Life mode, a 14 chapter story based career mode following Rena Hayami, a Japanese Ambulance driver who was recruited as a driver by the GVI coproration, and her rivalry with veteran racer Gina Cavalli. Other game modes include Event Challenge, Time Attack, Arcade, and Versus, with various race types like GT, Rally, and Drag racing.       One of the more unique gameplay features is the pressure system. When driving behind another car, a meter will appear above it, the longer you stay behind the car, the more pressure builds up filling the meter. Once the meter reaches a certain point, the driver will make a critical mistake, usually accompanied by a voiceover, allowing you to pass them.  Cars GT Class 1Chevrolet Corvette C5-RDodge Viper Competition CoupeHonda NSXBMW McLaren F1Calsonic SkylineSaleen S7 RToyota SupraVolkswagen W12Fiat 500 Type 110FBMW M3 GTRGT Class 2Pantera GT5 SLotus EliseAlfa Romeo 156 GTAHonda S2000Mazda RX-7Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution VIIIPeugeot 206Subaru WRX STi ImprezaDodge Charger R/TShelby G.T. 500DMC DeLoreanNissan 350ZGT Class 3Mini Cooper SAudi TT 1.8T quattroAcura RSX-Type SToyota VM180Prototype ClassAudi Infineon AUDI R8Bentley EXP Speed 8Advan Kondo S101Rally Class 1Ford FocusMitsubishi Lancer Evolution VIIIPeugeot 206Subaru WRX STi ImprezaMini Cooper SRally Class 2Acura RSX-Type SMini Cooper SAlfa Romeo Giulia GTA JuniorFiat 500 Type 110FRenault AlpineDrag ClassFord FocusDodge Charger R/TShelby G.T. 500Mazda RX-7Nissan 250ZPrivateer ClassAlfa Romeo Giulia GTA JuniorFiat 500 Type 110FRenault Alpine</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="941">Project Gotham Racing</game><game id="2279">Project Gotham Racing 2</game><game id="19809">Project Gotham Racing 3</game><game id="20729">GRID</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1797996-box_rre.png</image></root>