<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>5977</id><name>Need for Speed III: Hot Pursuit</name><description>Racing ModesSingle Race: Race on any track in any car. This was your overall basic race around the track.Practice: Self explanatory. This mode was offered in order for players to get a feel for the specifics of the track including each turn before trying in an actual race.Knock-out: A series of 7 races in which everyone except the car that ends up in last place continues to the next race. Last car left is the winner. In multiplayer, knocked out players come back in later races as a slow delivery truck (Multiplayer only available in PC version, not PS1 version)Tournament: A series of races in which racers accumulate points. At the end of the tournament the car with the most points win.Hot Pursuit: A mode in which cops are present while the player is race against an opponent. The PC version also lets the the player take controls over a cop car. This was the brand new feature for the series and ultimately the main draw of Need for Speed III.Hot PursuitIf the player chooses to race in Hot pursuit mode he/she will not just try to outrace an opponent, but also trying to escape pursuing cops. When the cops manages to slow down the player to under a certain speed, he/she will get a ticket. The player will lose the race if he/she receives more tickets than the number of laps in the race. The cops will not only try to stop the racers by overtaking them, but also use roadblocks and spike strips.Players can also be issued "warnings" if they pull over right away the first time the police are chasing them. This will only work once. Every other time, they will be fined until they are ultimately arrested.The player does get to listen in on police radio chatter, which reveals current locations of racers, police cars, as well as roadblocks and spike strips. It also reveal reactions to specific events, such as a racer's collision with a parked police car, as well as referencing the racer's passing speed.If the player chooses to be the cop. He/she must ticket all six racers before they complete their race (only available in the PC Version, not the PS1 version).TracksThe game has a total of nine tracks (including one bonus track), all of which are set in varied locations around in United States.HometownRedrock RidgeRocky PassAtlanticaCountry WoodsLost CanyonsThe SummitAquaticaEmpire City (bonus track)CarsFerrari 550 MaranelloFerrari 355 F1 Spider (not available in Hot Pursuit Mode)Italdesign ScigheraLamborghini Diablo SVLamborghini CountachJaguar XJR-15Jaguar XK8Aston Martin DB7'98 Corvette C5Mercedes SL600Mercedes CLK GTR.Lister Storm (Available from the Need for Speed website)El Nino (unlockable car with cheat code "SPOILT on Playstation"Police Pursuit VehiclesChevrolet Caprice ClassicFord Crown VictoriaEagle TalonFord Falcon (PC only)Lamborghini LM002 (PSX only)Land Rover DiscoverySoundtrackMusic was done by Rom Di Prisco, Saki Kaskas, and Matt Regan.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11055">NASCAR 08</game><game id="20038">NASCAR: Dirt to Daytona</game><game id="941">Project Gotham Racing</game><game id="2279">Project Gotham Racing 2</game><game id="19809">Project Gotham Racing 3</game><game id="8437">TOCA 2: Touring Car Challenge</game><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="7019">Ridge Racer V</game><game id="16276">Ford Bold Moves Street Racing</game><game id="20919">Ford Racing: Off Road</game><game id="1101">Ridge Racer 7</game><game id="531">TOCA Race Driver 2</game><game id="5869">TOCA Touring Car Championship</game><game id="13734">TOCA Race Driver 3</game><game id="17872">TOCA Race Driver 3 Challenge</game><game id="20927">Midnight Club: Los Angeles</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="21114">Midnight Club: Los Angeles Remix</game><game id="20418">Midnight Club II</game><game id="5875">Midnight Club 3: DUB Edition</game><game id="6499">RalliSport Challenge 2</game><game id="3916">DiRT</game><game id="20597">Gran Turismo 5 Prologue</game><game id="2416">Gran Turismo</game><game id="17784">Gran Turismo 4</game><game id="12950">Gran Turismo 3 A-Spec</game><game id="8100">Gran Turismo 2</game><game id="21297">Gran Turismo HD</game><game id="7482">Gran Turismo Concept: 2001 Tokyo</game><game id="21390">Gran Turismo Concept: 2002 Tokyo-Seoul</game><game id="7313">Gran Turismo Concept: 2002 Tokyo-Geneva</game><game id="13895">Gran Turismo 4: Prologue</game><game id="5881">Forza Motorsport 2</game><game id="17599">Forza Motorsport</game><game id="5648">Burnout Paradise</game><game id="16492">Burnout Revenge</game><game id="4970">Burnout Legends</game><game id="13514">Burnout 2: Point of Impact</game><game id="8459">Burnout Dominator</game><game id="20484">Burnout</game><game id="10149">Burnout: Championship Drag Racing</game><game id="788">The Fast and the Furious</game><game id="8779">Sega GT 2002</game><game id="14428">Sega GT Online</game><game id="15965">Sega GT</game><game id="20858">NASCAR 09</game><game id="21724">NASCAR Racing 2002 Season</game><game id="18428">NASCAR Thunder 2004</game><game id="5856">NASCAR Racing 2003 Season</game><game id="7431">Ford Racing</game><game id="7777">Juiced</game><game id="284">NASCAR 2005: Chase for the Cup</game><game id="8438">NASCAR 06: Total Team Control</game><game id="21164">Moscow Racer</game><game id="1052">Super PickUps</game><game id="6628">Test Drive 6</game><game id="24792">Asphalt 4: Elite Racing</game><game id="25485">Test Drive Unlimited 2</game><game id="31698">Need for Speed: Hot Pursuit</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1793299-box_nfs3hp.png</image></root>