<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6</id><name>WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2007</name><description>OverviewSmackdown Vs. Raw 2007 is a wrestling game developed by Yuke's and published by THQ on November 14th 2006. Smackdown Vs. Raw 2007 is the third game in WWE's Smackdown Vs. Raw franchise. Smackdown Vs. Raw 2007 was the first game in the series to be released on a non-Sony console.WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2007 was originally planned to also be released on the PlayStation 3 platform, but was ultimately cancelled before release.GameplayNew FeaturesSmackdown vs Raw 2007 introduced the analog grappling system to the series, allowing the player to grapple using the right analog stick. Using the stick alone would do a weak grapple, while using RB(R1 for PS2) together with the right stick would cause the player's wrestler to hold the opponent in a grapple hold. Moving the right analog stick again makes the player's wrestler perform a grapple move.Another new feature brought to Smackdown Vs. Raw 2007 is the fact that a characters move set changes depending on the weight class assigned to them. Also new to Smackdown vs Raw 2007 are environmental grapples. These environment hot spots allow the player to perform moves in a quick time event style control scheme that uses a specific place or item.MomentumMomentum MeterSmackdown Vs. Raw 2007 uses a momentum system for it's finishing maneuvers. The momentum meter will fluctuate back and forth depending on how well the player is doing in the match. If the player can pull off multiple types of moves in succession the momentum meter will rise quickly, however getting hit by the opponents moves will lower the meter. The characters attribute of clean or dirty will make a difference as to which moves will build the momentum meter quickly. Performing the same move repeatedly will make the players momentum meter fall.Location Specific DamageIn Smackdown Vs. Raw 2007 a player can target individual body parts. There is a graphic on the top of the screen that shows a silhouette of a wrestler for each player. As damage on a specific body part increases it will change color on the silhouette.StaminaStamina MeterEach player has a stamina meter located near the location damage image. If a player is using moves continuously without a break the stamina meter will drop. If the stamina meter drops all the way down the player will not be able to move for a short period of time. The stamina meter will replenish on it's own over time while not using any attacks.Game ModesWWE Smackdown Vs. Raw 2007 features several different game modes including many improvements over Smackdown Vs. Raw 2006.ExhibitionExhibition mode is the customizable, one match mode. Exhibition mode does not affect the players other modes and can be tweaked to choose the match type, modifiers, characters, arena, and can be played by two human players.SeasonIn season mode the player chooses a character and will play through a season. Throughout the season players will be involved in story lines which will change slightly depending on how the player performs in the matches.GM (General Manager)In GM mode the player assumes the role of the general manager on one of the brands competing against the general manager of the other brand. GM mode lasts for one in game year and the goal is to win GM of the Year award at the end of the year. In the role of GM the player can make trades, sign free agents, set up shows, initiate story lines, and more.PPV (Pay-Per-View)In Pay Per View mode the player creates a pay per view show. The player chooses the matches on the card, what kind of matches, and arena the event takes place in.Locker RoomThe locker room is mainly used throughout a season mode, but can be used at other times. The locker room is where the player can go to do thing such as: adjust wrestler attributes, visit the WWE Shop, check the trophy/belt case, and view the challenges.OnlineOnline mode is where the player would go to play Smackdown Vs. Raw 2007 online. The online mode is much like exhibition mode in single player, but instead it is against other human opponents over the internet. In order to play the online mode on the PS2 version of the game the online adapter must be attached.RosterRaw SuperstarsSmackdown SuperstarsLegendsThe Big ShowCandice MichelleCarlitoChavo GuerreroChris MastersDaivariEdgeJohn CenaKaneKurt AngleLance CadeLitaMick FoleyMickie JamesRic FlairRob Van DamShawn MichaelsShelton BenjaminSnitskyTorrie WilsonTrevor MurdochTriple HTrish StratusUmagaVisceraBatistaBobby LashleyThe BoogeymanBooker TChris BenoitFinlayThe Great KhaliGregory HelmsHardcore HollyJohn "Bradshaw" LayfieldJillian HallJoey MercuryJohnny NitroKen KennedyKid KashMark HenryMatt HardyMelinaPaul BurchillPsicosisRandy OrtonRey MysterioSuper CrazyThe UndertakerVitoWilliam RegalBam Bam BigelowBret HartCactus JackDude LoveDusty RhodesEddie GuerreroHulk HoganJerry LawlerJim NeidhartMankindMr. PerfectThe RockRoddy PiperShane McMahonSteve AustinTazzSoundtrackBandSong TitleNonpointAlive and KickingNonpointBullet With a NameThree Days GraceRiotThree Days GraceAnimal I have BecomeVersus the WorldForgive MeBullets and OctaneI Ain't Your SaviorBlack Stone CherryLonely TrainLil' Scrappy Feat. Young BuckMoney in the BankAlleleStitchesRise AgainstSurviveGhostface KillahThe ChampGodsmackThe EnemyXbox 360 InstallationThe amount of memory it takes to install this game is 6.5 GB.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20469">TNA iMPACT!</game><game id="18333">Backyard Wrestling 2: There Goes the Neighborhood</game><game id="10158">M.U.S.C.L.E.</game><game id="22464">Wrestling Encore</game><game id="20723">WWE Legends of WrestleMania</game><game id="28430">WWF Royal Rumble</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2139899-box_wwesdraw07.png</image></root>