<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6016</id><name>Worldwide Soccer Manager 2007</name><description>World Wide Soccer Manager (Sold in the United Kingdom as Football Manager ) is the third game in the Football Manager series by Sports Interactive. Sports Interactive are known for their Championship Manager Series but split with Eidos and went to sega to produce the game under the new name. Championship Manager is still developed every year by a company called Beautiful Game Studios. It was released for the PC, Mac, Apple-Intel on 18 October 2006 . The Xbox 360 versions were released in December 2006.The new version includes over 100 new features as well as small adjustments and bug fixes which is generally what the annual update of the series is suppose to do.New FeaturesSports Interactive continue to evolve the series in the 2007 edition. Some of these new features are:A new default GUI, created with the input of user feedback. The new interface is said by SI to be more user-friendly.A revamped scouting engine, allowing for more realistic scouting of potential stars. including the ability for scouts to 'learn' from their experience. A "scout report card" is also included, in order to provide easier access to important, detailed information about scouting targets.Enhanced media interaction, including the ability to make comments on any player in the game world. In previous versions featuring media commentary, managers could only comment on other managers.An improved youth team system. The method for generating new players is completely revamped, with the older "regen" system - using recycled statistics from retired players - no longer in use.Pre-match team talks. Previously, only half-time and full-time team talks could be given. SI has also increased the half-time team talk functionality: managers can now target individual opposition players for special attention, such as instructing players to close them down or always to tackle them with force.A hints and tips screen appears when the game is being saved or loading is taking place.An option to ask your own team's players what staff (e.g. coaches, physios) or players they would like you to bring to the club has been added.Interactions with the board are improved. The board can authorise the building of new stadia. Clubs can be taken over by a group of investors, who may opt to fire the manager (a player may get sacked in the process).The manager, as well as NPCs, can comment on referees' decisions, which are not always correct.Feeder ClubsA significant new addition is the ability to create a feeder club affiliation. This allows larger clubs to set up a relationships with a smaller club and vice versa. This can be used by users managing larger clubs to 'farm' out players to their feeder club to gain the first team experience that they are unable to get at higher levels. They both work together for mutual benefit, Smaller clubs can benefit from the ability of these players on loan deals, and can also receive financial help. The larger club may also profit from merchandising in the smaller club's country.The smaller club may also benefit from lucrative friendly matches against their parent side, as well as getting "first option" on signing players that are to be released by the larger team. American and Chinese teams used as feeder clubs are generally known to be extremely lucrative to a parent club's income through merchandising.You will sometimes find when you take control of a feeder team that some of your players are currently loaned out to one of your feeder clubs. Manchester United and Royal Antwerp have feeder club affiliation in the game.DemoOn Saturday, September 30, 2006 a demo of the game was released in four different versions: Strawberry and Vanilla for both Mac and PC.The Vanilla demo is basic and only includes English language, and the English league, with no kits, player photos, sound, graphics etc.The Strawberry demo includes playable leagues for Brazil, Denmark, England, Finland, France, Italy, Norway, Portugal, Scotland, Spain and Sweden, many kits and player photos, and language support for many other regions.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="454">FIFA Soccer Manager</game><game id="3753">FIFA Manager 07</game><game id="19272">FIFA Manager 07: Extra Time</game><game id="5605">FIFA Manager 06</game><game id="11964">Pro Cycling Manager: Season 2006</game><game id="21612">90 Minutes: European Prime Goal</game><game id="8108">Championship Manager Season 97/98</game><game id="1586">Total Club Manager 2003</game><game id="9757">Front Office Football 2001</game><game id="6697">Premier Manager Ninety Nine</game><game id="4805">Soccer Team Manager: English and Italian Leagues</game><game id="32911">FIFA Manager 11</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4527/2179826-1.jpg</image></root>