<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6029</id><name>Super Punch-Out!!</name><description>Summary Super Punch-Out!! is the sequel to the original game on the  Nintendo Entertainment System,  Mike Tyson's Punch-Out!!. Although Super Punch-Out!! does not contain the likeness of  Mike Tyson, it brings over familiar characters from the first Punch-Out!!! The returning characters are  Super Macho Man,  Bald Bull, and  Mr. Sandman. Super Punch-Out!! was released on October 1, 1994 in  North America, on March 1, 1994 in  Japan, and on January 26, 1995 in  Europe.Gameplay  Super Punch-Out!! has similar gameplay to the original. You face a single opponent, and are able to sway left and right, and do both right and left punches to the body and head. From there, however, there are several subtleties to the gameplay that--for better or worse--make Super Punch Out!! a much deeper experience than the original.Basic PunchingThe four normal punches you can throw vary in speed and strength. The relationship of how fast a punch is to how powerful it is is inverse. From quickest and weakest to slowest and most powerful, the order of the punches is as follows: Left  Jab, Left Body, Right Jab, Right Body. Mixing the punches up accordingly may yield extra hits or extra damage, so finding the proper mix of punches can yield quicker K.O. times for time trials.As in the original Punch Out!!, you can throw a powerful  uppercut, but instead of stars, this time you have a meter that fills up as you fight. This meter does not deplete as you use it. Instead, getting hit by your opponent depletes the meter. (The amount is based on the damage of the punch.) Your uppercut, furthermore, is simply one of four available "special" punches. You can also deal a vicious hook to the body, and rapid punches to both the head and body. The difference between the head and body special blows is the speed and power with which the blows connect, with shots to the head being slightly quicker and less powerful and shots to the body being slightly slower and more powerful.Counter PunchingCounter-punching is much more fleshed out and flexible this time around. In the original Punch Out!!, there were a few rare instances during which you could hit your opponent just as he was about to land a punch (throwing a body punch at  Von Kaiser or  Great Tiger as they crouch to launch an uppercut, or tagging  Bald Bull in the head just before he throws a jab). In Super Punch Out!!, the counter punch's rate of success is much, much higher and the appropriate techniques are called out in the game's tutorial. When your opponent is about to throw a left-handed punch, you counter with a right-handed punch, and vice versa. You must also take the height of the blow into consideration. If he's about to throw a jab or hook at your face, you counter with a jab to his face; similarly, if he's about to throw a hook at your body, or crouches for an uppercut, you must counter with a body blow. The challenge is in reading the opponent's tell--each punch's tell is distinguishable from one another, but sometimes only subtly so (most difficult being the difference between a hook to the face and a hook to the body). Mastering the counter-punch is key to speedy victories and--in some cases--survival, as a successful counter-puncher ends up nullifying many opponents' attacks before they can even be unleashed.Dizzy SpellsSuccessful counter-punching or otherwise dominant performances will sometimes yield a "dizzy" animation, in which your opponent either doubles over, sways from side to side, or otherwise stumbles about. Hitting your opponent with a power punch during a precise moment in these "dizzy" animations may yield an instant knockdown and, in rare cases, result in a full 10-count and victory.Other DifferencesSuper Punch-Out!! sports a Time Attack mode, which allows you to fight against fighters from any circuit you've beaten to try and improve your K.O. times.Unlike the original, in Super Punch Out!!, speech bubbles will appear from both sides of the screen, representing orders and hints coming from the opponent's coach.  These often clue you in to which technique your opponent is about to unleash, giving you time to take proper action.Techniques employed by the fighters in Super Punch Out!! require a much higher level of suspension of disbelief in relation to the original Punch Out!!. Several fighters use weapons and what would normally be illegal blows and tactics, including but not limited to: overhead blows; grabbing and throwing; kicking; spitting;  headbutts; juggling balls; elbows; and a walking stick. Super Punch-Out!! contains four circuits. However, unlike Mike Tyson's Punch Out!!  the final boss does not have its own circuit. The circuits--and the fighters within--consist of:Minor Circuit Gabby Jay  Bear Hugger -- uses illegal two-handed overhead strikes Piston HurricaneBald BullMajor Circuit Bob Charlie Dragon Chan -- uses illegal kung fu kicks Masked Muscle -- uses illegal spitting and headbuttsMr. SandmanWorld Circuit Aran Ryan -- uses illegal grab-and-throw tactics Keike Kagero -- uses illegal strikes via his long hair Mad Clown -- uses illegal juggling balls which he throws at you, as well as illegal two-handed overhead strikesSuper Macho ManSpecial Circuit Narcis Prince Hoy Quarlow -- uses illegal kung fu kicks and strikes with his walking stick Rick Bruiser -- uses illegal elbows Nick Bruiser -- uses illegal shoulder chargesReception When Super Punch-Out!! was released it was praised for the style of it's graphics, the simple controls and the diversity of the characters. IGN said that the game overall was great but that it lacks the appeal that the original game has. They also said that the sound and music was not as memorable. The game has a 83.5% score at GameRankings. Re-ReleasedSuper Punch-out!! was available as a bonus for  GameCube owners for the lack of online play that the  Xbox/ PS2 version had. If the player beats Super Punch-Out!!, Little Mac will be unlock as a playable character in  Fight Night Round 2.  Opponent DetailsBelow are images and statistics for your opponents, grouped by circuit:Minor CircuitThe Minor Circuit is the easiest circuit in the gameGabby JayGabby JayGabby Jay is the first opponent in the Minor Circuit."Fighting" Gabby Jay He is also pathetically easy.The instruction booklet says he was trained by  Glass Joe, who is the only person he's ever won against. From....France  Age.... 56Weight....110lbs.Record....1-99Quotes: First Match: Let me win.  I've lost so many times I forget how winning feels.Rematch: I like winning!  Keep challenging me, it's good for my ego.Ending:  I'll never retire!  I can win at least one more! C'mon!Bear HuggerBear HuggerBear Hugger is the second opponent in the Minor Circuit.Stomach punches are no match for the wrath of Bear Hugger! He, like many other fighters, is an semi-offensive stereotype, this one being of  Canadians.He amps up the difficulty slightly, but is still pretty easy if you know what you are doing.  From....CanadaAge....32Weight....440lbs. Record.... 17-12Quotes: First Match: Watch out! I am a killer- I am the Bear HuggerRematch:  You've come back for another spanking, eh?Ending:  I've heard someone can beat me in 17 seconds.Piston HurricanePiston Hurricane  Piston Hurricane is the third opponent in the Minor Circuit.  He was a fighter in the original  Punch Out!!! for arcade.Feelin' the Hurricane Rush. He is yet another easy opponent.His stereotype is  CubanFrom.... CubaAge..... 25Weight.... 170lbs.Record..... 21-10Quotes:First Match: Can you ride out the storm or be caught in my "Hurricane Rush"?Rematch: Hmmph!!  Don't you know when to give up?Ending: My Hurricane Rush must not have worked... Bald BullBald Bull Bald Bull returns from  Mike Tyson's Punch Out!!!He is the last opponent in the minor circuitHe is significantly easier than he was in Mike Tyson's Punch Out!!!Look out for the Bull Charge. His stereotype is  Turkish.From....TurkeyAge....36Weight....290lbs.Record....34-19Quotes:First Match:  You'll be down for the count with one punch from my "Bull Charge"Rematch: You've got a lot of guts to challenge me again!Ending: Don't be so proud.  I pulled my punches when we fought.Major Circuit               The Major Circuit is the second circuit in the game.  This is where things start to get difficult.Bob CharlieBob CharlieBob Charlie is an original character for Super Punch Out!!!   He is the first opponent in the Major Circuit, and as far as difficulty goes, he possesses a moderate challengeHis stereotype is clearly  Jamaican  (Get it?! Bob Marley?! Bob Charlie?!)From....JamaicaBob Charlie, Lookin' Intense.Age....26Weight....140lbs.Record....24-13Quotes:First Match:  "People who can't feel the rhythm are so lost, do you have the rhythm?"Rematch: "Hey you! You don't seem to have the rhythm."Ending: "Hey mon! Let's have fun once more!"Dragon ChanDragon ChanDragon Chan is the second fighter in the Major Circuit, and the first really difficult one.  He uses a lot of kicks, which the ref says nothing about, partly due to this being a video game.  He has one move where he does a random set of kicks to the right and left, and knowing where to dodge takes some good reaction timeHis stereotype is  Chinese.Dragon Chan. Getting ready to practice his kicks....in a boxing ring.From.... Hong KongAge.... 22Weight....130lbs.Record....15-7Quotes:First Match: "You will find yourself face down... When you wake up."Rematch: "Same results each time.  The world of fighting is a harsh one, isn't it?"Ending: "When I woke up... It was me lying on the mat"Masked MuscleMasked MuscleMasked Muscle is the third fighter in the Major Circuit, and he is quite difficult.  He is not a fair fighter, throughout the match, his coach will yell "Spit in his eye", at which point he will try to douse your perfect eyes in his saliva.  If hit by this vicious attack, you will be unable to attack for about 10 seconds.His stereotype is  Mexican.Luchadeer take note, this is where it's at.From....  MexicoAge.... 29Weight.... 240lbs.Record....19-5Quotes:First Match: "You should give up now senor"Rematch: "Cheater? I don't know what you're talking about, amigo."Ending: "Have your bruises healed yet amigo?Mr. SandmanMr. Sandman.Mr. Sandman returns from Mike Tyson's Punch Out!!!, presumably to get revenge for Little  Mac beating him down right before he reached Super Macho Man.  Mr. Sandman is pretty difficult, but he is a lot easier than his NES counterpart.Stereotype: None really... But before Bob Charlie he was the only African-American in the series.Enter the Sandman Express.From.... U.S.AAge.... 28Weight.... 230lbs.Record .... 29-3Quotes:First Match: "Had your goodnight kiss?  'Cause I'm about to put you down for the night."Rematch: "I hate holding back.  This time I won't hesitate to use all my power on you"Ending: "Ready for your nap now? I demand a rematch!"</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="20">Boxing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13997">George Foreman's KO Boxing</game><game id="14685">Fight Night Round 2</game><game id="14768">Boxing Fever</game><game id="14857">Toughman Contest</game><game id="20930">FaceBreaker</game><game id="19836">Ready 2 Rumble Boxing</game><game id="16516">Seconds Out</game><game id="17218">Riddick Bowe Boxing</game><game id="18841">Crossed Swords</game><game id="32275">Pilgrim's Punch-Out</game><game id="19968">Champion Boxing</game><game id="30215">Onizuka Katsuya Super Virtual Boxing</game><game id="28262">TKO Super Championship Boxing</game><game id="37375">Ring ni Kakero</game><game id="36937">Sakura Samurai: Art of the Sword</game><game id="34475">Hajime no Ippo: The Fighting!</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2364843-snes_superpunchout.jpg</image></root>