<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6049</id><name>Sam &amp; Max Save the World</name><description>OverviewSam  Max Save the World consists of: Episode 1: Culture Shock Episode 2: Situation: Comedy Episode 3: The Mole, the Mob, and the MeatballEpisode 4: Abe Lincoln Must Die!Episode 5: Reality 2.0Episode 6: Bright Side of the Moon Distribution Sam and Max Season One was initially distributed through  GameTap, a subscription based PC gaming service, and followed by a worldwide release through Telltale Games' own website 15 days later. The series also saw a full release on    Valve's Steam distribution service. A Wii version of the game was announced on April 4th 2008, and is a port of its PC counterpart, albeit with integrated motion controls. On February 26th 2009, Telltale announced the game would be released on XBLA with the new name of 'Sam  Max: Save the World' (instead of the season one subtitle). Episode 4, Abe Lincoln Must Die!  is available for free both on    Steam  and from    Telltale's website. The XBLA version of the game was released on Wednesday, June 17 for 1600 Microsoft points.GameplayThe primary gameplay in Sam and Max consists of leisurely walking around the Freelance Police officers' office and its city surroundings, such as a continuously career changing lady friend's office, Bosco's Inconvenience Store and various other locations, depending on the episode. Players are tasked with solving puzzles and answering riddles to advance the game's story, which shoots for the comical stars. Bosco's in Reality 2.0.Pointing and clicking on an area allows the player to move Sam (Max follows without getting in the way), while "clicking/button pressing" examines specific objects, and adds them to your inventory as necessary. Items are often needed for later puzzles, so combining certain collected goods and inserting, dropping, or applying them to things will usually solve a good chunk of the game's puzzles. From Sam's revolver to a slice of cheese, the variety of collectibles is ridiculously varied.There is also a driving component of the game, where the player controls the gas and side-to-side motion of Sam's police cruiser, while simultaneously integrating a combat mechanic using Sam's revolver. Shooting out baddies tires completes certain objectives, and also garners some angry remarks from civilian traffic. Innocents can be pulled over for speeding (or a busted tail light, should you decide to shoot it out) if players bore of driving aimlessly.The dialogue system heavily influences the story, though in a linear fashion. Sam and Max will need to be quick on the tongue with witty dialogue to get the info they need, or out of a dilemma. Many puzzles center around this conversation mechanic, such as talking down crazed enemies, and immense trickery!</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game><game id="8759">The Longest Journey</game><game id="20696">Penny Arcade Adventures: On the Rain-Slick Precipice of Darkness - Episode One</game><game id="21174">Full Throttle</game><game id="7894">Phoenix Wright: Ace Attorney - Trials and Tribulations</game><game id="7088">Toonstruck</game><game id="265">CSI: Crime Scene Investigation - Hard Evidence</game><game id="209">Tiny Toon Adventures: The Great Beanstalk</game><game id="21914">A Vampyre Story</game><game id="2845">Gabriel Knight 3: Blood of the Sacred, Blood of the Damned</game><game id="9345">Zack &amp; Wiki: Quest for Barbaros' Treasure</game><game id="16965">Syberia</game><game id="1975">Syberia II</game><game id="2564">Overclocked</game><game id="22262">Dracula Origin</game><game id="21670">Wallace &amp; Gromit's Grand Adventures Episode 1: Fright of the Bumblebees</game><game id="21090">A New Beginning</game><game id="5729">The Curse of Monkey Island</game><game id="22111">The Whispered World</game><game id="10837">Bone: Out from Boneville</game><game id="10505">Bone: The Great Cow Race</game><game id="21667">Gray Matter</game><game id="23689">Penny Arcade Adventures: On the Rain-Slick Precipice of Darkness - Episode Two</game><game id="24962">Full Throttle: Payback</game><game id="17638">Scooby-Doo Mystery</game><game id="26776">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 1: Launch of the Screaming Narwhal</game><game id="27084">Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People</game><game id="23066">Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People Episode 2: Strong Badia The Free</game><game id="26777">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 2: The Siege of Spinner Cay</game><game id="27322">Time Gentlemen, Please!</game><game id="31059">Nelson Tethers: Puzzle Agent</game><game id="31965">Revenge of the Balloon-Headed Mexican</game><game id="26778">Tales of Monkey Island Chapter 3: Lair of the Leviathan</game><game id="32796">Tales of Monkey Island</game><game id="32592">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 1: It's About Time</game><game id="34211">Hector: Badge of Carnage</game><game id="33414">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 2: Get Tannen!</game><game id="33415">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 3: Citizen Brown</game><game id="33416">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 4: Double Visions</game><game id="33417">Back to the Future: The Game - Episode 5: OUTATIME</game><game id="38889">Back to the Future: The Game</game><game id="40113">Edna &amp; Harvey: Harvey's New Eyes</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4938/902611-savetheworld_big.jpg</image></root>