<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6101</id><name>Kung-Fu Heroes</name><description>STORY  Jacky and Lee   return from a long trip to find out that their princess, Min-Min, had been kidnapped.  10 of their kingdom's treasures had been stolen as well.  They set off to 8 of the enemy's      castles in  order to reclaim these treasures as well as rescue the princess. Title Screen  GAMEPLAY The game consists of 8 castles consisting of 4 stages each and is playable by two players cooperatively.  In order to exit each stage, the brothers must defeat 12 enemies before the exit door at the top of the screen will open.  Players can punch various blocks throughout each of the stages (as well as somersault into hidden spaces on the stage) to find power ups and hidden treasures that will help them get through each stage.  First Stage   ITEMS  ?-Ball : Randomly generated when punching blocks, can give you either $-Bags or the dreaded X-Ball.$-Bags: Collect 5 and an E-Ball will be generated.  If you are able to collect 6 without encountering an X-Ball, you can create a P-Ball.  You can hold up to six $-Bags at a time.X-Ball: Causes your $-Bag counter to drop to zero.     E-Ball:  Collect 5 of theses to get a 1-UPG-Ball:  Allows you to shoot fireballs at enemies for a short time, however these fireballs are not effective on all enemies.   Using the G-Ball P-Ball:  Invincibility (except from pits, moving walls, and certain other hazards).  It allows you to kill enemies by touching them while it lasts.  Normally available only if you have 6 $-Bags, but one can be found on stage 7-1.  1-UP:  Extra life, you can have up to 9 at a time. Key:  Opens up a stairway to a bonus stage or warp.Treasure Box:  Contains a punch power up, 5 miracle kicks (a more powerful moonsault), or one of the 10 treasures.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2361934-nes_kungfuheroes.jpg</image></root>