<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6124</id><name>Venture</name><description>ObjectiveYou play as Winky, a circular smiley face with a bow and arrow for a weapon. Winky can move and shoot in eight different directions. While he moves in straight lines quickly, Winky's gameplay control when shifting directions is slow and awkward. Most of the game's difficulty comes from Winky's lack of directional agility.Upon beginning a stage, you will be located in the outside "hallway". When Winky is in the stage's hallway, he is represented as a small dot and cannot shoot. The objective in the halls is to avoid green Hall Monsters while entering white doors to individual rooms.In each stage, there are four individual rooms with one or two entrance points each. In each room there is a treasure that Winky needs to grab, but also enemy creatures that will impede his path. After grabbing the treasure, Winky needs to exit the room alive. After succeeding in this task, the completed room will "white out" and become inaccessible. By completing all four individual rooms in each stage, that stage is considered complete, bonus score is tallied, and the next stage begins with new rooms and new treasure.The bonus score is determined by a timer. The faster you finish a stage, the more bonus points you earn. There's no penalty for being slow, however you may not receive any bonus points. These bonus points are instrumental in racking up extra lives.The Treasure ChartIncomplete ChartEach time you start a game, start a new stage, or die, you will be shown your blue treasure chart, which contains 36 question marks. Each time you find a treasure, it will replace the question mark on the chart. The act of finding a treasure requires you to enter each room, grab the treasure, and make it out of the room alive (killing all enemy creatures is, however, not required). There are nine total stages with four treasures each. While Venture is played for score, the ultimate goal is to complete the treasure chart.Hall MonstersThe Hall Monster means RUN FOR IT!The Hall Monsters are green evil entities that inhabit the halls of each stage. Each one is invincible and will pursue Winky tirelessly. In addition to guarding the halls, they will also enter individual rooms if you stick around for too long. They can not be defeated by any means, so the the only way to avoid Hall Monsters from inside rooms is to exit the room immediately. Their main purpose to to supply Winky with a sense of urgency, as each room must be completed rapidly to avoid death by Hall Monster.Enemy CreaturesEach room is named after its creature inhabitant. These creatures almost always act identically. Some creatures won't appear until Winky enters a specific portion of the room or until he grabs the treasure. One arrow shot will kill any creature, and that creature's corpse will remain on the screen for a short period of time. In a unique twist, the corpse of any creature is just as deadly as a live creature, so touching dead enemies is not allowed. Even more so, shooting a dead corpse will reset its decomposition timer, keeping it on screen for a longer period of time. In this way, shooting wildly can be terribly counterproductive, especially if enemy corpses are blocking your path to the treasure or your only exit!Stage 1: PinkGoblin RoomStage 1 LayoutMost outside doors are easy to get to, so navigating the inner hallways is not necessary nor recommended. Only the top right Serpent Room requires using the inside door, and it's generally simple to get to without much threat from Hall Monsters.Goblin RoomSkeleton RoomContains two doors and three goblins. The lower door is the preferred entrance, with a more direct path to the treasure and more time to line up your arrow shots. Grabbing the treasure and heading out the way you came in makes this room pretty painless.Skeleton RoomSerpent RoomContains two doors and three skeletons. The left door is the safer entrance, but it's a longer path to the treasure and it can sometimes be difficult to sneak in that door from the outside. With the treasure tucked away down a far path, you've got to be quick! Exiting out to the right is the safest play.Serpent RoomContains two doors and three serpents. Entering from the left is practically required, as the three serpents crowd around the right door and there's little to no time to react. Shoot yourWall Roomenemies fast, as their corpses will likely block access to the treasure for a short duration due to the cramped quarters.Wall RoomContains two doors and four moving walls. Either entrance is a safe bet. Wait for the top or bottom wall to open all the way up, then sneak into the center. The middle areais safe, so wait patiently for the upper or lower walls to completely retract again, then run back out.Stage 2: BlueSpider RoomStage 2 LayoutUse the wide open spots on either side of the map to avoid the Hall Monsters. These spots can also be used to lure Hall Monsters away from the middle room's door, which can be difficult to get into. Most other doors are fairly unobstructed and easy to get to.Spider RoomTroll RoomContains two doors and three initial spiders, followed by two additional spiders. Either entrance works fine. Kill what spiders you can, moving into the wider open spots to the top and bottom of the screen. Once you grab the treasure, any remaining spiders and spider corpses will immediately disappear, and two new, yellow spiders will appear, one in front of each door. If you kill both spiders, make a run for the door that is less obstructed.Troll RoomTwo-Head RoomContains one door and three trolls. The room is initially blocked off so you cannot get into the inner chambers. After a few moments, wall sections will disappear allowing you to get inside. Kill what trolls you must and navigate between the remaining obstacles to find the safest and quickest path, then get the heck out!Two-Head RoomContains two doors and four two-headed creatures. The enemies do not appear until you grabDragon Roomthe treasure, and two will appear down each of the exit paths. Try to concentrate diagonal fire down one path and don't get stuck in a crowded path with live monsters. If a creature on one side is tucked away in a corner where you can't get to it, switch sides, but be fast about it. It's quite difficult to get out of the room before the Hall Monster shows up.Dragon RoomContains one door and four dragons. You'll be bombarded from the moment you come in the room, so the best tactic is to shoot to the sides and try to move left or right into the open spaces in order to buy time. If the dragons are driven away from the treasure, go grab it and shoot the dragons on the way out. If you miss your first few shots when you come in, go back out the door and come back in to reset the room and try again.Stage 3: YellowCyclops RoomStage 3 LayoutStick to outside doors, as they are easiest to get into and also tend to give the best tactical advantages once you get inside individual rooms. Getting into the center room can be tricky if the Hall Monsters gather there. Try to lure them out one side, then go around the other side to the door.Cyclops RoomContains one door and three cyclops. The cyclops have theGenie Roomunique ability of warping around the room, to they can be tough to kill and tougher to anticipate. It's completely possible for a cyclops to warp on top of you, registering instant death. Kill what you can, but the ultimate goal of this room is to grab the treasure and get out as fast as humanly possible.Genie RoomContains two doors and three genies. The top door is too tight to maneuver, so use the bottom door to come in and leave. Move right first to give yourself more shooting room, and try to drawDemon Roomthe last genie out of the small corner where the treasure is.Demon RoomContains two doors and three demons. The demons won't appear until you enter the narrow area of the key-shaped room, forcing you into a difficult shooting position. Grabbing the treasure and moving back out of the narrow area fast can keep this from happening, and usually shooting only one or two demons is necessary.Bat RoomBat RoomContains one door and three bats. There's not a lot of room move around and the bats close in fast, so accuracy matters most here. If you miss your first few shots, exit the room and come back in to reset the enemy locations.Stages 4 - 9Treasure Hoarding!After completing the three initial stages, stage four will return you to the "pink" hall with faster Hall Monsters and slightly faster creatures in each room. The same goes for stages 5 (blue) and stage six (yellow). Stage seven again returns you to the pink hall with very fast Hall Monsters that tend to make a direct beeline for you. The creatures in each room also waste less time meandering and instead rush forward to attack you. After completing stages 8 (blue) and 9 (yellow), you will have completed your treasure chart. Stage 9 will continue to repeat endlessly until you run out of lives.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="40771">Route-16</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2367842-a2600_venture_none.jpg</image></root>