<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6141</id><name>Mega Man Anniversary Collection</name><description>OverviewThe Mega Man Anniversary Collection contains all six of the original                       NES                      Mega Man games,         Mega Man 7 released on the                    SNES, and the                   PlayStation version of      Mega Man 8.These versions are not emulated, but are rather ports.  As a result, slowdown has been reduced (although not entirely eliminated) and various additional features have been added, such as the  rapid fire ability and NAVI mode for the original NES games.  NAVI mode adds an improved                 HUD interface, a map screen with hints, and remixed music.  In addition, a save feature replaces the need for a                password system in all games that previously used it.Rather than using a typical select screen to choose a game, the menu contains Mega Man 8               sprites of Mega Man, which the player  must control and move towards the capsule that marks the game that they want to play.  List of games in collection:                           Mega Man (NES)                          Mega Man 2 (NES)                          Mega Man 3 (NES)                          Mega Man 4 (NES)                          Mega Man 5 (NES)                          Mega Man 6 (NES)                          Mega Man 7 (SNES)                          Mega Man 8 (PlayStation)                          Mega Man: The Power Battle (             Arcade Release)                          Mega Man 2: The Power Fighters (Arcade Release)Mega Man: The Power Battle and Mega Man 2: The Power Fighters take the series' trademark             boss fights and turn them into a game all their own.  The player chooses among Mega Man and some of his familiar allies, fighting against the series' boss robots en route to defeating    Doctor Wily.  The boss robots have slightly modified powers, though they still fit thematically with the enemy. Version differences:In the           PlayStation 2 and            Xbox version of Mega Man Anniversary Collection, players can select between using the original game music and remixed music during each game.  The          GameCube version only uses the original music during the games, though players can listen to the remixed music in a separate   Jukebox mode. The PS2 version also contains an episode of the Mega Man animated TV series.  The GameCube and Xbox versions of the game had a series of interviews with the staff from G4's program  "Icons" (now called "Game Makers"), although the video of         Pokémon Ruby had been taken out due to obvious legal  issues.   Port Issues In Mega Man 7 The port of Mega Man 7 lacks support of the Mode-7 chip, used for high-tech graphics. This is hard to emulate, so        Atomic Planet had to cut some graphics out of this game port, most notoriously the credits sequence, which is a normal white-on-black scroll in the ported version of this title.    Cancelled Game Boy Advance PortInitially, this game was to be put on the      Game Boy Advance using ports of the     Game Boy Mega Man titles instead. However, the game soon was put on hold for a long time, and eventually was officially canceled by       Capcom. The reason for this is still unknown.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="15">Compilation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1483">Mega Man X Collection</game><game id="29768">Mega Man Zero Collection</game><game id="544">Super Mario All-Stars &amp; Super Mario World</game><game id="18529">Super Mario All-Stars</game><game id="9463">Mega Man X</game><game id="18707">Final Fantasy Collection</game><game id="14455">Final Fantasy Chronicles</game><game id="7866">Final Fantasy Origins</game><game id="38070">Kirby’s Dream Collection Special Edition</game><game id="1164">Dragon Warrior I &amp; II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2525214-box_mmac.png</image></root>