<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>620</id><name>Star Ocean: The Second Story</name><description>  OverviewStar Ocean: The Second Story is a Japanese Role-Playing game developed by Tri-Ace and released in 1999 under the publisher Enix, before they merged with Squaresoft. It takes place 20 years after the events of the first game, but prior knowledge is not required to understand The Second Story. The game has sold over 1 million copies worldwide, and was remade for the PSP under the name Star Ocean: The Second Evolution.Story Star Ocean: The Second Story allows the player to choose one of two main characters at the beginning of the game –                  Claude C. Kenny, son of the war hero                 Ronixis J. Kenny; or                Rena Lanford, a peaceful girl living in a small rural village. The overall plot remains the same for each, but there are certain scenes and characters exclusive to each. Claude is suddenly transported to Rena’s home planet of               Expel when investigating some ruins on an alien planet, and her village recognizes him as the Hero of Light of their legends. Claude tries to explain that it’s a misunderstanding, but ends up traveling with her to investigate the Sorcery Globe, a meteorite that recently crashed on the planet and seems to be causing animals to go berserk and attack people. At first, Claude tries repeatedly to get in contact with his father and their ship; but when he finally does, he realizes that he’d much rather stay on Expel with Rena. The story unfolds as they uncover more secrets and end up on another planet with their fellow travelers they pick up on the way.  Characters  Claude Kenny   Along with Rena, Claude is one of the main heroes of Star Ocean.  Claude is the son of Ronixis Kenny, captain of the Calnus. While on an away team sent to investigate a strange signal coming from the planet Milocinia, Claude gets caught in a transporter beam and is             teleported to a far away planet called Expel.  In Claude's efforts to find a way home, he becomes involved in a quest to save Expel. Race: Human Race: Human  Type: Fighter  Gender: Male                                           Age: 19 years old                                                                              Rena Lanford  Along with Claude, Rena is one of the main heroes in Star Ocean. Rena Lanford's journey begins with one of her many travels into the Shingo Forest.  After traveling further into the forest than ever before, Rena gets attacked by a beast. She is then rescued by a mysterious stranger wielding a "Sword of Light" who turns out to be Claude.  Rena believes that Claude is a Legendary Warrior, who was coming was foretold.  Race: Nedian  Type: Mage   Gender: Female Age: 17 years old                                                                      Celine Jules  Celine is a child of well known mages from Mars Village.  Celine practices the Heraldic Arts, and uses her abilites to explore the dungeons and caves of Expel.  She searches for the thrill of danger, as well as for all of the treasures they contain.  Race: Expel  Type: Mage  Gender: Female  Age: 23 years old             Ashton Anchors    Ashton is a "Sword for hire" who often ends up being in the wrong place at the wrong time.  When you first meet Ashton, he is victim to an accident that has caused him to be fused with the two headed dragon he had been fighting.  He joins your quest with the hopes of finding a way to cure what has happened.   Race: Expel  Type: Fighter  Gender: Male  Age: 20 years old            Precis F. Neumann   Precis is a incredibly perky, hyper inventor.  Precis is from the town of Linga, and is from a long line of respected inventors.  She develops a crush on Claude which causes her to join the party.    Race: Expel  Type: Fighter  Gender: Female  Age: 16 years old           Opera Vectra   Opera is from an extremely wealthy family on the highly advanced planet of Tetragenes.  Opera crash landed on Expel while searching for her boyfriend named Ernest.  Opera joins your party in hopes of finding her Boyfriend   Race: Tegragenes  Type: Fighter  Gender: Female  Age: 23 years old            Bowman Jean   Bowman is a pharmacist, and runs a small pharmacy in Linga.  Despite his appearance, Bowman is a skilled fighter who craves for adventure.   Race: Expel  Type: Fighter  Gender: Male  Age: 27 years old          Ernest Raviede  Ernest is an archaeologist from the advanced planet of Tetragenes.  He came to Expel to research some ruins.  He is the boyfriend of Opera Vectra.     Race: Tetragenes  Type: Fighter  Gender: Male  Age: 35 years old         Leon Geeste   Leon is a scientific prodigy, and works with his parents inside of Lacour Castle.  They research magical ways to help Expel fight off evil brought on by the Sorcery Globe.   Race: Fellpool  Type: Mage    Gender: Male  Age: 12 years old      Dias Flac  Dias is a friend of Rena, who is extremely skilled with a blade.  You often get to see him prove it in battle, however due to his preference to travel alone causes him not to join your party.    Race: Expel  Type: Fighter  Gender: Male    Age: 25 years old      Noel Chandler   Noel is the caretaker of the Cavern of the Red.  He aides you as you travel through the cavern as you attempt to tame the last wild Synard.   Race: Nedian  Type: Mage  Gender: Male  Age: 24 years old    Chisato Madison  Chisato is a reporter for the Nede Chronicle.  She follows your party looking for a good story while you travel around Nede.     Race: Nedian  Type: Fighter  Gender: Female  Age: 22 Years old  Combat  Combat in Star Ocean 2 The combat uses a random battle mechanic, and the battles themselves are fought in real-time (except for spell animations). Up to four characters can be    in battle simultaneously, with the player controlling one and the computer handling the others. There are a variety of AI settings and formations to choose from to make fighting easier. The system allows the player to run around freely in the battle area, which is useful for dodging enemy attacks and choosing which enemy to attack first. There is a simple attack button, which causes the character to run up to the nearest enemy and attack with their weapon. There are also special techniques characters can learn that can be assigned to the L1 and R1 buttons. This limits the player-controlled character to only two techniques in battle, but they can be swapped out of battle. Techniques level up and get more powerful the more they are used.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="595">Tales of Eternia</game><game id="11497">Final Fantasy XII</game><game id="12277">Final Fantasy VIII</game><game id="6336">Final Fantasy VI</game><game id="4793">Final Fantasy V</game><game id="8825">Final Fantasy IX</game><game id="259">Grandia III</game><game id="10129">Grandia II</game><game id="20818">Infinite Undiscovery</game><game id="18304">Xenogears</game><game id="17659">Grandia</game><game id="10518">Eternal Sonata</game><game id="10896">Vagrant Story</game><game id="16716">Legend of Legaia</game><game id="13053">Final Fantasy VII</game><game id="20829">Final Fantasy IV</game><game id="11237">Final Fantasy X</game><game id="3762">Thousand Arms</game><game id="19621">Ys: The Ark of Napishtim</game><game id="10401">Radiata Stories</game><game id="13180">The Legend of Dragoon</game><game id="11602">Valkyrie Profile</game><game id="7940">Rogue Galaxy</game><game id="23947">Tales of the World: Radiant Mythology 2</game><game id="34076">Final Fantasy IV: The Complete Collection</game><game id="36336">Tales of Graces F</game><game id="36335">Tales of Destiny</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2108512-box_so2.png</image></root>