<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>621</id><name>Doom II: Hell on Earth</name><description>OverviewDoom II: Hell on Earth is a first-person shooter developed by id and published by GT for the PC on September 30, 1994. The direct sequel to Doom, Doom II: Hell on Earth pits the nameless space marine through 30 levels (this time not split into episodes) taking place on a demon-infested Earth, as he tries to liberate the last remaining space port (which would allow all of the surviving humans to evacuate), and then attempts to shut down the portal (located in his home city) where the invaders are coming from. The game adds a variety of new enemies (including chaingun-equipped Heavy Weapon Dudes and the Lost Soul-spawning Pain Elementals), a new weapon (the Super Shotgun, a more powerful version of the Shotgun), and a new powerup (the Megasphere, which grants 200% health and 200% armor).Along with the 30 main levels, there are two secret levels based on id's previous first-person shooter, Wolfenstein 3-D. Along with the map layout and textures, these levels have a secret enemy ripped from the game, the SS Officer. Commander Keen, from id's first game series, does make an appearance in one of these levels....An official level pack for Doom II: Hell on Earth was released on December 26, 1995. Titled "Master Levels for Doom II", the expansion includes 21 new levels (not tied together in a stream of levels) contracted to different mapmakers (including John W. Anderson, Jim F. Flynn, Christen David Klie, Sverre Andre Kvernmo, Tom Mustaine, and Tim Willits). As a bonus, 1,830 amateur WAD files (for Doom, Doom II: Hell on Earth, and Heretic) from the internet are also included as "Maximum Doom".StoryPublic services have suffered during the invasion.Picking up where Doom left off, the space marine has made it back to Earth at the conclusion of the first game, only to find that Hell has infested the planet. Cities burn and Humanity is on the brink of extinction. In a last ditch effort to save what is left of the Human race, the last remnants of mankind attempt to evacuate the planet via a giant space faring vessel. However a defensive barrier shield is keeping them from leaving orbit, and can only be disabled inside the heart of an infested space port. Having successfully fought through the invasion on Phobos and Deimos (which was floating above the surface of Hell itself) in the last game, this last suicide mission to infiltrate the spaceport and deactivating the barrier falls upon our stalwart hero.Upon reaching level 11 in the game, Circle of Death, the player character successfully deactivates the field and frees the vessel in orbit, allowing Humanity to escape their dying world. Having apparently accomplished his mission the player sits down to wait for death, until a new mission goal is received during the game's story intermission sequence:Should I come back later?"You have won! Your victory has allowed Humankind to evacuate Earth and escape the nightmare. Now you are the only Human left on the face of the planet. Cannibal mutations, carnivorous aliens, and evil spirits are your only neighbors. You sit back and wait for death, content that you have saved your species. But then, Earth control beams down a message from space: "Sensors have located the source of the alien invasion. if you go there, you may be able to block their entry." The alien base is in the heart of your own home city, not far from the starport. Slowly and painfully you get up and return to the fray."No explanation is ever made for the text confusing demonic entities from Hell for extraterrestrials. The main character's "home city" is never mentioned by name, as the level's title reads only "Downtown." Once reaching "The Suburbs" in level 16, the player finds the gateway and realizes the only way to seal it must be from the other side, meaning that once again, our hero must make another incursion into Hell itself. After fighting his way through various stages of Hell, we arrive at the Icon of Sin, which seems to be the entity creating the physical manifestations of the demon army. Upon entering its chamber, the Icon of Sin greets the player with unintelligible backwards speech and begins spawning demons into the chamber. Firing missiles into the exposed brain of the Icon of Sin kills the horrific abomination, and in its death throes its massive tentacles destroy "untold miles of Hell's surface" and closing the gateway just after the space marine flees through it, having saved the universe from an invasion by Hell itself.Health StatesHealthVisual80%-200%Normal60%-79%Slightly bloody nose40%-59%Grimace with bloody nose20%-39%Fatigued with gushing nose1%-19%Fatigued with bloody eyes and nose0%Completely covered with bloodInvulnerabilityNormal, with glowing golden eyesDifficulty LevelsSkill LevelNotesI'm too young to die!Ammo items: double amount. You take half damage. Far fewer enemies.Hey, not too rough.Ammo items: regular amount. Fewer enemies.Hurt me plenty.The default difficulty level.Ultra-Violence.Ammo items: regular amount. More enemies than usual.Nightmare!Ammo items: double amount. Cheat codes disabled. Same amount of enemies as Ultra-Violence, but they move faster and respawn after death.* Doom also alters placement and amount of monsters and items depending on difficulty level.WeaponsDoom II: Hell on Earth adds a single new weapon to the Doom arsenal: the Super Shotgun.FistFistDamage: 10 per punch, 200 with Berserk PackWhen entirely out of ammo, your fists are your last option of self defence. The damage and attack rate of the fists are very low, however, with the berserk power-up the fists turn into a deadly weapon for the duration of the level.ChainsawChainsawDamage: 20 per 'hit'The chainsaw nearly nullifies the fists' existence with its superior damage and attack speed. The chainsaw is particularly useful against Demons or Lost Souls, as they only have melee attacks and cannot harm you while you use the chainsaw in their direction. It is most effective against one enemy at a time, since multiple enemies can get around the blade and damage you. Despite its usefulness, aside from Demons and Lost Souls, the chainsaw should still be seen as a last resort when low on ammo.PistolPistolDamage: 10 per bulletThe starting weapon, the Pistol uses Bullet ammunition. Its damage and attack speed are low and crappy, and once the player is in possession of the Chaingun, which also uses Bullets, it can be safely disregarded.ShotgunShotgunDamage: 10 per pellet, 7 pellets per shell, 70 damage maximumThe shotgun was the "go-to" weapon of the original Doom, and it retains that usefulness in this sequel. Its fire rate is slow, but the high damage output makes up for it. Many players remembers the enemies' HP by how many shots from the shotgun they require. The shotgun is surprisingly good at taking out enemies at medium-to-long range, as its pellets are more concentrated than those of the Super Shotgun. It uses Shell ammunition.Super ShotgunSuper ShotgunDamage: 10 per pellet, 21 pellets per 2 shells, 210 damage maximumThe sole new addition to the Doom II arsenal, the double-barrelled "Super Shotgun" won the heart of many gamers. The fire rate is even slower than that of the original Shotgun, and the spread is much wider, rendering it useless at long range, but the damage output is very, very high, so at close range, it is absolutely devastating. This property makes it a valid weapon to use against powerful adversaries such as Hell Knights or Arch-Viles. It uses Shell ammunition and fires two shots at a time.ChaingunChaingunDamage: 10 per bulletThe chaingun is the second fastest firing weapon in the game. Its damage per bullet is at the same level of the pistol, but the high fire rate makes it into a deadly weapon. It is especially useful against enemies such as Cacodemons or Pain Elementals, since it fires so often that it causes them to flinch a lot, making it difficult for them to finish an attack.Rocket LauncherRocket LauncherDamage: 200 per rocketThis is a very deadly weapon - both to the enemies and the player himself, thanks to the unexpectedly large splash damage radius. The rockets deal a very high amount of damage and have splash damage. Furthermore, the Rocket Launcher's fire rate is high, which makes the player able to carpet bomb areas. The Rocket Launcher, predictably, uses Rocket ammunition.Plasma GunPlasma RifleDamage: 20 per cellThe Plasma Gun is often compared to the Chaingun, because of their similarities. They both have a high firing rate and is generally useful in the same situations. The main difference between them is the projectile speed. Whereas the Chaingun's bullets hit the target instantly, the Plasma Gun's shots have to travel through the air before hitting the target, making it possible for enemies to dodge incoming attacks. The trade-off for this inaccuracy is a much higher damage output. The Plasma Gun uses Cell ammunition.BFG 9000BFG 9000Damage: 1000 per blast, 40 cells expendedBig-Fantastic-Gun, Big-Fucking-Gun, Bio-Force-Gun - no one really knows what the "BFG" stands for, but one thing is certain: it is a big freaking gun. The BFG 9000 fires a ginormous plasma ball which moves slowly through the air. Upon impact, the target it hits receives a huge amount of damage, and nearby enemies in the player's visual range receive additional attacks for a high amount of damage as well. The player in unable to damage himself with the weapon, which makes it the best weapon of choice against large groups of enemies that are relatively close to the player. It uses Energy Cell ammunition, and burns up 40 Cell with each shot.EnemiesEnemies returning from the original DoomFormer HumanHealth: 20Former Human(AKA Zombie, Zombieman)One of the most common enemies encountered. These are the reanimated bodies of humans killed during Hell's invasion of Earth as foot soldiers for Hell's Legions. They commonly use one shot rifles and can drop clips of Bullet ammo upon dying.Shotgun GuyHealth: 30Shotgun Guy(AKA Zombie Sergeant, Shotgun Zombie, Former Human Sergeant)A variant of the Former Human. More physically fit than most reanimated corpses, these undead soldiers are equipped with shotguns which can drop for your own use.ImpHealth: 60ImpWeakest among Hell's Legions, these low ranking Hell Spawn are roughly the size of a human. While only slightly stronger than a human, they are the most numerous of Hell Spawn along with Demons and fling burning hellfire at foes, as well as being able to slash at foes with their razor-sharp claws at close range.DemonHealth: 140Demon(AKA Pinkies, Pinky Demons)These are average Hell Spawn. They make up the bulk of Hell's Legions along with Imps. They are not very intelligent, but they are much larger and faster than humans. They tear enemies apart with teeth and claw, but have no ranged attack to speak of. They are best dispatched with the Chainsaw, which prevents them from attacking.SpectreHealth: 140Spectre (artist's impression)The Spectre is a variation of the Demon, the creature's skin is translucent making it appear partially invisible. Just as aggressive, strong and fast as normal Demons, its natural camouflage makes it much more dangerous.Lost SoulHealth: 100Lost SoulMuch larger than an actual Human head, the exact origins of these flying, flaming, horned skulls is unknown, though it is known that they travel in numbers, and move slowly until they charge a target without warning, rushing in to bite at them from close range. The best tool to deal with Lost Souls from a distance is the Chaingun.CacodemonHealth: 360CacodemonCacodemons are high ranked Hell Spawn. Unlike their less intelligent brethren, they are capable of using powerful magic and will breath balls of arcane lightning at foes. Less numerous, they are far deadlier. Heavy weaponry, such as the Plasma Rifle or Rocket Launcher, is suggested, especially if they appear in numbers.Baron of HellHealth: 1000Baron of HellLeading the forces of Hell's Legions are Barons of Hell. They are Hell Spawn of the highest order and as such far more powerful. They are very few in number but their sheer strength makes death among their ranks very rare. Like Imps, they are capable of attacking with claws from up close, or with flaming projectiles from afar, but both of their attacks are significantly more powerful than those of their weaker brethren. Heavy, focused firepower is necessary to take even one Baron down.CyberdemonHealth: 4000CyberdemonIn the rare event that a Baron of Hell is killed, a much more dangerous creature is born. A perverted fusion of magic and machine, the Cyberdemon is a reanimated Baron of Hell merged with the very technology used to slay it. Its left hand has been replaced with a rocket launcher, equipped with an endless supply of rockets; even one direct hit can kill a soldier in perfect health if he isn't wearing heavy armour. Although it can be countered with another rocket launcher, realistically, the BFG 9000 is going to be required to kill this monstrosity, the most powerful monster in the game.Spider MastermindHealth: 3000Spider Mastermind(A.K.A. Spiderdemon)Highest ranked among Hell Spawn, acting Generals for Hell's Legions. There are even fewer of them than the Baron's of Hell. Physically they are even weaker than Imps, but they possess a vast intellect. They direct all of Hell's designs and employ human technology, re-enforcing their frail bodies with mounted chain guns.New Enemies introduced in Doom IIHeavy Weapon DudeHealth: 70Heavy Weapon Dude(A.K.A. Former Commando, Chaingunner)Another variation of the Former Human. In life they were the strongest soldiers among Humans, now in death they carry the most devastating of human weapons in the service of Hell's Legions. Their chainguns can be collected upon dying.Hell KnightHealth: 520Hell KnightPowerful Hell Spawn that failed to join the ranks of the Baron's of Hell, the Hell Knight are direct servants of the true Barons. They are not as powerful but do not take them lightly.ArachnotronHealth: 450Arachnotron(A.K.A. Spider babies, Mini-Masterminds)A young Spider Mastermind that has equipped itself with more cutting edge technology than its brethren. It's weapon of choice is a mounted plasma cannon.Pain Elemental(A.K.A. Cacodads)Health: 350Pain ElementalUnique Hell Spawn of high rank, these creatures refuse to directly combat their foes. Instead they vomit forth an army of corrupted Lost Souls to do their killing for them. They have two sphincters.RevenantHealth: 380RevenantWhen the bodies of Former Human's decay, they become Revenants. Casting away the shackles of muscle and flesh, and powered by foul magic, these undead monstrosities are far stronger and faster than human beings and no longer need to wield human weaponry.MancubusHealth: 650Mancubus(A.K.A. Fatties)High ranked Hell Spawn that have been fused with human technology. They are massive and hard to kill, and their arms have been augmented with Flame Throwers.Arch-VileHealth: 700Arch-VilePowerful even among the highest order of Hell Spawn, the Arch Vile wields foul magic that perverts life itself. This rare creature holds mastery over death and can resurrect fallen Hell Spawn back into service, though magical interference renders them incapable of returning other Arch-Viles to life; in addition, they cannot return Spider Masterminds or Cyberdemons to the realm of the living, perhaps because even in death they are more powerful than the Arch-Vile performing the incantation.Wolfenstein SSHealth: 30Wolfenstein SS(The SS Officer enemy from Wolfenstein 3-D makes a special cameo in two secret levels in Doom II.)Special enemies found only after certain conditions are met, they are Nazi officers last seen pursuing allied soldier B.J. Blazkowicz. No one knows how they are connected to Hell's Legion. They can drop a clip of Bullet ammo upon dying.The Icon of SinHealth: 400The Icon of Sin(A.K.A. The End Boss, the Final Boss, the Great Big Face, Baphomet, The Gatekeeper, Demon-Spitter, The Head of John Romero)Ruler of Hell's Legions and the true mastermind behind Hell's Invasion of Earth. Known as Baphomet, the goals of this demonic being are shrouded in mystery. It is the most powerful of all Hell Spawn, summoning entire scores of Hell Spawn to assist it and using the most devastating of all hellish magic. What could possibly be behind it?Damage Table AveragesMonsterPistol/Chaingun/FistsChainsawShotgunSuper ShotgunRocketPlasmaBFG 9000Human2111111Sergeant3211121Imp6311131Commando7421151Lost Soul10521151Demon14731171Specter14731171Pain Elemental3518522301Cacodemon3618622181Revenant3819732141Arachnotron4523733301Hell Knight5226833261Mancubus65331044301Arch-Vile70351044351Baron100501555501Spider Mastermind3001504315151502Cyberdemon4002005820202004Final Boss4020622201Ports and Other VersionsXbox Live ArcadeDoom II for XBLAThe Xbox Live Arcade version, developed by Nerve and published by Bethesda, is a direct port of the PC version, and came out in 2010. Like the Xbox Live Arcade release of the original Doom, this port adds new features such as achievements, leaderboards, and 4-player multiplayer via split-screen and Xbox Live. Most of the names and concepts of the achievements reference the infamous Doom comic book. The port also changes the red cross from stimpacks, medikits, and berserk packs into a red and white pill. This port also features avatar awards that can be unlocked by beating any level in single-player (netting you a t-shirt with the Doom II logo on it) and by completing the new episode in single-player (giving you a loose adaptation of the Doom marine's suit). Image.This version also features a brand new episode called "No Rest For the Living", which consists of 9 brand new levels created by Nerve:Level 1: The Earth BaseDesigner: Russell MeakimPar time: 1:15Level 2: The Pain LabsDesigner: Richard HeathPar time: 1:45Level 3: Canyon of the DeadDesigner: Russell MeakimPar time: 2:00Level 4: Hell MountainDesigner: Russell MeakimPar time: 1:45Level 5: VivisectionDesigner: Richard HeathPar time: 3:30Level 6: Inferno of BloodDesigner: Richard HeathPar time: 1:45Level 7: Baron's BanquetDesigner: Richard HeathPar time: 2:45Level 8: Tomb of MalevolenceDesigner: Richard HeathPar time: 1:45Secret Level: March of the Demons (accessible from Hell Mountain)Designer: Russell MeakimPar time: 2:15The episode is significant for its carefulness with weapon spawns and power-ups in single-player. For example, you will never find a backpack (which doubles your ammo capacity) until the end of the campaign. Weapons are carefully placed to increase their value, such as the Super Shotgun being the reward for accessing the yellow door in the first level, and the BFG-9000 being located only in level 6 (after searching the level for well-hidden switches).MusicMuch like the first Doom's music, Hell on Earth also used a few actual tracks as a main basis for level music. While some used riffs, verses, openings, or most of the song, it should again be noted that there were actually more original tracks in this one than in the original Doom. Like the first game, most of the samples used were from Heavy Metal bands. Some tracks were used by the same bands from the first, and new bands as well. The band tracks featured in Doom II are from bands such as Pantera, Megadeth, Slayer, Black Sabbath, Atheist, Stone Temple Pilots, and Alice In Chains.Map 01 is based on Megadeth's "Hangar 18" main verse.Map 02 is based on Atheist's "Samba Briza" main rhythm.Map 07 is based on Slayer's "South of Heaven" rhythm opening.Map 09 is based on Stone Temple Pilot's "Sex Type Thing" main riff.Map 10 is based on Black Sabbath's "After All (The Dead)" opening riff.Map 18 is based on Pantera's "This Love" opening rhythm.Map 23 is based on Alice in Chains' "Them Bones" main riff.Map 25 is based on Alice in Chains' "Angry Chair" main intro.TriviaA Doom II arcade cabinet (which never actually existed) can be seen in the background in the movie Grosse Point Blank, when protagonist Martin Blank goes into a convenience store.The SS Trooper from Wolfenstein 3-D appears in the two secret levels, which are remakes of the very first level of Wolfenstein 3-D and the last level of Wolf3D's first episode, with the first boss replaced by a Cyberdemon. Also, a hanged Commander Keen figure makes a cameo in the second secret level.System RequirementsMinimum System Requirements486 IBM compatible computerHard Drive - 17 MBExternal linksDOOM wikiZDOOM - Popular source port for modern operating systems.Skulltag - Source port focused on multiplayer.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3407">Duke Nukem 3D</game><game id="97">Serious Sam: Next Encounter</game><game id="65">Serious Sam</game><game id="21530">NecroVisioN</game><game id="5403">Rise of the Triad: Dark War</game><game id="23289">Robotica</game><game id="2699">Alien Breed 3D</game><game id="8569">KISS: Psycho Circus - The Nightmare Child</game><game id="24657">HacX</game><game id="9048">Blood Plasma Pak</game><game id="14819">Tron 2.0</game><game id="25814">Painkiller: Resurrection</game><game id="3061">Will Rock</game><game id="2600">Halo: Combat Evolved</game><game id="975">Killing Time</game><game id="17017">Alien Resurrection</game><game id="6730">Painkiller</game><game id="25062">Painkiller: Hell Wars</game><game id="14462">Ken's Labyrinth</game><game id="34086">Painkiller: Redemption</game><game id="7418">Star Wars: Jedi Knight - Dark Forces II</game><game id="20672">Rage</game><game id="35888">Hard Reset</game><game id="16971">Disruptor</game><game id="22548">Hexen</game><game id="5793">Gloom</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2353149-untitled.png</image></root>