<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6212</id><name>Dark Fall: Lights Out</name><description>OverviewDark Fall: Lights Out is the second game in the Dark Fall series. Developed by Darkling Room and XXv Productions, the game was released on PC in 2004. The game's story was written by Jonathan Boakes.GameplayThe game follows the same point-and-click style as the previous game.StoryIt is 1912, the shores of Trewarthan, England are dangerous and have cost many ships and lives. Benjamin Parker, a cartographer has been sent to map the area in order to allow a safer passage. He notices that there is a lighthouse on an island out at sea. Why would he be sent here if an operational lighthouse is already here? Benjamin soon learns from his employer that something is happening at the lighthouse and the keepers may be in danger.As the game unfolds, you discover a sinister enemy has been behind the disappearances of many people at Fetch Rock. Throughout the game you traverse through four different time periods as you try to stop whatever evil is under the Fetch Rock lighthouse from claiming any more lives. System RequirementsRecommendedOS: Windows® ME/2000/NT/XP/Vista.CPU: Pentium® III 450 MHz Equivalent or Better Processor.RAM: 128 MB RAM (256 MB Recommended).Video: SVGA Graphics Card or better with 32-Bit Colour (32-Bit Colour at 800x600)  800x600 capable monitor.Sound: DirectX 9 Compatible Sound Card.MinimumOS: Windows 98/se.CPU: Pentium 233 MHz Equivalent or Better Processor.RAM: 128 MB RAM (256 MB Recommended).Video: SVGA Graphics Card or better with 32-Bit Colour (32-Bit Colour at 800x600)  800x600 capable monitor.Sound: DirectX 9 Compatible Sound Card.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22665">The Lost Crown: A Ghost-Hunting Adventure</game><game id="7276">Pathologic</game><game id="5010">Dark Fall: The Journal</game><game id="574">Sherlock Holmes: Nemesis</game><game id="4897">The Moment of Silence</game><game id="12912">NiBiRu: Age of Secrets</game><game id="31615">Dark Fall: Lost Souls</game><game id="16298">The 7th Guest</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13292/810837-919798_58088_front.jpg</image></root>