<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6311</id><name>Guitar Hero</name><description>AbstractGuitar Hero was the first major success from Harmonix Music Systems, who had developed several other, less successful, rhythm based games before hitting their stride. The game involves using a guitar controller to play along with popular songs. The first Guitar Hero game was a huge success, and the series has spawned numerous sequels, expansion packs, and a spiritual successor, Rock Band.GameplayThe gameplay of Guitar Hero is based around a rhythm mechanic. The player uses a guitar shaped controller with five buttons to hit color-coded notes, and a "strum bar" to simulate the picking of strings in time with the music. A "Rock Meter" on the side of the screen indicates the crowd's satisfaction with the performance. Hitting notes raises the meter, missing notes lowers it. Some notes have long tails behind them, indicating that the fret button must be held for the duration of the note. A "Whammy Bar" can be used to gain additional points from these points, as well as producing a tremolo effect. Certain phrases notes are colored white-blue, and hitting these notes gains "Star Power". Star Power is represented by a meter on the side of the screen. When this meter is half-full or more, star power can be deployed by tilting the guitar controller. Doing this doubles the note multiplier, and increases the amount the rock meter is raised with each note hit. This implies that star power can be used for two purposes; surviving difficult song sections, and gaining points on easier ones. It should be noted that most of the songs featured throughout the game are covers by Wavegroup.DevelopmentThe idea for Guitar Hero came from the GuitarFreaks arcade game from Konami. The founders of RedOctane, a company that had been making music game peripherals for some time, wished to bring the same sort of experience to North America. They were successful in raising $1.75 million for the project but were turned down several times. Eventually Harmonix was asked to help with the project and the company agreed to assist in developing the game.Once development started, the team wasn't sure about the tracklist that was going to be in the game. They mainly wanted to focus on hard rock songs but there were limitations in licenses that they could require for the tracks. The note patterns for songs were created by a Harmonix team and they usually spent a day on each track. Software algorithms that assessed the difficulty of the songs and the quality of the note patterns created by the team were used as well.CharactersAxel SteelClive WinstonJudy NailsJohnny NapalmIzzy SparksXavier StonePandoraGrim ReaperCanceled Xbox VersionIn an interview in January 2010, Mad Katz CEO revealed to Kotaku that an Xbox version of the first Guitar Hero was planned, and that they were in charge of it. However Konami threatened to sue and Mad Katz broke off the deal.Track ListingTier 1: Opening Licks"I Love Rock and Roll" by Joan Jett and the Blackhearts"I Wanna Be Sedated" by The Ramones"Thunder Kiss '65" by White Zombie"Smoke on the Water" by Deep Purple"Infected" by Bad ReligionTier 2: Axe-Grinders"Iron Man" by Black Sabbath"More Than a Feeling" by Boston"You Got Another Thing Comin'" by Judas Priest"Take Me Out" by Franz Ferdinand"Sharp Dressed Man" by ZZ TopTier 3: Thrash and Burn"Killer Queen" by Queen"Hey You" by The Exies"Stellar" by Incubus"Heart Full of Black" by Burning Brides"Symphony of Destruction" by MegadethTier 4: Return of the Shred"Ziggy Stardust" by David Bowie"Fat Lip" by Sum 41"Cochise" by Audioslave"Take It Off" by The Donnas"Unsung" by HelmetTier 5: Fret-Burners"Spanish Castle Magic" by Jimi Hendrix*"Higher Ground" by Red Hot Chili Peppers"No One Knows" by Queens of the Stone Age"Ace of Spades" by Motörhead"Crossroads" by CreamTier 6: Face Melters"Godzilla" by Blue Öyster Cult"Texas Flood" by Stevie Ray Vaughan"Frankenstein" by The Edgar Winter Group"Cowboys from Hell" by Pantera"Bark at the Moon" by Ozzy OsbourneBonus Songs"All of This" by Shaimus"Behind the Mask" by Anarchy Club"The Breaking Wheel" by Artillery"Callout" by The Acro-Brats"Caveman Rejoice" by The Bags"Cheat on the Church" by Graveyard BBQ"Decontrol" by Drist"Eureka, I've Found Love" by The Upper Crust"Even Rats" by The Slip"Farewell Myth" by Made in Mexico"Fire it Up" by Black Label Society"Fly on the Wall" by Din"Get Ready 2 Rokk" by Freezepop"Guitar Hero" by Monkey Steals the Peach"Hey" by Honest Bob and the Factory-to-Dealer Incentives"Sail Your Ship By" by Count Zero"Story of My Love" by The Model SonsHidden Songs:"Trippolette" by Andrew Busch"Graveyard Shift" by Unknown</description><genres><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5825">Frequency</game><game id="9860">Rock Band</game><game id="20808">Rock Band Track Pack Volume 1</game><game id="1420">Amplitude</game><game id="11281">Shredz64</game><game id="12108">Mad Maestro!</game><game id="20714">Rock Band 2</game><game id="1872">Frets on Fire</game><game id="9436">Audiosurf</game><game id="20635">Rock Revolution</game><game id="7477">Phase</game><game id="18366">Dance Dance Revolution ULTRAMIX 2</game><game id="22167">Synthesia</game><game id="21844">GuitarFreaks V &amp; DrumMania V</game><game id="22632">pop'n music 10</game><game id="22628">pop'n music 9</game><game id="22625">pop'n music 8</game><game id="22623">pop'n music 7</game><game id="22622">pop'n music 6</game><game id="22621">pop'n music 5</game><game id="22619">pop'n music 4</game><game id="22618">pop'n music 3</game><game id="22617">pop'n music 2</game><game id="21655">pop'n music</game><game id="8631">GuitarFreaks 3rdMIX &amp; DrumMania 2ndMIX</game><game id="23613">Guitar Praise: Solid Rock</game><game id="23880">Ultrastar Deluxe</game><game id="21290">Tap Tap Revenge</game><game id="23848">Rock Band Track Pack Volume 2</game><game id="24594">Tap Tap Revenge: NIN Edition</game><game id="5639">Quest for Fame</game><game id="25047">Dance ManiaX 1ST MIX</game><game id="20872">Battle of the Bands</game><game id="18157">Um Jammer Lammy</game><game id="10051">PaRappa the Rapper 2</game><game id="25385">Tap Tap Dance</game><game id="25642">Rock Band Track Pack: Classic Rock</game><game id="25421">Rock Band Unplugged</game><game id="25871">Tap Tap Revenge: Coldplay Edition</game><game id="25765">LEGO Rock Band</game><game id="21232">DJMAX Portable 2</game><game id="23882">DJ Hero</game><game id="26367">Band Hero</game><game id="25484">Tap Tap Revenge 2</game><game id="31427">DJMAX Portable 3</game><game id="32141">Rhythm Zone</game><game id="32905">Singstar Guitar</game><game id="35165">Sequence</game><game id="39228">Stay Dead</game><game id="40411">Guitar Idol</game><game id="43060">Performous</game><game id="44404">Music Master Chopin</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1891342-box_ghero.png</image></root>