<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6338</id><name>TimeShift</name><description>Gameplay and StoryTimeShift is a First-Person Shooter developed by Saber Interactive that was released on the Xbox 360, PS3 and PC. TimeShift was published by Sierra Entertainment and allows the player to manipulate time to survive impossible situations.The player has the ability to pause, rewind, and slowdown time. The player can use these time manipulating abilities to walk on electrified water, dodge enemy grenades and steal enemy weapons. In the game, you play as an unnamed scientist who goes back in time with the help of the local rebellion to stop the antagonist Dr. Krone, who is attempting to become the ruler of the world. Standing in your way is Dr. Krone's faithful army. You must use your time manipulating abilities to overcome your foes and save future humanity.LevelsArrivalBack AgainNew BloodInfiltrationGround FloorHeistGetawayDisputed AirspaceBetter Late...Point of ImpactLiberationRoad TripForced EntryTest LabsFactory RecallSome Assembly RequiredSabotageExeuntDrive-ByGate CrashersThe Wind TunnelRepo MenEn RouteConsequencesCritical ReceptionTimeshift currently holds a score of 70 for PS3 and X360 versions and 71 for its PC version on Metacritc. Critics complained mainly of the game's lack of challenge, the short length, and occasionally wonky frame rate. While the consensus is that the game handles the time manipulation abilities well, it just didn't have enough new, innovative gameplay mechanics to be considered anything more than "average" or "vaguely enjoyable".SoundtrackSoundtrack cover.TimeShift features an original soundtrack composed by Rebecca Kneubuhl and Gabriel Mann.TimeShift ThemeTimeShift MenuMaze BattleDire CityRooftop HelicopterFlash BattleStriderZeppelinCity ExplorationAerationStrider PassingHeavy RewindCity of IndustryStrider CollapseStrider BattleGet ChipTimeShift Menu LightTimeShift Theme LightPC System RequirementsMinimumOS: Windows XP/VistaProcessor: Pentium 4 @ 2 GHzMemory: 1 GbHard Drive: 8 Gb freeVideo Memory: 128 MbVideo Card: nVidia GeForce 6600 / ATI Radeon x700Sound Card: DirectX CompatibleDirectX: 9.0cRecommendedOS: Windows XP/VistaProcessor: Intel Core 2 DUO E6400 / AMD Athlon X2 4200+Memory: 2 GbHard Drive: 8 Gb freeVideo Memory: 256 MbVideo Card: GeForce 8600 GTSSound Card: DirectX CompatibleDirectX: 9.0cXbox 360 Game InstallationTimeShift requires 5.8GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20516">Fracture</game><game id="8099">TimeSplitters: Future Perfect</game><game id="18569">BlackSite: Area 51</game><game id="20532">Legendary</game><game id="593">Shadowrun</game><game id="4800">F.E.A.R.: First Encounter Assault Recon</game><game id="25091">Deus Ex: The Conspiracy</game><game id="21144">Singularity</game><game id="18385">Blinx the Time Sweeper</game><game id="20455">Haze</game><game id="21119">Wolfenstein</game><game id="24858">Darkest of Days</game><game id="35936">Recall</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2243885-box_tshift.png</image></root>