<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6343</id><name>Daigasso! Band Brothers Request Selection</name><description>AboutDaigasso! Band Brothers Request Selection is an expansion pack for the first Band Brothers game for Nintendo DS.  It comes on a Gameboy Advance cartridge, which when inserted in to the DS makes 31 new songs available to play in Daigasso! Band Brothers.  No gameplay changes are made, and the songs simply appear at the bottom of the song selection screen.  The game was released exclusively in Japan on September 26th 2005.  The video game song choices were selected based on a survay conducted by Nintendo on their Japanese website.TracklistingJ-Pop  AnimeORANGE RANGE - Onegai! SenoritaSukima Switch - Zenryoku ShounenAi Ōtsuka - SMILYPorno Graffiti - NeomelodramaticORANGE RANGE - HanaKobukuro - Koko ni Shika Sakanai HanaFLOW - DAYS - Opening to "Eureka Seven"Ketsumeishi - SakuraYuzu - Eikō no KakehashiMahora Gakuen Chūtōbu 2-A - Happy Material - Opening to "Mahou Sensei Negima!"SMAP - Sekai ni Hitotsu Dake no HanaASIAN KUNG-FU GENERATION - Rewrite - Fourth opening to "Fullmetal Alchemist"day after tomorrow - Starry Heavens - Opening to "Tales of Symphonia"Karyūdo - Azusa Ni-GōBUMP OF CHICKEN - Tentai KansokuSasuke - Aoi BenchMan Z - Nihon Break Kōgyō ShakaUndergraph - TsubasaJanne Da Arc - Gekkō Ka - Opening to "Black Jack"ORANGE RANGE - Love ParadeKen Matsudaira - Matsuken Samba Part 2WorldO-Zone - Dragostea din teiVideo GamesStar Fox 64 - Star Wolf ThemeShin Onigashima - Yama e no MichiCatch! Touch! Yoshi! - Tokotoko YoshiSawaru Made in Wario - SONG OF ASHLEYAnimal Forest   - Title ThemeDonkey Kong Jungle Beat - ThemeSuper Mario 64 DS - SliderFamicom Tantei Club - Ayumi's ThemeYoshi's Island - Athletic</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21427">Korg DS-10</game><game id="7037">Osu! Tatakae! Ouendan</game><game id="254">Moero! Nekketsu Rhythm Damashii Osu! Tatakae! Ouendan 2</game><game id="22176">Taiko no Tatsujin DS</game><game id="11982">Elite Beat Agents</game><game id="492">Electroplankton</game><game id="18573">Jam Sessions</game><game id="20556">Ontamarama</game><game id="24117">Meccha! Taiko no Tatsujin DS: 7-tsu no Shima no Daibouken</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/7465/782006-41ttvcg_5zl._sl500_aa275_.jpg</image></root>