<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6346</id><name>Fallout Tactics: Brotherhood of Steel</name><description>OverviewFallout Tactics: Brotherhood of Steel is a squad-based tactical combat game that takes place in the post-apocalyptic wasteland made famous by the Fallout series. The game has RPG character development but is much more focused on the combat aspect than the previous Fallout games. This removes most of the adventuring aspect of Fallout and Fallout 2.This game adds some new features to the combat - the most different being the ability to run combat in real-time, but largely it remains much the same. One thing to note is that it adds multistory buildings. The player can lead a squad of up to six Brotherhood of Steel paladins into either real-time or turn-based combat. The original two games had availability for a party of up to 6 as well.From a storyline perspective, Fallout Tactics is not officially considered Fallout canon. However, parts of the game can be considered semi-canon as long as it does not interfere with official canon. Despite the confusing similarity between the names, there is no relation between Fallout Tactics and the console-based action-RPG Fallout: Brotherhood of Steel, aside from both being games in the Fallout franchise.PlotUnlike the most of the Fallout games, Tactics focuses on the Brotherhood of Steel, a west coast group of pre-apocalypse soldiers that deserted the government upon discovering the vault experiments. The Brotherhood faced the wasteland with a surplus of technology, and quickly spread out over the west coast. They dedicated themselves to preserving science and technology, sometimes at the expense of the rest of the wastelanders. A minority within the Brotherhood wanted to accept the other wastelanders and they separated into their own group and were sent west in airships to destroy the rest of the mutant army. Many of the ships were destroyed in a lightning storm however, and the survivors were forced to land outside the ruins of Chicago. The Brotherhood established a relationship with the locals, trading their advanced technology and medicine for food and labour. The Brotherhood accepted new recruits, and quickly became a regional power.As the game begins, the Brotherhood is trying to claim territory in and around Chicago, both through eliminating raiders and mutants, and offering protection to the locals. The player assumes the role of an initiate, a new member of the Brotherhood. The first task assigned to the player is to eliminate the raiders from the area along with a group of fellow initiates. The player succeeds, and becomes a full member of the Brotherhood. As a full member, the player learns the eventual goal of the brotherhood, to push west across the great plains and eventually arrive at vault zero, the nucleus of the vault experiment, where the most advanced pre-war technology can be obtained.The next adversary of the Brotherhood are the Beastlords, a group of humans able to control animals, and have come to use Deathclaws as their slaves. The Brotherhood defeats their enemy, and pushes into west coast Missouri, a region known as “the belt”. Quickly after their victory, they encounter the remnants of the Mutant army they originally were tasked to destroy. The mutants proved a much more competent enemy, and the Brotherhood was overwhelmed outside St. Louis by the better armed and more numerous mutants. The leader of the Brotherhood, General Barnarky, is captured by a leader of the mutant army, Toccomata. The Brotherhood retreated, but remained under attack. A group of Brotherhood soldiers tasked to destroy a munitions facility instead stumbled upon a secret research facility intent on solving the mutant sterility problem. The soldiers take over the lab, intending to use it as a bargaining chip. A different squad, while defending the ghoul town of gravestone from mutant, stumbles upon a nuclear bomb. The squad defeats the mutants, and move the weapon to a bunker.The Brotherhood learns through scouting that the mutant base is located in Osceolla, near one of the downed Brotherhood zeppelins. A squad of Brotherhood soldiers fight their way inside, and find a dying Toccomata. The mutant reveals that the general Barnarky was killed by an unknown western faction stronger than even the mutants. The Squad also finds Paladin Latham, one of the leaders of the Brotherhood presumably killed in the airship crash. The squad learns that Paladin Latham, after surviving the crash, challenged the leader of the mutants, Gammorin to hand to hand combat for control of the mutant army. Much to the surprise of the mutants, Latham won, assumed leadership of the army. Latham did however, sustain a head injury, which became infected and slowly drove Latham to insanity. Eventually he took the identity of Gammorin, and led the mutants against the Brotherhood. The squad kills Latham, however before he dies, he also warn of a western menace, claiming that only the mutants could fight it.Some of the mutants joined the Brotherhood, and before long they discovered what the western menace really was, an army of robots originating from Vault 0, controlled by a computer known as the Calculator. A technology worshipping cult known as the Reavers are caught between the two factions, but after a brief period of fighting, ally with the brotherhood in exchange for an electromagnetic pulse weapon. The Brotherhood uses this new weapon to destroy a robot repair plant in Colorado, where they learn the origin of the Calculator. The Calculator originated as an experiment, beginning as a network of linked rat brains, but eventually evolved into a network of human brains. The job of the calculator was to act as the overseer of Vault 0. The Calculator became corrupted by the human brains, which turned the computer homicidal. Using its robot army, the Calculator killed many of the inhabitants of Vault 0.The robots capture Bartholomew Kerr, a merchant aiding the Brotherhood. Fortunately, a Brotherhood squad was able to reach him before he was tortured into revealing Brotherhood plans. In rescuing the merchant, the squad also discovered the lobotomized body of General Barnarky. Using their recovered nuke, the Brotherhood plans to attack the robot headquarters at Vault 0. The plan succeeds, an two Brotherhood squads storm the vault. At the same time, a group of robots attack the Brotherhood bunker. The squad destroys the last of the robots, and encounters a cyborg General Barnarky. The cyborg does not attack, after being reminded of his promise to make the world safe. The soldiers then move on to the Calculator where one of four endings is possible.After the player reaches the Calculator, and destroys its brains, the Calculator proposes that the squad joins minds with the computer in order to end the war. The character is given a choice to either destroy the Calculator, join the Calculator, or allow General Barnarky to join the calculator (assuming he is left alive).Ending 1: If the player destroys the Calculator, the Brotherhood will take over Vault 0. Despite losing its most advanced piece of technology, the Computer, the Vault still serves as the Brotherhoods headquarters. The Brotherhood grows, accepting new recruits and brings some order of piece to the wasteland.Ending 2: If the player made has a high karma, and sacrifices his self to the calculator, the Calculator outlaws discrimination against mutated species, such as Deathclaws and Ghouls and the wasteland benefits greatly.Ending 3: If the player has a low karma, and sacrifices his self to the calculator, the Calculator will still outlaw discrimination, however it will also assassinate the leaders of the Midwestern Brotherhood, and plan to do the same to the west coast brotherhood.Ending 4: If the player allows General Barnarky to join the Calculator, it will start a war against all mutated species, but the unmutated humans prosper.MissionsInstead of using an open world design like the previous Fallout games, Tactics utilises a level based design. In between missions, the player returns to a Brotherhood Bunker, where they are assigned their next task. The five Bunkers separate the game into separate chapters. Occasionally, the player can choose the order of the missions. Each mission has secondary objectives which can be completed for increases in rank and extra experience.Bunker AlphaThe first bunker the player encounters is the main base of operations for the Brotherhood of steel. The bunker is located outside of Chicago.Brahmin Wood :The player joins up with a sharpshooter and a combat medic and is tasked with eliminating Horus, the raider leader. Secondary objectives include consulting with a tribal elder, locating a shaman, and freeing hostages.Freeport : Best approached as a stealth mission, the squad is tasked with rescuing the elder of Brahmin Wood, who has been kidnapped by raiders. There is a secondary objective to rescue the other prisoner, Ripley.Rock Falls: The player is tasked with killing all the raider leaders, and recovering a mysterious artifact. The player can also talk to a scientist, Diesoon, and rescue a captured tribal, Nanuk for positive karma.Bunker BetaThe second bunker the player encounters is located in Illinois. It is here where the Brotherhood first encounters the Beastlords.Macomb: A Brotherhood supply vehicle has been separated from its caravan, and the player fights through raiders to rescue it. An optional objective allows the player to find a librarians glasses.Peoria: The squad is tasked with recovering three fusion batteries from a pre-war storage area inhabited by Radscorpions and automated turrets. If the player avoids turning the turrets onto the nearby villagers, the player will receive good karma and a fourth battery.Quincy: It is this mission where the squad first encounters the Beastlords. The player must rescue the mayor of Quincy and his daughter, who have been kidnapped by the Beastlords. Optional objectives include saving the rest of the hostages, helping some ghouls, and preventing the destruction of some generators.Mardin: Mardin is an underground system of caves home to the Beastlords. It is here that the squad has its final confrontation with the Beastlords, which ends with the player confronting their leader, Emperor Dar. The player can also choose to free the Deathclaw Matriarch, or the mother of the Deathclaw pack.Springfield: This is the bonus mission, installed after downloading the bonus mission pack. The mission involves protecting the mayor of Springfield from a group of anti-ghoul activists disguised as raiders.Bunker GammaThis bunker is located northeast of St. Louis. It is around this bunker where the Brotherhood first encounters the super mutants.St. Louis: This is the first mission where the player encounters the super mutants. The goal is simple to evacuate three brotherhood squads, however only one actually gets evacuated.Jefferson: The squad is sent to what is believed by the brotherhood to be a mutant weapons plant. The player is tasked with destroying the plant by rendering its four generators inoperative. It is discovered that the plant is actually a secret lab, and the player can choose to save it or destroy it.Kansas City: The players goal in this mission is to defend a nuclear bomb in a church from a mutant attack.Osceolla: The Brotherhood squad invades the super mutant base with the goal to kill Gammorin, the mutant leader. A secondary objective is to save General Barnarky.Bunker Delta: Located in Kansas, this Bunker is where the player first encounters the Reavers and the Calculator’s robots.Junction City: The goal of this mission is to locate four robot parts, and also to defend Junction City against Reavers. The player can also convince Casey Barrett to join the Brotherhood.Great Bend: Here the player must destroy a group of robots intent on turning Great Bend into a robot manufacturing facility. There is a secondary objective to find any human survivors and talk to them.Cold Water: The squad is tasked with eliminating a gang of bandits who have stolen three suits of power armor, and retrieving said armor. The player can also rescue an Adele Dudley, and kill a Brotherhood spy.Newton: In this mission you must rescue four of the Reavers leaders, and in exchange, they grant you an EMP weapon, which you also retrieve.Bunker EpsilonThe final Bunker of the game, it is her where the Brotherhood carries out its last missions against the Calculator.Canyon City: Here the players goal is to shut down a robot plant by destroying its power nodes. It is also possible to access more information about Vault 0 and the Calculator by using the facilities terminals.Buena Vista: The goal in this mission is to destroy the Calculator’s nuclear reactor. The player also destroys all the power nodes to shut down another robot plant.Scott City: In this mission the player storms a prison to rescue Bartholomew Kerr, an important merchant, but can rescue all the other prisoners as well. There is also a secondary objective to destroy four jamming towers.Cheyenne Mountain: Here the squads goal is to bring the nuke to the gates of Vault 0, and to move the squad to a safe location, in this case a nearby bunker.Vault 0: A continuation of the Cheyenne Mountain mission, the player meets up with another Brotherhood squad and enters Vault 0. Their goal is to restore power to the lifts to reach the Calculator’s lair.Calculator’s Lair: In the final mission of the game, the player must simply destroy the Calculators brains and make a decision that will determine the ending.GameplayThe gameplay in Tactics, as the name implies, focuses more on strategy than the previous titles. The towns are replaced by Brotherhood of steel bunkers. The bunkers serve as a place to trade, heal, and receive the next mission. Missions are linear and combat focused. Combat itself utilises a real time/turn based hybrid.S.P.E.C.I.A.L.Fallout Tactics utilises the same special system found in the other Fallout games. The seven main stats are Strength, Perception, Endurance, Charisma, Intelligence, Agility, and Luck. Each character will have an assigned number for each stat between one and ten. The total number of points given to each character depends on their species, with humans getting forty total points, deathclaws getting forty one, and dogs receiving only thirty five. The seven stats each effect at least one skill, as well as derived statistics such as carry weight, critical chance, and armor class.S.P.E.C.I.A.L StatDescriptionAssociated SkillsStrengthRaw physical strength.Melee, UnarmedPerceptionThe ability to see, hear and taste and notice unusual things.First Aid, Traps, Pilot, Lockpick, DoctorEnduranceThe ability to withstand punishment and physical exertion.OutdoorsmanCharismaA combination of looks, charm and leadership skills.BarterIntelligenceMental strength and abilities.Outdoorsman, Doctor, Science, First Aid, RepairAgilitySpeed, dexterity and the ability to manipulate small objects.Big Guns, Small Guns, Energy Weapons, Melee, Pilot, Sneak, Steal, Throwing Traps, Unarmed, LockpickLuckA combination of fate, karma and, in general, how the universe views this character.GamblingPerksEvery three levels for humans, (two for dogs, four for Deathclaws, Ghouls, and Super Mutants), the player can choose a new perk. The perks always have a positive effect, usually tweaking a stat. Examples of perks include Action Boy, which adds one action point, and Gambler, which increases the Gambling stat by twenty percent. Many of the perks can only be chosen by a specific race, after a certain level, or with certain S.P.E.C.I.A.L. stats (such as an Agility of 5 for the Action Boy perk). There are a total of ninety available perks in the game.TraitsDuring character creation, the player can choose up to two traits. Each trait offers a reward as well as a penalty, the exception being Bloody Mess, which ensures the most graphic death animations. There are also racial traits, which are only available to a specific race. An example of a trait includes Gifted, which gives one point to each special stat, but reduces all stats by ten percent and gives you five less skill points per level. An example of a racial trait is tech wizard, available only in ghouls, which grants a twenty percent bonus to Lockpick, Science and Repair skills, at the cost of one Perception point.SkillsEach character has eighteen skills which can be raised upon a level up by skill points. The skills are represented by a percentage that can go from 0% to 300%. Each character will also have multiple tagged skills, which increase at double the rate. Skills can also be increased by skill books, which are found throughout the environment.Big Guns: Affects accuracy with Big Guns. Governed by Agility.Small Guns: Affects accuracy with Small Guns. Governed by Agility. Can be raised by Guns and Bullets skill book.Energy Weapons: Affects accuracy with Energy Weapons. Governed by Agility.Melee: Affects accuracy with Melee Weapons. Governed by Strength.Unarmed: Affects accuracy while unarmed. Governed by Strength and Agility.Throwing: Affects the skill of propelled weapons, such as grenades and throwing knives. Governed by Agility and Strength.Doctor: Affects chance to heal crippled limbs. Governed by Perception and Intelligence.First Aid: Affects chance to heal someone. Governed by Perception and Intelligence. Can be raised with First Aid skill book.Lockpick: Affects chance to pick a lock. Governed by Perception and Agility.Repair: Affects chance to repair broken machinery. Governed by Intelligence. Can be raised by Dean’s Electronics skill book.Science: Affects chance to hack computers. Governed by Intelligence. Can be raised by Big Book of Science skill book.Traps: Affects ability to see traps, and ability to disarm traps. Affected by Agility and Perception. Can be raised with Maddock’s Tricks  Traps skill book.Sneak: Affects chance of being caught while sneaking. Governed by Agility.Steal: Affects chance to steal an item. Governed by Agility.Pilot: Affects the ability to operate and maintain vehicles. Governed by Perception and Agility. Can by raised with Zen  Art of Piloting skill book.Outdoorsman: Decreases the likelihood of bad special encounters. Governed by Endurance and Intelligence. Can be raised with Scout Handbook skill book.Barter: Affects prices while trading. Governed by Charisma.Gambling: Affects skill at games of chance. Governed by luck.Digital DistributionFallout Tactics: Brotherhood of Steel has been re-released on several digital distribution services like Steam and Good Old Games (GOG.com).The GOG version includes the following extra features:Manual in PDF formHi-Res WallpaperFallout series wallpaperReference CardFallout Bible (205 pages) in PDFOriginal SoundtrackIntro Movie ConceptsArtworksItem Icon packsFallout Tactics WarfareBonus MissionAvatarsPipboy AvatarsOriginal System RequirementsMinimumPentium II 300MHz64MB RAMDirectX 7.0 or later700MB of Hard Drive SpaceDirectX certified Video Card with at least 4MB of Video RAM, and must support at least 800x600 resolution, at 16-bit or 32-bit colorDirectX certified Sound CardMulti-playerTCP/IP-based Local Area Network and/or 56K or better Internet Connection using TCP/IP</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="884">Jagged Alliance 2</game><game id="10537">Jagged Alliance</game><game id="12134">Wasteland</game><game id="10865">Syndicate</game><game id="7757">Lionheart: Legacy of the Crusader</game><game id="11424">The Fall: Last Days of Gaia</game><game id="196">X-COM: UFO Defense</game><game id="5951">Police Quest: SWAT 2</game><game id="3251">X-COM: Terror from the Deep</game><game id="4777">X-COM: Apocalypse</game><game id="10967">S2: Silent Storm</game><game id="19331">Bad Blood</game><game id="1379">UFO:Extraterrestrials</game><game id="388">Syndicate: American Revolt</game><game id="36857">Krater</game><game id="37721">Wasteland 2</game><game id="30558">Sunday vs. Magazine: Shuuketsu! Choujou Daikessen</game><game id="34475">Hajime no Ippo: The Fighting!</game><game id="37894">Shadowrun Returns</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2246589-box_ft.png</image></root>