<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6368</id><name>Mickey's Speedway USA</name><description>OverviewMickey's Speedway USA is a game released late in the life span of the Nintendo 64 and Game Boy Color consoles. With several tracks, characters and quirky items, it was an unique game compared to other kart racers. It is one of the few games developed by Rare to use a license from an outside company (Disney). The game sports a large cast of most major Disney characters. Both versions make use of the Transfer Pak to connect both games to unlock hidden features.GameplayMickey's Speedway USA has a Grand Prix mode which works similarly to how the cups in Mario Kart 64 works, you have each cup containing 4 tracks and the characters race to acquire points, the better position you finish the race the more points you get, in the end of the cup whoever has more points wins. There's also modes to run against the clock and try to set the fastest time and multiplayer, being race and battle modes.The characters have different focuses, some focus on speed and less on playability, others won't focus on speed but will be a lot easier to make turns, while some are somewhat balanced.CharactersMickey MouseMinnie MouseDonald DuckDaisy DuckGoofyPeteLouie DuckDewey DuckHuey DuckProfessor Von DrakeItemsSpritzer: The standard speed boost item.Baseball Chucker: Explodes when hit by another racer. It can be tossed behind you.Paint Splotcher: It lies on the ground and makes the first racer that lands on it skid. Can be tossed forward.Tracechaser: Homes in on a racer directly ahead of you.Magno Flyer: Follows the track to hit a racer ahead of you.Shield Shell: Grants a temporary shield, a speed boost and allows you to move at top speed on "hazardous terrain."Stormy Weather: Rains on every racer ahead of you, slowing them down.TracksNintendo 64Traffic TroublesIndianapolisSan FrancescoNew MexicoGrand CanyonMotorway ManiaLos AngelesAlaskaLas VegasPhiladelphiaFreeway PhobiaDakotaSeattleNew YorkChicagoVictory VehiclesYellowstoneWashington D.C.EvergladesMalibuFrantic Finale CupHawaiiOregonTexasColorado</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14279">Land of Illusion starring Mickey Mouse</game><game id="5864">Chocobo Racing</game><game id="16875">Mickey Mania</game><game id="1922">The Magical Quest Starring Mickey Mouse</game><game id="20906">Cocoto Kart Racer</game><game id="21205">Crash Bandicoot Nitro Kart 3D</game><game id="8660">Crash Bandicoot 2: Cortex Strikes Back</game><game id="7380">Crash Bandicoot</game><game id="2278">Crash Nitro Kart</game><game id="6196">Crash Team Racing</game><game id="15990">Diddy Kong Racing</game><game id="5561">Diddy Kong Racing DS</game><game id="22442">F1 ROC: Race of Champions</game><game id="18808">F-Zero X</game><game id="11174">LEGO Racers</game><game id="4902">Mad Dash Racing</game><game id="16769">Mario Kart: Super Circuit</game><game id="19071">Super Mario Kart</game><game id="6539">Mario Kart DS</game><game id="18757">Mario Kart: Double Dash!!</game><game id="11831">M&amp;M's Kart Racing</game><game id="25026">MySims Racing</game><game id="24733">NASCAR Kart Racing</game><game id="310">NASCAR Rumble</game><game id="14134">Pac-Man World Rally</game><game id="4622">Pocketbike Racer</game><game id="1101">Ridge Racer 7</game><game id="18062">Snowboard Kids</game><game id="18426">Snowboard Kids 2</game><game id="22102">SBK: Snowboard Kids</game><game id="15802">Sonic Riders</game><game id="13178">Speed Punks</game><game id="1052">Super PickUps</game><game id="15977">Walt Disney World Quest Magical Racing Tour</game><game id="26848">ModNation Racers</game><game id="4515">RC Revenge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2543562-box_msusa.png</image></root>