<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6465</id><name>Dino Dini's Soccer</name><description>OverviewGoal! (aka Dino Dini's Soccer on the Mega Drive) is Dino Dini's next soccer game after Kick Off 2. Dino Dini is a musician, singer and songwriter who happens to also be a computer game developer specializing in football games, which is the field he is most known for. It's a top down soccer game.Goal! might look like Sensible Soccer (little men on the pitch) but plays very differently. In order to pass the ball the player needs to press and hold the joystick button. The player will keep the ball at his feet. Choose a direction with the joystick and release the button. The player will pass the ball in the designated direction. Shooting is done by pressing the button once and applying after touch. You can chip the ball, by pushing the joystick up and down quickly. Pressing the button while the ball is in mid air will result in a header by the nearest player. Sliding is really exaggerated. Sometimes players come flying in. Taking corners and free kicks is easy. Before the kick is taken, a dotted line is drawn away from the ball. This is controlled by the joystick, and is used to determine the angle, strength and trajectory of your shot.Throw-ins also use this method, though, which is a shame because now they tend to break up the flow of the game.The game is real fast paced.There are four views to choose from. A bird's eye view and a close-up view, up or down or left to right. The close-up view makes the game unplayable because you almost can't see where your team members are positioned.The game features very intelligent computer opponents who do not just stick to set pieces- they actually think for themselves.The action replay facility has been extended over the previous Kick Off games. The function keys are used to control fast forward, rewind and slow motion functions, very much like a video editor. When a goal is scored, the replay is shown automatically, as is the trend with recent games. The facility is also available for you to record all of the action replays within a game to disk.Graphics are clear 2D sprites. Sound effects are limited to the occasional crowd noise and ball bouncing and whistle.You can compete in a lot of different European leagues and international tournaments. No licensed players though. You can play with a range to European country teams, of which you can change the starting line-up and formation. All the Premier leagues are in there, with authentic home and away kits and up-to-date squads, as well as a full complement of international teams. You can also edit them to create your own custom teams, change the names of all the players and redesign the kit designs and colours, although the actual statistics of the individual players can't be altered, and the teams are all of differing standards. You can even choose the referee for the match, with each ref's statistics determining what percentage of fouls he spots and how tough he is on penalising. If a player gets away with a couple of fouls, he's more likely to get a yellow or red card when he commits another foul later on.Also there, is the arcade Challenge mode, in which your games play successively in five different speeds, until you lose. As you win each game, your goal difference is multiplied by the number of the stage, and added to your overall score.A competition or a practise match is also possible. The most notable exception, however, is the lack of a cup competition. Finally the game lets you adjust some of the settings, like wind strength, the kind of pitch, the game duration, level of difficulty and game speed of the computer opponent, etc. Goal! was published by Virgin games and it shipped 60,000 units on the first day. Goal! is also converted to Sega Mega Drive (Genesis in North America) and Super NES.captioncaptioncaption</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5626">Kick Off 2</game><game id="19591">Kick Off 3</game><game id="19165">Sensible World of Soccer</game><game id="14324">Striker</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/2/23093/2368572-dino_dini_goal_ami.png</image></root>