<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6467</id><name>Castlevania: Legacy of Darkness</name><description>Playable Characters There are four characters which are playable  in Castlevania: Legacy of Darkness, each have very different storylines and attack styles.     Cornell (aka. "Blue Crescent Moon")Through the magic of the Ancients, this man-beast warrior has obtained a physical body of near immortality, and power that surpasses that of a wild beast.The man-beasts, choosing to live in harmony with humans, sealed away their enormous magical powers to prevent them from being used. However, through severe ascetic training,       Cornell acquired the art of releasing the sealed man-wolf power.Returning to his village after a year of ascetic training, Cornell finds the village engulfed in flame, and his only living blood relative, his sister Ada, kidnapped by evil spirits. Using his man-wolf's acute sense of smell to track the scent of his sister's blood, Cornell begins his long journey to rescue Ada.     Henry Oldrey Henry's first appearance is as a small child during Cornell's quest. The man-beast saves him from the hedge maze's Frankenstein gardener and helps him escape from the Villa, which up until that point had been his home.   After Cornell's quest, adult Henry becomes a playable character, where which he must save six children who were kidnapped and taken to Dracula's castle to be sacrificed. Unlike most Castlevania protagonists, he uses a gun as his main weapon of choice.        Reinhardt  Schneider  Like his brethren  (                                                           Ralph,                                                           Simon and                                                          Richter),                                                         Reinhardt is a vampire                 killer descended by blood and ancestry from the infamous  Belmont                 clan of vampire hunters. The past acts of legend, valor  and  life-saving                are now long forgotten among the Schneider's  peers.  Schneider vows                to renew his family's honor. "Some  day, the time will come  when                I have to fight the dark  again!" he mutters.   When  Reinhardt's father,                 Michael, decides to become a vampire hunter to honor the  family                 tradition, Reinhardt spends his time training in a forest  near  to                his hometown of Wallachia. After his father's  retirement  ten years                later, a rumor surfaces that  Dracula has been  resurrected, and                Reinhardt begins his  journey to the castle holding the  whip of the                 Belmonts... According to those villagers who know him,  Reinhardt                 has an unapproachable atmosphere around him. This is due  to  his                revered but mysterious background. An intrepid  figure, he  is a gentle                yet highly combative young man  with a righteous mind.       Carrie  Fernandez The family of  Fernandez, Spanish immigrants  travelling throughout              Eastern Europe, chanced upon  Dracula's castle many moons  ago, and              utilizing a sacred  family power of the orb, managed to repel  both              bandits,  demonic intrusions and all manner of evil from  their wagon               train. However, after a particularly vicious attack by a  form of  Dracula              himself, the patriarchal figure of the Fernandez  family (a  great warrior              known as                                                      Sypha) fell under dark trickery.   The  family,  although wracked              with despair, did not cease to  be. A small orphan called                                                      Carrie, exhibited              strange  talents of light summoning and was traced back to  the family               after a lengthy search through records by her foster mother.  A  gentle              child, Carrie watched with horror as a band of  devils  descended upon              their Romanian village and attempted  to attack her. Diving  to save              her child, Carrie's mother  was killed and at that moment, a  great              orb of light was  instantly summoned by the screaming Carrie  and directed              at  the demons, which promptly writhed in agony and  vanished. Her               destiny has called, and Carrie realizes she must fight the  demonic               intrusions.   Carrie's parents exhibited the same  power and  were condemned              and burnt as witches by a  suspicious judiciary, fearful of  anything              that could be  likened to the resurrection of Dracula. Only  recently               realizing this fact, Carrie halts her beliefs in an uncaring  God and               closes her mind to adults, disliking them. Hearing of   Dracula's most              recent resurrection, Carrie decides to  investigate the  castle...  Other Notable Characters   Ada  Cornell's cheerful, lively little sister who has been kindnapped by the evil Count Dracula's minions. She is to be used as a sacrifice in order for the Vampire Count to fully complete his recovery.In order to save his sister from the clutches of Dracula Ultimate, Cornell relinquishes his man-beast power.      Ortega Cornell's childhood friend, Ortega is a fellow beast-man soldier and master of the martial arts. Though he is Cornell's best friend, he is also his rival. Ortega is often frustrated because it seems that whatever he does, Cornell does it better. From this jealousy, Ortega sells his soul to the devil, and allies himself with Dracula's minions in return for a power that can surpass that of Cornell.  Mary Oldrey The mother of Henry Oldrey. After learning that her husband has become a vampire, she hides herself inside of her room until Cornell appears. She then asks the man-beast warrior to seek out and protect her son.  Master Oldrey Lord of the Castle's Villa and father of Henry Oldrey. He was turned into a vampire by Actrise and Gilles de Rais. After failing to apprehend his wife with the intention of drinking her blood, he decides to attack Cornell instead.   Malus In  a tiny hamlet  to the south of Wallachia, Malus lived a a happy                 life with his parents. However, when the resurrection of   Dracula                occurred, a messenger rode into his village with  the news  that dark                flying figures had been seen in the  nearby moors. Surely  enough,                the hamlet was subsequently  attacked and burned to the  ground by                devils. Amid the  ashes, Malus is plucked from the  smoldering ruins                of his  home, borne on the back of a devil, and flown to  Dracula's                 citadel where he remains a prisoner in a dungeon cell.  Obviously,                 the ingenuity of the child knows no bounds, and he seems   to have                broken free of his prison.   He has no  clue to why Dracula  kidnapped                him, indeed he appears  startlingly calm for one so young...        Rosa  A beautiful, yet  luckless woman who has recently been  infected by              a vampire. Once a servant girl in the castle's  rose-garden,  tending              to many bouquets of white satin  roses. Alas, since the bit  infected              her nervous system,  she no longer feels like the Rosa of  old, but              continues to  water her roses... although she has found a new  liquid               fertilizer. Despite her vampirec appearance, her soul has  been fighting               this state, and she has been known to shout "I curse my  own               rotting body" and "do not let my unsaved soul die!"                Somewhere deep in her thoughts lies the promise of   salvation, she              sees a brave man striding in to save her and  the world from  the terrible              fate that awaits...      Vincent  the Vampire Killer A rather boastful  and arrogant, yet  slightly jolly fellow, especially                for a Vampire Hunter,  Vincent calls himself "the strongest                 vampire Killer". He  is a scholar who has spent his entire  life                studying  vampires and lycanthropy, and well-known in  literary circles                 as an authority on these dreaded beings, publishing his  results                 of "field study" in hugely detailed tomes.                 His clothing comes complete with a number of additional  extras,                 including holy water, garlic, a wooden stake and a   crucifix. Although                he loves to sleep, he provides vitally   important                information in regard to the quest.     Heinrich Meyer Heinrich Meyer, a nearby merchant, visited the castle of Dracula five years prior to ply his trade of wooden artifacts, aware of the presence of evil, but not letting that get in the way of a sale. Once inside the castle, he  was offered some tea buy a rather pale looking butler... Waking up three days later, he discovered to his horror that he was tied to a huge wooden operating bench, and a small mad scientist was working furiously on inserting a number of needles into his arm. The rest of his body covered in leeches, Heinrich let out an awful scream and then realized the true terror of his predicament. A thick rasping noise sounded from his lips... As he looked down, he saw blue scales covering his torso and legs. He was changing...   The fearful and quite mad Heinrich, now completely transformed into a lizard man, is kept in a castle bedroom. He keeps a key for company, and runs from the slightest aggression.    Renon  the Salesman          Masquerading as a salesman (complete  with an old suit, a  rather dapper              bowler hat and ornate  hand watch),                 Renon's pointed  tail  gives his              true nature away, he is a devil.               His chosen profession however, is to sell items to   adventures or brave              souls who visit the castle, before  watching their demise  with amused              glee. A mysterious man  who is initially very friendly and  cooperative, though his contract  comes with some fine print that is not to be ignored.                      Actrise                     Actrise was a   stage actress who wished for eternal beauty and fame.                 To this end, she bargained with the Devil himself, and her  soul                 was thus sold. Now completely deranged after years of  creeping  madness,                she shows her willingness to become a vampire by   journeying to the                Count's castle and proclaiming her  foul deed: She slays  one hundred                children a year in  praise of Dracula, and collects their  souls in                a number  of gems. To make matters worse for this hated  hag, she                 sacrificed her own doughter to the Devil when her contract  with                 him suddenly ended, and was restored to eternal life  shortly  thereafter.                Sensing the power present in Carrie,  Dracula orders  Actrise to                win over the girl to the cause  of evil, or die trying.                   The  Fernandez Warrior  One of Actrise's brood and Carrie's  blood-relation, the Fernandez warrior  only appears              briefly  during Carrie's journey, tormenting and taunting her  to return               to her family roots and become a witch herself. She can  summon               in spirits by a simple smile (she calls it her " death   grin"),              and physical attacks are difficult to land as she  lives  in the              Astral plane, and her earthly body is  completely ethereal.  Recently              vampiric, she strikes with  force against her will, as she  would never              intentionally  harm her family.       Death The  confrere of  Dracula himself, this lesser God has descended from                 another world to pursue a perverse set of goals, to  confront  Reinhardt,                blood-relations of the Belmonts, Dracula's  arch rivals.  Previously,                   Death  controlled the soul of Rosa and sent her to defeat  Reinhardt                 when he realized that Reinhardt could not be swayed to the  path                 of Vampirism. Of course, the pure heart of Rosa allows her   to protect                Reinhardt, although she herself dies. A now  furious  Reinhardt faces                this flying scythe-wielding  fiend, who can summon both  sickles and                huge green fish  to aid him.     Gilles  de Rais A faithful servant who has  worked for Dracula  since ancient times. His great age makes him the  closest to               a complete vampire in all facets, but he serves his darker lord all  the same.              Gilles de Rais knows that Dracula was born again  as a human child.  In order              to locate his master and  control the power, he commences a  mass kidnapping              of all  the children from nearby hamlets, using both his  devils and the help of  Actrise to help his cause. He gathers the children in  the castle,               and locates the resurrected power of Dracula in a small boy   called              Malus. However, before the complete transformation  and  rebirth can              be completed, he hears that two vampire  hunters have  infiltrated his              castle. To deceive them, he  changes his appearance and behaves as if he is Dracula himself.     Dracula  After being  defeated be the Belmonts,                  Dracula's  material body vanished,              and his soul was banished for one  hundred years, only to be  resurrected              in the form of  Malus. Malus does not have any memories of  his previous               life, but the devils notice their evil leader's traits in  the immense               dark power that Malus wields.             One devil  was even honored enough to transform into a  demonic steed               for the boy. However, another even more frightening power he  wields               appears to be being summoned by Malus. By the ritual   sacrificing of              the children captured by the devils, Malus'  powers of  transformation begin to surface as he remembers his true  vicious  nature. Malus is only the  initial              stage of  ultimate evil, as Dracula's true form reveals. </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16990">Hybrid Heaven</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2111575-box_cvlod.png</image></root>