<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6487</id><name>Peggle Extreme</name><description>OverviewAn example of the Valve themed levels to the game.  PopCap Games released Peggle Extreme, a shorter version of  Peggle, with  The Orange Box on the PC. The game has 10 levels which are unique to this version of Peggle and not included in the full  version of the game. The levels background themes are all related to Valve games  Half Life 2,  Portal,  Team Fortress 2 and  Counter-Strike: Source (even though it isn't part of The Orange Box), and  voices for each level are from their respective Valve game.   Peggle Extreme features one playable character which is  Bjorn, a  unicorn with the ability to show the player the direction in which their ball will bounce. The game also includes five master challenges for players to test their skills even further!GameplayGameplay revolves around the player trying to bounce balls on pegs and other obstacles in a level to clear as many of the orange pegs as possible with a limited number of balls. Along the bottom of the screen is the "free ball bucket" which provides the player a free ball should one of their balls fall into it. The pegs in each level come in a variety of colors, blue being the basic peg that has no purpose other than to increase a players score, purple pegs which provide bonus points but appear randomly after each shot never staying in the same location more than once, green pegs which activate the chosen characters special ability, and orange pegs which must be cleared to pass the level. The game provides an option for players who are colorblind, which adds triangles to the green pegs and a plus sign to purple pegs so they are easier to spot.Scoring in the game is done in a few ways, the most simple bouncing your ball on any peg will give points. Another way is "Style" points an example of this is the long shot where your ball hits an orange peg and bounces across the level to strike either a purple or orange peg thus creating a long shot. Apart from these two methods there is also completion bonuses which appear once the last orange peg has been struck the bottom of a level is replaced by buckets granting bonuses points. The center bucket has a bonus of 100,000 points while the buckets on either side of it grant 50,000 points and the two furthest buckets on each side side grant 10,000 points.This game is now free for everyone on Steam,  Download it here!  System RequirementsMinimum Requirements Operating system: Windows 2000/XP/VistaProcessor: 700 MHzRAM: 256 MBDirectX: 7.0</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="45">Block-Breaking</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21635">Neves</game><game id="29660">Trajectile</game><game id="36016">Kickin' Momma</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1220/216482-capture.jpg</image></root>