<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6490</id><name>Hogan's Alley</name><description>OverviewHogan's Alley is a NES game that used the NES Zapper, one of the first games released to use the Zapper.Shoot gangs only!The main objective of the game is to get as much points as possible by shooting the gangsters, while not shooting the civilians. The level is over when the player gets 10 'misses', misses include missing a gangster and shooting a civilian.Gangster A is worth 500 points, he is wearing a brown jacket and has brown hair.Gangster B is worth 1000 points, he is wearing a tan trench coat and wearing a trilby hat.Gangster C is worth 2000 points, he is wearing a tuxedo with a rose and a trilby hat.Game A - Hogan's Alley ATake that you gang!Game A is a simple target shooting level, 3 targets appear on the screen and the player has to shoot the gangster, or gangsters, that appear. The longer the game goes on, the faster the targets move and the less time the player has to shoot them. If the player misses 10 times, it's game over.Game B - Hogan's Alley BGame B takes place in a made up town consisting of a generic building with four windows, a gunWhoops, sorry about that.shop and a fenced area with a 'keep out' sign. 5 targets would appear at each area before the level scrolls over to the next area. If the player misses 10 times, it's game over.Game C - Trick ShotCome on, 5000 points.Game C doesn't use the targets that Game A and Game B uses, instead the player has to shoot cans that appear on the right hand side of the screen over to the left hand side of the screen, there are four different platforms on which the cans can land, the top left platform gives the player 300 points, the middle left platform gives the player 800 points, and the bottom left platform gives the player 5000 points. There is also a platform in the middle that gives the player 100 points.Game C was also featured in WarioWare: Touched! as a boss in 9-Volt's stage.</description><genres><genre id="35">Light-Gun Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1074">Link's Crossbow Training</game><game id="9645">Time Crisis: Project Titan</game><game id="12460">Super Mario Bros. / Duck Hunt</game><game id="2758">Duck Hunt</game><game id="17486">Mad Dog McCree</game><game id="15365">Time Crisis 2</game><game id="15867">Time Crisis</game><game id="10543">Virtua Cop</game><game id="9281">Point Blank</game><game id="20460">Target: Terror</game><game id="2817">Corpse Killer</game><game id="19246">Vampire Night</game><game id="1744">Lethal Enforcers</game><game id="17503">Who Shot Johnny Rock?</game><game id="13798">Safari Hunt</game><game id="12829">Revolution X</game><game id="9780">Silent Scope</game><game id="4125">The Lost World: Jurassic Park</game><game id="1113">Gumshoe</game><game id="103">Area 51</game><game id="14088">Operation Thunderbolt</game><game id="14869">Operation Wolf</game><game id="16218">Battle Clash</game><game id="16148">To the Earth</game><game id="12102">Baby Boomer</game><game id="8177">Barker Bill's Trick Shooting</game><game id="17826">Outlaw</game><game id="4116">Wild Gunman</game><game id="5967">Chiller</game><game id="3484">Metal Combat: Falcon's Revenge</game><game id="17980">Gotcha! The Sport!</game><game id="29088">Shooting Range</game><game id="29501">Lethal Enforcers I &amp; II</game><game id="20354">Gangster Town</game><game id="16834">City Killer</game><game id="4368">Marksman Shooting &amp; Trap Shooting</game><game id="11214">Bank Panic</game><game id="35952">Freedom Force</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2361809-nes_hogansalley.jpg</image></root>