<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6499</id><name>RalliSport Challenge 2</name><description> Gameplay Like its predecessor, Rallisport Challenge 2 is an arcade style rally game featuring a wide array of cars and tracks. Compared to other contemporary racing titles like Colin McRae 2004, the handling is much more accessible and arcade-like, but the realism is still greater than that of the original Rallisport Challenge.  All the cars handle differently, especially when switching between classes. Group B cars are infamous for their insane speed and hard controls, while the Ice Racing cars slide around ice tracks with four-wheel steering. Tuning allows for smaller adjustments like gear ratios and suspension stiffness. Damage modeling and crash physics play an important role in the game. Hitting a ramp-like set of rocks at the right angle and seeing your car roll vigorously while parts fly off makes for some intense replays. The game even included a cockpit camera where rotating the camera backwards meant looking through the rear window. Many tracks are available, ranging from hillclimbs in the USA to ice tracks in Canada, and if you tally up all the tracks and include all track variations the number will reach 90. Add impressive graphics and weather effects and you get a rally game ahead of its time. The game boasts a career mode with modes like Hillclimb or Rallycross, and skins could be unlocked for each car by reaching a certain mileage. Xbox Live support was available for this game, where players could host or search for lobbies. Hosts could force camera angles or tuning and decide whether collisions were enabled, which had an effect of the amount of players that could be in the race. Collisions turned off meant 16 players where the other players were represented by ghosts, while collisions turned on meant 4 players. XSN support was also available, which allowed tournaments that tied into the XSN website. System Link also added the ability of 16-player local multiplayer.Cars RallyHyundai Accent Evo 3 Škoda Octavia RSMitsubishi Lancer Evolution VIIISEAT Córdoba Evo 3 Ford Focus Air Force ReserveSubaru Impreza WRX Peugeot 206Citroen Xsara T4 Group B Renault 5 TurboMG Metro 6R4Toyota Celica Twincam TurboLancia 037 RallyFord RS200Peugeot 205Lancia Delta S4Audi Sport Quattro S1  Ice Racing  Toyota Corolla GTRenault Megane V6Peugeot 306 MaxiVolkswagen Beetle RSiBMW 318ti CompactFord Puma Evolution 4WDSNissan Micra V6Opel Astra V6 Rally Cross Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution VIHyundai Accent GTFord RS200 EvoVolvo 240 TurboOpel Astra T16Citroen Xsara T16Volvo S40 EVOSaab 9-3 TurboHillclimb Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution 6.5 RSPeugeot 405 T16Subaru Impreza 22B STiAudi Quattro S1 Pikes PeakSuzuki Grand VitaraToyota Tacoma Pikes PeakSaab 9-3 ViggenToyota Celica Pikes PeakClassic  Ford GT70Renault A110 AlpineLancia Stratos HF   DLC Saab 96 (Classic) Volvo Amazon (Classic) BMW X5 (SUV) Volkswagen Touareg (SUV)</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3916">DiRT</game><game id="15863">Colin McRae Rally 2005</game><game id="20033">Colin McRae Rally 3</game><game id="8944">RalliSport Challenge</game><game id="941">Project Gotham Racing</game><game id="19809">Project Gotham Racing 3</game><game id="8437">TOCA 2: Touring Car Challenge</game><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="7019">Ridge Racer V</game><game id="16276">Ford Bold Moves Street Racing</game><game id="20919">Ford Racing: Off Road</game><game id="5977">Need for Speed III: Hot Pursuit</game><game id="7431">Ford Racing</game><game id="12950">Gran Turismo 3 A-Spec</game><game id="7777">Juiced</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="17872">TOCA Race Driver 3 Challenge</game><game id="23461">FUEL</game><game id="20132">Sega Rally Revo</game><game id="24513">DiRT 2</game><game id="30383">DiRT 3</game><game id="34757">Test Drive V-Rally</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2276069-box_rsc2.png</image></root>