<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>65</id><name>Serious Sam</name><description>OverviewSerious Sam on the                Xbox, the first entry of the series onto the console, also known as Serious Sam Gold on the               PC takes everything from              First Encounter and             Second Encounter then throws on a whole new layer of new graphics and extra multi-player options. The            Serious Sam game series has been known to be "cartoony", super fast paced and           extremely violent/         gory. Developer         Croteam has stated that it's a        homage to       old school shooter      Duke Nukem. The basic concept behind Serious Sam is that you are given loads of ridiculous weapons which are stocked with LOADS of     ammo and are pit up against thousands of enemies in a single level. Take into account that there are over 35 levels and you're in for some major action. The game doesn't exactly take itself seriously). There are plenty of funny    cutscenes, goofy levels and great cartoony enemies. Serious Sam is a   First-Person shooter that runs on the in-house engine, the Serious Engine. Serious Sam on Xbox was considered a sleeper hit and was even enjoyed by the most hardcore of shooter fans.EnemiesMarsh-Hopper from Rigil KentaurusSize: 3 ftWeapons: Toxic Slime SplashScore: 50Threat: Very lowBeheaded RocketeerSize: 6 ftWeapons: Magic-Missile LauncherScore: 100Threat: Very lowBeheaded FirecrackerSize: 6 ftWeapons: Triple Magic-Missile LauncherScore: 100Threat: Very low Beheaded BomberSize: 6 ftWeapons: Hand GrenadesScore: 200Threat: LowMale GnaarSize: 4 ftWeapons: Bites, PunchesScore: 200Threat: LowZorg Mercenary from Beelmez IVSize: 6.5 ftWeapons: Burst LaserScore: 300Threat: LowZorg Commander from Bellmez IVSize: 7 ftWeapons: Sweep Burst LaserScore: 400Threat: LowFemale GnaarSize: 5 ftWeapons: Bites, PunchesScore: 500Threat: LowReeban Electro-FishSize: 11 ft in lengthWeapons: Electric DischargesScore: 1000Threat: MediumBeheaded KamikazeSize: 6 ftWeapons: Hand GrenadesScore: 1000Threat: MediumScythian Witch-HarpySize: 5 ft StandingWeapons: Magic Projectiles, ClawsScore: 1000Threat: MediumKleer SkeletonSize: 9 ftWeapons: Two-ball Projectiles, ClawsScore: 1000Threat: MediumBio-Mechanoid, MinorSize: 15 ft StandingWeapons: Pulse LasersScore: 1500Threat: MediumCucurbito the PumpkinSize: 7.5 ft StandingWeapons: ChainsawScore: 1500Threat: MediumZumb'ul from Planet Ras-ad-NykSize: 10 ftWeapons: Twin Hand Plasma LaunchersScore: 2000Threat: MediumJuvenile ArachnodSize: 10 ftWeapons: Chain-Gun, Tail StingScore: 2000Threat: MediumSirian WerebullSize: 9 ftWeapons: HornsScore: 2500Threat: MediumCannonSize: 12 ftWeapons: CannonballsScore: 2500Threat: MediumAdult ArachnoidSize: 20 - 25 ftWeapons: Chain-Gun, Tail StingScore: 3000Threat: MediumAludran Reptiloid, CommonSize: 15 ftWeapons: Magic Homing MissilesScore: 4000Threat: MediumFiendian Reptiloid DemonSize: 20 ft StandingWeapons: Lavaball Projectile, ClawsScore: 5000Threat: MediumBio-Mechanoid, MajorSize: 30 ft StandingWeapons: Rocket LaunchersScore: 7500Threat: HightLava GolemSize: 10 - 100 ftWeapons: FireballsScore: 500 - 250,000Threat: Low to ExtremeAludran Repriloid, HighlanderSize: 45 ftWeapons: Magic Homing MissileScore: 25,000Threat: High</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="7338">Earth Defense Force 2017</game><game id="621">Doom II: Hell on Earth</game><game id="8099">TimeSplitters: Future Perfect</game><game id="17246">TimeSplitters 2</game><game id="1854">Devastation</game><game id="17746">Shadow Warrior</game><game id="14537">Doom 3</game><game id="13683">Quake 4</game><game id="3207">Quake II</game><game id="8015">Quake</game><game id="17646">Unreal</game><game id="19181">Return to Castle Wolfenstein</game><game id="7814">Half-Life: Blue Shift</game><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="25048">Drug Wars</game><game id="25062">Painkiller: Hell Wars</game><game id="25814">Painkiller: Resurrection</game><game id="34086">Painkiller: Redemption</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1796279-box_ssxbox.png</image></root>