<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6525</id><name>Thunder in Paradise Interactive</name><description>TV Show BackgroundThunder in Paradise for the Phillips CD-I was based on a direct to video movie made in 1993 staring Hulk Hogan and Christopher Lemon.  The movie was followed by a TV show which debuted in 1994 and only lasted one season.  The show was about 2 for hire mercs based out of Florida who designed and built Thunder a highly advanced speed boat with weapons, hidden jet ski's and optical camo capabilities.  The team of ex Seals fought various sea and land based crime while trying to keep their home lives in check.  The show also features wrestlers such was Brutus Beefcake, Sting, and Jim Neidhart as guest stars.  Sting was Hulk Hogans main nemesis of the series.  It was mainly aimed at children and young adults. The GameThe CD-I game was based on the final 2 episodes of the series titled "The Major and the Minor" which was a 2 part conclusion to the show airing in November of 1994.The game is divided into 3 main events or sections much in the same way as "Die Hard" for Sega Saturn was set up except the last 2 are identical in terms of gameplay.  You can play the sections of the game in any order that you want but doing so might mess up plot points.  Being able to select the section from the main menu was probably done because the game cant be saved.The first event is titled "Thunder Encounter".  In Thunder Encounter you control the weapons on the war ship Thunder.  You cannot control the boat itself as the game is FMV based.  The object is to protect Thunder and destroy as many targets as possible.  You can switch which side of the boat the camera is on instantly or you can slowly rotate the camera yourself.  There is a radar that tells you where threats are coming from so you know where you should be looking but the often sluggish controls can make destroying the targets harder than it really should be.The second and third event are titled "Island Encounter"  and "Lab Encounter".  Both of these sections of the game play like classic arcade and console shooters.  You dont control the movement of your character but you control a cursor which you use to aim and shot at targets.  One big difference between this game and others like the original Area 51 or Mad Dog McCree is the actors you are shooting arent always in the same location.  They were filmed independent of the scene itself so their locations can be randomized.  The action is also fairly fast paced thanks to the health bar system instead of the (at the time) standard 1 shot and you're dead in FMV games.PrototypeThe prototype of Thunder in Paradise which you can buy on ebay if you're lucky and would want such a thing differs from the retail release in a couple of ways but it is really only meant for collectors.  Some basic art was changed as well as certain menus and video files.  There was also the possibility of a difference video codec being used or a higher bit rate.  File structure and file names on the discs was also modified as were some of the security files standard on all Phillips CD-I games.  In terms of sheer gameplay there are no noticeable changes therefore there is no reason for any non collecting gamer to seek this very rare prototype out.  </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14975/1339651-thunder_in_paradiseboxart.jpg</image></root>