<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6557</id><name>Revelations: Persona</name><description>General InformationRevelations: Persona was released by Atlus for the PlayStation in the United States in 1997 and is the first in the Persona series of games. Notable for being set in modern day, the plot involves an unnamed protagonist and his classmates at St. Hermelin High School. The story begins as the protagonist and his classmates play a game called "Persona", akin to the ritual game "Bloody Mary". While playing, the students lose consciousness and meet a mysterious man in a butterfly mask named Philemon, who gives them the ability to summon reflections of their personalities, which are known as Personae. A bit shaken by their collective experience, the group visits a hospitalized friend but are attacked by demons. It is up to the protagonist and his friends to save the now isolated town and figure out the mystery behind the demon attacks and their new ability to summon Persona.CharactersProtagonistThe silent protagonist of the game, He's described as a boy from St. Hermelin High School with dark hair and a pierced ears. He is sometimes unofficially referred to by fans as Naoya Toudou; the name given to him in the game's manga adaptation. The protagonist wields a rapier and an MP5 as his weapons, and his initial Persona is Seimen Kongou of the Emperor Arcana.Maki SonomuraU.S. Localization Name: MaryA frail, bedridden girl who is a student from St. Hermelin High School, however she appears as being healthy and cheerful after the incidents with the demons begin. She is not playable in the Snow Queen Quest, but is mandatory for the main quest. Maki uses a bow and a handgun, and her initial persona is Matsu of the Priestess Arcana.Masao InabaU.S. Localization Name: MarkA friend of Naoya who has a crush on Maki. He hopes to be an artist. He is not playable in the Snow Queen Quest, but is mandatory for the main quest. Masao uses an axe and shotgun, and his initial Persona is Ogun of the Chariot Arcana.Kei NanjouU.S. Localization Name: NateA wealthy student who stands to inherit a large company. He is a very rational and has a stiff personality. He was renamed as Nate Trinity in the US version. He is optional in the Snow Queen quest, and is mandatory for the main quest. Kei uses a broadsword and rifle, and his initial Persona is Aizen Myouou of the Hierophant Arcana.Hidehiko UesugiU.S. Localization Name: BradClass clown who tells jokes to get attention. He is optional in both the main quest and the Snow Queen Quest. Hidehiko uses a spear and a TMP machine gun, and his initial Persona is Nemhain of the Justice Arcana.Eriko KirishimaU.S. Localization Name: EllenA popular girl who is interested in being a model. She is optional in both the main quest and the Snow Queen Quest. Eriko uses a rapier and a rifle, and her initial Persona is Nike of the Judgment Arcana.Yuka AyaseU.S. Localization Name Name: AlanaA student who is popular with the guys, but her habit of being overly frank gets her into problems. She is optional in the main quest, but is mandatory in the Snow Queen Quest. Yuka uses a whip and handgun in battle, and her initial Persona is Houri of the Magician Arcana.Reiji KidoU.S. Localization Name: ChrisA transfer student who is often antisocial and rarely attends class. He is known for being hard to acquire as a party member, having a long list of requirements to get him to join. He is not available in the Snow Queen Quest. Reiji uses his fists and an assault rifle, and his initial Persona is Bres of the Devil Arcana.Yukino MayuzumiU.S. Localization Name: YukiA former delinquent who reformed due to the efforts of her teacher. She is not available in the main quest, but she is mandatory in the Snow Queen Quest. Yukino uses razorblades and a shotgun, and her initial Persona is Vesta of the Empress Arcana.GameplayA Persona is summoned in battle.Similar to other role-playing games, Revelations: Persona utilizes a turn-based combat system that allows the player to manage a party and use various attacks, items, and spells to defeat the enemy. Additionally, the game allows the player to avoid some combat situations by talking, bribing, and flirting with the enemy. These non-combat options are not always available to the player and fighting cannot be avoided. While not in combat the party explores city streets, the high school, shopping malls, and other locations in the town. During interior exploration the camera takes a first-person perspective but when the party moves into enclosed rooms or cuts to dialog scenes the camera takes a third-person isometric perspective. When navigating the city streets the camera takes a top-down perspective with the party and the buildings being represented with abstract geometric shades.LocalizationMasao from the Japan release (left), Mark from the North America release (right)The western release of Revelations: Persona saw many cosmetic and technical changes. Many details of the plot were changed to "westernize" the game for the North American market. Characters were renamed, sprites and character portraits were redrawn to look more "western", and items in the game were changed to downplay the games original Japanese origin. In the most extreme example, the character Masao Inaba from the Japanese version was renamed Mark, redrawn to have darker skin, and his dialog was changed to be more urban, essentially making the character African-American. All references that the game takes place in modern day Japan were stripped out; the name of the town, originally Mikage-cho, was renamed Lunarvale and yen currency was changed to dollars. The game was also made easier for the western market. In the North American version, the randomly triggered encounters are less frequent and experience points awarded for each battle was increased. Additionally, the Snow Queen quest, an alternate, optional story route with completely different challenges, was removed from the game entirely.CompendiumAnother result of the game's localization was that many of the personas' and demons' names were mistranslated or altered. What follows are their names as presented in the game, but linked to their real identities.PersonasPersonas are ordered by level, from highest to lowest.0. Fool61 Karma47 Nari30 TenjiI. Magician80 Leuda68 Hannu59 Flare47 Vora35 Helion28 Lance14 Ix18 FuryII. High Priestess88 Scrag70 Racsha61 Valzante53 Chatz46 Vixen37 Wals29 Deva18 Crosscut11 Virgo5 MariaIII. Empress85 Kari65 Ishtal57 Dorga44 Celes36 Brigit27 Iron bride15 Rain6 VestaIV. Emperor86 Ashura62 Ra55 Bard43 Odin34 Ug23 Brax12 Pawn5 StarionV. Hierophant89 Endora74 Bucho52 Thor39 Mephisto25 Omah17 Shogi6 Voodoo4 TricksterVI. Lovers20 Jack O'10 Jack Frost5 PixieVII. Chariot96 Shiva59 Demo48 Shaolin33 Mordo18 Vortek5 ShamanVIII. Justice90 Athena66 Bushido54 Darkside46 Morie37 Region28 Mach19 Dark Rider8 TalonIX. Hermit39 Frost25 Stalios16 HellcatX. Fortune40 CerebusXI. Strength50 ViperXII. Hanged Man59 JesterXIII. Death58 Mondo44 Inferno34 HeraXIV. Temperance45 Gemb32 AnuvisXV. Devil99 Lucifer77 Beezlebum51 Loki10 GuniXVI. Tower88 Shaa66 MassacreXVII. Star22 SumiXVIII. Moon53 Succubus21 RemyXIX. Sun79 Garuda55 Phoenix41 Crow24 Gasious10 VenXX. Judgement94 Abracab79 Dark angel62 Michael60 Alfred55 Allmighty36 Azreal18 Halo7 NikeXXI. World97 Zuma76 Borax49 St. Dragon29 Leviathan17 HiveDemonsLike the persona table, this lists demons as they were originally translated, but linked to their actual names.Revelations: Persona was also the first localized Shin Megami Tensei game to feature the series' traditional demon races. However, due to space restraints, they were confined to two-letter abbreviations for each. The real race name follows in parentheses.ND (Night)64 Moonchild58 Insibus51 Succubus42 Incubus34 Hinos27 Mermaid19 Remy13 Nightmare7 HermitFY (Fairy)57 King fly49 Queen fly40 Princix31 Hellion23 Dark elf18 Water elf15 Jack o'8 Jack frost2 PixieFA (Fallen)71 Rainchild65 Abax56 Jester48 Palerider41 Astral33 Blax knight26 Arapachi17 Dev chef9 GrubED (Drake)70 Faefnel58 Weirdo51 Felios43 Snaketail33 Drac23 Wyvern15 CockatriceCB (Raptor)66 Light dove53 Alecto36 Gargos25 Beezley14 KimonoWM (Wilder)75 Fenril63 Bufflax52 Dragos43 Sucula31 Black widow22 Babe16 Nuea9 SharktoothWD (Brute)52 Yaksha44 Puru37 Valkyrie32 Dead chef25 Ripper16 Hanya8 FrumanEM (Jaki)61 Manimal53 Durahan42 Maui35 Landshark27 Fugly19 Ogre13 GremlinEG (Spirit)45 Macabre34 Lips25 Flower kid19 Toilet kid15 Dribbler8 Ghost5 Static2 WraithOL (Foul)68 Grimy50 Shadow41 Clone32 Anatomy24 Flux15 Yakuza8 Thug1 SlimeSM (Meta)56 Blackman20 Agent14 S.S.SD (Yoma)65 Ganesha60 Moai51 Tengu43 Cupid35 Zin26 Raksha18 Cyrus10 Magic urnAL (Divine)64 Kelpi57 Chronos52 Dominion44 Virtue36 Power29 Principal21 Arch angel14 AngelDN (Snake)67 Shin59 Vixen50 Viper44 Water asp38 Naga30 Shadow asp22 LeachBD (Flight)55 Ramia47 Bumbo39 Ithl28 Sith19 Owl10 FirebirdMA (Beast)54 Leo46 Scorpio37 Otros29 Hemes20 Felicia12 Kariee6 MuskatDW (Femme)59 Randa51 Warchild43 Dance34 Rantula29 Chomp23 Siren17 SacrificeDD (Jirae)54 Golem45 Karak32 Dwarfen20 Kobold11 Goul4 ImpGT (Haunt)66 Chow54 Moroku47 Insectoid34 Shremlin28 Karen21 Ifirit12 Shpos3 GoblinZE (Grave)41 Painter35 Psycho26 Gleeb11 Zombie cop5 Dead nurse4 Zombie girl3 Zombie boy1 ZombieSS (Karma)55 Arrogance52 Sloth50 Bellycasey49 Jealousy47 Greed45 ObsceneDM (Fiend)99 AliceBossesWhere applicable, boss names are linked to their real identities. Otherwise, the actual names are listed in parentheses. Certain bosses in the game can be encountered at different levels depending on criteria met or failed by the playerNormal BossesSnow Queen Quest Bosses30 SM Tiny (Meta Takeda)36 OL RoboRat (Foul Tesso)39 EM Yoga Jr. (Jaki Yog-Sothoth Jr.)40/50 SM Queen (Meta Harem Queen)48 OL Teddybear (Foul Mr. Bear)55 KD Salavino (Tyrant Saurva)61 ?? (Lady) Norn66 SM Guido, with his persona Massacre76 DM Super Guido (Deity God Kandori)85 KD Pandora (Tyrant Pandora)99 KD Pandora (Butterfly form)31/38/41/48 ND Hypnos31/36/38/41/45/52 DW Nemesis50/64 GR (Reaper) Nucleus70 KD Snow Lady (Karma Lady Snow)67 SS Lax (Karma Lady Masquerade)99 KD Ashura (Tyrant Queen Asura)PSP RemakeThe new localization has double the meat of the previous.A remake of the game from 1996 was released on the PSP on September 22, 2009. It contains new and updated animated cut-scenes from Kamikazegouga, revamped UI to take advantage of the PSP widescreen, a rebalanced game system with the option to adjust the difficulty, new dungeon floors added that were not included in either the Japanese or American releases, and finally, rearranged music featuring Yumi Kawamura, the vocalist for the Persona 3 tracks, composed by Shoji Meguro. In this remake, battle animations can now be skipped entirely, and the battle load times have been decreased to 2/3 the rate of the original game, There are more save points available throughout the game, as well as a quicksave feature. Additionally, the overworld map has been redrawn to bring it up to the standard of the rest of the series.The PSP version also contains extra dungeons, including the Snow Queen quest not included in the original PS1 US release. The English edition also features a completely redone localization more faithful to the original material. The remake's new animated cutscenes are also fully voiced. Every copy of the game released in North America was packed with a two-disc soundtrack. It was also one of the first PSP titles to be released simultaneously on UMD and PSN.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13053">Final Fantasy VII</game><game id="12277">Final Fantasy VIII</game><game id="8825">Final Fantasy IX</game><game id="17659">Grandia</game><game id="7866">Final Fantasy Origins</game><game id="19349">Breath of Fire III</game><game id="9177">Breath of Fire IV</game><game id="595">Tales of Eternia</game><game id="2254">Dragon Warrior VII</game><game id="8810">Suikoden</game><game id="18304">Xenogears</game><game id="15962">Wild Arms 2</game><game id="2222">Wild Arms</game><game id="17767">Lunar: Silver Star Story Complete</game><game id="4248">Lunar 2: Eternal Blue Complete</game><game id="8048">Dragon Warrior Monsters 2</game><game id="13470">Dragon Warrior Monsters</game><game id="21676">Pokémon Platinum</game><game id="3966">Pokémon Red/Blue</game><game id="10122">Pokémon Ruby/Sapphire</game><game id="8210">Pokémon Gold/Silver</game><game id="14522">Pokémon FireRed/LeafGreen</game><game id="11552">Pokémon Emerald</game><game id="24009">Dragon Quest Monsters 1 &amp; 2</game><game id="23128">Robopon: Sun Version</game><game id="3755">Persona 2: Innocent Sin</game><game id="34076">Final Fantasy IV: The Complete Collection</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1845425-box_smtp.png</image></root>