<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6582</id><name>Test Drive Unlimited</name><description>Test Drive Unlimited is the latest installment of the Test Drive video game series. Released in 2006, the game contains a new concept for MMOs and any other game. MOOR (Massively Open Online Racing) lets you drive around in an open world with many other drivers without having to go though any lobby system. You are always be connected to any other player around that area you are driving in and at any point may challenge them to a quick race or just drive by them and ignore them.Burning rubber for the camera.Test Drive Unlimited opens with you flying to Honolulu, Hawaii and renting a car - there is a distinct lack of story outside your typical 'earn money and buy everything in sight,' but the game never forces you down any particular path and every race is open from the start provided you can find it. Every section of road you drive on is marked, and you're free to leap around from point to point. If you haven't reached a race or dealership the game will flag the location on your GPS and you have to drive there - given the size of the island, driving around the whole thing can take upwards of an hour in a slower vehicle. And naturally, there is a late-game race that does ask you to drive the entire island in one go.Single and multiplayer races are available, with the multiplayer races queuing up available racers in the area. It's also possible to initiate impromptu one-on-one sprints against opponent cars that you encounter in the game world by flashing your lights - you then pick an end point and the first to reach it wins.Test Drive Unlimited also features motorcycles, which can make races interesting due to their small size and weight when compared to all of the cars. Getting nudged by anything larger than another bike is a sure way to send your rider head-first into the ditch.Test Drive Unlimited for PSP and PS2The PSP and PS2 versions of Test Drive Unlimited are a different game from the Xbox 360 and PC version, and by a different developer. (Melbourne House, also known as Krome Studios)Despite this the PSP and PS2 version is still a massively open world game where the player can traverse the entire island, and even includes racers that span the entire island. (i.e. no loading screens) Both versions also contains online functionality.However there are some shortcomings and/or differences, these include:Downscaled visuals.No NPC characters, for that matter no humans are ever seen aside from the prerendered intro cutscene when starting the game for the first time.No motorcycles.No DLC.The online functionality of the PSP versions seems to be no longer functioning.All differences listed are based on the PSP version of the game.CarsImages:A Shelby GT50An Alfa Romeo GTA Nissan 350ZA Pagani ZondaCar List:AC Cobra 289AC Cobra 427Alfa Romeo 8C CompetizioneAlfa Romeo BreraAlfa Romeo GT 3.2 V6 24VAlfa Romeo GT 3.2 V6 24V Sporting Technical KitAscari KZ-1Aston Martin DB4 GT ZagatoAston Martin DB7 ZagatoAston Martin DB9 CoupeAston Martin DB9 VolanteAston Martin V8 VantageAston Martin Vanquish S V28Audi A3 3.2 Quattro DSGAudi A6 4.2 QuattroAudi RS4 Quattro SedanAudi S4 CabrioletAudi TT Quattro SportCaterham CSR260Chrysler 300C® SRT8Chrysler Crossfire® SRT6 CoupeChrysler Crossfire® SRT6 ConvertibleChrysler Firpower Concept CarChrysler ME-FOUR TwelveDodge Challenger R/T '71Dodge Charger Super Bee Hemi '71Dodge Viper SRT-10Dodge Viper SRT-10 CoupeDucati 999RDucati Monster S4RDucati Supersport 1000DSB. Engineering Edonis V12Farboud Supercharged GTS PrototypeFerrari 250 GTO '62Ferrari 288 GTOFerrari 308 GTSFerrari 360 ModenaFerrari 575M MaranelloFerrari 612 ScagliettiFerrari Enzo FerrariFerrari F40Ferrari F430Ferrari F430 SpiderFerrari F599 GTBFord GTFord GT40Ford Mustang GT-R ConceptFord Mustang GTFord Mustang GT ConvertibleFord Shelby Cobra ConceptFord Shelby GR-1 ConceptCadillac® Cien ConceptCadillac® CTS-VCadillac® XLR-VCheverolet Matiz 0.8Chevrolet® Camaro® Z-28™ '67Chevrolet® Cobalt SS Supercharged Coupe ConceptChevrolet® Corvette® C1 '57Chevrolet® Corvette® C2 '63Chevrolet® Corvette® Stingray™ C3 '69Chevrolet® Corvette® Stingray™ Convertible C3 '71Chevrolet® Corvette® C6™ Coupe '05Chevrolet® Corvette® C6™ Convertible '05Chevrolet® Corvette® C6 Z06™ '06Chevrolet® SSR™ '05Pontiac® Firebird™ '70Pontiac® GTO® '04Pontiac® Solstice '06Saturn™ Curve Concept '04Saturn™ Sky™ '07Jaguar E-Type '64Jaguar XJ220Jaguar XK Coupe '06Jaguar XK Convertible '06Jaguar XKR Coupe '05Kawasaki Ninja ZX-10R '05Kawasaki Ninja ZX-12R '05Kawasaki Z1000 '05Koenigsegg CC8SKoenigsegg CCRLamborghini Countach 25th Anniversary '89Lamborghini Diablo GT '99Lamborghini Gallardo Coupe '04Lamborghini Gallardo SE '05Lamborghini Gallardo Spyder '06Lamborghini Miura P400 SV '71Lamborghini Murcielago 6.2Lamborghini Murcielago RoadsterLamborghini Gallardo 2dr CoupeLexus IS 350Lotus Elise R '05Lotus Esprit V8 '02Lotus Sport Exige 240R '05Maserati 3500 GT '60Maserati GranSportMaserati MC12Maserati Spyder 90th AnniversaryMaserati Spyder Cambiocorsa '04Mazda MX-5 Miata '06Mazda RX-8McLaren F1 '97McLaren F1 GT '97McLaren F1 GTR '95McLaren F1 LM '95Mercedes-Benz 300SL '57Mercedes-Benz CLK55 AMG '05Mercedes-Benz CLK DTM AMGMercedes-Benz CLK GTRMercedes-Benz CLS55 AMGMercedes-Benz SL65 AMGMercedes-Benz SLK55 AMGMercedes-Benz SLR McLarenMV Agusta F4 Brutale 910SMV Agusta F4 TamburiniNissan 350Z CoupeNissan 350 Nismo S-TuneNissan Skyline GT-R R34Noble M12 GTO-3RNoble M14Noble M400Pagani Zonda C12SPagani Zonda C12S RoadsterRuf RGTRuf Rt 12Ruf RturboSaleen S281 3 Valve CoupeSaleen S281 3 Valve ConvertibleSaleen S281 Extreme CoupeSaleen S281 Supercharged CoupeSaleen S281 Supercharged ConvertibleSaleen S281 Supercharged SpeedsterSaleen S7 Twin-TurboShelby Cobra Daytona CoupeShelby GT500 '67Spyker C8 LavioletteSpyker C8 SpyderSpyker C8 Spyder TTriumph Speed TripleTVR SagarisTVR Tuscan SVolkswagen Golf V R32Volkswagen W12 CoupeVolkswagen W12 RoadsterWiesmann GT MF4Wiesmann Roadster MF3DLC CarsThe cars that have been released through Downloadable content are:RUF RK SpyderCadillac CienAudi RS4 quattro SaloonNissan Skyline GTR R341971 Dodge Challenger RTLexus IS 350Chevrolet Corvette C1 1957Lexus GS 450hLexus LS 460Cadillac CTS-VSaturn CurveLexus LS600h LLexus SC 430Holden Efijy ConceptNissan 350Z Roadster 2004RUF RGTKoenigsegg CCRNoble M400Corvette C6 ConvertibleFerrari 250 GTO 1962Lamborghini Countach 25th Anniversary EditionFerrari 612 ScagliettiMcLaren F1 GTDodge Viper SRT-10 CoupeRUF Rt 12Alfa Brera1971 Dodge Challenger RTEdonisFerrari F40Chrysler Crossfire SRT6 RoadsterRUF RturboAudi S6Chevrolet Corvette Stingray Convertible 1971Mercedes-Benz CLK GTRDino 246 GTFerrari Challenge StradaleCadillac CienRUF RK SpyderLamborghini Murci lago RoadsterTVR T440RChryslerCrossfire SRT6 CoupeDodge Charger Super BeeFerrari 308 GTS QuattrovalvoleFerrari 512 TRKawasaki Ninja ZX-12RSpyker C8 SpyderAudi A4 Touring CarCadillac SixteenDino 246 GTSTriumph Daytona 995iPontiac SolsticeLamborghini Diablo GTSoundtrack9 Volter - Colour of FireAnd I'm Hip - Sgt RockAngels Go Bald: Too - Howie BAnother Excuse - SoulwaxA Gritty Nitty - The Pazant BrothersBack Again - Boy Kill BoyBig Bird - Eddie FloydBlack Powder - MotorCarbon Kid - AlpinestarsCissy Popcorn - PrestonLoveCompute - SoulwaxComin' Down - The ViewFeels Closer - Layo  Bushwacka ft. Mino CineluFinally Free - ClearlakeFix the Cracks - HumanziFunk #49 - The James GangFunky Chicken - Preston LoveHandshakes - MetricHe's Gonna Step On You Again - John KongosHere We Go - Broken DollsHired Goons - Evil 9I Live For - Johnny PanicI'm A Road Runner - Jr Walker ft. The All StarsInformation - Black DanielNo One Knows (UNKLE REMIX) - Queens of the Stone AgePWSteal.Ldpinch.D - AFXRestless - The CobrasSling Shot - Lefties Soul ConnectionSilver Buddha - The Domes of SilenceYou're Wasting My Time (PT1) - Billy GarnerSystem RequirmentsOperating System: Windows 2000/XP/VistaCPU: Intel P4 @ 2.4 GHz or AMD Athlon 2800Video Cards: ATI Radeon 9800 256MB VRAM or Nvidia 6600 GT with 256 MB of VRAM. (Video Cards with vertex/pixel shaders 2.x and above are recommended.)Sound Cards: DirectX 9.0 compatible Sound CardSystem Memory: 512 MB, 1 GB recommendedHard Disk Space: 8GBDVD-ROM drive: 8x minimumDirectX: DirectX 9.0C (included)</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12976">Need for Speed: Most Wanted</game><game id="788">The Fast and the Furious</game><game id="5648">Burnout Paradise</game><game id="1052">Super PickUps</game><game id="25226">Need for Speed World</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="20418">Midnight Club II</game><game id="5875">Midnight Club 3: DUB Edition</game><game id="20927">Midnight Club: Los Angeles</game><game id="21114">Midnight Club: Los Angeles Remix</game><game id="13751">Test Drive 4</game><game id="35499">Thrill Drive 3</game><game id="36067">Destiny</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1795448-box_tdu.png</image></root>