<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6588</id><name>Mortal Kombat: Deadly Alliance</name><description>Overview   Shang Tsung, one of the two main antagonists of Mortal Kombat: Deadly Alliance.     Mortal Kombat: Deadly Alliance is a 3D fighting game developed and published by                                                       Midway on November 2002 for the                                                      PlayStation 2,                                                     GameCube, and                                                    Xbox. It is the fifth installment in the                                                   Mortal Kombat franchise, changing various gameplay mechanics while adding new modes and features. The plot follows evil sorcerors                                                  Quan Chi and                                                 Shang Tsung, who form a deadly alliance (together killing                                                Shao Kahn and                                               Liu Kang) in order to revive the                                             Dragon King's undead army.   This is the first game in the franchise to include the concept of "koins", which can be used in                                            The Krypt mode to unlock characters, arenas, alternate costumes, concept art, promotional material, and the                                           Mortal Kombat Collector's Edition comic book. Players can also store their battle stats and unlockables in unique "player profiles" passworded with a four-button combination. Two ports of Mortal Kombat: Deadly Alliance for the                                          Game Boy Advance were developed: "Mortal Kombat: Deadly Alliance" and "Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition", each featuring a mostly-different character roster. Although these versions had 2D character sprites, the gameplay was in 3D.  Gameplay Mortal Kombat: Deadly Alliance plays differently to previous Mortal Kombat games. Players have four attack buttons (however, they do not represent specific punches or kicks), a Block button (R2 in the PlayStation 2 version, R in the GameCube version, and Right Trigger in the Xbox version), a Special Attack button (R1 in the PlayStation 2 version, Z in the GameCube version, and Black Button in the Xbox version), and a Change Fighting Style button (L1 in the PlayStation 2 version, L in the GameCube version, and Left Trigger in the Xbox version). Special Attack buttons have a wide range of utility depending on the character's current fighting style, including throws, taunts, and "Power-Ups".  Fighting Styles Each character has three fighting styles. Two of them are based on actual fighting styles while the third fighting style allows the character to brandish a weapon. (With the exception of secret characters Blaze and Mokap, who instead possess three actual fighting styles and no weapons) Pressing the Change Fighting Style button immediately switches the character to the next fighting style. Players can also press the Change Fighting Style button in the middle of certain combos to switch fighting styles while continuing the combo, allowing for more devastating combos. Unlike Mortal Kombat 4, the character equips and unequips weapons on the fly and the character's weapon cannot be dropped and picked up. Characters have a minimal amount of Special Moves, forcing players to focus on the fighting styles.  Fatalities Mortal Kombat: Deadly Alliance is the only fighting game in the franchise to not include Stage                                       Fatalities. However, several stages include environmental interaction, such as obstacles. Although each character has only one Fatality in the game, Mortal Kombat: Deadly Alliance introduces a Fatality "fighting style" system that, when players can perform Fatalities, they can press the Change Fighting Style button to lock the character down to perform the Fatality easier. Konquest Mode Along with the traditional Arcade and Versus modes, Mortal Kombat: Deadly Alliance includes Konquest Mode, which tutors the player on each character while building upon the character's fiction. After completing the eight introductory challenges, players can perform ten challenges with each character. Each character has their own unique challenges, ranging from performing specific combos and techniques to winning against hard computer opponents. Konquest Mode is the primary means of earning "koins" for The Krypt. Completing all challenges with all characters unlocks Blaze and Mokap as playable characters.  Mini-games Mortal Kombat: Deadly Alliance includes two mini-games: Test Your Might and Test Your Sight.                                     Test Your Might is the mini-game from the original                                    Mortal Kombat, where players have to tap buttons to build up a bar (which quickly decreases) until it reaches a certain point, at which the player presses another button and the character attempts to break the object. Test Your Sight (a name parody) forces the player to follow the movement of a set of cups in order to find the one with the Mortal Kombat logo hidden underneath it.Characters  The character select screen with the 12 starting characters.   Mortal Kombat: Deadly Alliance includes 12 starting playable characters, 9 unlockable characters (that must be bought from The Krypt), 2 secret characters, and 1 unplayable sub-boss. Raiden, Shang Tsung, Quan Chi, Scorpion, Sub-Zero, Johnny Cage, Kano, Sonya, Jax, Reptile, Kung Lao, Kitana, and Cyrax return from previous Mortal Kombat games. New characters that are playable include Kenshi (a                              blind warrior), Bo' Rai Cho (a                               drunken martial arts master), Li Mei (a warrior from                                 Outworld), Nitara (a vampire), Mavado (a high-ranking member of the Red Dragon clan, a rival clan of Kano's), Hsu Hao (henchman of Mavado), Frost (Sub-Zero's female apprentice), and Drahmin (a vile, decomposing                                Netherrealm demon). The one unplayable sub-boss is Moloch, another Netherrealm demon who guards the main antagonists.  The two secret characters, who can only be unlocked when the player fully completes Konquest Mode with all characters, are Blaze (a fire elemental) and Mokap (a                                  motion-capture artist). The first port of Mortal Kombat: Deadly Alliance for the Game Boy Advance included 7 starting playable characters and 5 unlockable characters. The second port, Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition, included 10 starting playable characters and 5 unlockable characters, including characters not included in any other version (Sareena, Sektor, and Noob Saibot).                            Shang Tsung (boss, unlockable in the first GBA port)                          Bo' Rai Cho (not available in the first GBA port)                         Quan Chi (boss, unlockable in the first GBA port)                        Li Mei (not available in the second GBA port)                       Scorpion                      Sonya (not available in the second GBA port)                     Kenshi (not available in the second GBA port)                    Mavado (not available in the first GBA port)                   Johnny Cage (not available in the first GBA port)                  Sub-Zero (not available in the second GBA port, unlockable in the first GBA port)                 Kano (not available in the second GBA port, unlockable in the first GBA port)                Kung Lao (not available in the second GBA port)               Nitara (unlockable, not available in the first GBA port, standard in the second GBA port)              Drahmin (unlockable, not available in the first GBA port)             Hsu Hao (unlockable, not available in the first GBA port)            Frost (unlockable, not available in the second GBA port, standard in the first GBA port)           Jax (unlockable, not available in the second GBA port, standard in the first GBA port)          Kitana (unlockable, not available in the second GBA port)         Raiden (unlockable, not available in the first GBA port, standard in the second GBA port)        Reptile (unlockable, not available in the first GBA port)       Cyrax (unlockable, not available in the first GBA port, standard in the second GBA port)      Moloch (unplayable sub-boss, not available in any GBA port)     Blaze (secret character, not available in any GBA port)    Mokap (secret character, not available in any GBA port)   Sareena (only available in the second GBA port)  Sektor (unlockable, only available in the second GBA port) Noob Saibot (unlockable, only available in the second GBA port)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="22292">Dead or Alive 2: Hardcore</game><game id="7792">Dead or Alive 4</game><game id="16793">Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="721">Ehrgeiz: God Bless the Ring</game><game id="11065">Shaman King: Power of Spirit</game><game id="13753">Dead or Alive Ultimate</game><game id="22953">Ultimate Fighter</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="23833">Tekken 6: Bloodline Rebellion</game><game id="10476">War Gods</game><game id="16870">Tao Feng: Fist of the Lotus</game><game id="866">Kakuto Chojin: Back Alley Brutal</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1881077-box_mkda.png</image></root>