<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6645</id><name>Caesar III</name><description>SettingThe game takes place in Europe during Rome's rise to power. Players will build cities in North Africa, Asia Minor, present day Spain, Britain, France and Germany. Europe is under the control of barbarian tribes that will attempt to thwart the player's advances.GameplayThe player is assigned with completing specific objectives in each city they build. The player is given a choice of which city they wish to work on after completing the previous scenario. Some cities are more dangerous then others, with large barbarian tribes roaming around. Others have an economy focused on a particular material such as iron ore. Neutral tribes may also be present that the player can convert to Roman ways of thinking.ManagementThe player must balance housing, trade, taxes and food among other things while in control. Fires will occur if prefects are not built to prevent them and buildings will collapse if engineers don't inspect the buildings in your city. At any time the player may click on a citizen to be provided with info about the current sentiment in the city. If the people are happy, the population will increase, production will increase, and profits will as well. If people are unhappy, riots break out and robberies occur. If things become serious enough, people will emigrate from your city.ReligionCaesar III ImageIf the Gods are angered they will punish the player. Neptune will cause a storm at sea, destroying your trade network, Ceres will kill all your crops at the time, and perhaps worst of all, Venus will cause city mood to plummet, ending immigration and causing riots to break out. They may be kept happy by erecting large temples and holding festivals in their honor.WarA player may create an army of different units such as legionaries, javelin throwers and cavalry. Combat involves different formations and a rock, paper, scissor style damage system. A cheat may be entered to cause massive enemy armies to appear, if the player feels like having all his work destroyed. If your debt to the emperor is not payed off, a legion will be sent to capture you, however if the player can beat them the emperor will end all their debt.WorkforceA player must have enough population to support their economy, this is the most common objective in campaign scenarios. It is affected by city sentiment, the gods and war.Other InformationThe game includes a free play mode that lets the player take on the challenge of any if they wish, with customizable settings.A map creator was eventually released a few years after the release of the game, which lets the player affect all the dynamics seen in the scenario mode, along with crafting the environment in which the player builds his empire. Factors such as fishing and herd locations, the cost of goods throughout the years, include price fluctuations, natural disasters, invasion spots, and starting Denarii.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17680">Pharaoh</game><game id="6724">1602 A.D.</game><game id="13760">SimCity 2000</game><game id="10733">SimCity 3000</game><game id="11466">CivCity: Rome</game><game id="4736">SimCity 4</game><game id="21729">Cities XL</game><game id="3009">Immortal Cities: Children of the Nile</game><game id="3769">Zeus: Master of Olympus</game><game id="5211">Zeus Official Expansion: Poseidon</game><game id="6946">The Settlers: Fourth Edition</game><game id="28310">The Settlers 7: Paths to a Kingdom</game><game id="3144">Cleopatra: Queen of the Nile</game><game id="26943">Children of the Nile: Alexandria</game><game id="14638">Northland</game><game id="1489">8th Wonder of the World</game><game id="12474">Black &amp; White 2</game><game id="738">Black &amp; White 2: Battle of the Gods</game><game id="3642">The Settlers II: 10th Anniversary - Vikings</game><game id="16757">Tropico: Paradise Island</game><game id="32326">Tropico 4</game><game id="24458">Tropico 3</game><game id="7965">Tropico 2: Pirate Cove</game><game id="8460">Diggles: the Myth of Fenris</game><game id="10942">The Nations</game><game id="625">Alien Nations</game><game id="18721">Cultures</game><game id="19132">Cultures 2: The Gates of Asgard</game><game id="2859">Cultures: Die Saga</game><game id="5457">Cultures: Die Abenteuerbox</game><game id="12922">The Settlers</game><game id="10978">The Settlers III</game><game id="2081">The Settlers II</game><game id="16829">The Settlers II: Veni, Vidi, Vici</game><game id="22372">The Settlers IV: The Trojans and the Elixir of Power</game><game id="1128">The Settlers II: 10th Anniversary</game><game id="2815">The Settlers: Rise of an Empire</game><game id="3449">The Settlers II Mission CD</game><game id="9828">The Settlers: Rise of an Empire – The Eastern Realm</game><game id="22371">The Settlers IV: Mission CD</game><game id="15294">The Settlers III: Quest of the Amazons</game><game id="18623">Black &amp; White</game><game id="14823">Black &amp; White: Creature Isle</game><game id="17620">Dungeon Keeper</game><game id="4820">Dungeon Keeper 2</game><game id="32175">Dungeon Keeper 3</game><game id="19042">Dungeon Keeper: The Deeper Dungeons</game><game id="21454">Majesty 2: The Fantasy Kingdom Sim</game><game id="18490">Majesty: The Northern Expansion</game><game id="11751">Majesty: The Fantasy Kingdom Sim</game><game id="29811">Majesty 2: Kingmaker</game><game id="31820">Majesty 2: Pocket Kingdom</game><game id="36948">Majesty 2: Monster Kingdom</game><game id="36949">Majesty 2: Battles of Ardania</game><game id="6210">Populous</game><game id="10562">Populous II: Trials of the Olympian Gods</game><game id="12757">Tropico</game><game id="30573">Tropico 3: Absolute Power</game><game id="4102">Emperor: Rise of the Middle Kingdom</game><game id="15035">SimCity</game><game id="1628">SimCity Societies</game><game id="18443">SimCity 3000 Unlimited</game><game id="14865">SimCity 4: Rush Hour</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15693/1393024-caesar_3_a.jpg</image></root>