<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>67</id><name>Tiger Woods PGA Tour 07</name><description>New FeaturesGame FaceSelecting the Game Face menu will present the player with the Game Face tool (if the player has not created any golfers yet), which the player will use to create a golfer. If the player has already created a golfer, they will be presented with a list of their golfers. Choosing one will take the player to the My Team menu.My TeamMy Team is where players can modify their golfers' attributes. Contained within the menu are the options My Skills (view and modify golfer stats), My Appearance (takes the player to the Game Face tool), My Animations (choose the various animations the golfer uses, including swing, celebrations, etc.), Pro Shop (equip over 3000 bits of clothing and accessories, though many of them must be unlocked through gameplay before they are accessible), Team Name, Team Logo, and Team Uniform.RosterTiger Woods 07 has a Total of 53 playable golfers, 21 of which actually exist.Real golfersTiger WoodsStuart ApplebyRicky BarnesRich BeemJohn DalyChris DiMarcoLuke DonaldJim FurykRetief GoosenNatalie GulbisJustin LeonardColin MontgomerieIan PoulterJustin RoseAdam ScottVijay SinghAnnika SörenstamMichael CampbellJesper ParnevikSteve ElkingtonMike WeirCoursesThe K ClubRiviera Country ClubBay HillHarbour TownColonial Country ClubFirestone Country ClubPasatiempo Golf ClubPinehurst No. 2Pebble BeachTPC at SawgrassOld Course at St Andrews</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21379">ProStroke Golf : World Tour 2007</game><game id="2573">Tiger Woods PGA Tour 2001</game><game id="2302">PGA Tour Golf: Tournament Course Disk</game><game id="5493">Tiger Woods PGA Tour 2000</game><game id="697">PGA European Tour</game><game id="6799">PGA Tour Golf</game><game id="1336">Cyber Tiger</game><game id="1760">PGA Tour 96</game><game id="14247">PGA Tour Golf III</game><game id="1547">Hot Shots Golf: Open Tee</game><game id="21797">Golf</game><game id="6957">Outlaw Golf 2</game><game id="17375">Jack Nicklaus 6: Golden Bear Challenge</game><game id="10089">Jack Nicklaus 5</game><game id="19715">Jack Nicklaus 4</game><game id="2617">Jack Nicklaus' Unlimited Golf &amp; Course Design</game><game id="1598">Mario Golf: Toadstool Tour</game><game id="22203">Super Swing Golf</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2269431-box_twpgat07.png</image></root>