<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6709</id><name>Hitman: Codename 47</name><description>OverviewStanding over a victimIn Hitman: Codename 47, you play as the hitman called Agent 47. Using his superior fighting and sneaking skills, you must unravel what happened to him in the past, and who he is.The game was praised for it's richly detailed and vibrantly colored worlds, but criticized for frustrating control system and lack of mid-mission saves. People that could look past it's faults, found Hitman to be a challenging game with an intriguing main character.GameplayThe objective for each level is to kill one or more assigned targets. This can always be done with stealth and without raising an alarm. Often the game gives you more than one way to achieve the objectives. The use of disguises are often required to gain entry to sealed off areas.Plot SummaryThe bathroom in the famous "hide weapon in bathroom" scene. "I need to use the bathroom... bang!"The story behind Hitman: Codename 47 is probably the most important part of it when looking at the ongoing franchise. It sets up the basis of who 47 is and who created him among other things.The game starts with 47 waking up in a sterile looking area and being talked through an obstacle course by a man on a speaker system. This man is Dr. Otto Wolfgang Ort-Meyer, a doctor at a sanitarium in Romania (however the player does not realize this yet). He sets up a way for 47 to escape, making him think that he accomplished this feat on his own. A year later 47 is working for the International Contract Agency (The Agency), as a freelance assassin taking on lucrative and dangerous contracts. It is believed that Dr. Ort-Meyer had a hand in pulling some strings to get 47 into The Agency, as a test to see if 47 had what it really takes to be the super assassin he was designed to be.During this time working for The Agency, 47 has already established a reputation for being one of the best assassins in the organization. You go through several missions in the game, delivered to you by computer. Your contact in The Agency is called Diana Burnwood. There are always a few small missions setting up the big hit at the end of an "episode".First you must assassinate Lee Hong, the head of the Red Dragon Triad. All these missions take place in Hong Kong.Your next major target is Pablo Belisario Ochoa, a Colombian druglord.Next is an Austrian terrorist named Franz Fuchs followed by the gunrunner Arkadij Jegorov (aka Boris Ivanovich Duruska).Throughout these missions you can collect various letters which your main targets sent to each other. In fact, it appears they were all members of the French Foreign Legion at the same time. All of the letters contain something about an experimental human, and they all seem to know a 'Professor' Ort-Meyer.The fiberwire in actionAt the end of the final contract, Diana warns you that something is amiss. All the previous hits were ordered from the same client. and this client has ordered one more hit on a Doctor Odon Kovacs, who so happens to work at a sanitarium in Romania. When 47 checks in, you learn that the mysterious voice from the start of the game is actually 'Professor' Ort-Meyer, as he calls in S.W.A.T. who start a search of the building for an intruder.Once you kill your target, you must find a way deeper into the building. 47 finds help in Agent Smith (A recurring CIA agent in the Hitman franchise, which 47 comes into contact with in every game). Agent Smith tells you that there is a secret underground laboratory in the sanitarium. Here you find an advanced lab, and you finally learn the truth about yourself.It becomes clear that 47 is a genetically engineered clone, who was derived from the DNA of the 4 criminal masterminds he was contracted to kill. Only one of these 'fathers' remains and that is Dr. Ort-Meyer. It is implied that Ort-Meyer put out the contracts on these men because they wanted the technology and clones he had been working on for their own purposes, which he obviously did not want.When you reach this lab, Ort-Meyer releases the next series of clones, the 48 series. These clones are more easily controllable and supposedly more efficent then 47. However 47 is superior to these mindless drones, dispatching them with a high powered mini-gun. He then gains access to the main lab in the back through a barcode scanner using one of the fallen 48's, where Dr. Ort-Meyer confronts him. He mistakes 47 for a 48 in the beginning, and so you have some time to decide what to do. Kill him, or let him be.If you let him be, he embraces you and stuns you. This leads to the game starting over again.If you shoot him however, he will stumble back knocking over trays with a bullet wound to his stomach.47 then walks up to him and kneels down behind him, with Ort-Meyers back leaning on his chest. Ort-Meyer says "I didn't even recognize my own son." To which 47 responds by snapping his neck.Many of the missions in Hitman: Codename 47 are reinvented in Hitman: Contracts. This may have been done because of better technology at the time, and the fact that many people may have never played the first Hitman. Also Contracts story is told via flashbacks to previous hits 47 has fulfilled. Also the scene where 47 snaps Dr. Otto Wolfgang Ort-Meyer's neck is reflected upon in Hitman: Blood Money, in a cutscene where “ Jack” Alexander Leland Cayne is explaining how 47 killed Dr. Ort-Meyer.Missions (in chronological order)Hong Kong1. Kowloon Triads in Gang WarObjectives:Eliminate Red Dragon NegotiatorEscape to Rendezvous PointMoney:$13,0002. Ambush at the Wang Fou RestaurantObjectives:Eliminate Blue Lotus EmissaryEliminate All Blue Lotus Triad MembersReturn to Rendezvous PointMoney:$12,0003. The Massacre at the Cheung Chau Fish RestaurantObjectives:Eliminate Red Dragon NegotiatorHide the Body of the Red Dragon NegotiatorEliminate the Chief of PolicePlace a Red Dragon Amulet Inside the RestaurantEscape to the Rendezvous PointMoney:$15,0004. The Lee Hong AssassinationObjective:Find Safe CombinationFind Safe LocationDeliver Jade Figure to the Herbal ShopEliminate Lee HongCaptured Agent Must SurviveEscape to Rendezvous PointMoney:$15,000Columbia5. Find the U'Wa TribeObjectives:Secure Religious IdolBring Idol to Indian VillageMoney:$5,0006. The Jungle GodObjectives:Find the Secret Passage to Pablo's CampMoney:$5,0007. Say Hello to My Little FriendObjectives:Eliminate the Drug LordBlow Up the LaboratoryUse the Airplane to EscapeMoney:$30,000Budapest8. Traditions of the TradeObjectives:Eliminate FranzFuchs Secure Terrorist BombEscape to Rendezvous PointMoney:$55,000Rotterdam9. Gunrunner's ParadiseObjectives:Place GPS Tracker in the Gang CarMoves GPS Tracker to the SuitcaseGive the Suitcase to IvanMoney:$50,00010. Plutonium Runs LooseObjectives:Eliminate BorisNuke Must be DisarmedTake Ship to International WatersMoney:$75,000Asylum11. The SetupObjectives:Eliminate Doctor KovacsMoney:$100,00012. Meet Your BrotherObjectives:None (Kill Everyone)Money:NoneWeaponsSilverballersAMT Hardballer, fondly called Silverballer by 47The so-called AMT "Silverballers" ( Hardballers) are his signature guns. In this game you can only use one at a time. You can pick up two for some dual-wielding action, if you fiddle around a bit. To do this you must drop one gun, wield the other then pick up the first gun.Beretta 92 This is a common pistol used by many characters in the game.Desert EagleThe DeagleThe desert eagle, "Deagle", is a common pistol in games. The Deagle is known for being very powerful.Luger P0B SDLugerA common German pistol used in the late 19th century and the 20th century.MP5MP5A standard sub-machine gun, or SMG. This is a powerful weapon to have, but does not benefit players who wish to use stealth.UziUziA fast firing SMG.Assault RiflesSniper RiflesM16A2AK-47OtherAK-103Walther WA 2000Blaster 93PC RequirementsGE M134 MinigunM60E3Franchi PA3, 12 GaugeWindows 95/98/Me/XP (Home Edition);Pentium II 266 (Min.), Pentium III (Rec.);8x CD-ROM drive;64 MB RAM (Min.), 96 MB (Rec.);12 MB DirectX 7 compatible 3D graphics card (Min.);DirectX 7 compatible sound card;400 MB hard drive space (Min.).</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2335">Thief: Deadly Shadows</game><game id="4523">Thief: The Dark Project</game><game id="19998">Tenchu: Dark Secret</game><game id="7787">Thief II: The Metal Age</game><game id="20669">Metal Gear Solid 4: Guns of the Patriots</game><game id="15549">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Pandora Tomorrow</game><game id="15282">Tenchu: Fatal Shadows</game><game id="12354">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Chaos Theory</game><game id="19316">Headhunter</game><game id="21654">Metal Gear Solid 2: Substance</game><game id="22928">Assassin's Creed II</game><game id="27248">Frame City Killer</game><game id="7539">Tenchu: Wrath of Heaven</game><game id="16004">Tenchu: Stealth Assassins</game><game id="24617">Tenchu: Shadow Assassins</game><game id="15737">Tenchu 2: Birth of the Stealth Assassins</game><game id="2077">The Mark of Kri</game><game id="33251">Stacking</game><game id="20464">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Conviction</game><game id="35850">Dishonored</game><game id="30093">Monaco: What's Yours Is Mine</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/15/155745/2250638-12313287056.jpg</image></root>