<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6728</id><name>Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders</name><description>PlotZak McKracken is a tabloid reporter who discovers a plot by aliens to decrease the intelligence of the people of Earth. He embarks on a globe-trotting adventure to stop the aliens plans, teaming up with scientist Annie Larris and the first human astronauts to land on the surface of Mars, Melissa China  Leslie Bennett.Zak discovers a number of special crystals in his adventure that give him powers including teleportation  the ability to jump into the body of animals.Playable CharactersThe player is able to control 4 characters:Zak McKrackenAnnie LarrisMelissa ChinaLeslie BennettUnlike the First SCUMM game Maniac Mansion you are not able to control  switch between all characters from the start of the game. Only as the plot progresses and the characters are introduced are you able to control them.TriviaUnlike most other LucasArts games (with the exception of Maniac Mansion) you were able to die in Zak McKracken.The original box came with a fake newspaper with several humorous articles in it.There is a can of chainsaw fuel on Mars, if you try to pick it up characters will say it's for a different game, in Maniac Mansion there was a chainsaw in the kitchen that was out of fuel, but there was no fuel for it in that game.CameoLou's Pawn Shop (AST)In Maniac Mansion, another game by Lucasarts, a poster with Zak McKracken on it can be found in the arcade hall. And vice versa, in Lou's pawn shop a Maniac Mansion advertisement poster can be found on the wall.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2037">Maniac Mansion</game><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game><game id="12260">Simon the Sorcerer</game><game id="3633">Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis</game><game id="10927">Loom</game><game id="8664">5 Days a Stranger</game><game id="7947">Lure of the Temptress</game><game id="9527">Flight of the Amazon Queen</game><game id="600">Future Wars</game><game id="8430">Pajama Sam: No Need to Hide When It’s Dark Outside</game><game id="23532">Nikopol: Secrets of the Immortals</game><game id="4372">Maniac Mansion: Day of the Tentacle</game><game id="11852">Sam &amp; Max Hit the Road</game><game id="13230">Grim Fandango</game><game id="5729">The Curse of Monkey Island</game><game id="9058">Escape from Monkey Island</game><game id="21174">Full Throttle</game><game id="14748">Indiana Jones and The Last Crusade: The Graphic Adventure</game><game id="10915">Beneath a Steel Sky</game><game id="161">Simon the Sorcerer II: The Lion, the Wizard and the Wardrobe</game><game id="3970">Myst</game><game id="16230">Riven: The Sequel to Myst</game><game id="18742">Myst III: Exile</game><game id="7863">Myst IV: Revelation</game><game id="1961">Myst V: End of Ages</game><game id="16965">Syberia</game><game id="1975">Syberia II</game><game id="22111">The Whispered World</game><game id="23778">Strong Bad's Cool Game for Attractive People Episode 3: Baddest of the Bands</game><game id="21667">Gray Matter</game><game id="24962">Full Throttle: Payback</game><game id="18976">Alien Incident</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2277758-zak.jpg</image></root>