<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>68</id><name>Crash Bandicoot: The Wrath of Cortex</name><description> OverviewCrash Bandicoot: The Wrath of Cortex is the sixth game in the Crash Bandicoot series, however it is the first game to not be developed by Naughty Dog.  Instead the game was developed by Traveller's Tales and published by Universal Interactive Studios.  The game is available for Playstation 2, Xbox, and Gamecube and it was released in the United States on October 29, 2001 for Playstation 2, April 15, 2002 for Xbox, and September 17, 2002 for Gamecube.  It was released on the American Xbox Live Marketplace on December 4th, 2007. StoryThe story begins when we see Dr. Neo Cortex's space station and Uka Uka awakes the Destructive masks who each have a power over Earth, Fire, Water, and Air.  If they unleash their power then Cortex will be able to power his secret weapon which could be capable of crushing mountains, demolishing entire cities, and even destroy Crash.  Crash with the help of his sister Coco Bandicoot and Aku Aku need to find a way to stop Cortex and the destructive masks before Cortex's weapon is powered.   The Wrath of Cortex is the first game to feature Crunch Bandicoot, one of Cortex's creations who turns good by the end of the game.Xbox Originals  On December 4, 2007, Crash Bandicoot: The Wrath of Cortex became available on the Xbox 360's Xbox Originals download service for  1200 Microsoft Points.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2931">Super Mario 64</game><game id="19026">Star Fox Adventures</game><game id="9669">Jak 3</game><game id="8420">Spyro: Enter the Dragonfly</game><game id="6649">Super Mario Sunshine</game><game id="4228">Haven: Call of the King</game><game id="1563">Spyro 2: Ripto's Rage</game><game id="6134">The Legend of Spyro: The Eternal Night</game><game id="20330">Gex 3: Deep Cover Gecko</game><game id="15991">Chameleon Twist 2</game><game id="18376">Looney Tunes Back in Action</game><game id="2906">Psychonauts</game><game id="11188">Kao the Kangaroo Round 2</game><game id="14623">Jak and Daxter: The Precursor Legacy</game><game id="15114">Scooby-Doo!: Night of 100 Frights</game><game id="609">Rayman 2: The Great Escape</game><game id="15353">Sly Cooper and the Thievius Raccoonus</game><game id="7212">Klonoa 2: Lunatea's Veil</game><game id="20178">Pac-Man World 2</game><game id="13169">Ty the Tasmanian Tiger</game><game id="10297">Jimmy Neutron: Boy Genius</game><game id="3075">Frogger: The Great Quest</game><game id="673">Portal Runner</game><game id="20963">Wario Land: Shake It!</game><game id="11470">Scaler</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1881043-box_cbtwoc.png</image></root>