<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>680</id><name>Chaos Island</name><description>OverviewChaos Island is a real-time strategy game based in the Jurassic Park universe that uses a top-down perspective. It loosely follows the storyline of The Lost World, the second instalment of the movie franchise.GameplayThe game plays much like strategy games from the Command  Conquer franchise. The player has a base with supporting buildings. Every building allows different functions, such as being able to heal units or protect units. Eggs can be collected from nests to make more dinosaurs available to the players. Buildings require “supplies” to create, as does making dinosaurs and characters for the player to control. Each main character has separate stats which can be upgraded throughout the game. The player may also build walls for protection and containment of their base. Each mission has one or more objective for the player to complete to progress to the next mission.CharactersThere are human characters as well as dinosaurs in the game. The player has access to five characters from the movie as well as “research assistants.” You can have as many research assistants as you want and are able to build, but you can only have one of each main character. Eight species of dinosaurs exist in the game. There are wild dinosaurs as well as those built by the player and by the enemy hunters. Hunters exist as NPCs on foot, jeeps, and as tanks. There is also an alien character that can be created by using a cheat code.Characters from movieEddie CarrIan MalcolmKelly CurtisNick Van OwenSarah HardingDinosaursCompsognathusDilophosaurusPachycephalosaurusParasaurolophusStegosaurusTriceratopsTyrannosaurusVelociraptor</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="249">Command &amp; Conquer: Red Alert</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2289855-c.png</image></root>