<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6828</id><name>Cool Boarders 3</name><description> OverviewCool Boarders 3 is quite different from the first two  games in the series.  Rather than having a focus on wide open racing  down a mountain, players ride down very narrow courses.  Racing can get  very crowded, so a punching mechanic was added to slow down / knock down  other snowboarders.  As with previous games in the franchise, the focus  is on performing tricks in various game modes such as boardercross,  slalom, and slope style.  Characters Cool Boarders 3  has an extensive list of characters. They each have their own skill set  and have significantly varied appearances. The characters that are  available from the start of the game are:  Cliff  Summer FlintSashaNickGrantVioletJokerBlakeTravisAkikoTadashiGordon     There are many different secret characters as well. They include: Fast EddieMarsKimberIrvingBobJoshuaCoolBurg Snowboards There are three categories of snowboards in  the game: Freestyle, Free ride, and Alpine.  Freestyle boards are used  predominantly for tricks meaning they can spin fast, but are generally  very slow.  Free ride are the all around boards.  Alpine boards are for  pure speed and nothing else.  They have terrible handling and are a very  poor choice for tricks.  Freestyle BoardsSpecialChopperPunchCanyonConceptSecret  Freestyle Boards BalanceCustomWaaraBrushieFLFreeride  BoardsChargerMotionSwatchSupermodelMountain Secret  Freeride BoardsElementTimelessFreedomMahaffeyJohan Alpine  BoardsWire Secret  Alpine BoardsFactory PrimeUltra  Prime Courses There are  five courses (mountains) that have different areas for each event.  The  mountains are Powder Hill, Devil's Butt, Mt. Koji, Alps, and Everest.   Once you get to the end of the game, another mountain is unlocked  called Avalanche.  On Avalanche, you are dropped out of a helicopter and  must outrun an avalanche!  TricksSpinsFrontside SpinBackside Spin FlipsFront flipBack FlipMistyRodeo  GrabsTailgrabStiffyStalefishSad  AirIndyMethodJapan AirMelancholyFS  ShiftyBS Shifty90 degree Noseslide180 degree  Noseslide</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="33">Snowboarding/Skiing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16640">Rippin' Riders</game><game id="31945">Phat Air: Extreme Snowboarding</game><game id="30947">Tony Hawk: SHRED</game><game id="5510">X-Games: Pro Boarder</game><game id="12112">Cool Boarders</game><game id="42370">R: Rock'n Riders</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/14912/810032-196981_50231_front.jpg</image></root>