<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>6922</id><name>Wing Commander IV: The Price of Freedom</name><description>OverviewWing Commander IV: The Price of Freedom is the third sequel to the original Wing Commander.  It was produced by Origin Systems and released in late 1995. Like the previous game in the series, it featured Full Motion Video starring Malcolm McDowell, John Rhys-Davies and Mark Hamill all reprising their roles as Tolwyn, Paladin and Blair respectively. These FMVs were filmed using real sets (on a budget of $12 million dollars) instead of the bluescreen techniques used in the previous game. For a while, it was considered to be the most expensive video game ever made. StoryBlair encounters "Seether"   The War with the       Kilrathi Empire is finally over. Peace has at long last come to the Terran Confederation. Things are not all well though. Tensions are higher than ever between the Border Worlds and the Inner Worlds of the Confederation. An open attack on a Medical transport by unknown fighters occurs with a bizarre new anti-ship weapon being used to destroy everything in the general vicinity.  The "savior" of the Confederation,       Christopher Blair, is trying to live out his life as a farmer on a desert world. An "old friend" from the Kilrathi war,       Todd "Maniac" Marshall, soon comes with good news for him: He's been recalled to active military duty by order of Admiral Geoffrey Tolwyn himself. Maniac is unfortunately unable to share many details about the recall order. However, Blair soon realizes what he's in for when the space station the two head towards comes under attack. The attacking fighter in question claims allegiance to the "Union of Border Worlds" and takes off.Characters  Confederation PilotsMost of the characters from the third game make a return.  Colonel       Christopher "Maverick" Blair : the main character and hero of the Kilrathi War. Played by Mark Hamill.  Major       Todd "Maniac" Marshall: A cocky and unpredictable veteran of the Kilrathi War who has flown with Blair since his days on the Tiger's Claw. Played by Tom Wilson of Back to the Future fame.  Lieutenant       Winston "Vagabond" Chang: Another veteran of the Kilrathi War who is rarely seen without a deck of cards in his hands. Played by Francois Chau.  Lieutenant      Troy "Catscratch" Carter: A young pilot who shows hero worship towards Blair. Played by Mark Dacascos.   "Seether": The best of the Genetic Enhancement Program, now known as Black Lance. His real name is never revealed and he serves as an adversary of Blair's. Played by Robert Rusler.    Confederation Personnel      Admiral Geoffrey Tolwyn: A charismatic Admiral who feels that the human race must always be at war. Played by Malcolm McDowell.Malcolm McDowell returns to his role of Admiral Tolwyn. Captain William Eisen: The former commander of Blair, Maniac and Vagabond during the Kilrathi War. He is the captain of the Lexington. Played by the late Jason Bernard. Brigadier General       James "Paladin" Taggert: A former comrade and wingmate of Blair's who now serves as a Senator on the Confederation Assembly. Played by John Rhys-Davies. Captain Hugh Paulson: Part of the conspiracy against the Confederation, he was briefly the Captain of the Lexington before he was killed by Seether. Played by John Spencer.   Border Worlds PilotsColonel    Jacob "Hawk" Manley: A fellow TCS Tiger's Claw veteran who serves as the voice of decisive, aggressive action. Played by Chris Mulkey. Colonel   Tamara "Panther" Farnsworth: A veteran of the Kilrathi War who is more of a pacifist than Hawk. Played by Elizabeth Barondes.   Border Worlds PersonnelPilers can improve and upgrade your fighter in various waysChief Technician Robert "Pilers" Skyes: An old man who loves his work and does his best to improve the various fighter craft. Played by Richard Riehle. Lieutenant Velina Sosa: A pleasant woman who serves aboard the Intrepid and is seemingly untouched by the ongoing War. Played by Holly Gagnier. Vice Admiral Eugene Wilford: A Kilrathi War veteran who has lived in the Border Worlds for all of his life. Played by Peter Jason. Lieutenant Colonel John "Gash" Dekker: A man who managed the rare feat of escaping a Kilrathi POW camp. Played by Jeremy Roberts. </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10309">Descent: Freespace - The Great War</game><game id="12541">Freespace 2</game><game id="22334">Light Speed</game><game id="5584">StarLancer</game><game id="5565">Freelancer</game><game id="19727">Star Wars: TIE Fighter</game><game id="22979">Dark Horizon</game><game id="8415">Independence War: The Starship Simulator</game><game id="9503">Project Sylpheed: Arc of Deception</game><game id="19585">Descent: Freespace: Silent Threat</game><game id="433">Star Wars: X-Wing Alliance</game><game id="12111">Independence War 2: Edge Of Chaos</game><game id="38000">Babylon 5: Into the Fire</game><game id="16951">Inferno: The Odyssey Continues</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/118/608612-wing_commander_iv___the_price_of_freedom_coverart.png</image></root>