<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7004</id><name>Hitman 2: Silent Assassin</name><description>OverviewHitman 2: Silent Assassin is the second game in the Hitman franchise, in which players take the role of Agent 47 - a genetically engineered killing machine gone rogue. This game kicks off a while after the final showdown in Hitman: Codename 47, and Agent 47 has quit the assassin trade to work as a gardener in a Sicilian church. However, it doesn't take long until troublemakers stir things up and kidnap Agent 47's priest and mentor, Father Vittorio, which forces Agent 47 to return to his past.GameplayGameplay-wise, there are many refinements in this sequel to the original game. The first obvious change is the control scheme, which has been fine-tuned for the third-person shooter perspective. IO Interactivealso added an optional first-person perspective and a visual meter in order to give the player a basic outlook on the enemies' suspicion level, a feature that was further enhanced in later releases of the Hitman franchise.Another major addition in Hitman 2: Silent Assassin is the new rating system. In the first game, there weren't any real incentives to get players to take a stealthy approach during the missions, which basically went against the design philosophy. In Silent Assassin, players are rated after each mission according to how they've performed - the lesser kills and detections, the higher the rating. The challenge comes in approaching the main target without having any hoodlums seeing Agent 47 come in or out. Players who mastered this were given the honorable title "Silent Assassin", which locked up hidden weapons and tools. Players who just go on a mad gun-crazed frenzy are often branded as "Mass Murderer".LevelsSicilyAgent 47's mentor and friend, Father Vittorio, has been kidnapped by the Sicilian Mafia, and they demand 500,000 in ransom. Unfortunately, Agent 47 is all out of cash, so he'll have to take some other approach to free the Father.St. PetersburgIn return for information as to Father Vittorio's whereabouts, 47 must complete a small assignment for his former employers. This small assignment quickly evolves into four assassinations and a rather hairy run-in with a Spetznaz agent.JapanAgent 47 goes to Japan to eliminate an arms dealer and to recover a missile guidance system from his castle.MalaysiaThis time, the Agency calls in 47 to eliminate a powerful hacker who has his hands on an important piece of missile defense software.NuristanAgent 47 goes to the Middle East to retrieve some important piece of cargo for his Agency.IndiaA mysterious Indian cult has gotten their hands on some nukes.  WeaponsMeleeAnaestheticFiber WireKitchen KnifeCombat KnifeScalpelGolf ClubKatana SwordFire AxePistolsSilverballer .45Silverballer .45 Suppressed9mm Pistol9mm Pistol SuppressedDeagleStub-Nosed Revolver.54 Pistol.22 SuppressedSub-Machine GunsUziSMGSMG-SD6Assault RiflesAK-74M4ShotgunsDouble-Barreled ShotgunSawn-Off ShotgunSP12 ShotgunSniper RiflesCrossbowR93 SniperDragunov SVD SniperMI95 SniperW2000 SniperW2000 Custom Sniper RifleHeavy WeaponsM60 LMGHD Re-releaseHitman 2: Silent Assassin was re-released with high definition graphics as part of the Hitman: HD Trilogy on January 29, 2013. It was also made available as a standalone 1.1 GB download on the PlayStation Network for $16.99.System RequirementsMinimum: Microsoft Windows 98/ME/XP, Pentium 3 450 MHz or equivalent, 100% DirectX 8.1 compatible video card with at least 16 megabytes of video memory, 128 MB system RAM, 100% DirectX 8.1 compatible sound card, 800 MB uncompressed free hard drive space, 100% Windows 98/ME/XP compatible mouse and keyboardRecommended: Pentium 3 1GHz equivalent or greater, 256 MB system RAM, 100% DirectX 8.1 compatible 3D Accelerator video card with 32 MB video RAM, 100% DirectX 8.1 compatible EAX Advanced HD Sound Card</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5961">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell</game><game id="2335">Thief: Deadly Shadows</game><game id="21331">Tenchu Z</game><game id="15549">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Pandora Tomorrow</game><game id="12354">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Chaos Theory</game><game id="12388">Metal Gear Solid 2: Sons of Liberty</game><game id="21002">Tenchu: Time of the Assassins</game><game id="7539">Tenchu: Wrath of Heaven</game><game id="15282">Tenchu: Fatal Shadows</game><game id="15737">Tenchu 2: Birth of the Stealth Assassins</game><game id="4523">Thief: The Dark Project</game><game id="19998">Tenchu: Dark Secret</game><game id="7787">Thief II: The Metal Age</game><game id="20669">Metal Gear Solid 4: Guns of the Patriots</game><game id="19316">Headhunter</game><game id="23695">Shadow Harvest: Phantom Ops</game><game id="18411">Dead to Rights II</game><game id="21654">Metal Gear Solid 2: Substance</game><game id="22928">Assassin's Creed II</game><game id="27248">Frame City Killer</game><game id="16004">Tenchu: Stealth Assassins</game><game id="24617">Tenchu: Shadow Assassins</game><game id="2077">The Mark of Kri</game><game id="16093">Death to Spies</game><game id="20464">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Conviction</game><game id="5704">Shadow of Rome</game><game id="37494">Assassin's Creed III</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1891347-box_hitman2.png</image></root>