<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7052</id><name>Turok 2: Seeds of Evil</name><description>A sequel to the original Turok: Dinosaur Hunter on the Nintendo 64. It was also the first Nintendo 64 game to feature support for the Expansion Pak, which doubled the total amount of RAM in the Nintendo 64 from 4 MB to 8 MB. This allowed for a greater screen resolution, higher frame rate, and more detailed graphics.The story revolves around Joshua Fireseed, the modern Turok (taking the title from Tal'Set of the previous game) who is teleported into an alternate dimension by a character named Adon. She explains that the elders of the Lazarus Concordance need Turok's help in order to defeat the Primagen, an alien who seeks to free himself from his spacecraft, where he has been sealed for thousands of years, in order to enslave all life.The Primagen is using other creatures to attempt to destroy the energy totems of the Lost Land that maintain the seal over his spaceship. Turok's task is to protect each of the five totems and then defeat the Primagen himself.LevelsLevel 1: Port of Adia - A once bustling coastal city that has been devastated by the invading Dinosoids.Level 2: River of Souls - The water that flows through this river is imbued with the power of death itself, making travelling along it incredibly dangerous.Level 3: The Death Marshes - An ancient swamp that is home to more than one sentient race that wishes to see Turok dead.Level 4: The Lair of the Blind Ones - A pitch-black series of tunnels where eyeless creatures who have evolved perfect adaptation to the dark have an advantage over Turok.Level 5: Hive of the Mantids - The enormous labyrinthine home of a race of sentient insectoids who don't like mammals very much.Level 6: Primagen's Lightship - The starship the Primagen used to escape his home dimension eons ago, which crashed into the Lost Lands and was sealed under a magical barrier by the Lazarus Concordance, in order to prevent the Primagen from escaping and enslaving all life.WeaponsTalons -- Used as claws that attach to Turok's handsetsDamage: LowRange: LowWarblade -- An upgrade of the Talons. These claws have a higher damage output for an close range encounter, and also function underwater.Damage: MediumRange: LowBow and Arrow -- Standard bow and arrow used by Turok. The longer the player holds the trigger the further the arrow will travel and the more damage it will do.Damage: LowRange: LongTek Bow -- Upgraded version of the bow and arrow. "Charges" faster, has a higher damage output, has a sniper scope for more accurate arrow placement, and can fire Tek Arrows that explode on impact.Damage: MediumRange: LongPistol -- Standard 9mm pistol useful for standard enemies in earlier levels and weak enemies in later levels.Damage: LowRange: LongFlare -- Used to light up dark corridors. Causes no damage to anything. Unlimited charges, but must recharge between each shot. A very impressive feat of locational lighting for its time.Damage: NARange: LongMag .60 -- An upgraded version of the pistol. This will fire three rounds for each time the player fires and has a better damage output per bullet.Damage: MediumRange: LongHarpoon Gun -- Only usable underwater, the harpoon gun spears your enemies with merciless steel.Damage: LowRange: LongTorpedo Launcher -- Only usable underwater, this fires powerful exploding torpedoes at enemies with a much higher damage output than the harpoon gun. In addition, even if you have no torpedoes, the launcher itself has a portable impeller on it that allows Turok to swim much faster while it is selected.Damage: HighRange: LongTranquilizer Gun -- Using this on an enemy will put them to sleep for a short time and works on almost any enemy. However, if the enemy wakes up it will harbour a serious grudge.Damage: NARange: LongCharge Dart Rifle -- An upgraded version of the tranquilizer gun. Shocks an enemy which paralyzes them for a short time.Damage: NARange: MediumPlasma Rifle -- Fires plasma shells rapidly. Equipped with a sniper scope to attack enemies at long range.Damage: HighRange: LongCerebral Bore -- One of the most famous weapons in all of gaming, this delightful little gadget will lock on to the brain activity of an enemy and fire a small orb which attaches to an enemy's head, drills into their skull, and sucks out their brain in the form of a gooey liquid, before exploding violently and decapitating them for good measure. The major drawbacks are that it cannot fire until it achieves a lock on an enemy's brain patterns, which is difficult with fast-moving enemies, and can only happen at relatively close range. In addition, the Bore is useless against enemies wearing protective headgear, or non-sentient enemies whose brain activity is not powerful enough to achieve a lock.Damage: One shot, one killRange: LongShotgun -- A single-barred pump action shotgun. Oh yes. Devastating at close range.Damage: HighRange: LowShredder -- An upgraded version of the shotgun. Not only will this double the damage output but also the shells will have the ability to ricochet off of walls.Damage: Very HighRange: MediumRazor Wind -- A ridiculously sharp buzzsaw-shaped glaive that flies through the air, severing arms, legs, and heads as it goes, and then returns to Turok's hand, slick with gore.Damage: HighRange: LongGrenade Launcher -- Propels grenades at your enemies and will explode on impact.Damage: HighRange: LowFirestorm Cannon -- Essentially this weapon is a high powered minigun that fires exploding energy bullets. Exactly as satisfying as it sounds. Takes a second to warm up as you begin firing.Damage: HighRange: MediumFlamethrower -- This will set enemies on fire for a high damage output.Damage: HighRange: LowSunfire Pods -- Odd natural growths found only in the Lost Lands, Sunfire Pods release a quick burst of incredibly bright light when broken. Turok throws them like grenades in order to temporarily blind his enemies. The Blind Ones in particular, who evolved in eternal blackness, are so sensitive to light that the light burst will cause their heads to burst into flames, killing them instantly.Damage: None or Lethal, depending on targetRange: MediumProximity Fragramation Mine (PFM) Layer -- This device will lay proximity mines along the ground. When an enemies get close enough, the mines will jump into the air to knee-height and explode, severing unlucky enemies' legs and leaving them to quickly bleed to death in horrific agony.Damage: HighRange: LowScorpion Missile Launcher -- Will lock on to a single enemy and then fire a barrage of missiles. Almost nothing can survive even one barrage.Damage: Very HighRange: LongThe Nuke -- Judged by the Lazarus Concordence to be too powerful to allow anyone to use, this portable Weapon of Mass Destruction was broken into pieces, which were then scattered across the Lost Land, and Turok must find each and every piece in order to use it. The Nuke takes a very long time to charge up before firing, and ammo is very rare, but when it finally goes off, watch out. It fires a bullet into whatever it's pointed at that triggers an enormous energy burst which instantly incinerates every single enemy in the area, leaving behind crispy statues of ash in the shape of the enemies, yet is handily harmless to Turok.Damage: Utterly LethalRange: InfiniteItemsYellow Health -- Raises your health by 100 points (Ultra Health)Red Health -- Raises your health to 100 pointsBlue Health -- Raises your health 10 pointsSilver Health -- Raises your health 10 pointsSatchel Charge -- Used to destroy objectivesLevel Key -- Found in every level, used to open up new levelsRed Life Force -- Gives you 10 life force points (100 points will earn an extra life)Yellow Life Force -- Gives you 1 life force point (100 points will earn an extra life)Eagle Feather -- Take them to Talisman Chambers to receive a special abilityPrimagen Key -- You have to open up the door in the center of the HUB.Cave Door Key -- Used to unlock caves in the Lair of the Blind OnesEnemiesDinosoidsRaptoid -- A lizard-humanoid hybrid equipped with basic weapons.Endtrail -- A lizard-humanoid hybrid equipped with advanced weapons.Fireborn -- A lizard-humanoid hybrid that has various flame-type attacks.DinosaursCompy -- The tiny Compsognathus aren't much of a threat individually, but they always travel in groups.Raptor -- Classic dinosaur enemy, very fast and lethal if not taken down quickly. Smart enough to allow for Cerebral Bore lock.Dimorphodon -- Murderous creatures that can fly and attack quickly.The Blind OnesSentinel -- Standard minion equipped with an axe and grenades.Guardian -- Guardians are equpped with a crossbow to take Turok down at range.Pur-Linn WarriorsWar Club -- Standard Pur-Linn that uses mostly physical attacks.Gunner -- A smaller Pur-Linn equipped with a Gatling gunJuggernaut -- The largest of the species equipped with a giant sword.The DeadkinDeadman -- A zombie-like creature that can either attack in melee combat or throw one of it's ribs at you. If blown in half, it will crawl towards Turok in an attempt to deal more damage.Lord of the Dead -- Larger than the standard deadman, these guys have fireballs as well as melee combat.Sister of Despair -- These creatures are essentially floating torsos that cast energy skulls at Turok.The MantidsMite -- Smaller creatures that crave the delicious taste of Human feet.Worker -- Standard Mantid that attacks with their claws.Drone -- Equipped with a jetpack and a laser rifle, a drone can fly as it chooses and do a great deal of damage.Soldier -- Large cockroach-looking creature. They are equipped with laser rifles and plasma balls.The Primagen's Personal MinionsTrooper -- Well-armoured mutants equipped with a laser rifle and mini-gun.Bio-Bot -- These creatures are cyborgs equipped with a laser rifle.Elite Guard -- The most power minion, these are much larger troopers equipped with a mini-gun.The Flesh EatersSentinel -- Standard mutant-looking creature equipped with a sword and grenades.Death Guard -- Standard mutant-looking creature equipped with a sword and a rifle.Lord of the Flesh -- The toughest of the Flesh Eaters, cast spell like attacks.Unaffiliated EnemiesLeaper -- A dog-like creature that can approach quickly for heavy damage.Cave Worm -- A large greyish worm that comes up from the ground.Fire Worm -- Slightly smaller than the cave worm, they can appear from the ground and attack with fireballs.Skimmer -- These are essentially smaller green snakes, always travel in groups.Cave Spider (Infant) -- Smaller spiders, usually don't appear alone.Cave Spider (Adult) -- Much bigger and more damaging that an infant, these spiders are fast and can spit venom at Turok.Swamp Wasp -- A smaller wasp that can sting Turok for a low amount of damage.</description><genres><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="6563">Armorines: Project S.W.A.R.M.</game><game id="18569">BlackSite: Area 51</game><game id="28916">Jurassic: The Hunted</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1796151-box_turok2.png</image></root>