<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7099</id><name>Mat Hoffman's Pro BMX 2</name><description>GameplayThe game itself play's like a traditional extreme sport game.Players can select one of the bikers who are featured in the game, and go through levels while performing tricks.Several modes are available. The main single modes are the Session mode, Free ride and the Road Trip mode.The Road Trip mode is the so-called Career mode for this game. You select a character and you will thenprogress through the levels, while you have to complete objects on the levels to be able to move on.The game also features several multiplayer modes as well as an park editor, where the player can design their ownareas which they can ride on.RidersPro ridersRuben Alcantara Mike Escamilla Seth Kimbrough Mat Hoffman Cory Nastazio Simon Tabron Kevin Robinson Nate Wessel Rick Thorne Joe "Butcher" Kowalski  Bonus ridersBig Foot Day Smith Vanessa Mime Volcano  SoundtrackFugazi - Guilford Fall Bad Ronald - All a Dream Suicidal Tendencies - Institutionalized Eric B  Rakim - Juice (Know The Ledge) LL Cool J - Rock the Bells Bad Brains - I against I Spoon - Take a Walk Secret Hate - Kevsadic Dislocated Styles - Unified MC Cool Rock - Boot the Booty Dub Pistols - Official Chemical N.E.R.D. - Rock Star Iggy Pop - The Passenger Crazy Town - Toxic Bomfunk MC's - Freestyler Digital Assassins - Return of The Living Bassheads Swollen Members - Fuel Injected Jazzhole - Forward Motion Gang of Four - Damaged Goods Ice-T - Reckless </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="3">Sports</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3238">Dave Mirra Freestyle BMX 3</game><game id="5474">BMX XXX</game><game id="21793">Downhill Domination</game><game id="5688">Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3</game><game id="7222">Tony Hawk's American Wasteland</game><game id="10174">Dave Mirra Freestyle BMX 2</game><game id="27632">MTV Sports: T.J. Lavin's Ultimate BMX</game><game id="14896">Tony  Hawk's Underground</game><game id="22469">Dave Mirra BMX Challenge</game><game id="37026">Tony Hawk's Pro Skater HD</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2133353-box_mhpbmx2.png</image></root>