<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7131</id><name>Marc Ecko's Getting Up: Contents Under Pressure</name><description>OverviewMarc Ecko's Getting Up: Contents Under Pressure follows the story of Coltrane "Trane" Crowley, a young aspiring graffiti artist living in New Radius, a city where graffiti is considered a serious felony. In the beginning of the game Trane is trying to make a name for himself or 'get up', hence the title. Early on in the game you encounter and are beaten up by a rival graffiti group called the Vandals of New Radius. From now on your main task is to learn newTrane creating some graffitiskills by learning from top graffiti artists and have your revenge by ridiculing the VaNR. As time goes on, however, Trane realizes that the government is trying to eradicate all graffiti artists in the city, and that he must stop them at all cost.The game features many celebrities doing voice over, ranging from prominent rappers such as Talib Kweli, the RZA and Diddy to actors such as Giovanni Ribisi, Brittany Murphy and Rosario Dawson. Getting Up was highly praised for its fantastic soundtrack composed by producer RJD2 and featuring licensed songs from artists such as Mobb Deep, Serj Tankian, Pharoahe Monch, Eric B and Rakim and other artists.Cast ListWhite MikeTrane - Talib KweliGabe - MC Serch (Michael Barren)Dip - P. Diddy (Sean Combs)Tina - Rosario DawsonKry-1 - Giovanni RibisiWhite Mike - Charlie MurphyStake - RZADecoy - Sean SquireKaren Light - Brittany MurphyAunt Beth - Andy DickChief Hunt - Adam WestMayor Sung - George HamiltonSoundtrackSoundtrack cover artToo Cold - Roots ManuvaVersion 78 Style - Glen BrownBoxcutter Emporium Part 2 - SixtooAural Prostitution - DJ VadimMotion 2000 - Polyrhythm AddictsMountain Song - Jane's AddictionClub Foot - KasabianBook Of Judges - Pharoahe MonchMy People Hold On - Eddie KendricksCatch A Bad One - Del Tha Funkee HomosapienWho Shot Ya (Serj Tankian Remix) - Notorious B.I.G.Subway Theme (from the Wild Style soundtrack) - Grand Wizard TheodoreWanted - Rhymefest feat. Samantha RonsonClik, Clak, And Spray - PackFMGetting Up Anthem: Part 1 - Rakim and Talib KweliSinnerman - Nina SimoneShook Ones Pt. 1 - Mobb DeepSurvival Of The Fittest - Mobb DeepI Smell A Rat - Big Mama ThorntonCavern - Liquid LiquidThere They Go - Fort MinorChin High - Roots ManuvaDulce's Theme - DJ Nature feat. Tek One and VelcroBomba's Theme - DJ Nature feat. Tek One and VelcroWalk On By - Isaac HayesAuld Lang Syne - Thomas RusiakPodcastPrior to the release of the game, Marc Ecko was featured in a series of video podcasts on the popular videogame website 1UP.com where he answered questions and talked about the development process of the game.VerticalityGetting Up is one of the first games to tout " verticality" as a key component to the gameplay experience, effectively coining the phrase as a marketing buzzword.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20096">Jet Grind Radio</game><game id="5235">Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time</game><game id="12117">JSRF: Jet Set Radio Future</game><game id="23292">Free Running</game><game id="20646">de Blob</game><game id="32852">Sideway: New York</game><game id="37494">Assassin's Creed III</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2141563-box_megucup.png</image></root>