<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7140</id><name>Aliens Versus Predator</name><description>CampaignsThere are 3 distinct campaigns in Aliens versus Predator. They are the Aliens, Colonial Marines, and Predator. Each one plays very differently, offering different play styles, different levels, and weapons.The AlienWhen playing as the Alien the perspective is that of a fish eye lens. This is to give the visual effect of what the Alien sees. The Alien fights with his claws and tail. It can also climb walls.The Colonial MarineThis is the most familiar of the 3 campaigns since it plays like a traditional FPS. Most of the weapons from the Alien films are available, you can use an image enhancer which works as night vision, and you also have flares to use to also help you see in dark places.The PredatorAs the Predator you can use most of the weapons from the Predator films that include the wrist blades, a throwing disc, and a shoulder mounted cannon. You have several different modes of vision including infrared and you have the ability to cloak.ExtrasAvP included several different bonus levels that allowed you to play as different characters in different levels. To allow the Marines to progress through the Alien levels you were given a jetpack. To allow the Predator to progress through the Alien levels you were given a grappling hook.There are also different gameplay modes including a "Supergore" mode that enhances the blood and gore, "Pigsticker" mode that gives the Predators speargun a higher rate of fire, a "John Woo" mode where the action slows down, and a "Sniper Munch" mode where the Alien can use it's jaw attack from any distance.Millennium Expansion PackIt added two new weapons and the ability to save your game in a level (although it was limited) softening the difficulty of having to replay an entire level if killed.Gold EditionIn 2000 AvP was re-released as the Gold Edition. It included everything in the Millennium Expansion Pack, nine new multiplayer maps added onto the previous 16, and a strategy guide.Classic 2000In 2010 Aliens versus Predator was re-released on Steam ( Valve's digital distribution service), as Aliens versus Predator Classic 2000. It was enhanced to run on modern PCs using DirectX 9, true widescreen support, support for the Xbox 360 Controller, updated mouse support, the option for unlimited saves, and the option to lock the frame rate. At first it did not support multiplayer but has since been updated to support it using your Steam ID and friends list. There are no dedicated servers and they are not planned.It includes everything from the Millennium expansion and everything from the Gold Edition release.System RequirementsOriginal ReleaseClassic 2000 ReleaseOS: Windows 98OS: Windows XP / Windows Vista / Windows 7Processor: 200Mhz ProcessorProcessor: Pentium II 400MMX ProcessorRAM Memory: 32MBRAM Memory: 128MBGraphics Card: DirectX 6.0 CompatibleGraphics and Sound Cards: DirectX 9.0c CompatibleHard Drive Space: 64MBHard Drive Space: 500MB</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2699">Alien Breed 3D</game><game id="7227">Abuse</game><game id="34553">Resident Evil: Operation Raccoon City</game><game id="10630">Star Trek: The Next Generation - Klingon Honor Guard</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2415477-avp_cd.jpg</image></root>