<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7225</id><name>Fatal Frame III: The Tormented</name><description>OverviewTwo months ago, Rei Kurosawa lost her fiancee Yuu Asou in a car accident. Since then, she's tried to get on with her life by working on her photography.Recently Rei was asked to take photos of an abandoned manor that was supposedly haunted. While taking pictures Rei sees Yuu standing both in the photo  before her own eyes. She tries to follow him, but ends up in a creepy looking mansion.A woman with a tattoo running the length of her body is after Rei. Soon the tattoo begins appearing on her in her waking hours,  now she must figure out what it all means before it consumes her entirely.CharactersRei Kurosawa- A young woman devastated by the recent loss of her fiancé in an auto accident. She blames herself for the accident because she was driving. She is a professional photographer. [Playable Character]Miku Hinasaki- Rei's assistant and the sister of Yuu's best friend. She is the protagonist of the first Fatal Frame and is trying to put her brother's disappearance behind her. [Playable Character]Kei Amakura- A friend of Yuu's, he asked him to look into the legends surrounding the Manor of Sleep because he believes his niece is being affected by the mysterious malady the legends speak of. His niece is Mio Amakura, one of the protagonists of Fatal Frame II. [Playable Character]Yuu Asou- Rei's recently deceased fiance. His shade lures Rei into the Manor. In life, he was an editor of books about folklore  related fields. [ NPC ]Mafayu Hinasaki- Miku's missing brother and Yuu's best friend. [ NPC ]Mio Amakura- Kei's niece who has been acting strangely since her twin, Mayu, disappeared a while ago. [ NPC ]Mayu Amakura- Mio's twin, she disappeared into the Lost Village. [ NPC ]Yoshino Takigama- Only survivor of a recent airline crash that took the lives of her family and her lover, Yoshino wanders the Manor of Sleep and begs Rei for help. [NPC ]Reika Kuze- A.K.A. Tattooed Priestess. The game's main antagonist, a young woman covered in tattoos that pursues any visitors to the Manor of Sleep. [Ghost]Yashu Kuze- A.K.A. Kuze Family Head. The ghost of a stern matriarch. A powerful but slow ghost that usually appears as a chapter's boss. [Ghost]Kyoka Kuze- A.K.A. Brushing Woman. A female ghost that floats through the air. Encountered often, and prone to swooping making her hard to hit. [Ghost]Handmaidens- Three young girls who perform shrine rites. Very quick ghosts who are encountered often, occasionally as flying spirits. The fourth Handmaiden, Amane, never attacks you during the story. [Ghosts]Carpenters- A.K.A. Men in White  Hidden Face Man. Male ghosts that attack slowly and are easily dispatched. Hidden Face Man is their leader, and considerably stronger. [Ghosts]Makie  Kozue Kuzuhara- A.K.A. Wandering Mother  Daughter. A couple of ghosts met early in the game, with basic attack patterns to help new players learn the ropes. [Ghosts]Rope Priestess  Kusabi- Two ghosts making cameos from earlier Fatal Frame games. Both are fairly powerful, though encountered rarely. [Ghosts]Kiriko Asanuma- A.K.A. Crawling Woman. Usually appears in enclosed spaces, making claustrophobic areas even worse. Responsible for most of the "shock moments" in the game. [Ghost]ExtrasFirst beat the game once then load the Clear Save :Equipped Function: Fs ("Festival" - grants innumerable bonuses, making the game a cinch) : Clear all missions with S rankEquipped Function: In ("Infinity" - all film in the inventory can be used infinitely) : Complete the game in nightmare modeEquipped Function: Sn ("Sense" - reveals hidden ghosts that you couldn't capture in the first playthrough) : Complete the game in normal modeEquipped Function: Zm ("Zoom" - allows you to zoom with the camera) : Complete the game in normal mode and capture 100 or more ghostsKei-Browband : Complete the game in normal modeKei-Fox ears : Complete the game in hard or 3 times in normal modeKei-Glasses : Complete the game twice in hard or nightmare modeKei-Glasses (white) : Complete the ghost listKei-Yukata (navy) : Complete the game in normal modeKei-Yukata (orange) : Complete the game twice in hard or nightmare modeMiku-Barrette : Complete the game in normal modeMiku-Cat ears : Complete the game in hard or 3 times in normal modeMiku-Glasses : Complete the game twice in hard or nightmare modeMiku-Headband : Complete the ghost listMiku-Pinafore dress : Complete the game in nightmare mode or clear all missionsMiku-Yukata (blue) : Complete the game in normal modeMiku-Yukata (pink) : Complete the game twice in hard or nightmare modeMiku-Zero costume : Complete the game in hard or 3 times in normal modeRei-Cat ears : Complete the game in hard or 3 times in normal modeRei-Glasses :Complete the game twice in hard or nightmare modeRei-Hair ornament : Complete the game in normal modeRei-Headband : Complete the ghost listRei-Pinafore dress : Complete the game in nightmare mode or clear all missionsRei-Suit : Complete the game in hard or 3 times in normal modeRei-Yukata (black) : Complete the game in normal modeRei-Yukata (red) : Complete the game twice in hard or nightmare modeRuri-Bell : Complete the game in hard or 3 times in normal modeRuri-Ribbon : Complete the game in normal modeThe concept :Complete the game in normal mode and capture 50 or more ghostsTrailer : Complete the game in normal mode and capture 50 or more ghostsTrailer images : Complete the game in normal mode and capture 50 or more ghostsUpgraded Lens (Crush) : Complete the game in normal mode and capture 150 or more ghostsUpgraded Lens (Serial) : Clear all missionsUpgraded Lens (Stop) : Complete the game in normal mode</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2842">Haunting Ground</game><game id="22605">Cursed Mountain</game><game id="10369">Silent Hill 3</game><game id="17962">Clock Tower 3</game><game id="13488">Alone in the Dark 2</game><game id="7535">Alone in the Dark 3</game><game id="13817">Alone in the Dark: The New Nightmare</game><game id="6328">Silent Hill 4: The Room</game><game id="10780">Silent Hill 2</game><game id="4312">Silent Hill</game><game id="25707">Silent Hill: Shattered Memories</game><game id="26599">Ghostwire</game><game id="25888">Ju-On: The Grudge</game><game id="29295">Phase Paradox</game><game id="15099">Kuon</game><game id="42171">DreadOut</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1867805-box_fframe3.png</image></root>