<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7276</id><name>Pathologic</name><description>OverviewPathologic is a complex conceptual first-person adventure game with a few action elements, developed by the guys at        Ice-Pick Lodge studios in Russia. The game can be very hard to get into, but also hugely rewarding to those patient enough to venture its almost abstract game world.StoryA fatal disease is affecting a strange little town when three outsiders mostly referred to by their nicknames (  the Bachelor,      the Haruspicus and     the Devotress) arrive to this remote countryside location. Players can only choose one of these characters to play with as they try to get to the source of this illness. The storyline will always be the same for all of them, but seen that some of the town's secrets can only be accessed by each one of the three different characters, replaying the game with all three is pretty much key in order for the player to soak in as much from the story as possible, which goes on for 12 in-game days, upon which each of the characters will come to his own conclusions... It is then up to the player to make up their own mind, based on what they witnessed through the eyes of these three characters. Players will be given a major quest at the beginning of each of the 12 days that will get them through the main storyline-- the twist to Pathologic is that if players fail to complete these main quests by the end of their corresponding day, a major character will die, and the outcome of one's adventure may very well change!GameplayThe game works on a strict time table--5 seconds of real time being equal to 1 minute of game time; at the start of the 24 hours that make up a day (the 24 hours will not always start at midnight) the player is given a main objective to complete. That main objective must be completed, if it is not the game will end when the next day starts. However in addition to that main objective, the player will be constantly seeking out, or having thrust upon them, additional quests given by the denizens of the Steppe; while these quests will not end the game if they are not completed, they are almost as vital as the main objective due to the benefits they will bring the player character.    These benefits will often come in the form of vital supplies: food, ammunition, medicine, etc. Because in addition to managing their time schedule, the player must also keep a close eye on their characters state of being. Characters in the game are frail, and that include the main character: who must eat and drink or face starvation, use bandages to mend wounds, and make use of the extremely sparse medical supplies so as not to become another victim of the plague.  Characters  The Bachelor  Daniel Dankovsky, a young doctor seeking a method to terminate his nemesis: Death. Dankovsky is summoned to the Steppe in order to perform a postmortem autopsy on what is rumored to be an immortal; this purportedly immortal elder died under under mysterious circumstances, and upon arriving in the town Dankovsky finds himself tasked not only with being the sole professional doctor in the town, but with being chief investigator in the murder mystery which enshrouds the doomed village. The Town The gloomy town where the action takes place is almost a character in by itself, given its importance to the story. The most important building in the whole city would be The Polyhedron, which is a geometrically impossible architectural structure that the town's children use as a fortress. On the other side of town, an ominous mountain called The Abattoir looms over, whereas The Apiary, an insane asylum, lies next to it.System requirements MinimumRecommendedOperating System: Windows XPProcessor: Pentium III 800 MHz or equivalentRAM Memory: 384 MBHard Drive Space: 1500 MBOperating System: Windows XPProcessor: Pentium 4 1.4 GHz or equivalentRAM Memory: 512 MBHard Drive Space: 1800 MB</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4403">Post Mortem</game><game id="6515">Return to Mysterious Island</game><game id="943">CSI: Crime Scene Investigation</game><game id="17043">Agatha Christie: And Then There Were None</game><game id="10096">Law &amp; Order: Justice is Served</game><game id="821">Cold Case Files</game><game id="6212">Dark Fall: Lights Out</game><game id="24777">Return to Mysterious Island II</game><game id="25101">The Void</game><game id="18678">Call of Cthulhu: Dark Corners of the Earth</game><game id="11725">S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Shadow of Chernobyl</game><game id="17280">BioShock</game><game id="31594">Cargo! The Quest for Gravity</game><game id="37490">Cradle</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/13292/809736-pathologic.jpg</image></root>