<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7334</id><name>Crossfire</name><description>OverviewCrossfire is a free-to-play, online first-person shooter game, developed by SmileGate in South Korea and now being distributed by Z8Games Portal. The game originally released in 2007 in Korea and has now expanded worldwide because of its huge success there. The game utilizes wiselogic X-Trap, a system widely used in free online titles such as AIKA and CABAL to prevent hacking and cheating and to keep the playing field fair. One only downloads a 1.5MB download client that then downloads the real installer.The game has been grossing $1 billion every year in annual revenues (the majority of which comes from Asia, particularly China), making it the highest-grossing first-person shooter of all time and one of the highest-grossing online games along with World of Warcraft, which it overtook in annual revenues for the first time in 2012.GameplayCrossfire in practice handles much like the standard online shooter of todays age. In the beginning one begging their gaming careers with the standard weapons and through playing matches and gain experience, the player gains GP, the games in-game currency that the player utilizes to purchase weapons, clothes and gear to make use of in game to improve their experience. The player their own customization screen where they can change out the weapons they can use on their matches, note this is in the main menu of the game, once starts a match this menu can not be accessed. Once the player is happy with their character, they choose a game channel and the choose a game server.Once the player is in game, they are automatically positioned as either terrorist (Blacklist) or counter- terrorist (Global Risk), There is a 3 second spawn invulnerability that is illustrated to others by the character model flashing red. After the player has spawned in their respective places, that players can then rush various parts of the map to encounter with the opposing team and have it out in an all out gun fight much familiar to most people that have played Counter-Strike 1.6 or Combat Arms.There is the usual headshot and players take damage and as soon as one dies they are back at spawn with in 3 seconds. Once a Player makes a kill, a white star at the bottom of their screen appears with one spike shaded light gold, if the player manages to aquire a double kill the latter spike will shade, accompanied by the Quake-Style Announcer stating the respective "Double Kill" and "Multi Kill." Once the star has filled, the announcer shouts "Unstoppable" and every kill hence gets this response.The round ends according to the game mode that the server that the player joined has entered:EliminationConsist of an "every man for themselves" objective where each player has their own score and the player that reaches the winning number of kills first wins the round.Team DeathmatchEach player is assorted in a Terrorist or Counter-Terrorist team, the player that amounts the number of kills established by the server first wins the match.Search and DestroyA player in the terrorist (Blacklist) side holds a bomb that they must plant in one of two designated planting areas, The round is either won by the team that eliminates the opposing team first or by the bomb timer reaching 0 and the bomb exploding at the designated bomb site.Ghost ModeEssentially Search and Destroy with the exception that the Terrorist (Backlist) Cloaked and can only carry knifes, the round is won by either the bomb detonating or the elimination of the opposing team.The game controls in a relatively traditional, First person shooter way. The user moves using the WASD keys and uses the mouse to aim and left click to fire their weapon. With weapons that hold a scope, right click is to zoom in their scope. The user either uses their 1-4 keys or scroll wheel to select their weapon. Q is used to change between the two latest used weapons. Space bar jump etc. classic, Counter-Strike controls.Mutation Mode / Hero ModeA player at random is turned into a mutant at the start of the round and the objective is to infect the entire human team to mutants within the time limit. A variant on this mode is called "Hero Mode" where one person on the human team is turned into the hero who can survive multible hits from mutants and has a grenade launcher on his galilRankingsCrossfire uses a ranking system that utilizes the players experience points acquired in-game to give the player a credential that they can share with others and give them access to content such as weapons and attire exclusively available to that class. Here is a run down of the ranks:Trainee 1- This is the Rank the player starts off with.Trainee 2- The class requires 456 experience points to achieve and yields no unlockables.Private- This class requires 912 experience points to achieve and yields 10,000 GP as a bonus to achieving it.PFC- This class requires 1824 experience points to achieve and yields no unlockablesCorporal- This class requires 3192 experience points to achieve, the player is now able to join a clan, and can now wield the P90, flashbang, and K2Sergeant 1- This class requires 5016 experience points to achieve ad the player can now wield the Dragonov, STYER AUG A1, Scar Heavy, FAMAS, Desert Eagle, SG552 and a bonus of 20,000 GPSergeant 2- This class requires 7292 experience points to achieve and yields no unlockablesSergeant 3- This class requires 10032 experience points to achieve and yields no unlockables.Sergeant 4- This class requires 13224 experience points to achieve and yields no unlockables.WeaponsPrimary Weapons- MP5Power:47 Accuracy:91 Firing rate:79 Recoil:55 Weight:27 Ammo:30/120- P90Power:40 Accuracy:89 Firing rate:83 Recoil:62 Weight:31 Ammo:50/100- UZIPower:29 Accuracy:86 Firing rate:90 Recoil:70 Weight:19 Ammo:30/120- K1Power:47 Accuracy:93 Firing rate:70 Recoil:51 Weight:32 Ammo:30/90- M4A1Power:66 Accuracy:95 Firing rate:64 Recoil:60 Weight:43 Ammo:30/90- AK47Power:96 Accuracy:95 Firing rate:53 Recoil:76 Weight:49 Ammo:30/90- AK74Power:73 Accuracy:94 Firing rate:58 Recoil:59 Weight:46 Ammo:30/90- STYER AUG A1Power:64 Accuracy:97 Firing rate:65 Recoil:49 Weight:47 Ammo:30/90- M700Power:80 Accuracy:97 Firing rate:0 Recoil:55 Weight:41 Ammo:10/30- FAMASPower:57 Accuracy:93 Firing rate:76 Recoil:68 Weight:42 Ammo:25/75- M60Power:93 Accuracy:92 Firing rate:56 Recoil:90 Weight:79 Ammo:100/100- AWMPower:100 Accuracy:100 Firing rate:0 Recoil:80 Weight:100 Ammo:5/30- SPAS 12Power:70 Accuracy:30 Firing rate:15 Recoil:91 Weight:47 Ammo:8/40- DRAGUNOVPower:95 Accuracy:96 Firing rate:0 Recoil:70 Weight:94 Ammo:5/30- SG552Power:78 Accuracy:96 Firing rate:66 Recoil:56 Weight:49 Ammo:30/90- K2Power:58 Accuracy:35 Firing rate:21 Recoil:85 Weight:33 Ammo:6/30- MP7Power:37 Accuracy:90 Firing rate:95 Recoil:51 Weight:25 Ammo:40/80- XM 1014Power:58 Accuracy:35 Firing rate:21 Recoil:85 Weight:33 Ammo:6/30- G36KPower:56 Accuracy:89 Firing rate:59 Recoil:47 Weight:60 Ammo:30/120- SCAR LIGHTPower:80 Accuracy:96 Firing rate:61 Recoil:58 Weight:40 Ammo:30/90- SCAR-HEAVYPower:90 Accuracy:96 Firing rate:60 Recoil:63 Weight:46 Ammo:30/90- MP5-ADVPower:47 Accuracy:91 Firing rate:79 Recoil:55 Weight:27 Ammo:40/90- AK47-CAMOPower:73 Accuracy:94 Firing rate:58 Recoil:59 Weight:46 Ammo:35/90- XM8Power:92 Accuracy:96 Firing rate:63 Recoil:61 Weight:41 Ammo:30/90- PSG-1Power:93 Accuracy:99 Firing rate:0 Recoil:47 Weight:97 Ammo:5/30- M4A1-ADVPower:66 Accuracy:95 Firing rate:64 Recoil:60 Weight:43 Ammo:35/90- AWM-CAMOPower:100 Accuracy:100 Firing rate:0 Recoil:80 Weight:100 Ammo:10/30- GOLDEN AK-47Power:96 Accuracy:95 Firing rate:53 Recoil:76 Weight:49 Ammo:38/90- M4A1-CUSTOMPower:66 Accuracy:95 Firing rate:64 Recoil:60 Weight:43 Ammo:30/90- M4A1-GOLDPower:66 Accuracy:95 Firing rate:64 Recoil:60 Weight:43 Ammo:38/90- AK47-KNIFEPower:96 Accuracy:95 Firing rate:53 Recoil:76 Weight:49 Ammo:30/90- PSG-RED DRAGONPower:93 Accuracy:99 Firing rate:0 Recoil:47 Weight:97 Ammo:10/30- SG552-CAMOPower:78 Accuracy:96 Firing rate:66 Recoil:56 Weight:49 Ammo:35/90- AK47-SILVERPower:96 Accuracy:95 Firing rate:53 Recoil:76 Weight:49 Ammo:35/105- M16-S CAMOPower:96 Accuracy:95 Firing rate:53 Recoil:76 Weight:49 Ammo:35/105- AWM-ADV CHRISTMASPower:100 Accuracy:100 Firing rate:0 Recoil:80 Weight:100 Ammo:10/30- M4A1 CHRISTMASPower:66 Accuracy:95 Firing rate:64 Recoil:60 Weight:43 Ammo:30/90SECONDARY WEAPONS- COLT911Power:35 Accuracy:95 Firing rate:0 Recoil:63 Weight:17 Ammo:7/35- M9Power:16 Accuracy:96 Firing rate:0 Recoil:55 Weight:16 Ammo:15/60- DESERT EAGLEPower:59 Accuracy:96 Firing rate:0 Recoil:60 Weight:17 Ammo:7/35- SIG P228Power:30 Accuracy:96 Firing rate:0 Recoil:55 Weight:17 Ammo:13/39- COLT ANACONDAPower:49 Accuracy:86 Firing rate:0 Recoil:80 Weight:25 Ammo:6/30- GOLDEN DESERT EAGLEPower:59 Accuracy:96 Firing rate:0 Recoil:50 Weight:17 Ammo:10/40- DESERT EAGLE CAMOPower:59 Accuracy:96 Firing rate:0 Recoil:60 Weight:17 Ammo:7/35- ANACONDA-ADVPower:47 Accuracy:91 Firing rate:79 Recoil:55 Weight:27 Ammo:6/30Crossfire can be acquired by visiting their Website.System RequirementsMinimumProcessor: Intel Pentium 4 @ 1.5GhzRAM: 512MBGraphics Card: nVIDIA Geforce 5600 DirectX9 compliant card or betterOperating System: Microsoft Windows XP or Microsoft Windows VistaHard Driver Space: 1.2GBInternet Connection: Cable/DSL or betterRecommendedProcessor: Intel Pentium 4 @ 2GhzRAM: 1GBGraphics Card: nVIDIA Geforce 6600 DirectX9 compliant card or betterOperating System: Microsoft Windows XP or Microsoft Windows VistaHard Driver Space: 1.2GBInternet Connection: Cable/DSL or betterNote: the game does not run higher than 1440x900</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11339">Counter-Strike: Source</game><game id="11663">Half-Life: Counter-Strike</game><game id="5722">Counter-Strike: Condition Zero</game><game id="2133">Call of Duty 4: Modern Warfare</game><game id="21591">Combat Arms</game><game id="12716">Battlefield 1942</game><game id="16866">Battlefield 2</game><game id="20655">Battlefield: Bad Company</game><game id="16586">Battlefield Vietnam</game><game id="1986">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six: Vegas 2</game><game id="3550">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six: Vegas</game><game id="7887">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six</game><game id="1581">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six: Lockdown</game><game id="8728">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six: Rogue Spear</game><game id="17491">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six 3: Black Arrow</game><game id="18600">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six 3: Athena Sword</game><game id="15748">Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six 3: Iron Wrath</game><game id="40582">Mission Against Terror</game><game id="33265">Project Blackout</game><game id="42646">Battlefield Online</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3439/952514-cf_home.jpg</image></root>