<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7432</id><name>Formula One World Championship: Beyond the Limit</name><description>OverviewFormula One World Championship: Beyond the Limit is a F1 racing game that was developed by Fuji Television Network and published by Sega sometime in 1994. The game follows the 1993 F1 season, with every race accounted for and the majority of the drivers playable. The game was released in Japan as Heavenly Symphony: Formula One World Championship 1993.The GameThere are three modes in the game; Grand Prix, 1993 Mode and Free Run.In Grand Prix mode you follow a story line and meet with all the actual people who own, design and race the cars. Your first race here is a qualification race to see which teams want to recruit you. After you select which team you wish to race for you meet with the people who make that team work, learn a bit about the company and then head out to race with story bits cut in after each race to clue you in on the behind the scenes rivalries and drama.In 1993 Mode you follow along the 1993 Formula Season and the game then acts as a semi-documentary interlacing levels with FMV, giving the stats on each race and any unique events that happened during the race. You control a set character and then accomplish tasks that happened during the actual race. For the South African Grand Prix you play as JJ Lehto trying to catch up to Derek Warwick in the middle of a thunderstorm.Free Race mode is exactly as it sounds. You decide which track to race, how many laps and the weather conditions.TeamsWilliams FW 15C#0 Damon Hill#2 Alain ProstTyrrell 020C#3 Ukyo Katayama#4 Andrea de CesarisBenetton B193B#5 Michael Schumacher#6 Riccardo PatreseMcLaren MP4/8#7 Michael Andretti#_ Your CharacterFootwork FA14#9 Derek Warwick#10 Aguri SuzukiLotus 107B#11 Alex Zanardi#12 Johnny HerbertJordan 193#14 Rubens Barrichello#15 Ivan CapelliLarrousse LH93#19 Phillippe Alliot#20 Erik ComasLola-BMS- T93/30#21 Michele Alboreto#22 Luca BadoerMinardi M193#23 Christian Fittipaldi#24 Fabrizio BarbazzaLigier JS39#25 Martin Brundle#26 Mark BlundellFerrari F93A#27 Jean Alesi#28 Gerhard BergerSauber C12#29 Karl Wendlinger#30 JJ LehtoOne Missing DriverIt's worth noting that the missing driver in the roster (the second McLaren car) was Ayrton Senna. Ironic considering Sega's previous F1 game was Ayrton Senna's Super Monaco GP II, not to mention this game was released in the same year that Senna died at Imola.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8595">Formula 1</game><game id="27106">Joe Montana's NFL Football</game><game id="8564">Prize Fighter</game><game id="13338">Andretti Racing</game><game id="532">Super Monaco GP</game><game id="6638">Ferrari Grand Prix Challenge</game><game id="25985">F1 2010</game><game id="26638">Michael Andretti's Indy Car Challenge</game><game id="14919">Grand Prix Challenge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/10831/479150-587949_88031_front.jpg</image></root>