<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7485</id><name>WWF In Your House</name><description>OverviewWWF in Your House was released on the                      Sega Saturn and                     Sony Playstation consoles, as well as the PC, by                    Acclaim Entertainment, Inc. in last 1996. Developed by                                   Acclaim Studios Salt Lake City (formerly Sculptured Software), WWF in Your House was the follow up to                                  WWF WrestleMania: The Arcade Game, which was developed by Sculptured Software, and published by                   Midway Entertainment the previous year. Like its predecessor, WWF in Your House was heavily influenced by Midway's                                 Mortal Kombat franchise. Departing from earlier 16-bit era WWF licensed games developed by Sculptured Software, such as                                     WWF Royal Rumble and                                    WWF Raw, WWF in Your House uses digitized sprites and focuses on fast paced, strike and combo based fighting, common to the fighting game at the time. Unlike earlier titles which grounded the gameplay in "realistic" deliberately paced grappling and momentum based combat, the action in WWF in Your House is quick and over the top, with weapons appearing out of nowhere, characters morphing shape, and characters using lightening and fire attacks. Like other games in the fighting genre, WWF in Your House also features character-specific attacks and stages. For example, the                                British Bulldog's list of moves includes the Union Jack Attack and his stage appears to be in front of Buckingham Palace.  In game commentary is provided by                        Vince McMahon and                       Mr. Perfect.   Acclaim Studios Salt Lake City would abandon the digitized sprite style for polygonal 3D models and over the top action for grapple based combat in its 1998 follow up title                                      WWF War Zone.Playable RosterWrestler Info.Stats       From - Death Valley, California Height - 6'10" Weight -  328 Lbs.  Trademark Attack - Tombstone Favorite Quote - "Rest in Peace"            From - Parts Unknown Height - 6'2" Weight -  260 Lbs.  Trademark Attack -  Flying Shoulderblock, Big Splash comboFavorite Quote - "Always Believe"            From - San Antonio, Texas Height - 6'1" Weight -  227 Lbs.   Trademark Attack - Sweet Chin Music Favorite Quote - "Kickin' it with the Kliq"            From - Calgary, Alberta, Canada Height - 5'11" Weight - 227 Lbs.   Trademark Attack - Spinning Wheel Kick Favorite Quote - "I am the king of Harts"            From - Greenwich, Connecticut Height - 6'4" Weight -  246 Lbs.  Trademark Attack - The Pedigree Favorite Quote - "Arrogance is Truth"          From - Hollywood, CaliforniaHeight - 6'6"Weight - 280 Lbs.  Trademark Attack - Curtain Call Favorite Quote - "Remember the name....Goldust"           British Bulldog   From - Manchester, England Height - 6'0" Weight -  259 Lbs.   Trademark Attack - Powerslam Favorite Quote - "It's U.K, U.K not U.S.A, U.S.A"            From - Calgary, Alberta, Canada Height - 6'1" Weight -  234 Lbs.  Trademark Attack - Sharpshooter Favorite Quote - "I'm the best there is, the best there was, and the best there ever will be"            From - Pearl River, MS Height - 6'2" Weight -  305 Lbs.   Trademark Attack - Pearl River Plunge Favorite Quote - "Be Proud of who you are!"            From - Rocky Mountains Height - 6'5" Weight -  458 Lbs.  Trademark Attack - Vader Bomb Favorite Quote - "It's Vader Time"     </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3667">WWF Wrestlemania 2000</game><game id="8697">The Simpsons Wrestling</game><game id="30637">Lucha Libre AAA Heroes del Ring</game><game id="8027">WWF WrestleMania: The Arcade Game</game><game id="28430">WWF Royal Rumble</game><game id="37547">WWE WrestleFest</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2139908-box_wwfiyh.png</image></root>