<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>750</id><name>Final Doom</name><description>OverviewThe main menuFinal Doom was originally released in 1996 for the PC and widely considered to be the hardest of the original Doom series. Final Doom consists of two separate standalone games built on the Doom II engine. TNT: Evilution was developed by TeamTNT and The Plutonia Experiment was developed by the Casali brothers also from TeamTNT. Although not developed by id Software themselves, Final Doom is an official id Software product. Each game has a massive 32 levels (30 official and 2 secret levels.)The game was released as the definitive challenge for the Doom veterans wanting more, hence the high difficulty and the name Final Doom.A Playstation version was later released containing levels from Final Doom and the map pack "Master Levels for Doom II."TNT: EvilutionEvilution is a game containing entirely new sprites and music tracks made by the developers. Features a slightly easier difficulty level than Plutonia, which ramps up towards harder levels instead of starting out at the highest difficulty. Unlike the earlier Doom games, the stages in this episode are designed to more closely resemble the areas that their names suggest.LevelsDesigned by: TeamTNTSystem ControlHuman BBQPower ControlWormholeHangerOpen SeasonPrisonMetalStrongholdRedemptionStorage FacilityCraterNukage ProcessingSteel WorksDead ZoneDeepest ReachesProcessing AreaMillShipping / RespawingCentral ProcessingAdministration CenterHabitatLunar Mining ProjectQuarryBaron's DenBallistyxMount PainHeckRiver StyxLast CallPharaoh (secret level)Caribbean (secret level)The Plutonia ExperimentFinal Doom is considerably harder than both Doom and Doom 2The Plutonia Experiment is the more difficult of the two episodes. The player is immediately confronted with many of the game's most dangerous enemies while not yet entirely prepared to meet them. It also features a loose jungle theme and sends the player to some unusual environments not normally seen in the Doom Universe such as Aztec ruins and an ancient Egyptian Pyramid. Most of the stages in this episode also follow a more abstract layout more in line with those in the earlier Doom games.LevelsDesigned by: Milo Casali, Dario Casali.CongoWell of SoulsAztecCagedGhost TownBaron's LairCaughtyardRealmAbattoireOnslaughtHuntedSpeedThe CryptGenesisThe TwilightThe OmenCompoundNeurosphereNMEThe Death DomainSlayerImpossible MissionTombstoneThe Final FrontierThe Temple of DarknessBunkerAnti-ChristThe SewersOdyssey of NoisesThe Gateway of HellCyberden (secret level)Go 2 It (secret level)WeaponsFinal Doom adds no new weapons to the arsenal; it contains the same as found in Doom II.FistsWhen entirely out of ammo , your fists is your last option of self defense. The damage and attack rate of the fists are very low, but with the berserk power-up the fists turn into a deadly weapon for a short period of time.ChainsawThe chainsaw nearly nullifies the fists' existence with its superior damage and attack speed. The chainsaw is particularly useful against a single enemy since it stuns the enemy for periods of time. However, the chainsaw should still be seen as a last resort when low on ammo.PistolThe starting weapon. Its damage and attack speed is low and once the player is in possession of the chaingun, which uses the same ammunition, the pistol can be entirely ignored.ShotgunThe shotgun was the "go-to" weapon of the original Doom, but since the introduction of the Super Shotgun in Doom II, its existence is somewhat nullified. Its fire rate is slow, but the high damage output makes up for it. Many players remember the enemies HP by how many shots from the shotgun they require. In Final Doom, the Shotgun is acquired at the same time as the Super Shotgun, so it is up to the preference of the player which shotgun to use when.Super ShotgunFirst introduced in Doom II, the Super Shotgun became the favorite weapon for many players. The fire rate is even slower than the original Shotgun, but the damage output and spread is very high. It shares ammunition with the standard Shotgun and fires two shots at a time.ChaingunThe chaingun is the fastest firing weapon in the game. Its damage is at the same level of the pistol, but the high fire rate makes it into a deadly weapon. It shares ammunition with the pistol, which means the players can fully ignore the pistol once they get their hands on the chaingun since there are no disadvantages.Rocket LauncherThis is a very deadly weapon - both to the enemies and the player himself. The rockets deal a very high amount of damage and have splash damage. Furthermore, the Rocket Launcher's fire rate is high, which makes the player able to carpet bomb areas.Plasma GunThe Plasma Gun is often compared to the Chaingun. They both have a high firing rate and are generally useful in the same situations. The main difference between them is the projectile speed. Whereas the Chaingun's bullets hit the target instantly, the Plasma Gun's shots have to travel through the air before hitting the target, making it possible for enemies to dodge incoming attacks. The trade-off for this inaccuracy is a much higher damage output. The Plasma Gun shares ammunition with the BFG9000, so many players rarely use the Plasma Gun after getting the BFG.BFG9000Big-Freaking-Gun, Big-Fucking-Gun, Bio-Force-Gun - no one really knows what the BFG stands for, but one thing is certain: it is a big freaking gun. The BFG9000 fires a huge plasma ball which moves slowly through the air. Upon impact, the target it hits receives a huge amount of damage and hits additional nearby enemies for a high amount of damage as well. The player in unable to damage himself with the weapon, which makes it the best weapon of choice against large groups of enemies that are relatively close to the player.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3407">Duke Nukem 3D</game><game id="7694">Wolfenstein 3D</game><game id="23289">Robotica</game><game id="9048">Blood Plasma Pak</game><game id="34086">Painkiller: Redemption</game><game id="22548">Hexen</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/347/262038-finaldoom_cover.jpg</image></root>