<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7570</id><name>Enter the Matrix</name><description>OverviewEnter The Matrix is a game developed by Shiny Entertainment and published by Atari SA set in the Matrix universe. The game's plot is a sidestory that helps bridge the films The Matrix Reloaded and The Matrix Revolutions, as well as the Animatrix short Final Flight of the Osiris. It was released on all major platforms of its era, including the PC, PlayStation 2, GameCube, and Xbox, on May 15, 2003.StoryGhost, one of the two player-characters in Enter the Matrix's story. In Enter the Matrix, the player takes on the role of either Niobe or Ghost. The paths that each character takes during the story are different, but intertwine at select points.The game ties into Final Flight of the Osiris by starting the game off with a mission in which the player's chosen character must retrieve important information regarding an impending machine invasion left at the drop spot by the crew of the Osiris. Enter the Matrix mostly takes place in parallel to the events of The Matrix Reloaded, and follows Niobe and Ghost on their missions to aid and assist the efforts of Neo, Morpheus and the crew of the Nebuchadnezzar.The game contains live-action cutscenes that were shot during production of The Matrix Reloaded and Revolutions, offering character development for Niobe and Ghost not present in the films. Enter the Matrix also depicts Agent Smith's takeover of Mega City and the events that lead to the stranding of the Logos in the real world, as referenced at the beginning of The Matrix Revolutions.GameplayGameplay consists of third-person shooting and martial arts along with three driving sections. The game is also notable for having a "Hacking" mini-game which could be used to enter cheats and unlock Easter Eggs.In the hacking minigame, the player can enter a cheat that unlocks a multiplayer fighting mode. once unlocked, the player could choose from multiple stages based on the films and the game. This multiplayer mode is based on one-on-one battles between selected characters from the Matrix universe. However, the characters available for play are dependent on the stage selected. Most moves available in the normal single-player portion of the game are available in this mode, save for bullet-time.Stages and characters available for play include:The Bedroom - Cujo vs. VladThe Ballroom - Ghost vs. NiobeThe Dojo - Niobe vs. TrinityThe Pit - Seraph vs. BallardThe Subway - Morpheus vs. Agent SmithThe Atrium - the Janitor vs. the Sewing WomanThe Alleyway - Police Cruiser Man vs. Firebird Man - This stage features car models standing upright and fighting rather than human characters.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2414">Max Payne</game><game id="3032">Dead to Rights</game><game id="9987">Ghost in the Shell: Stand Alone Complex</game><game id="14523">Star Wars: Jedi Knight II - Jedi Outcast</game><game id="16922">Star Wars: Jedi Knight - Jedi Academy</game><game id="14871">The Terminator: Dawn of Fate</game><game id="11958">EOE: Eve of Extinction</game><game id="14819">Tron 2.0</game><game id="9051">Psi-Ops: The Mindgate Conspiracy</game><game id="3547">Max Payne 2: The Fall of Max Payne</game><game id="29284">Tron: Evolution</game><game id="36610">Psychic City</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1852733-box_etm.png</image></root>