<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7649</id><name>Mortal Kombat: Shaolin Monks</name><description>OverviewMortal Kombat: Shaolin Monks is a 3D action-adventure platformer developed by Midway Los Angeles and published by Midway for the PlayStation 2 and Xbox on September 16, 2005. Like Mortal Kombat Mythologies: Sub-Zero and Mortal Kombat: Special Forces, Mortal Kombat: Shaolin Monks is a spin-off of the Mortal Kombat fighting game franchise. The game infuses versus fighting game mechanics (as well as Mortal Kombat staples, such as Fatalities and the Test Your Might mini-game) with a 3D beat-em-up/platformer. Along with the main campaign, which can be played co-operatively with two local players, the game also features an offline Versus Mode, letting two players duke it out with unlockable characters and unique stages (each with different layouts and traps).Rather than serve as a character's prologue to the original Mortal Kombat (like the previous spin-offs), Mortal Kombat: Shaolin Monks retells the events of Mortal Kombat II through the perspective of two Shaolin Monks: Liu Kang and Kung Lao. Players assume the role as one of these warriors as they venture through the nightmarish realm of Outworld under the instruction of the thunder god Raiden (with assistance from action movie star Johnny Cage and elite Special Forces operative Sonya Blade) to save Earthrealm from the sinister plot of the sorceror Shang Tsung. Along the way, they encounter various allies and enemies from the first two Mortal Kombat games, including female fan-wielding warrior Kitana, four-armed behemoth Goro, and hellish ninja Scorpion.The NTSC version of Mortal Kombat: Shaolin Monks also includes an emulation of the arcade version of Mortal Kombat II, which is unlockable with either a special cheat code or by completing secret missions.GameplayGameplay features in the game include a fighting mechanic called Multi-Directional Kombat System. This system allows the player to form combo attacks on multiple enemies on the ground as well as bringing the opponent into the air like Devil May Cry and continuing the combo. Familiar to Mortal Kombat players are stage fatalities that can be performed when playing on certain key spots like pits in the floor or rotating spikes. Like stage fatalities another adoption of the Mortal Kombat franchise is the fatalities. These are performed different then the arcade versus counterpart, here the player has to perform combos on multiple enemies to fill up a fatality meter. Once this meter is filled a fatality can be performed at any point in the game against any enemy. A new finishing move called Mutalities can be performed like fatalities but on multiple opponents. Lastly, Brutalities are the last finishing move which like Mortal Kombat 3 is a explosive combo attack that can be performed on a opponent or multiple opponents.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16206">The Warriors</game><game id="15928">Naruto: Rise of a Ninja</game><game id="1330">Naruto: Clash of Ninja 2</game><game id="20544">Naruto: Clash of Ninja</game><game id="21375">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja 3</game><game id="20922">Afro Samurai</game><game id="8898">Genji: Dawn of the Samurai</game><game id="6959">God of War</game><game id="15394">Death by Degrees</game><game id="7105">Die Hard Arcade</game><game id="1590">Dynamite Cop!</game><game id="13809">Rise to Honor</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1340034-mksm_box.png</image></root>