<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7658</id><name>Wizardry: Tale of the Forsaken Land</name><description>OverviewWizardry: Tale of the Forsaken Land follows the player's customized character through the Labyrinth: A deep dungeon formed when a magical disaster hit the kingdom of Duhan. The player character will encounter various other NPCs in both the town hub and the dungeon itself and is able to hire up to five other characters to fight alongside them. As the game progresses, the player discovers that their character is deeply connected to the Kingdom and the disaster that occurred.   GameplayWizardry is a game that hybridizes both Western and Eastern styles of RPG gaming. Retained from the Western style are the expansive dungeons with meandering paths, traps and secrets, all depicted in a first-person perspective. The Eastern-style combat is a tactical, turn-based system whereby characters and monsters can attack one after the other using a selection of abilities. Its name is pretty much a homage to the old              Wizardry games, which were a big hit in Japan and inspired             Final Fantasy,            Dragon Quest and the whole JRPG genre.  Between trips to the Labyrinth, the game's central dungeon, the player can visit the town hub to sell and restock their inventory as well as save, hire new characters and remove curses/resurrect dead members. In this sense it is very much a standard dungeon-crawler. Once the game is a complete, a           randomized dungeon with infinite floors becomes unlocked for players to explore.  Like the Wizardry games, all characters have a standard class and alignment, the latter of which dictates which members will work with whom. The player character's alignment is malleable, and will change depending on the player's actions. Choosing members with a similar alignment allows them to build up their trust with the player character, unlocking powerful          combination attacks, such as those found in         Suikoden. Similarly to Suikoden, the party is set out in two rows of three members, with ranged characters placed on the back and well-defended short-range characters placed up front.  ClassesThere are eight classes to choose from, though only four are available from the offset. Once the player character has leveled up a bit, they are able to pick one of the more powerful classes, provided they have the stats for it.         Warrior - The standard fighter type, typified by short-range melee and the stronger armor and weaponry. Warriors are best employed in the front row to protect the physically weaker classes.        Thief - Though less powerful than Warriors, Thieves have many uses in the dungeons, including the ability to detect and disarm traps, open chests and locate secret areas. They are also able to cast limited Priest and Sorcerer magic, making them excellent support units early in the game.   Priest - Standard healer type, adept at using magic to assist or heal other characters. Though physically weak, they are decent support units and are vital when fighting the undead.      Sorcerer - Powerful spell-slingers, best put in the back row to annihilate enemies with ease. Keep an eye on their magic limit.  Bishop - Bishops are the upgraded magic-user class, able to use both Priest and Sorcerer magic. They are also able to dispel and undead and identify items instantly, when normally a trip back to the town hub is needed.   Samurai - Samurai are powerful combat units, able to use Sorcerer magic to complement their potent martial talents. Their equipment is unique to them.    Knight - Knights are highly defensive Warriors that can also use Priest magic, as well as the Priest's ability to dispel undead. Having at least one Knight in the party all but guarantees that someone will make it out the Labyrinth alive.   Ninja - The most difficult class to qualify for, Ninjas are units that are capable of attacking twice in one turn, occasionally insta-killing their opponent. On top of that, they can use low-level Priest and Sorcerer magic.  Each character can also be one of five races: Human (suited for any class), Elf (suited for spell-using classes), Dwarf (suited for non-agile combat), Gnome (suited for anything, though especially Priests) and Hobbits (suited for agile classes like Thief).</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19917">Might and Magic II: Gates to Another World</game><game id="33362">Students of the Round</game><game id="33763">Elminage Original</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2199436-box_wizardry.png</image></root>