<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7682</id><name>MySims</name><description>MySims was released September 18, 2007 on the Wii.This title is the first of the MySims franchise which takes roots from the original Sims and Sims 2. Unlike in the Sims, the player here has direct control over one character. The gameplay is similar to that of Animal Crossing , as players can do tasks for the town's residents and get items in return. Unlike in Animal Crossing games however, there is a much bigger focus on user created content. Most of the tasks in the game requires the player to build something for someone.The player does this within his workshop using a predetermined blueprint. The blueprint allows players to easily make the desired piece of furniture by selecting the block and snapping it into place. The blocks needed to complete each piece are highlighted in green, and the blueprint even tells them where the block goes on said piece. Despite the predetermined blueprints, improvisation is both encouraged. and in later tasks, required as many Sims require that furniture carry a certain "Essence"Essences are the main collectables in Mysims and they come in multiple flavors. From a basic standpoint essences fall into 5 different Categories: Cute, Party, Genius, Goth and Food. Within each of the categories there are many different types of essences and it is these subcategories which Sims require be attached to their furniture.Essences can be found in several different ways such as fishing, prospecting and chopping down trees among others. Part of the challenge in the game is finding out to find new essences which thetown residence request.PC VersionBuild and customize the bed to the player's likingMySims was officially announced for the PC at E3 2008. While the PC version is just a port of the Wii version, there are new additions which include multiplayer support. Multiplayer supports up to 8 players and can play hide-and-seek or tag, trade items or build a garden. There are two modes of tag: classic tag and zombie tag. In zombie tag, the person who is "it" has a storm cloud over their head and has to tag as many people until there is only one person left. Another addition is six new NPCs to meet and the ability to send creations to other friends via e-mail. The PC version ship October 28, 2008.PC SpecsOS: Windows XP SP2 or VistaCPU: 1.5 GHz or faster (2.4 GHz for Vista)RAM: 256 MB or more (512 for Vista)DISC DRIVE: DVD-ROMHDD SPACE: At least 3 GB of free spaceVIDEO CARD: 64 MB or moreSupported Cards [Windows XP]: NVIDIA GeForce 4 MX or HigherATI Radeon 8500 or HigherINTEL Integrated Graphics 945 or Higher[Windows Vista]: NVIDIA GeForce 7 Series or HigherATI Radeon X1600 Series or HigherINTEL Integrated Graphics X3000 or HigherSOUND CARD: DirectX 9.0c compatible sound cardElementsThere are 5 types of element: Cute, Party, Genious, Goth, Food.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21096">Animal Crossing: City Folk</game><game id="20581">The Sims 3</game><game id="21133">Six Flags Fun Park</game><game id="9238">Animal Crossing: Wild World</game><game id="12893">Animal Crossing</game><game id="25121">Spore Creature Keeper</game><game id="14043">The Sims: Bustin' Out</game><game id="26085">MySims Agents</game><game id="25026">MySims Racing</game><game id="24354">Magician’s Quest: Mysterious Times</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2243860-box_mysims.png</image></root>