<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7723</id><name>Grand Prix 4</name><description>OverviewGrand Prix 4 is the fourth game in the "Geoff Crammond Grand Prix" series and currently it is the last version of the game. The game originally developed for the PC featured a heavily revised graphics engine and updated physics including wet weather driving that even today is considered some of the best to ever feature in a motorsport simulation. An Xbox version was put into development but was cancelled in October 2002 while nearing completion. The game represents the 2001 FIA Formula 1 World Championship and holds an official FIA license.GameplayChampionship Season - This is a recreation of the 2001 Formula 1 season.  The player is able to participate in practice, qualifying and race sessions for each grand prix event.  Single Race -  The player is able to participate in practice, qualification, and a single race on a chosen circuit.  Quick Race - A quick race set up by yourself on any track in the game.Quicklaps - A time trial mode where multiple players can compete to see who is the fastest around the selected track  Multiplayer -  Is played in either hotseat mode on a single machine (players take it in turns to race) or over LAN. Internet gameplay was not possible, due to licensing restrictions. Teams and DriversFerrariMichael SchumacherRubens BarrichelloMcLaren MercedesMika HakkinenDavid CoulthardWilliams BMWJuan Pablo MontoyaRalf SchumacherBenetton RenaultGiancarlo FisichellaJenson ButtonBAR HondaOlivier PanisJacques VillenuevJordan HondaJarno TrulliHeinz-Harald FrentzenArrows AsiatechJos VerstappenEnrique BernoldiSauber PetronasNick HeidfeldKimi RaikkonenJaguarEddie IrvinePedro de la RosaMinardi EuropeanAlex YoongFernando AlonsoProst AcerJean AlesiThomas EngeTrack ListAustralia - MelbourneMalaysia - SepangBrazil - InterlagosSan Marino - ImolaSpain - CatalunyaAustria - A1-RingMonaco - Monte-CarloCanada - MontrealEurope - NurburgringFrance - Magny-CoursGreat Britain - SilverstoneGermany - HockenheimHungary - HungaroringBelgium - Spa-FrancorchampsItaly - MonzaUnited States of America - IndianapolisJapan - SuzukaSystem RequirementsWindows 98,ME, 2000, XP  Intel Pentium 2 400MHz  64MB ram  Direct X 8.1 video and sound card  500mb hard disk space  </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11033">Official Formula One Racing</game><game id="16220">GTR: FIA GT Racing Game</game><game id="14858">GTR 2: FIA GT Racing Game</game><game id="5890">CART Precision Racing</game><game id="20130">rFactor</game><game id="22194">F1 Career Challenge</game><game id="8360">F1 World Championship Edition</game><game id="23517">GTR Evolution</game><game id="14919">Grand Prix Challenge</game><game id="34542">F1 2011</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3699/679521-grand_prix_4_game_cover.jpg</image></root>