<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7730</id><name>Team Buddies</name><description>Overview In Team Buddies you play through campaign mode as any of the 8 different teams. Each team are a different colour but have no different specialities to other teams. The teams you can play as are, red, blue, green, yellow, pink, purple, orange and brown. The game is an RTS game with a twist. You control one buddy and give out orders to your team. Your team consists of 4 buddies including yourself. Building team mates and weapons is very simple, you don't need any resources except for crates. Each stage has 1 or more crate drop points. Crates constantly drop here so you can take them back to base to build stuff.  At your base is a 2 x 2 x 2 stacking grid. You can put crates on the grid in different combinations to get different weapons. All the crates are red except for some, which are blue, these are called super crates, if you add a super crate to any combination it makes you’re weapon a super weapon.  If your base is destroyed, your stacking grid can no longer be used, meaning you can't build any buddies or any weapons or any vehicles. One of the objective in the game would be to destroy your enemies base before they destroy yours giving you a huge advantage.  Some single player missions start you off at a disadvantage, either giving you limited crates to build with, meaning you have to think of how to use them in the best way, or try and steal your opponents crates. Some of the boss battles destroy your base right at the start you you have no weapons to begin with.  Plot  Buddy Land is a surprisingly peaceful land. All the buddies were friendly and happy. Until one day, something came out of the sky and blocked the sun, the buddies called it The Great Eclipse, this eclipse started dropping crates. The buddies kicked them open to find weapons, and before you knew it they had set themselves into coloured teams and started a full blown war.  The single player campaign sees you controlling one of the coloured teams, of your choices and playing missions from 8 different worlds. As you progress you unlock more weapons to make through crates, and even new buddies to make like ninja and cyborg buddies.  Multiplayer  Being an RTS, Team Buddies strong point is it's multiplayer games. You can play with up to 3 friends, each controlling a team and beating the hell out of each other's buddies. There is no option for co-op battles, you can't have 4 players each controlling 1 buddy of the team which is a real shame.     There are 4 different multiplayer match types:  Death Match  Quite simply out smart your opponent our rush in with all guns blazing and wipe out all the buddies off each teams to be the last buddy standing. There is always a time limit on this match which if you don't win by the time the timer hits zero, you automatically lose. You can choose which weapon set you use as well. Depending on what weapon set is chosen, different weapons will be created through crate combinations.  In some maps mega crates are dropped when something is triggered. These mega crates are hard to find but if you do, your in luck, the contain either a mega vehicle or a mega gun. These weapons can normally only be found in mega crates. In single player, mega crates allow you to use weapons from the next worlds weapon set.   DominationThe key to domination is to be the team with the most points when the timer runs out. The map has lots of relics that when you touch them, they turn your teams colour, after 5 seconds of it being your colour, you win 5 points. You can win by getting the set limit off points or having the most points when the timer runs out. If you lose all your buddies in this mode you will respond with a basic weapon. Even if your base is destroyed you will re spawn but can't build, this way your team always has a chance of victory. Capture  Capture is similar to CTF in many other games. Each team has an animal in their pen, could be a dog, or a pig, or anything else. You must capture your opponent animal and bring it you’re pen, if you bring their animal to your pen while your animal is still their, you score 15 points. If your animal isn't there, you score 10 points. First team to score the set amount of points, or most points when timer runs out wins. The same rules apply as they do in domination, if your team is wiped out, you will still re spawn.   Bomball  Bomball is like American football, you have a team of 3 buddies, a bomb spawns in the centre of the stage. Each team has a goal which consists of two goal posts and an explosion area. You must carry the bomb and throw it or drop it onto the opponents explosion area, if it goes through the goal post you score 5 points, and an additional 7 points if it explodes in the explosion area. Your team always re spawn with basic weapons, some levels have better weapons that can be found in the map. To win you must get the most points before the timer runs out or get the set points to win.    Crate Formations  Using the stacking pad, you can stack crates on it to create weapons and buddies. Below are all the different combinations, the weapon you get either depends on what worlds your in during single player or what weapon set you have chosen for multiplier matches: Light weapons (One crate) Uzi 9mmShotgunPocket RocketFireballIce GunTazarPocket MissileLaser Rifle Grenades (Two crates horizontally) GrenadesTime BombNapalm GrenadeCluster GrenadeIce GrenadeScatter BombLighting GrenadeDam BusterAnkh Heavy Weapon(Four crates horizontally) BazookaGatling GunFlamethrower4-Pack RocketPower Orb Gun4-Pack MissileLightning GunPulse RifleArmageddon Barrel Buddies (Two crates or four crates vertically) Infantry: Basic HP and moves.Commando: More HP than Infantry, moves faster.Medic: Can heal team mates and inflate enemies and has regenerating HP.Ninja: Very fast, equipped with Ninja sword, can cut down trees and cut blocks stacked on enemies stacking pads.Cyborg: High defence, can not be squashed by vehicles and can damaged vehicles with his melee attack.Stealthy: Can turn invisible, will de cloak if the player shoots a gun or steps in water. While invisible their melee attack will steal their opponents weapons.Super: Can glide while jumping, and have a powerful melee attack, can not equip weapons or get in vehicles. Vehicles (Eight crates) TankHelicopterAircraftBikesJeepMechwalkerUFO  </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1476/192112-team_buddies_pal.jpg</image></root>