<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7756</id><name>Star Trek: Armada</name><description>OverviewStar Trek: Armada is a real-time strategy game set in the Next Generation version of the Star Trek universe. It is similar in gameplay to Homeworld minus any of the 4X elements. The story begins shortly after the end of the dominion war with Captain Picard and the crew of the U.S.S. Enterprise protecting an under-construction outpost from dominion attack. During the attack a wormhole opens depositing two Borg spheres and a federation (U.S.S. Premonition) ship. After saving the federation ship from Borg attack, the captain (Thaddeus Demming) hails the Enterprise revealing that it is from the future and has come back to stop a Borg invasion. Thus ensues a whirlwind journey across multiple campaigns (and playable races) involving a Klingon Civil War instigated by the Romulans and a conflict between the Borg and the Romulans over stable omega particles.GameplayStar Trek: Armada is a surprisingly deep RTS with multiple systems that provide for some interesting scenario. Starships in Armada have multiple HP meters, one for shields, hull integrity, and one for weapons/ship systems. It also has a crew that can board other ships and take out the crew of the opposing ship. If one ship loses it's crew it becomes a derelict vessel that can be claimed and repaired. This leads to many different tactical situations in which you may not want to destroy a vessel, but if you don't have enough crew to capture it the enemy can retake and repair their vessel. Bases can also be captured in this manner.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13062">StarCraft</game><game id="9115">Sins of a Solar Empire</game><game id="17353">Star Wars: Force Commander</game><game id="11796">Star Trek: Armada II</game><game id="11590">Homeworld</game><game id="7070">Conquest: Frontier Wars</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2423341-armada_pc.jpg</image></root>