<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7777</id><name>Juiced</name><description> Juiced is a racing game produced and published by     THQ and   Juice Games. The game was released on the PS2, PC, and the original Xbox. Juiced is a racing game set in the fictional city of Angel City. You play as a nameless street racer trying to make a name for themselves.   Initial ProblemsOriginally, Juiced was owned by Acclaim. However, in 2004, Acclaim went bankrupt, and the future of the franchise was uncertain. The game was originally intended to release in 2004, but due to the setback, it was pushed back to 2005. THQ    Honda NSX at night      bought the rights to the franchise, and altered the game, pushing the release further back into 2005.  StoryYou take on the role of playing as a nameless street racer. You arrive in Angel City planning to become the number one street racer in the city. Initially, you meet a man called TK. TK is the leader of another team in the city, and he lets you borrow one of his cars for an initial race against him. After you complete this race, the rest of the game properly opens up and you are allowed to properly continue through the story.  The original Juiced arguably has the toughest story of any of the games in the franchise, due to the fact that you have to pay for any damage caused to your car, and damage prices are generally extremely high. To complete the story, you must earn the full 1000 respect from each team, and maintain all of the teams at 1000 respect to complete the game.   GameplayGameplay in Juiced is based around a calendar system (this system was reused in        Juiced Eliminator). Events are scheduled to occur on certain days and then you have the choice of partaking or not showing up at the event. There are several different racing teams who appear in Angel City, and each team has their own niche that will make earning their respect much easier.    Two modified Skylines     As you progress through the game, you will earn money that you can use to purchase new cars or upgrade currently owned ones. Generally, the 'best' cars are AWD, as they are the easiest to control, and they can be upgraded to reach extremely high speeds. The in-game system is arguably inspired by Need for Speed: Underground as it features some of the same elements, such as closed off city streets. There are several different forms of racing events in the game, and these are:   Circuit: Circuit races are just that. There is a fixed circuit with several laps, and you are challenged to win the race. The first person to complete all the laps and pass the finish line is the winner.    Point to Point: These events are similar to circuits, though they are not as fixed. You are given a route through the city and are told to reach the end first. The difference between Point to Point and Circuit races are that PtP events have no laps.     Skyline with custom paintjob   Drag: Drag races, or Sprint races as they are called in-game, are events where several cars line up along a straight. They are then challenged to cross the line first, which is generally one mile away. In Juiced these races are much easier by turning up with an AWD car, such as the Mitsubishi Lancer.   Showoff: Showoff events are events where you have a fixed amount of time, and are challenged to earn a certain number of points through performing tricks and stunts. An example of the stunts you are encouraged to do are 180-degree spins, and J-Turns.   All of these events are carried over from the original 'Juiced' into Juiced Eliminator.  Teams in-game Team LeaderTeam NameTeam Respects T.K Urban Maulerz Circuit Racing Biggi AWB Point to Point Racing Sue Yen Vixens  Showoff Racing Maria The Wild Cats Crew Racing Jack Walker  Omega Tau Best Car Melody  Public Chaos Car Collection Poppa Zee The Lordz Money Gambling Carlos  Legion  Pink Slip Racing Soundtrack  Beans - "Down by Law"    Bug Kann  The Plastic Jam - "Made in Two Minutes"    Dub Pistols - "Architect"  Every Move a Picture - "Signs Of Life"    The Exies - "What You Deserve"    Gat Decor - "Passion"   Guru -  "Cave In"   Hybrid - "Finished Symphony"    Ils - "6 Space (Next Level)"    Jonny L - "Hurt You So"    Kasabian - "Club Foot"    The Koreans - "How Does It Feel"    Lee Coombs, Dylan Rhymes - "Allright All Night"    Lee Coombs, Christian J. - "Dubhead"    Lemon Jelly - "Come Down On Me"    Moving Units - "Between Us and Them"    Paul Oakenfold - "Ready Steady Go"  Roni Size featuring Fallacy - "The Streets"    Shapeshifters - "Back to Basics"    Stereo 8 - "Flipmode"    Talib Kweli - "We Got The Beat"    TV on the Radio - "The New Health Rock"    Way Out West - "Killa"    Wordsworth - "Right Now"    Xzibit featuring Krondon - "Klack"  Acclaim LossesWhen Acclaim filed for bankruptcy, the company held an auction to sell off anything of valu e. Many of the original Juiced promotional posters were destroyed, though a few of them made it out. Some of them were  auctioned on eBay in the US in early 2007. None of the original copies of the Juiced game are known to exist, though some illegal copies have been         sold, supposedly.</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8844">Need for Speed: Carbon</game><game id="9927">SRS: Street Racing Syndicate</game><game id="20741">Need for Speed: Undercover</game><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="20919">Ford Racing: Off Road</game><game id="7431">Ford Racing</game><game id="12950">Gran Turismo 3 A-Spec</game><game id="12976">Need for Speed: Most Wanted</game><game id="18095">Need for Speed: ProStreet</game><game id="9651">Need for Speed Underground 2</game><game id="12254">Need for Speed Underground</game><game id="5977">Need for Speed III: Hot Pursuit</game><game id="8831">Need for Speed: Porsche Unleashed</game><game id="12395">Need for Speed: Hot Pursuit 2</game><game id="453">Need for Speed: High Stakes</game><game id="18021">Need for Speed: Carbon - Own the City</game><game id="367">Need for Speed II</game><game id="8437">TOCA 2: Touring Car Challenge</game><game id="531">TOCA Race Driver 2</game><game id="5869">TOCA Touring Car Championship</game><game id="13734">TOCA Race Driver 3</game><game id="17872">TOCA Race Driver 3 Challenge</game><game id="20597">Gran Turismo 5 Prologue</game><game id="2416">Gran Turismo</game><game id="17784">Gran Turismo 4</game><game id="8100">Gran Turismo 2</game><game id="21297">Gran Turismo HD</game><game id="7482">Gran Turismo Concept: 2001 Tokyo</game><game id="21390">Gran Turismo Concept: 2002 Tokyo-Seoul</game><game id="7313">Gran Turismo Concept: 2002 Tokyo-Geneva</game><game id="13895">Gran Turismo 4: Prologue</game><game id="20927">Midnight Club: Los Angeles</game><game id="5875">Midnight Club 3: DUB Edition</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="20418">Midnight Club II</game><game id="21114">Midnight Club: Los Angeles Remix</game><game id="19809">Project Gotham Racing 3</game><game id="2279">Project Gotham Racing 2</game><game id="941">Project Gotham Racing</game><game id="6499">RalliSport Challenge 2</game><game id="8779">Sega GT 2002</game><game id="14428">Sega GT Online</game><game id="15965">Sega GT</game><game id="20858">NASCAR 09</game><game id="11055">NASCAR 08</game><game id="5856">NASCAR Racing 2003 Season</game><game id="20038">NASCAR: Dirt to Daytona</game><game id="18428">NASCAR Thunder 2004</game><game id="21724">NASCAR Racing 2002 Season</game><game id="5648">Burnout Paradise</game><game id="357">Burnout 3: Takedown</game><game id="16492">Burnout Revenge</game><game id="4970">Burnout Legends</game><game id="10149">Burnout: Championship Drag Racing</game><game id="5881">Forza Motorsport 2</game><game id="17599">Forza Motorsport</game><game id="11625">Ridge Racer DS</game><game id="10370">Street Legal</game><game id="7007">Tokyo Xtreme Racer</game><game id="24995">Forza Motorsport 3</game><game id="21310">Juiced: Eliminator</game><game id="1591">Need for Speed Underground: Rivals</game><game id="17220">Top Gear RPM Tuning</game><game id="1321">L. A. Rush</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1803135-box_juiced.png</image></root>