<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7792</id><name>Dead or Alive 4</name><description>OverviewDead or Alive 4 is a 3D fighting game developed by Team Ninja and published by Tecmo for the Xbox 360 on December 29, 2005. It is the fourth official fighting game installment in the Dead or Alive franchise. Along with tweaks to the fighting engine, the game includes expanded online modes (known as DOA Online) and an expanded story involving the battle between the Mugen Tenshin ninja clan (in their quest for vengeance) and DOATEC (taken control by fighter/opera singer Helena).Along with the standard cast of characters from previous installments, the game introduces three new playable characters: Kokoro (a young Japanese geisha in training), Eliot (a British high school student and apprentice of Gen Fu), and Lisa (an American Lucha Libre wrestler introduced in Dead or Alive Xtreme Beach Volleyball). A new boss, Kasumi clone Alpha-152, appears as the final boss for most characters in Story Mode. Dead or Alive 4 also includes a secret crossover with the Halo franchise, including playable guest character SPARTAN-458 (a SPARTAN-II soldier in MJOLNIR Armor temporarily transported through time) and the Nassaru Orbital Station stage (a space station orbitting Earth, featuring docked vehicles and architecture from the franchise), both of which are exclusive to the game.Story ModeThe CG Endings provide an insight on character backgroundsDead or Alive 4's story mode delivers different story lines depending on the character chosen during the character select screen. Players will fight their way through eight stages, viewing in-engine cutscenes and participating in event fights specific to the chosen character. Upon completing the final stage, players will be presented with a CG ending movie pertaining to their character. These ending cinematics can range from humorous to incredibly serious, specifically when dealing with the main storyline involving the Mugen Tenshin Clan and DOATEC.The final challenge presented to a character at the end of a character's story mode differs from character to character. The main final boss of Dead or Alive 4 is Alpha-152, the evolved form of the Kasumi Alpha clone from Dead or Alive 2. However, due to the fact that not all character stories involve DOATEC, not all characters will fight Alpha-152 as their end boss. Hitomi will fight Ein, Eliot will fight Gen-Fu , Kokoro will fight Helena and Tina Armstrong will fight Bass Armstrong.PlotWhile most stories are independent to the character of choice, the story lines of Ayane, Kasumi, Hayate, Hayabusa, Christie and Helena are all linked together to create the main story arc pertaining to the Mugen Tenshin clan's quest for vengeance and to seek the destruction of DOATEC due to their evil experiments on Mugen Tenshin clan members. These experiments have ranged from Ayane's foster father Genra, all the way to the Kasumi Alpha clone.The game ends with Helena Douglas self-destructing the DOATEC headquarters, resulting in success for the Mugen Tenshin clan.CharactersDead or Alive 4 consists of 16 stock characters, 5 unlockable characters, and 1 non-playable character.Stock CharactersKasumiA Kunoichi's DestinyFighting Style: NinjutsuNationality: JapaneseGender: FemaleOccupation: Exiled NinjaRyu HayabusaThe Singular Super-NinjaFighting Style: Hayabusa Clan NinjutsuNationality: JapaneseGender: MaleOccupation: Antique Shop OwnerKokoroThe Ba Ji DancerFighting Style: Ba Ji QuanNationality: JapaneseGender: FemaleOccupation: Apprentice GeishaHitomiThe Fist of InnocenceFighting Style: KarateNationality: GermanGender: FemaleOccupation: High School StudentBrad WongThe Drunken MasterFighting Style: Zui Ba Xian QuanNationality: ChineseGender: MaleOccupation: UnemployedEliotThe Immovable ApprenticeFighting Style: Xing Yi QuanNationality: BritishGender: MaleOccupation: High School StudentBass ArmstrongKing of the RingFighting Style: Pro WrestlingNationality: AmericanGender: MaleOccupation: Pro WrestlerZackThe Crazy ClimberFighting Style: Muay Thai (Self-Taught)Nationality: AmericanGender: MaleOccupation: DJJann LeeA Scorching SoulFighting Style: Jeet Kune DoNationality: ChineseGender: MaleOccupation: BouncerLei FangTai Ji Quan GeniusFighting Style: Tai Ji QuanNationality: ChineseGender: FemaleOccupation: College StudentTina ArmstrongThe SuperstarFighting Style: Pro WrestlingNationality: AmericanGender: FemaleOccupation: Pro WrestlerLa Mariposa (Lisa)SupernovaFighting Style: Lucha LibreNationality: AmericanGender: FemaleOccupation: LuchadoraBaymanThe Assassin of SteelFighting Style: Commando SamboNationality: RussianGender: MaleOccupation: AssassinChristieBlood-Soaked HandsFighting Style: She QuanNationality: BritishGender: FemaleOccupation: AssassinAyaneA Kunoichi's ImpulseFighting Style: Mugen Tenshin Clan Ninjutsu Hajin Mon SectNationality: JapaneseGender: FemaleOccupation: KunoichiHayateThe Wind of the HeavensFighting Style: Mugen Tenshin Clan Ninjutsu Tenjin Mon SectNationality: JapaneseGender: MaleOccupation: NinjaUnlockable CharactersEinGen-FuHelenaLeonSpartan-458 (Nicole)TenguNon-Playable CharactersAlpha 152The Devil of Misguided ScienceFighting Style: UnknownNationality: UnknownGender : UnknownOccupation: UnknownGameplayThe game consists of many different game modes in which the user can play in Singleplayer.Story ModeStory Mode allows the user to advance the characters throughout their respected stories unlocking their various endings. Each match consists of one round with unlimited time.Time AttackRyu Hayabusa and Spartan-458 fight it outTime Attack is very similar to Story mode except it removes the cutscenes and switches up your opponents. The main goal of time attack is to beat it in the fastest time possible. Each match consists of multiple rounds, the first person to two wins. Each round lasts 1 minute.SurvivalSurvival is much like a mini game. The main goal is to fight off a never ending stream of opponents for as long as you can. Each round has a time limit of 1 minutes. You collect points by performing various combos, counters, hold, etc. You also receive points for picking up items that defeated opponents drop. At the defeat of each opponent you regain half of you max health.Team BattleTeam Battle is another mini game added in. You create a team of up to seven people and face off against a CPU team for dominance. Each round last for 40 seconds. Once you are defeated another of your team members is subbed in. The first person to defeat everyone on the other team wins.VersusVersus is just what you think it would be. You select a character and face off against a CPU of your choice. It is a multiple round match, first to two wins, each round lasting 40 seconds.SparringSparring is also exactly what you would imagine. Sparring allows the used to practice combos on a non attacking CPU. There are no round time limits and no health so these matches can last as long as you would like.Online ModeThe online mode consists of 6 different gametypes and has a unique ranking system that will have players playing for hours and hours. Rooms can carry up to 16 players and players can choose to tag up with others in the room making 4 players playing one match at once. The ranking system assigns letter grades for a certain amount of points earned, letter grades range from F- to A S, and SS. Each match a player wins will award points, 50 being the lowest and 150 being the highest. If a player has a win streak of 1, 10 more points will be awarded, it will continue to add 10 points for each win until they reach 20 wins, then they will stay at 200 additional points per win until a loss is obtained. If a player loses to a player with a lower rank the higher player will lose handicap points that can end up costing 1000 points, the amount of points lost to a lower rank depends on the range of points between each player. Only players that are skillful will be able to reach the highest rank, the rank system really identifies a players skill.Lobby and AvatarsThere are over 100 customizable avatars to choose from which can be bought from the Zack Shop that can be used anywhere in the online mode. Players join rooms and start out in the lobby, it can be confusing at first but players will get used to manually joining the match. The lobby supports keyboard chat and has a gigantic TV where players can watch each match that players in the room are currently playing. The avatars have 8 different functions that are controlled with the right analogue stick and perform different actions and emotions.Winner StaysThe player that has won the last match will continue playing the other players in the room until a loss is obtained.Loser StaysThe player that has lost the last match will continue playing the other players in the room until a loss is obtained.KumiteThe player with the crown (Host) will play the other players in the room regardless of win or loss.Team BattleTeams can be formed in any sum up to 16 players to verse each other, one player will fight until all health points are lost and the next player on the team will fight until one team is eliminated.SurvivalThe player with the crown (Host) will play the other players in the lineup during one whole match, the players in the line will be able to continuously choose a character until the host has been defeated. The host regains health for each player defeated.TournamentAll players in the room will be matched up to fight against others until the last player stands.StagesThe Dead or Alive series has always had multi tiered stages since Dead or Alive 2. These stages are very interactive; you can knock your opponents over railings, off buildings, through glass, into traffic and more.The interactive stages are only in singles battles, as Tag battles are restricted to arenas with Danger Zone. A change in Dead or Alive 4 was that a player can no longer be knocked out from an interactive event (ex: if you have no health after being smashed through a window, you will not be knocked out until your opponent hits you) as opposed to the other games in the series.Gambler's ParadiseGambler's ParadiseThis stage is set on a Las Vegas style street. You can hit your opponent into an electric sign and you can also get hit by moving vehicles. This is useful for chaining combos and doing great damage. Not to mention, it's entertaining.Experimental PlaygroundExperimental PlaygroundA strange stage set in a beach-like area. There are Dinosaurs (!!) in this stage and you can knock your opponent over them or into them.Kyoto in BloomKokoro in "Kyoto in Bloom" 's daytime stage.As the title suggests, it's based on the real life city of Kyoto, Japan. This is supposedly Kokoro's home. There are cherry blossom trees and beautiful petals in the air. Can be played in Day or Night time.Nassu StationNassu StationTeam Ninja's association with Bungie ended up with a Spartan (Nicole) as a playable character and a Halo themed stage. This is one of the only stages to have it's own theme. The stage is decorated with Banshees and other Halo themed decorations.The Crash ClubA flashy nightclub setting with danger zone (electric walls and floor) and players of Dead or Alive 2 will find this stage to be a treat. In the background, remixed versions of Dead or Alive 2 character themes suited for the nightclub setting. Also for play in Tag mode.DOATEC Great HallTaking place in no other than the DOATEC building, this is where most of the Story Mode showdowns occur. This stage has breakable glass and stairs to throw your opponent down.DWA ColiseumDWA ColiseumThe setting for Survival Mode and Tina's wrestling ring, the DOA Coliseum is a very flashy stage featuring it's own System Voice (a energetic announcer) and explosive ropes (which can be toggled) along with a screaming crowd.Biolab CoreBiolab CoreThe room where Alpha 152 is fought. It contains pods and an explosive floor that deals massive damage when somebody is slammed on it.Waterfall ValleyWaterfall ValleyA small, wood bridge that sits over a beautiful waterfall and river. Players start on the top of the bridge and can knock opponents off the bridge into the water.Tritower HeliportAn arena style stage with electric barriers that deal big damage in combos. This stage is next to a helipad and is used in Tag matches.TatamiA stage designed for sparring. This stage has a floor.. and that's it. There are no obstacles, different levels or anything at all. The background is pitch black. This stage can only be unlocked by completing all the training sets for all characters.Seaside MarketSeaside MarketAs the name suggests, this stage is a market at a seaside. You can hit your opponent into street vendors and knock your opponent down a flight of stairs or over a barrier. They both lead to the beach where you can fight in the sand and partially in the water.Ninja HideoutNinja HideoutA Dojo-type stage with secret doors and breakable objects. Players can hit each other through secret sliding doors and off a balcony into a different area with a fire place.Savannah SafariA large grass field with animals that can interfere during a match. Animals can hit other players that can lead into combos.Temple on the MountainTemple on the MountainA mountain temple where there are tons of stairs to send your opponent down. It's also possible to hit your opponent through a wall into a building.UnlockablesDead or Alive 4 has a vast array of unlockables that range from costumes to stages. There are over 40 total costumes to unlock and 2 stages to unlock.It's possible to unlock characters in two ways:Completing the story modes of a character using different costumes each time.Completing Time Attack using a character multiple times to unlock them.There are 6 unlockable characters in Dead or Alive 4.CharacterHow to UnlockEinComplete Story Mode as HitomiGen FuComplete Story Mode as EliotLeonComplete Story Mode as ZackHelenaComplete Story Mode with all charactersSpartan - 458 (Nicole)Complete Story Mode as HelenaTenguComplete Time Attack for all characters.There are also various costumes to unlock for all characters.CharacterUnlockable CostumesKasumi5Kokoro5Hitomi6Helena3Lei Fang5Tina3Lisa3Ayane4Christie2Spartan-4585Ryu Hayabusa2Eliot2Brad Wong1Bayman1Bass Armstrong2Zack2Jann Lee2Hayate2Ein2Gen Fu2Leon2Xbox 360 Hard Drive InstallationDead or Alive 4 requires 6.8GB of space to install on a Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4891">Virtua Fighter 4: Evolution</game><game id="41">Virtua Fighter 2</game><game id="707">Virtua Fighter 5</game><game id="15584">Virtua Fighter</game><game id="11606">Tekken: Dark Resurrection</game><game id="10081">Tekken</game><game id="10162">Tekken Tag Tournament</game><game id="10387">Tekken 2</game><game id="11189">Tekken 3</game><game id="14684">Tekken 4</game><game id="19766">Virtua Fighter 3</game><game id="4313">Virtua Fighter 4</game><game id="21375">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja 3</game><game id="20689">Tekken 6</game><game id="2895">Battle Arena Toshinden 3</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="12635">Rumble Roses XX</game><game id="18086">Rumble Roses</game><game id="19043">Fighters Megamix</game><game id="12411">Soulcalibur</game><game id="11822">Soulcalibur II</game><game id="9855">Soulcalibur III</game><game id="11843">Mortal Kombat: Armageddon</game><game id="15234">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai 2</game><game id="20500">Dragon Ball Z: Burst Limit</game><game id="21195">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai Tenkaichi 3</game><game id="5206">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai</game><game id="690">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai Tenkaichi</game><game id="8789">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai Tenkaichi 2</game><game id="6421">Mortal Kombat 4</game><game id="6588">Mortal Kombat: Deadly Alliance</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="11065">Shaman King: Power of Spirit</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="22895">Godzilla Kaiju Daikessen</game><game id="23007">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja Heroes</game><game id="21007">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja Heroes 2: Phantom Fortress</game><game id="8673">Fighter Destiny 2</game><game id="18251">Deadly Arts</game><game id="21582">Naruto Shippuuden: Gekitou Ninja Taisen! EX 2</game><game id="23833">Tekken 6: Bloodline Rebellion</game><game id="20749">Virtua Fighter 5 R</game><game id="10126">X-Men: Next Dimension</game><game id="18753">Tekken 5</game><game id="28865">Naruto Shippuden: Clash of Ninja Revolution 3</game><game id="32716">Tekken Tag Tournament 2</game><game id="30064">Virtua Fighter 5 Final Showdown</game><game id="37482">Girl Fight</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1894014-box_doa4.png</image></root>