<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7894</id><name>Phoenix Wright: Ace Attorney - Trials and Tribulations</name><description>Overview Phoenix Wright: Ace Attorney - Trials and Tribulations (known as Gyakuten Saiaban 3 in Japan) is the third game in the Ace Attorney series. Players take on the role of Phoenix Wright, a   defense attorney known for taking  on A young Phoenix Wright.seemingly impossible cases. While the game focuses on a  few specific cases, the overarching story of the Phoenix Wright franchise spans the length of  the series, involving obscure characters from large families and intricate webs of lies, plots, and murder. The nature of the series remains generally lighthearted, something that's reinforced by its playful, anime-inspired visual style, but the nature of the crimes committed can be cold and downright disturbing. While the game's legal acumen is highly dubious, its aim seems to be more about producing comedic or stereotypically dramatic courtroom moments. Ace Attorney 3 makes light use of the DS touch screen, allowing the player to examine crime scenes and inspect evidence and character profiles. The top screen is used more for storytelling purposes, displaying various dialogue and conversations between characters. During these sequences  the lower screen becomes a selection menu, displaying a series of questions to ask witnesses and further your investigation in search of evidence to use in defense of your client in each chapter.Characters                                 Phoenix Wright Original Japanese Name: Naruhodō Ryūichi (成歩堂 龍一)  Phoenix Wright is back as he tackles the biggest mysteries he's yet faced!   As a young man Phoenix was inspired by a strong defense attorney who would become his mentor, Mia Fey. Though she saved Phoenix from a murder sentence, the outcome would haunt him. In Trials and Tribulation, the ghosts of Phoenix's past will be exposed and exorcised in the court.                              Godot Original Japanese Name: Godō (ゴドー)   Little is known about the mysterious masked prosecutor called simply Godot, other than that  he loves coffee and seems to have it in for Phoenix for some sin of the past. What could his  connection to Phoenix be that would create such a vendetta?  You'd think a man with white hair and a glowing red mask would be hard to forget.                          Mia Fey Original Japanese Name: Ayasato Chihiro (綾里 千尋)   Though dead, Mia Fey yet has a part to play. One of her biggest  mysteries, an unsolved case, will come back to haunt Phoenix, and the  player will assume control of Mia in flashback sequences. How much does  her past have to do with Phoenix's problems now?  Not only would her first case cause the loss of a man she loved, but would put her entire family at risk.      Maya Fey Original Japanese Name: Ayasato Mayoi (綾里 真宵)   Maya Fey once again fill the role of Phoenix's trusty sidekick, and her psychic powers prove invaluable once again.                        Pearl Fey Original Japanese Name: Ayasato Harumi (綾里 春美)   Mia and Maya's niece is once again present as her family ties involve her yet again.                     Miles EdgeworthOriginal Japanese Name: Mitsurugi Reiji (御剣 怜侍)   Miles Edgeworth in this game  when Wright is incapable of fulfilling his duties as a defense attorney, and for the first time the player gets the chance of playing the no nonsense prosecutor from a side of the courtroom he never thought he would ever see.He seems to be much more friendly with the  titular character than in the early days of the series.     Franziska Von Karma Original Japanese Name: Karuma Mei (狩魔 冥)   Franziska Von Karma is back to the court, but this time she isn't eyeballing Phoenix or lining him up for her whip. The attorney she's taking a crack at this time is Miles Edgeworth, and she's bound to prove who's better. She seems to be more involved in investigation than anything else,  gathering information for the prosecution while continuing to abuse  Gumshoe.        Winston Payne Original Japanese Name: Auchi Takefumi (亜内 武文)   At one time the meek trial lawyer Winston Payne was once known as known as the "Rookie Killer". It was the fault a young rookie lawyer that caused his personality to recede along with his hair, but it wasn't Phoenix.             The Judge Original Japanese Name: Saibanchō  (裁判長)   Here comes The Judge. He's back again to adjudicate between the prosecution and the defense, but he's mostly along for the ride, as usual. The latest prosecutor Godot seems more in control of this court, but it's still put to the judge to give the final verdict.                  Detective Gumshoe Original Japanese Name: Itonokogiri Keisuke (糸鋸 圭介)     Dick Gumshoe, now seemingly friendly with Phoenix, once again does his  best not to have his salary reduced to nothing as he investigates the  crimes.                 Larry Butz  Original Japanese Name: Yahari Masashi (矢張 政志)    The ever annoying Larry Butz continues to be a bit of a pain in Phoenix's side, though as  usual he proves helpful in the end. Larry is taking on a variety of jobs this time from security worker to artist. As always, a woman is involved, and Larry has to testify to the court.          Dahlia Hawthorne Original Japanese Name: Miyanagi Chinami (美柳 ちなみ)   Dahlia is the subject of Mia Fey's first case, and an acquaintance of  Phoenix. Is it really possible to be as sweet as she seems. She seems like an innocent girl, but there is something  more to this one...         Wendy Oldbag Original Japanese Name: Ōba Kaoru (大場 カオル)   Just when you thought you were free, Wendy Oldbag is back to harass Phoenix Wright in his investigation, and she still has her eyes out of poor Miles Edgeworth. Story This game, as did the original                                     Phoenix Wright and                                     Phoenix Wright: Justice for All, centers around the exploits of Phoenix Wright and the Fey clan.  This time, three of the five cases are linked with an overarching story that covers most of the questions left by the previous games. That includes a look back at Phoenix's younger days (he wasn't always so cool) and the case that led to the disappearance of Mia and Maya's mother, Misty Fey. Also, the plan alluded to by Pearl's mother Morgan in the previous game is set into motion, culminating in a great tragedy for all involved. SoundtrackThe music of Phoenix Wright: Ace Attorney - Trials and Tribulations originally appeared in the form of a one disc compilation. However later printings include a second bonus disc. Gyakuten Saiban 3 OST was composed by Noriyuki Iwadare, Masakazu Sugimori, and Akemi Kimura. It was released on March 31st 2004 in Japan.   Track Listing Disc One (Gyakuten Saiban 3 OST)    Cover Artwork    Gyakuten Saiban 3 - PrologueCourtroom Lounge ~ Neverending OvertureGyakuten Saiban 3 - TrialExamination ~ Moderate 2004Ryuuichi Naruhodou ~ Objection! 2004Examination ~ Allegro 2004Investigation ~ Cross-ExaminationAnnounce the Truth 2004Investigation ~ Cross-Examination / VariationDistant Traces of BeautyGodo - The Fragrance of Dark CoffeeJingle - Can't Turn Back to Everyday LifeSearch ~ Opening 2004'Stolen Reversal'Takabishiya Department StorePolice Cell ~ Elegy of the CapturedMysterious Masked Person ~ Please Listen!I Just Want Your LoveYahari Masashi ~ In the Shadows of the Government'Reversal Recipe'Beauty HermitageThe Igarashi Officers - Inspection War SongWarehouse TigerReminiscence- I Begrudge YouThe First ReversalReminiscence - Hazy Scenery from the BridgeHazakurainTerujotko Ellis ~ Simple MelodySearch ~ Middle Stage 2004Reminiscence - The Bitter Taste of TruthPursuit ~ Cornered 2004Winning! - The Victory Does Not EndGyakuten Saiban 3 - EndArrival Melody / Godo Total Time: 68:03   Disc 2 (Gyakuten Saiban Reversal Bonus Disc) SE - System Version   Bonus Disc Cover SE - Courtroom VersionSE - Psychological Descriptions VersionSE - Character VersionSE - Animal VersionSE - Mechanical VersionMayoi Ryouri ~ Gyakuten Sisters' Theme (Arrange Version)Psycho Lock (Arrange Version)Gyakuten Saiban ~ 2003 Promotion Image Sound TracksGyakuten Saiban 3 ~ Special Blend MixTotal Time: 15:05</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1159">Hotel Dusk: Room 215</game><game id="21826">Defenders of Law Inc: Crime in Willburg</game><game id="9648">King's Quest</game><game id="6049">Sam &amp; Max Save the World</game><game id="20522">Harvey Birdman: Attorney at Law</game><game id="17990">Trace Memory</game><game id="12998">Sherlock Holmes: Consulting Detective</game><game id="18297">Where in Space is Carmen Sandiego? (Deluxe Edition)</game><game id="1182">Sherlock Holmes Consulting Detective: Volume II</game><game id="23075">Ikatan: Ikamono Tantei</game><game id="20529">Insecticide</game><game id="22330">Jake Hunter: Detective Chronicles</game><game id="21807">Unsolved Crimes</game><game id="24237">Again</game><game id="21845">Death Note: Kira Game</game><game id="25340">Tokyo Twilight Busters</game><game id="25446">Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kizuna: Daisankan Rasen</game><game id="25583">Yuzai x Muzai</game><game id="17544">Broken Sword: The Shadow of the Templars</game><game id="21052">Time Hollow</game><game id="25156">Lux-Pain</game><game id="25654">Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kizuna: Daiichikan Tatari</game><game id="25655">Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kizuna: Dainikan Sou</game><game id="21411">Theresia</game><game id="25685">Miami Law</game><game id="26447">Hayarigami: Toshi Densetsu Kaii Jiken</game><game id="24071">So Blonde</game><game id="20145">Sprung</game><game id="28435">Agatha Christie: The ABC Murders</game><game id="29344">Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kizuna: Daiyonkan Kizuna</game><game id="26608">Case Closed: The Mirapolis Investigation</game><game id="30111">Disney Guilty Party</game><game id="40045">Devil's Attorney</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1836594-box_pwaa3.png</image></root>