<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>7907</id><name>Donkey Konga 3: Tabe-houdai! Haru Mogitate 50 Kyoku</name><description>OverviewDonkey Konga 3: Tabe-houdai! Haru Mogitate 50 Kyoku is a music/rhythm game developed and published by Nintendo in Japan for the GameCube in 2005. Donkey Konga 3 is the third in the Donkey Konga series and contains the largest number of songs in the series.GameplayThe gameplay in Donkey Konga 3 is similar to that of the previous games in the series. There is a lane for each player which the notes stream by from the right to the left. On the far most left side of each players lane is a clear outline of a circle, when the notes reach this spot that is when the action must be performed. Sometimes these notes are also extended into a long stretched out note. When these come down the lane the player must repeatedly hit the indicated note until the end of the stretched out note.There are various types of notes that will come down the lane:Yellow Note - The yellow note is filled in on the left half. When this note comes down the lane the player must hit the left side bongo.Red Note - The red note is filled in on the right side half. When this note comes down the lane the player must hit the right side bongo.Pink Note - The Pink note is completely filled in. When the pink note comes down the lane the player must hit both bongos at the same time.Star Burst - The star burst note indicates a clap. When this symbol comes down the lane the player must clap their hands.Gameplay ModesStoryThe progression mode of the game. The story mode can be played either single player or multiplayer with another human player or computer player. There are three different difficulty levels to choose from: Easy, Medium, and Hard. Each of these three difficulty levels can also be played in shuffle mode, which will play the songs with randomized patterns.BattleRock, Paper, ScissorsBattle mode is the two player mode in which both players compete to get the highest score. There are various power-up style items that will scroll by that will hurt the opponents score or help the player who gets them. At the end of the battle mode the two players will play a game of Rock, Paper, Scissors. Whichever player wins the game of Rock, Paper, Scissors will gain 5,000 points to the total.POW Block - If the POW Block is hit close enough for a "great", the opponents score will become 0. If the POW Block is hit for an "Ok" the opponents score will be reduced by 90%. If the player hits the POW Block with a "Bad" or misses it completely then the POW Block will do nothing.Star Fox Cards - When a set of the Star Fox Cards appears for a player there will also be a barrel with the word stop on it. When a stop barrel is hit the player will receive one of the Star Fox Cards. When the barrel is hit the accuracy of the hit will determine the card received. If the three cards are a match then the player will receive a large point bonus.ChallengeIn Challenge Mode the goal is to get through a set number of songs without losing. There are multiple difficulty levels with varying amounts of songs to be played through. As the player progresses through a set the songs will increase in difficulty. The player will receive a small amount of their meter refilled in between songs.FamicomAfter a set amount of gold and silver medals have been obtained in the story mode then Famicom mode is unlocked. Famicom mode contains songs from Nintendo and Namco Famicom games. There is no difficulty choice in Famicom mode. Famicom mode can be played either single player or two player. Famicom mode also supports the shuffle mode.TrialTrial mode is another mode that will be unlocked after a set number of gold or silver medals. In trial mode the player must pay some of the coins earned in the story mode. Once paid a random challenge will be played. While playing in trial mode there are skull barrels that if hit will cause a failure immediately. The prize for completing a trial is a chance to play a memory card matching game. Trial mode can be played either single player or two player. There are three different difficulties that can be chosen in Trial mode: Cheap ($100), Moderate ($200), and Expensive ($300). There are six different trials that can be played.The Star Fox Card Game in ActionPOW - In the POW trial the goal is to hit the POW blocks with a "Great" hit as they scroll by.Tramp - The Tramp trial is basically the Star Fox matching game. Winning this trial will allow the player to play the memory matching game 2 times.Claps - In the Claps trial the goal is to get either 100, 200, or 300 claps during the designated song. Only the clap hits will count towards finishing this trial. A win in Claps will award the player 2 chances at playing the memory card game.Points - In the Points trial the goal is to attain a certain point amount that is set before the song starts. The number shown on the screen will be a single digit number, which is then multiplied by 10,000 to calculate the goal score. If this trial is won then 2 chances at the memory card game are awarded.Beats - The goal in Beats is simple, attain the set number of beats in the song to win.Combo - In the Combo trial the goal is to attain a certain number of hits in succession without missing or getting a bad hit. There are goals of 50, 100, or 150 hit combos depending on the difficulty played.Rhythm BananaThe Banana TreeIn Rhythm Banana mode the player must give the banana tree combo points. Combo points are attained in the story mode by successfully completing combos. Once the player has collected and given the banana tree 100 combos the banana mini game can be played. If the player has given the banana tree 1,000 or more combos then the banana mini game can be played at any time without giving any more bananas.ConcertIn this mode there are blue circles around some of the notes, and if they are hit the player will hear a round of applause. At the end of a song in Concert mode the player will be awarded money based on their performance. In order to play songs in Concert mode the player must have already unlocked them in Story mode.Ad-Lib PlaceAd-Lib Place is the no fail mode of Donkey Konga 3. In Ad-Lib Place the player can play any song, but will get no rewards for doing well.Non Gameplay ModesMuseumMuseum mode is where the player would go in order to see rankings and items unlocked. There are three sub-sections in the museum.Request Rankings - Request Rankings is to see how many times the player has played any given song in any of the modes.Face Collection - This is the location to see what faces have been unlocked for use in the high score screen.Funky News - This is where all the Funky's Tips that have been unlocked can be viewed.Shopping MallThe shopping mall is the place to go for purchasing new items. There are only two sub-menus in the Shopping Mall.Bongo Sounds - Here is where new sounds for the bongos can be purchased. The sounds will play in place of the normal bongo sounds while playing a song.Records - This is where new expert difficulty songs can be purchased.Track ListingHana - By Orange RangeStart (Detective Boy Conan Opening Theme) - By Rine AiuchiRokoroushonGO!!! (Naruto Opening Theme 4) - By FLOWBingo (Classic Children's Song)Aine Kuraine Nahato Majiku - By MozartKochira * Mona’s Pizza - From Wario Ware Twisted!Donkey’s Groove - Donkey Konga 3 ThemeTouch - By Iwasaki YoshimiMezase Pokémon Master - Pokemon Opening ThemeFire Emblem TV Commercial ThemeYodel Tabe HoudaiSuper Mario Bros. Chijou Theme\Balloon Fight ThemeDr. Mario ThemeDonkey Kong ThemeIce Climber ThemeGalaxian ThemeRolling Thunder ThemeDragon Buster ThemeStar Luster ThemeYokai Douchuuki ThemeFamily Circuit ThemeMappy Kids ThemeMetro-Cross ThemeHappy Days - By Ai OtsukaSeishun Kyousou Kyoku (Naruto Opening Theme 5) - By SambomasterRewrite - By Asian Kung-Fu GenerationKore Ga Watashi no Ikiru Michi - By Puffy Ami YumiLa CucarachaThe Entertainer - By Scott JoplinJungle Beat - Donkey Kong Jungle Beat ThemeBanana TengokuCha-la Head Cha-la - Dragonball Z Opening ThemeKatamari on the Rocks - From Katamari DamacyDo, re, mi, fa Daijoubu - Hajimete no Otsukai ThemeMakkensanba IIZelda no Densetsu - From Legend of Zelda Famicom DiskHoshi no Kirby Yume No Izumi No Monogatari - From Kirby's AdventureSuper Mario Bros. Underwater ThemeDonkey Kong Jr. ThemeClu Clu Land ThemeDig Dug ThemeMappy ThemeDig Dug 2 ThemeBattle City ThemePac-Land ThemeFamily Jockey ThemeFinal Lap ThemeValkyrie no Bouken themeBaka Survivor (Bobobo Bobobobo Opening Theme) - By Ulfulsignited (Gundam Seed Opening Theme) - By T.M. RevolutionKimi ni BumpTomorrowWilliam Tell OvertureSuper Smash Brothers DX ThemeStar Fox - From Star Fox AssaultAshita ni Nattara - From Donkey KongOra wa Ninki Mono - Crayon Shin Chan OpeningKite Kite Atashinchi - Atashinchi ending themeIiyudanaDonkey Konga - NES style Donkey Konga ThemeSuper Mario Bros. 3 ThemeParthena no Kagami - From Kid IcarusGalaga ThemeXevious ThemeTower of Druaga ThemeSky Kid ThemeGenpei ToumaDen ThemeWarpmanMappy Land ThemeThe Quest of Ki ThemeBabel No Tou Theme</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21099">Wii Music</game><game id="18157">Um Jammer Lammy</game><game id="10051">PaRappa the Rapper 2</game><game id="25988">Cool Cool Jam</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9446/291455-donkey_konga_3_coverart.png</image></root>