<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8028</id><name>Star Trek: The Next Generation - A Final Unity</name><description>Star Trek: The Next Generation - A Final Unity is an adventure game based on the popular TV series Star Trek: the Next Generation (STTNG). In the game, the player has control over the entire main bridge crew of the Enterprise, both on the ship and during away missions to various planets. Over the course of the game, the Enterprise will visit several planets, in a race with the Romulans and the mysterious Chodak to unravel the galaxy-spanning enigma of the "Unity Device."Gameplay:Aboard the bridge of the U.S.S. EnterpriseWhile on the Enterprise, the player has access to several "duty stations," including navigation, engineering, and tactical. Each station can be either manually controlled or left automated. Each station provides access to a number of ship functions. For example, navigation allows courses to be plotted throughout the galaxy with a surprising amount of freedom given the game's linear plot. In ship-to-ship combat, if the player chooses to manually control the tactical station, a top-down tactical view of the immediate area is presented, with various weapon firing patterns and maneuvers available for the player. Outside of the duty stations, the player can hail other ships, speak with guests on board the enterprise in the captain's ready room, or click on various crew members to have Captain Picard speak with them.When an away team mission begins, the player chooses a group of four crew members out of all available to "beam down," each with his or her own inventory, skills, and conversation options. Certain NPCs will react differently to different away team members, and certain actions can only be completed by individuals with specific skills, so there is a fair amount of strategy involved in selecting away team members. The away missions control like classic Lucasarts-style point-and-click adventures, with similar movement, inventory puzzles, and "pixel hunt" mechanics. Occasionally, simple combat scenarios occur, involving "using" the phaser inventory item on an enemy or object.Story:The game's story begins when the Enterprise encounters a ship full of asylum-seekers fleeing their own race's fleet. Upon granting them asylum, the player learns of their search for a mysterious scroll and an ancient artifact. The stakes grow higher, however, as the initial search intersects with several other major events, including large numbers of Romulan ships fleeing into Federation space, and the emergence of the Chodak, a strange water-breathing race never encountered by humans before.A Final Unity's story is especially notable for its framing. The game is designed to mirror the structure of an episode of Star Trek: The Next Generation - the game begins with a in introductory plot "teaser," followed by opening credits, followed by the main story. The overall impression is that the user is "playing" a particularly long episode of the TV series, with his or her actions affecting how specific scenes play out in meaningful ways. This impression is strengthened by the voice acting, performed by the original television cast.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4031/628842-star_trek_tng_a_final_unity.jpg</image></root>