<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8052</id><name>Pokémon Puzzle League</name><description>OverviewPokémon Puzzle League is a Pokémon-themed version of the Super Nintendo game Panel de Pon, also known as Tetris Attack in North America. The game was originally released for the Nintendo 64 and is currently available as a downloadable Virtual Console title on the Nintendo Wii. The game can be played in standard 2D mode or a 3D mode in which the player can rotate the field. As in Tetris Attack, the goal of the game is to clear blocks from the field by lining up three or more blocks of the same color horizontally or vertically. The game includes several modes of play including a single-player vs. mode against the CPU, a two-player versus mode, and challenge modes including a time attack, puzzle mode, and line-clearing mode.Pokémon Puzzle League is unique among Pokémon games in that it is one of the very few games to use characters originally created for the Pokémon anime series as opposed to the characters actually featured in the games. It also features art and brief animated cinematics from the anime, as well as voice acting from the anime series' English cast.CharactersThe game features fifteen characters that appear in the anime. They all use three Pokémon each.Ash Ketchum - Pikachu, Squirtle, BulbasaurMisty - Horsea, Psyduck, StaryuBrock - Geodude, Vulpix, ZubatTracey Sketchit - Marill, Venonat, ScytherTeam Rocket ( Jessie, James, and Meowth) - Weezing, Arbok, GolbatGary Oak - Nidoran, Growlithe, KrabbyGiovanni - Persian, Sandslash, NidokingRitchie - Sparky ( Pikachu), Zippo ( Charmander), Happy ( Butterfree)Bruno - Onix, Hitmonchan, PrimeapeErika - Tangela, Weepinbell, GloomSabrina - Abra, Hypno, AlakazamBlaine - Arcanine, Charmeleon, MagmarLt. Surge - Raichu, Jolteon, MagnetonKoga - Venomoth, Voltorb, GolbatLorelei - Cloyster, Poliwhirl, DewgongThe final boss, unplayable without the use of a cheat code, is Mewtwo. He uses clone versions of Ash's Pokémon: Pikachu, Squirtle, and Bulbasaur.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="19256">Planet Puzzle League</game><game id="1916">Puyo Puyo</game><game id="21635">Neves</game><game id="13130">Tetris Attack</game><game id="21253">Aurora Feint</game><game id="22787">Wrecking Crew '98</game><game id="20862">Octomania</game><game id="23694">Lumines Supernova</game><game id="10515">Magical Tetris Challenge</game><game id="26918">Puzzlegeddon</game><game id="29126">Arkedo Series - 02 SWAP!</game><game id="1271">Columns Crown</game><game id="29108">Columns II: The Voyage Through Time</game><game id="23375">Gangway Monsters</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/608/222950-pokemonpuzzleleagueboxart.jpg</image></root>