<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8102</id><name>The Bard's Tale</name><description>OverviewThe Bard's Tale is a comedic parody of RPGs. The Bard's Tale is to  Baldur's Gate what Space Balls was to Star Wars. The Bard himself is voiced by  Cary Elwes of The Princess Bride and Robin Hood: Men in Tights fame. The bard is a drunk, womanizing, lazy, musician who has no aspiration of saving the world. His only motivation is coin and cleavage. Another comic element in the game is the narrator (voiced by  Tony Jay) who wishes the bard was a traditional "RPG Hero" instead of the lazy drunk he is.GameplayThe Bard and His Dog, From the Gameplay AngleThe Bard's Tale takes place in a 3D environment but from a top down perspective. It plays closer to an action adventure game like Gauntlet than a traditional RPG. The Bard has Melee and Ranged weapons at his disposal and an interesting Magic system.The magic system is a summon system, where you play songs to summon allies. Some are great fighters, like the Brute, Knight and Mercenaries. Some heal you. One of the most entertaining is the Trap Finder. A hysterical dwarf- like creature who when summoned utters "You need me to find some traps?". He then whistles cheerfully as he walk into the nearest trap and sets if off killing him in the gruesomest ways imaginable. All of the Summoned creatures have developed characters and are some of the most playful parts of the game.The Bard also has a pet dog who follows him throughout the story. The dog guides the player to new areas, and tells the player where to go next.The Summoned Characters.The Knight, Thunder Spider, and ElementalBehemothThe BodyguardBruteCroneElementalEnchantressHealth StealerKnightKnockerLight FairyMercenaryRatRogueThunder SpiderTrap FinderPC RequirementsOS: Windows 2000/XP/VistaProcessor: Pentium 4 2Ghz / AMD AthlonXP 2400Memory: 512MbGraphics: GeForce FX5700 or better / ATI Radeon 9600 or betterDirectX®: 9.0cHard Drive: 6GB of free spaceSound: DirectX 9 Compatible Sound Card</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13091">Baldur's Gate: Dark Alliance</game><game id="13217">Champions of Norrath</game><game id="3661">Shining Force: Neo</game><game id="13087">X-Men: Legends</game><game id="1288">Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Heroes</game><game id="1341">Fallout: Brotherhood of Steel</game><game id="2025">Revenant</game><game id="3264">Fable</game><game id="1119">Diablo II</game><game id="5985">Diablo</game><game id="15589">Diablo II: Lord of Destruction</game><game id="2890">Arkadian Warriors</game><game id="15067">Eric the Unready</game><game id="4426">The Bard's Tale Trilogy</game><game id="10846">Avatar: The Last Airbender</game><game id="23974">Eat Lead: The Return of Matt Hazard</game><game id="10473">The Witcher</game><game id="19627">Armed &amp; Dangerous</game><game id="20238">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion</game><game id="10740">The Elder Scrolls IV: Shivering Isles</game><game id="30393">Hunted: The Demon's Forge</game><game id="32416">DeathSpank: Thongs of Virtue</game><game id="27878">Fable III</game><game id="36425">Frayed Knights: The Skull of S'makh-Daon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1801415-box_bardtale.png</image></root>