<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8108</id><name>Championship Manager Season 97/98</name><description>GameplayPlayable leaguesCM97/98 marked a step forward for this aspect of the game - nine playable nations/league systems, three times more than in the previous version. It was also the first time ever that players could run more than one league concurrently (up to three in this edition). For example, the English, Spanish and Italian leagues would all be simulated and players could manage a club in any of these nations and move between them. It also allowed the user to view results and league tables in these selected leagues, adding to the sense of realism. The full selection of playable leagues was as follows:BelgiumEnglandFranceGermanyHollandItalyPortugalScotlandSpainThis was also the first time in the series that the Portuguese league system had ever been a playable league.TriviaChampionship Manager 97/98 was the top selling PC game of 1997, despite Sports Interactive encouraging game-sharing by not including any CD-protection; The game could be installed on any number of PCs without needing a copy of the CD to play it, which indicates that it was most likely even more popular than it seemed. SI have since said that this move was to gain as much exposure from the CM2 series as possible before the release of the CM3 series.</description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="40">Soccer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11964">Pro Cycling Manager: Season 2006</game><game id="20784">Football Manager 2008</game><game id="17092">Worldwide Soccer Manager 2005</game><game id="6016">Worldwide Soccer Manager 2007</game><game id="5919">The F.A. Premier League Football Manager 2000</game><game id="17090">LMA Manager</game><game id="4728">LMA Manager 2001</game><game id="13450">LMA Manager 2002</game><game id="2237">LMA Manager 2004</game><game id="2004">LMA Manager 2006</game><game id="4715">LMA Manager 2003</game><game id="8249">LMA Professional Manager 2005</game><game id="11938">LMA Manager 2005</game><game id="22092">LMA Manager 2007</game><game id="1586">Total Club Manager 2003</game><game id="15714">Total Club Manager 2005</game><game id="1064">Ultimate Soccer Manager</game><game id="22117">Worldwide Soccer Manager 2006</game><game id="30751">Football Manager 2011</game><game id="6697">Premier Manager Ninety Nine</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/18185/639477-cm9798.jpg</image></root>