<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8121</id><name>The Elder Scrolls III: Bloodmoon</name><description>OverviewBloodmoon is the second expansion pack for Bethesda Softworks' The Elder Scrolls III: Morrowind . The expansion pack was originally released as an expansion for PC, and Bloodmoon is also included in the Morrowind: Game of The Year edition for PC and Xbox.While the first expansion, Tribunal, added the city of Mournhold in a separate instanced worldspace from that of Morrowind, Bloodmoon adds an entire island to the original world map: Solstheim, a cold northern territory. Unlike Vvardenfell, which is mainly populated by the Dunmer (the dark elves), Solstheim is occupied by the Nord race. This is largely due to Solstheim's proximity to the Nord home province of Skyrim.The expansions adds several new things to the game: New enemies, a new joinable guild called the East Empire Company, werewolves, and the possibility to become one, much like the vampires seen in Morrowind. There are new interior environments such as ice caves and burial mounds, and the outdoor environments in Bloodmoon are larger and far more detailed with the added effect of snowfall, which raises the minimum system requirements for the game.Bloodmoon has many side-quests to be undertaken and many more caves discovered through general exploration not related to the main quest of the expansion. Unlike Tribunal, which is meant to be played after the completion of Morrowind’s main quest, Bloodmoon’s main quest is self-contained within the expansion and is not dependent upon the events of the base game.StoryUpon inquiring on rumors with NPCs, the player hears rumors of a fortress on a remote island in the north that is in need of assistance. Further investigation reveals that Fort Frostmoth is suffering from low morale due to a recently introduced dry fort policy and missing weapon shipments. To resolve these problem, the player is sent to a nearby cave to investigate a smuggling ring. Upon returning to the fort, the player finds it in a dire state from a werewolf attack and the captain of the guard, Falx Carius, missing from his chambers.The player is then pointed to the Skaal village to shed light on the matter. After performing several rituals to be initiated as a member of the village, the player then learns of the Bloodmoon Prophecy, a hunt led by a Daedric Prince, Hircine. Eventually the player is captured by werewolves and taken to Hircines' plane of Oblivion where he must compete against three other champions to survive.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows ME/98/XP/2000Processor: 500 MHz Intel Pentium III, Celeron, or AMD AthlonMemory: 256 MBGraphics: 32MB Direct3D Compatible video card with 32-bit color support and DirectX 8.1DirectX®: 8.1Hard Drive: 1GB free hard disk spaceSound: DirectX 8.1 compatible sound card</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3239">Might and Magic VIII: Day of the Destroyer</game><game id="7885">Lands of Lore: Guardians of Destiny</game><game id="8033">Lands of Lore III</game><game id="16507">Lands of Lore: The Throne of Chaos</game><game id="4398">Might and Magic VII: For Blood and Honor</game><game id="15589">Diablo II: Lord of Destruction</game><game id="10637">Baldur's Gate II: Shadows of Amn</game><game id="52">Baldur's Gate</game><game id="6795">Baldur's Gate II: Throne of Bhaal</game><game id="7392">Baldur's Gate: Tales of the Sword Coast</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15693/610615-589642_front_1_.jpg</image></root>