<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8141</id><name>Mega Man 4</name><description>OverviewTitle screen.Mega Man 4 is an                                            NES action platformer released by                                             Capcom on January 8, 1992. While not straying too far from the formula of its predecessors, Mega Man 4 nonetheless introduced some new gameplay features such as the                                           Mega Buster                                          charge shot, an item-dispensing ally named                                         Eddie, and was the first game to feature someone other than                                       Dr. Wily as the initial                                        villain, and a character who didn't turn out to be Wily in disguise.  Mega Man 4 was re-released on the                                      Xbox,                                     PlayStation 2, and                                    Gamecube as a part of the                                   Mega Man Anniversary Collection.PlotFrom Rock to Man. In addition to the plot of the game itself, Mega Man 4's prologue divulges the origin story of                                  Mega Man, told via graphic                                 cutscenes much like                                Ninja Gaiden's. Once a normal housekeeping                               robot named Rock, Mega Man volunteered to be turned into a fighting robot when                              Dr. Wily's wild robots began running amok. After defeating Dr. Wily for the third and seemingly final time, a new problem arises in the form of an evil scientist named                             Dr. Cossack, whose eight robots are making due destruction in Wily's absence. Dr. Light equips Mega Man with a powerful new weapon called the Mega Buster, setting the game into action. Of course, Dr. Cossack was blackmailed by Dr. Wily to do his bidding, as Wily had kidnapped Dr. Cossack's daughter                            Kalinka.                           Proto Man returns Kalinka to Dr. Cossack's side as Dr. Wily curses Mega Man for ruining his mad scheme. The game ends with another showdown at one of Dr. Wily's many castles, but Dr. Wily escapes before Mega Man can truly defeat him.GameplayDANCE, SUCKA. The biggest change to Mega Man 4's gameplay is the new inclusion of the Mega Buster charge shot, which would become a standard feature even in the Mega Man X series. It allows Mega Man to store up a powerful burst that can inflict three units of damage to enemies and even Robot Masters. In fact, it becomes the preferred weapon to use against a few of them. Certain enemies also have a gimmick requiring the use of the Mega Buster to defeat them. Stage Select screenMega Man also keeps all of his previous abilities from Mega Man 3, including the slide and his canine compatriot                          Rush. Additionally, Mega Man can also find two special items called the Wire and                         Balloon hidden in certain stages. The Wire acts like a grappling hook that can launch Mega Man vertically, and the Balloon creates floating platforms nearly identical to Item-1 from Mega Man 2. The inclusion of                        Eddie is a minor addition as the items he dispenses are chosen at random. StagesRobot Master StagesDr. Cossack's mechanical minions consist of a standard group of eight Robot Masters. As usual, Mega Man will gain their weapon powers when he defeats  one. As in, illuminated. DWN-025:       BRIGHT MAN Bright Man's stage evokes a power plant, with enemies that can either turn out and turn on the lights when defeated. Mega Man will also have to make use of robotic grasshoppers to cross dangerous spike floors also guarded by robotic totem poles.   Bright Man can stop time with his Flash Stopper, which can be dangerous if he decides to tackle Mega Man with his body.    DOKI DOKI ROCKMAN DWN-026:        PHARAOH MAN Pharaoh Man's desert tomb consists of sinking quicksand and robotic mummies with heads that aren't wrapped too tight.   Pharaoh Man also takes a page from Mega Man's new book with his charge-up Pharaoh Shot.  Let sleeping bats lie. DWN-027:         DRILL MAN Excavating god-knows-what in the name of science, Drill Man's stage is fairly straightforward until the end, where switches must be used to make an invisible ground appear.   Drill Man himself likes to burrow into the ground and reemerge at Mega Man's feet, then drill-baby-drill him with his Drill Bomb.  This is when the series jumped the hippo. DWN-028:          RING MAN Ring Man calls home amongst a bizarre circus/planetarium crossover. Giant robo-hippos in precarious balanced positions and disappearing platforms juxtapose the playful mood.   Things come full circle with Ring Man and his fast-acting Ring Boomerang, but like many Robot Masters, the true danger comes from how quick Ring Man is and the high amount of damage you will take if you so much as touch him.   Sewer flyin'. DWN-029:           TOAD MAN Taking a page from some turtles, Toad Man's sewer hideout is initially drenched in some pretty heavy precipitation that will push Mega Man back as he jumps. Toad Man himself will shake and shimmy a rain dance to get his Rain Flush mojo moving.   That would be rubbish. DWN-030:            DUST MAN The  humble Dust Man doesn't mind hanging out in a rubbish-themed stage  whose most significant feature is a huge trash compactor that Mega Man  will have to blast his way through. Dust Man's Dust Crusher is used in  tandem with a powerful vacuum that makes him temporarily invulnerable.    Whale wars. DWN-031:             DIVE MAN   Safety takes a dive, Fridays after five in Dive Man's dangerous  aquarium. The rising and falling of the tide can affect the height of  Mega Man's jump as he batttles robotic whales and stingrays. The  submarine-themed Dive Man can both fire his homing Dive Missiles and  pretend he is one as he barrels toward Mega Man.  Dr. WIly COULDN'T be behind this one... DWN-032:              SKULL MAN Skull Man's mountainside dinosaur dig is comprised itself almost entirely of bones. It's not so much scary as it is arduous. His Skull Barrier makes him invincible, but Skull Man can't do anything but stand there while using it. More dangerous is when he deactivates his shield, he'll make a quick sprint towards Mega Man.  Castle Stages  Dr. Cossack's lair of EVIL Russian stereotypes.In addition to the Robot Masters, Mega Man will also have to fight through both Dr. Cossack's and Dr. Wily's castles. This was the first Mega Man game to feature multiple castles, starting a trend subsequently seen in    Mega Man 5 and   Mega Man 6 of a "psyche-out" acting as a thinly-veiled ruse to hide Dr. Wily's involvement.  MusicMega Man 4's music was composed by Capcom employees with the pseudonyms                       Ojalin (Minae Fujii) and                    Bun Bun (Yasuaki Fujita). Yasuaki Fujita had previously composed the music for                  Mega Man 3.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="10152">Bucky O'Hare</game><game id="2866">Super Mario World 2: Yoshi's Island</game><game id="16783">The Krion Conquest</game><game id="4350">Contra</game><game id="4237">Contra 4</game><game id="3016">Contra III: The Alien Wars</game><game id="10299">Super Mario Bros. 3</game><game id="15544">Super Mario Bros.</game><game id="16188">Clash at Demonhead</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2362051-nes_megaman4.jpg</image></root>