<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8146</id><name>The King of Fighters '96</name><description>The King of Fighters '96 is a 2D 3-on-3 fighting game developed and released by                           SNK for the                                           Neo Geo. It is the third installment in the                          King of Fighters franchise, featuring new gameplay mechanics, changes in the character roster, and a new plot involving                         Kyo Kusanagi,                        Iori Yagami, and the power of the demon                       Orochi. (Though it is the second installment in the "Orochi Saga") Unlike the previous King of Fighters games, the tournament is a major international event instead of an unknown, obscure tournament. The tournament is run by                      Chizuru Kagura, who uses it to find and recruit Kyo and Iori in order to stop the Orochi threat.  The character roster underwent some changes in this installment.                     Heidern and                    Takuma Sakazaki retired and were replaced by newcomer                   Leona and                  Yuri Sakazaki. Yuri's missing spot in the Women Fighters Team was replaced by                 Kasumi Todoh from  Art of Fighting 3: The Path of The Warrior. The Rivals Team (             Iori Yagami,             Eiji Kisaragi, and            Billy Kane) was replaced by the Iori Team (Iori Yagami and           Rugal Bernstein's two former assistants:          Mature and         Vice). A new team, the Boss Team, entered the tournament, featuring        Fatal Fury bosses       Geese Howard and      Wolfgang Krauser and     Art of Fighting boss   Mr. Big.  All of the characters received improved graphics in a style that would remain all the way to  King of Fighters XI. The movesets for most of the characters were also changed, where some characters play radically different from the previous installments. Dodging from the previous installments was replaced by a rolling technique, allowing the player to dodge attacks while moving forward or away from their opponent. Players can now also perform a more powerful version of their Super Special Move when the player has 25% on the life gauge remaining or less (as indicated by the gauge flashing red) and has a full power gauge.Characters Japan Team                                                                                                              Kyo Kusanagi                                                                                                            Benimaru Nikaido                                                                                                           Goro Daimon     Fatal Fury Team                                                                                                          Terry Bogard                                                                                                         Andy Bogard                                                                                                        Joe Higashi     Art of Fighting Team                                                                                                       Ryo Sakazaki                                                                                                      Robert Garcia Yuri Sakazaki     Ikari Warriors Team                                                      Leona                                                                                                Ralf Jones                                                                                              Clark SteelPsycho Soldier Team                                                                                                     Athena Asamiya                                                                                                   Sie Kensou                                                                                                  Chin Gentsai Women Fighters Team                                                   Kasumi Todoh                                                 Mai Shiranui                                                King     Korea Team                                                                                           Kim Kaphwan                                                                                          Chang Koehan                                                                                         Choi Bounge Iori Team                                                Iori Yagami                                        Mature Vice Boss Team                                Geese Howard                              Wolfgang Krauser                             Mr. BigOther                             Chizuru Kagura (sub-boss)                           Goenitz (boss)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11156">X-Men vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="7751">Art of Fighting Anthology</game><game id="22362">Street Fighter II': Hyper Fighting</game><game id="18484">Killer Instinct</game><game id="21952">Killer Instinct 2</game><game id="10614">Killer Instinct Gold</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1465983-kof96_box.png</image></root>