<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8210</id><name>Pokémon Gold/Silver</name><description>OverviewThe box art for GoldThe box art for SilverPokémon Gold and Silver were released on October 14, 2000 in North America (November 21, 1999 in Japan and April 6, 2001 in Europe) for the Game Boy Color (although it also supported the Game Boy Pocket and Game Boy). Development was done by Game Freak, publishing by Nintendo, and marketing and licensing from The Pokémon Company.Taking place in the Johto region, the second generation of Pokémon introduced 100 new Pokémon. Besides several unique Pokémon and other minor details, Gold and Silver are identical to each other. However, to collect every single one of the Pokémon, players must trade between not only Gold and Silver, but also the first two games, Pokémon Red and Blue.ReceptionWell-received by critics with an 89% average rating according to Game Rankings, Pokémon Gold and Silver was a critical success. Gold and Silver are regarded as some of the best iterations in the Pokémon franchise, getting a ten out of ten from IGN, and high scores from many other publications. Together, Gold and Silver sold 6.5 million in Japan alone, while sales in North America beat previous sales records, selling 1.4 million copies in the first week of sales.Pokemon Gold silver return as DS Remakes.Pokémon Crystal was later released as an updated version of Gold and Silver. It came out on July 29, 2001 in North America, and was the only Pokémon game to be released exclusively for the Game Boy Color. Despite being largely similar to Gold and Silver, Crystal added many new features, including new series' staples such as the ability to choose the player's gender.A remake of Gold and Silver was developed for the Nintendo DS. Pokémon HeartGold and SoulSilver were released on March 14, 2010 in North America, and on September 12, 2009 in Japan. It is predominately a graphical remake of the game, but it also brings all of Johto's Pokémon into the latest generation of Pokémon (despite all of them being available across many of the later games released). The remakes also have new modern features added from the fourth generation of Pokémon games, new characters, and special functionality with a device called the Pokéwalker.GameplayCyndaquil fights Pidgey; a traditional battle.Set in the Johto Region, Gold/Silver is a traditional role-playing game with gameplay essentially the same as Pokémon Red/Blue and Yellow. There are two different "types" of gameplay. In battles, players have several options. The Pokémon that is in battle can attack the rival Pokémon (be it a wild Pokémon or a trainer Pokémon) with a variety of attacks. The player can also use many items, including healing items, battle items, or Poké Balls (used to catch wild Pokémon, who upon being caught can be used in battle). Players can switch out Pokémon and run away as well.Players can talk with non-playable characters.The main goal of these battles is to get the rival Pokémon to "faint." When all of an opponent's Pokémon have fainted, the battle is won. However, when fighting a wild Pokémon, players can attempt to catch it for further use. Other trainers' Pokémon cannot be caught. After winning a battle, the Pokémon gain experience, and eventually level up. For many Pokémon, when they reach a certain level they evolve into another form of the Pokémon (e.g. Pidgey evolves into Pidgeotto, Totodile evolves into Croconaw). Some Pokémon have special requirements to evolve, such as having specific items equipped, or leveling up during a specific time of day.Each Pokémon has a type, mostly based on nature (e.g. water, grass, fire, earth). Each type has a (or some) strength(s) and weakness(es). These types also affect the Pokémon's statistics, such as, defense, attack power, and speed. Some types are completely immune to another type's attacks. In addition to stat bonuses and immunity, many Pokémon have unique attacks available relating to their type. Gold/Silver were also the first games to introduce dark and steel type Pokémon, thus completing the 17 types of Pokémon that remains the standard in all games in the series since.Overworld gameplay follows Gold, the protagonist of Gold/Silver. He can travel to the various towns of Johto region, along with many other locations. Players can interact with objects and non-playable characters, sometimes relating to the plot. In towns, players have a variety of options, including purchasing items, healing all of the Pokémon in the party (as well as switching out Pokémon), and challenging that city's gym leader. There are many other areas to visit, including caves, forests, and even the ocean. While in the overworld, it is also possible to trigger a random battle with a wild Pokémon.New features of Gold and Silver are numerous. It implements a day and night system that is based on a real-time internal clock. Influenced by this clock are many things, including specific events and what Pokémon appear. With the ability for Pokémon to hold items introduced, many items were created to take advantage of this mechanic, including berries (which can do many things, including boosts to power, healing status effects, and restoring health). Pokégear, a new key item introduced featured a map, watch, radio, and phone, allowing the player to call non-playable characters (and to be called by non-playable characters) and listen to the radio at certain times (according to the real-time clock).Gold and Silver's legendary Pokémon include Raikou, Entei, and Suicune, who are a completely new type of legendary Pokémon. Instead of encountering them at a specific location, they appear randomly around Johto, and will run away occasionally. However, they retain any status effects or damage upon running away.Unique "shiny" Pokémon were added, which were a different color than the regular version of the Pokémon, and extremely rare. The Pokémon types Steel and Dark were added in Gold and Silver. Steel type are strong and have a high defense, while Dark type are powerful against Psychic Pokémon (they are even immune to any Psychic attacks).Breeding was a feature that has stayed since Gold and Silver, allowing players to leave two Pokémon in the day care center for a chance for them to breed. Many species of Pokémon cannot breed, however. The child of the Pokémon will gain whatever moves its father has, while it gets the species of its mother.PlotChikorita, one of the three starter Pokémon.Taking place in the Johto Region, Gold and Silver follows Gold, a young boy for New Bark Town. In the beginning of the game, he moves to New Bark Town and meets Professor Elm, who gives him the choice of one of three starter Pokémon: Cyndaquil, Totodile, or Chikorita. Later, you will run into your rival, Silver, and he will challenge you to your first of many Pokémon battles with him. After the battle, he will flee from you and you will discover that you have just fought against the thief who stole one of Professor Elm's Pokémon. You will also meet Professor Oak, who gives you the Pokédex and the important task of catching all of the Pokémon in the Johto Region.To do so, Gold must battle the eight gym leaders of Johto, each specializing in a particular type of Pokémon. After defeating each of the gym leaders and collecting their badges, Gold must fight the Elite Four and the Champion, and eventually the eight gym leaders of Kanto. In the very end, Gold fights the protagonist of Red and Blue, Red, in the final battle. Along this path, Gold must also battle the remaining members of the organization known as Team Rocket, as they try to re-unite and contact their old boss, Giovanni, to convince him to lead them again.PokédexThe Pokémon Gold/Silver Pokédex starts out as if it were separate from that of Pokémon Red/Blue, however after defeating the elite four, the player gains access to a national Pokédex that allows them to see all of the 'old' Pokémon from the original game. The first 151 Pokémon are as per the Pokémon Red/Blue Pokédex. The remaining Pokémon, those that are new to this game, are listed below.152 ChikoritaChikorita, the new Grass type starter153 Bayleef154 Meganium155 Cyndaquil156 Quilava157 Typhlosion158 Totodile159 Croconaw160 Feraligatr161 Sentret162 Furret163 Hoothoot164 Noctowl165 Ledyba166 Ledian167 Spinarak168 AriadosFeraligatr, the final form of the water-type starter, Totodile.169 Crobat170 Chinchou171 Lanturn172 Pichu173 Cleffa174 Igglybuff175 Togepi176 Togetic177 Natu178 Xatu179 Mareep180 Flaaffy181 Ampharos182 BellossomTyphlosion, the final evolution of the fire-type starter183 Marill184 Azumarill185 Sudowoodo186 Politoed187 Hoppip188 Skiploom189 Jumpluff190 Aipom191 Sunkern192 Sunflora193 Yanma194 Wooper195 Quagsire196 EspeonFurret is an average normal-type Pokémon197 Umbreon198 Murkrow199 Slowking200 Misdreavus201 Unown202 Wobbuffet203 Girafarig204 Pineco205 Forretress206 Dunsparce207 Gligar208 Steelix209 SnubbullAzumarill, an evolved water-type Pokémon210 Granbull211 Qwilfish212 Scizor213 Shuckle214 Heracross215 Sneasel216 Teddiursa217 Ursaring218 Slugma219 Magcargo220 Swinub221 Piloswine222 CorsolaBellossom, a new evolution of an old grass-type Pokémon223 Remoraid224 Octillery225 Delibird226 Mantine227 Skarmory228 Houndour229 Houndoom230 Kingdra231 Phanpy232 Donphan233 Porygon2234 Stantler235 Smeargle236 TyrogueAmpharos, an electric-type Pokémon237 Hitmontop238 Smoochum239 Elekid240 Magby241 Miltank242 Blissey243 Raikou244 Entei245 Suicune246 Larvitar247 Pupitar248 Tyranitar249 Lugia250 Ho-oh251 CelebiPokémon GymsThe system where the player has to get badges throughout the world to be allowed to enter the Elite Four and try to become the greatest Pokémon Trainer ever returns from Red/Blue/Green/ Yellow. This time the region where the game primarily takes places is called Johto and the gym leaders are all different than its prequel. Eventually, when all eight gym leader are defeated in the Johto region and the Elite Four is also defeated, there is an opportunity to go back to Kanto (the region of the first generation) to a replay on all past Gym leaders, assuring a total of 16 Gym Leaders and 16 possible badges.Violet City GymLeader - FalknerBadge - Zephyr BadgePokémon Type - FlyingPokémon Used - Pidgey, PidgeottoAzalea City GymLeader - BugsyBadge - Hive BadgePokémon Type - BugPokémon Used - Metapod, Kakuna, ScyterGoldenrod City GymLeader - WhitneyBadge - Plain BadgePokémon Type - NormalPokémon Used - Clefairy, MiltankEcruteak City GymLeader - MortyBadge - Fog BadgePokémon Type - GhostPokémon Used - Gastly, Hunter, Hunter, GengarCianwood City GymLeader - ChuckBadge - Storm BadgePokémon Type - FightingPokémon Used - Primeape, PoliwrathOlivine City GymLeader - JasmineBadge - Mineral BadgePokémon Type - SteelPokémon Used - Magnemite, Magnemite, SteelixMagohany City GymLeader - PryceBadge - Glacier BadgePokémon Type - IcePokémon Used - Seel, Dewgong, PiloswineBlackthorn City GymLeader - ClairBadge - Rising BadgePokémon Type - DragonPokémon Used - Dragonair, Dragonair, Dragonair, KingdraVermilion City GymLeader - Lt. SurgeBadge - ThunderbadgePokémon Type - ElectricPokémon Used - Raichu, Electrode, Electrode , Magneton, ElectabuzzSaffron City GymLeader - SabrinaBadge - MarshbadgePokémon Type - PsychicPokémon Used - Espeon, Mr. Mime, AlakazanCerulean City GymLeader - MistyBadge - Cascade BadgePokémon Type - WaterPokémon Used - Golduck, Quagsire, Lapras, StarmieCeladon City GymLeader - ErikaBadge - Rainbow BadgePokémon Type - GrassPokémon Used - Tangela, Victreebel, Jumpluff, BellossomFuschia City GymLeader - JanineBadge - Sould BadgePokémon Type - Bug/PoisonPokémon Used - Crobat, Ariados, Weezing, Weezing, VenomothPewter City GymLeader - BrockBadge - Boulder BadgePokémon Type - Rock/GroundPokémon Used - Graveler, Rhyhorn, Omastar, Kabutops, OnyxSeafoam Islands City GymLeader - BlaineBadge - Volcano BadgePokémon Type - FirePokémon Used - Magcargo, Magmar, RapidashViridian City GymLeader - GaryBadge - Earth BadgePokémon Type - Gary has a very varied teamPokémon Used - Pidgeot, Alakazan, Rhydon, Exeggutor, Gyarados, ArcanineThe Elite FourThe Elite Four works pretty much like in the previous games. The player first faces the four members of the elite four, then battles against the Elite Champion for the title of greatest of all. Bruno from the previous Elite makes a come back, while the previously gym leader Koga appears as one of the four.Elite Four WillPokémon Type - PsychicPokémon Used - Xatu, Exeggutor, Slowbro, Jynx, XatuElite Four KogaPokémon Type - Bug/PoisonPokémon Used - Ariados, Forretress, Muk, Venomoth, Crobat,Elite Four BrunoPokémon Type - FightingPokémon Used - Hitmontop, Hitmonchan, Hitmonlee, Onyx, MachampElite Four KarenPokémon Type - DarkPokémon Used - Umbreon, Vileplume, Gengar, Murkrow, HoundoomElite Four Champion LancePokémon Type - DragonPokémon Used - Gyarados, Charizard, Aerodactyl, Dragonite, Dragonite, DragoniteLegendary PokémonLegendary Pokémon are Pokémon generally found in a very limited amount in the world of Pokémon, so unique there is only one of each of them. These Pokémon have more experience than the rest, and can be found in already high levels ranging from 30 to 70. Like Moltres, Articuno, and Zapdos were the Legendary Birds of the previous games, this time there are Legendary Dogs, called Entei, Suicune and Raikou. There's also two new birds, Lugia and Ho-oh; although when purchasing one or the other version of the game one of these two Pokémon come printed on the cover, Both can be captured in each of the distinct versions. There's also a time-traveler Pokémon called Celebi that wasn't included in this version, and got removed from American and European cartridges of Crystal, was only obtainable through Nintendo Events.EnteiType - FireLevel - 40Location - Awaken Entei in one of Ecruteak's buildings and then chase him down across Johto.SuicuneType - WaterLevel - 40Location - Awaken Suicune in one of Ecruteak's buildings and then chase him down across Johto.RaikouType - ElectricLevel - 40Location - Awaken Raikou in one of Ecruteak's buildings and then chase him down across Johto.LugiaType - Flying / PsychicLevel - Gold 70 / Silver 40Location - Lugia is found in the caverns south of Olivine. In the Gold version, he isan't available until the player has the Silver Wing in Pewter. In the Silver version, the player can just surf there and explore the dungeon until the player finds him.Ho-ohType - Flying / FireLevel - Gold 40 / Silver 70Location - On the top of the Tin Tower after receiving the Rainbow Wing. In the Gold version the item is in the Radio Tower in Goldenrod. In the Silver version is it found in Pewter.CelebiType - Grass / PsychicLevel - 30Location - Illex Forest, only obtainable in the Japanese version of Pokémon Crystal, Nintendo Events or GameShark.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13470">Dragon Warrior Monsters</game><game id="3879">Digimon World 3</game><game id="23117">Robopon 2: Cross/Ring Version</game><game id="17530">Jade Cocoon: Story of the Tamamayu</game><game id="8307">EarthBound</game><game id="2731">Mega Man Zero</game><game id="26576">Shaman King: Legacy of the Spirits, Sprinting Wolf</game><game id="26575">Shaman King: Legacy of the Spirits, Soaring Hawk</game><game id="6557">Revelations: Persona</game><game id="24009">Dragon Quest Monsters 1 &amp; 2</game><game id="8048">Dragon Warrior Monsters 2</game><game id="24011">Dragon Quest Monsters: Caravan Heart</game><game id="6632">Dragon Quest Monsters: Joker</game><game id="1164">Dragon Warrior I &amp; II</game><game id="27048">Fossil Fighters</game><game id="22912">Magi Nation</game><game id="27976">Koto Battle: Tengai no Moribito</game><game id="21079">Dinosaur King</game><game id="23375">Gangway Monsters</game><game id="17113">Hey You, Pikachu!</game><game id="33000">Shin Megami Tensei: Persona 2 - Innocent Sin</game><game id="17979">Digimon World 2</game><game id="40423">Keitai Denjuu Telefang</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/17172/1276964-pkmn_goldsilver.png</image></root>