<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8279</id><name>Mortal Kombat Trilogy</name><description>OverviewMortal Kombat Trilogy is a compilation of each previous Mortal Kombat game, bringing them together in a new, single title. Every fighter and most levels from every preceding title returns, bringing the total roster to over 32 fighters. Due to technical limitations at the time, there are several slight differences between the CD and cartridge based versions, most relating to the need to load and cache things on the CD version before play, such as transformations for Shang Tsung in order to reduce loading during a fight (an issue that existed in Mortal Kombat 3 and Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3). The most obvious difference is the extension of the " Shao Kahn's Treasure" in the Nintendo 64 version, where players have twenty-four options to pick from instead of twelve seen in the other versions. The CD versions feature more bosses than the N64 version as well as improved sound quality. Conversely, the Nintendo 64 version lacks several characters seen in the disc versions because of a lack of space on the cartridge. These are mainly classic versions of several characters, but two bosses were excluded as well: Goro and Kintaro.In 1998, Mortal Kombat 4 proceeded Mortal Kombat Trilogy on home consoles.StoryMortal Kombat Trilogy uses the same story as Mortal Kombat 3, which has Shao Kahn acting as the main antagonist. Shao Kahn is presented as the millennium-old emperor of Outworld, a dark world that exists in parallel to Earth. Many years ago, the Elder Gods created the Mortal Kombat tournament in order to prevent an invasion from Outworld. For many years, Goro reigned as the supreme champion of the tournament, but eventually Liu Kang defeated him and became the new champion. Liu Kang, along with other fighters from the tournament, were drawn into Outworld and forced to compete in a new tournament. But the tournament was merely a ruse to distract the warriors from his true intentions: resurrecting Queen Sindel and taking over Earth. At the onset of the game, players must fight their way up the tournament roster, eventually reaching Shao Kahn and defeating him, thwarting his invasion and releasing many souls of fallen warriors from his body.GameplayMortal Kombat Trilogy plays much like its predecessor Mortal Kombat 3/UMK3, with a few additions. Several characters have new moves, previously not seen in the series or ones that had to be cut for one reason or another. Another addition was the "Aggression" bar, which would increase as a player landed successful hits on their opponent; when the bar filled, they would temporarily move faster and deal more damage.Players can choose from the story-based Tournament mode as well as other arcade modes for quick matches. In the Tournament mode, a player selects one character and then battles their way up a tower of AI controlled opponents until the eventual showdown with Shao Kahn. The higher the difficulty level a player chooses, the more combatants they much fight as well as an overall increase in AI competency. A player works their way up the tower by beating each opponent in a standard match of first to get two victories. At the end of the second victory, the announcer shouts "Finish Him!" and players are able to perform a hallmark " Fatality" or any other finishing move that had been introduced in previous titles, including " Animalities," " Babalities," " Friendships" and the new " Brutalities," 11-input combos that result in the explosion of their opponent. Players will face off with bosses at various segments throughout their progression up the tower, most of which are less phased by attacks than a standard foe. The final boss of the tower is Shao Kahn, and upon defeating him, players can choose a "treasure" which demonstrates a certain aspect of the game or in one case on the Nintendo 64, shows each finishing attack for every character in the game.CharactersThe Character Select Screen from the PlayStation, PC, and Sega Saturn versions.The character roster is built from the roster from the console versions of Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3, adding characters and appearances from previous Mortal Kombat games while making boss characters playable. The PlayStation, PC, and Sega Saturn versions of the game include the full roster with the exception of Khameleon (bringing its total roster to 37). The Nintendo 64 version of the game includes Khameleon as a secret character, but leaves out Chameleon, Kano and Raiden's MK1 appearances, Jax and Kung Lao's MK2 appearances, unmasked Sub-Zero, Goro, and Kintaro (bringing its total roster to 30). The Game.com port includes only 13 playable characters.Johnny Cage is the only character in the game to receive entirely new digitized graphics (using another actor). Some characters received new graphics, primarily due to missing animations. The two new characters, Chameleon and Khameleon, are simply based on the male and female ninja bases from UMK3.Johnny Cage (not available in the Game.com version)Noob Saibot (console Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3)Baraka (Mortal Kombat II, not available in the Game.com version)Cyrax (Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3)Sonya (Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3, not available in the Game.com version)Raiden (known in the game as Rayden, Mortal Kombat II (with secret Mortal Kombat appearance in all versions except Nintendo 64 and Game.com))Rain (console Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3)Shang Tsung (Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3, not available in the Game.com version)Kitana (Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3)Kano (Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3 (with secret Mortal Kombat appearance in all versions except Nintendo 64), not available in the Game.com version)Scorpion (Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3, not available in the Game.com version)Sub-Zero (Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3, both masked and un-masked in all versions except Nintendo 64 (where only masked Sub-Zero is included), not available in the Game.com version)Smoke (Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3, both human and robot, not available in the Game.com version)Reptile (Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3)Jax (Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3 (with secret Mortal Kombat II appearance in all versions except Nintendo 64), not available in the Game.com version)Mileena (Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3)Sektor (Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3)Liu Kang (Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3, not available in the Game.com version)Jade (Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3)Sheeva (Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3, not available in the Game.com version)Kung Lao (Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3 (with secret Mortal Kombat II appearance in all versions except Nintendo 64), not available in the Game.com version)Nightwolf (Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3)Sindel (Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3, not available in the Game.com version)Ermac (Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3)Stryker (Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3, not available in the Game.com version)Kabal (Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3, not available in the Game.com version)Goro (Mortal Kombat, not available in the Nintendo 64 or Game.com versions)Shao Kahn (final boss, Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3)Motaro (boss, Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3)Kintaro (Mortal Kombat II, not available in the Nintendo 64 or Game.com versions)Chameleon (secret character, not available in the Nintendo 64 or Game.com versions)Khameleon (secret character, Nintendo 64 version only)</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3185">ClayFighter 63 1/3</game><game id="11156">X-Men vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="7751">Art of Fighting Anthology</game><game id="14669">Virtua Fighter Animation</game><game id="16793">Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="11065">Shaman King: Power of Spirit</game><game id="13753">Dead or Alive Ultimate</game><game id="22953">Ultimate Fighter</game><game id="21277">Ultimate Mortal Kombat</game><game id="39751">Death Cargo</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/395/190270-mktbox.jpg</image></root>