<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8339</id><name>Hidden Agenda</name><description>Game play of Hidden Agenda      In Hidden Agenda, the player is the president of Chimerica, a fictional Latin American country which has been controlled by an autocratic dictator for many years. As the leader of the revolutionary government, the player must try to balance the competing needs of the different factions to survive three years in office, after which the game grades the player's presidency and gives the player a short description of what happens to the country. He or she does this by appointing a cabinet made up of politicians from the country's three competing political factions and makes decisions on a wide range of political decisions with their advice.    The player's actions can lead to their own ousting by the military, foreign powers, a spurned political faction or even a member of their own cabinet. By their decisions, Chimerica can end up as a military dictatorship, a communist or kleptocratic regime, or a moderate western democracy. The effects of the player's actions are reflected in the game's various newspapers, which comment on the player's actions from conservative, moderate and leftist viewpoints.Major Political factions in Hidden Agenda Successful play in Hidden Agenda requires careful balancing of competing interests.  The National Liberation PartyMade up of the various left-wing movements in Chimerica. The National Liberation party was instrumental in bringing about the fall of the previous regime. The National Liberation party is the game's leftist political party.   The Christian Reform PartyRepresenting Chimerica's small middle class, Christian Reform is one of the few opposition parties that thrived under the previous regime.  The Christian Reform party is the game's moderate political party. The Popular Stability PartyPopular Stability is the game's conservative party.  The revolutionary army Led by sub-commandant Correa, the revolutionary army are  the guerilla forces that destroyed the previous regime. The traditional armyLed by Colonel Erlich, the traditional army represent the part of Chimerica's armed forces that joined the revolution. Although they start the game loyal to the player, the human rights violators they harbor are a source of potential conflict with the revolutionary army.The United States and the Soviet UnionThe United States and the Soviet Union will provide aid and arms to the player if they side with the left or right-wing factions in the Chimerican government. The United States can be provoked into harassing the Player with guerrilla Contra-style insurgents and organizing a coup.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/97089/2464574-box.png</image></root>