<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8421</id><name>Outlive</name><description>Outlive is a RTS (Real-Time Strategy) game, developed by Continuum Entertainment, where the player can assume the role of the human or robot race to eradicate the opposite faction. This is one of thefew Brazilian games to be published in the United States and Europe.  The game features Over 20 units, more than 40 single-player maps and three campaigns as well as an easy-to-use map editor. Outlive also features a multiplayer mode that supports up to 16 players over an Internet connection or LAN.Robot RaceHuman RaceHere is a list of all the units in Outlive:Human RaceAbominable  Builder - This unit builds buildings. Chopper Dominator Explorer Fighter Flamethrower - Ground unit that uses fire in a short range. Gatherer - Human unit that gathers resources. Heavy tank Rocket Launcher - Anti-air ground unit. Tank Transporter - This air unit can transport other ground units. Vampire  Robot RaceAvenger Apocalypse Chaos Electro Incinerator Marauder - This unit transports resources from ore mines. Morpher - This unit transforms into robot buildings. Raider Tempest Thunder Twister - Similar to the human transporter, it can transport other units but it can also teleport.   </description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="12">Real-Time Strategy</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13062">StarCraft</game><game id="20674">StarCraft II: Wings of Liberty</game><game id="5415">StarCraft: Brood War</game><game id="14073">Warcraft III: The Frozen Throne</game><game id="4867">The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth II</game><game id="7701">The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth</game><game id="6447">The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth II - The Rise of the Witch-King</game><game id="11165">Enemy Infestation</game><game id="9719">Warcraft: Orcs &amp; Humans</game><game id="20103">Warcraft II: Tides of Darkness</game><game id="11816">Warcraft II: Beyond the Dark Portal</game><game id="20660">Command &amp; Conquer: Red Alert 3</game><game id="17551">Command &amp; Conquer 3: Tiberium Wars</game><game id="4384">Command &amp; Conquer</game><game id="2068">Command &amp; Conquer: Tiberian Sun</game><game id="5550">Command &amp; Conquer: Yuri's Revenge</game><game id="6164">World in Conflict</game><game id="1901">Supreme Commander</game><game id="2115">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War</game><game id="10883">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War - Soulstorm</game><game id="21175">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War II</game><game id="10485">Age of Empires</game><game id="2846">Age of Empires II: The Age of Kings</game><game id="8546">Age of Empires III</game><game id="12483">Age of Empires III: The WarChiefs</game><game id="14590">Age of Empires II: The Conquerors</game><game id="13076">Age of Mythology</game><game id="19857">Empire Earth</game><game id="1565">Empire Earth II</game><game id="13037">Empire Earth III</game><game id="19199">Empire Earth II: The Art of Supremacy</game><game id="3693">Empire Earth: The Art of Conquest</game><game id="18901">Star Wars: Galactic Battlegrounds</game><game id="24079">StarCraft II: Legacy of the Void</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/15/155745/2168482-outlive_coverart.png</image></root>