<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8430</id><name>Pajama Sam: No Need to Hide When It’s Dark Outside</name><description>OverviewPajama Sam: No Need to Hide When it's Dark Outside is a children's adventure game developed by Humongous Entertainment. Released on October 4, 1996, Pajama Sam received numerous awards and for the time was a hit among the younger audience. Pajama Sam featured a kid friendly version of the SCUMM engine that made the game very accessible for younger players.PlotSam courageously confronts Carrot.Sam, a life long fan of Pajama Man scared to sleep because of the monster in his closet. He decides to vanquish this foe and after donning his mask he becomes Pajama Sam! Sam ventures into the closet with his trusty flashlight, collectable Pajama Man lunchbox, and his mask. Unfortunately for Sam upon entering his closet he falls into the Land of Darkness. Seemingly unfazed he sets off to Darkness' house but before he can reach the dwelling of his dreaded foe he is captured by a host of trees who quickly relieve him of his lunchbox, mask, and flashlight. After escaping their trap Sam finds that without his trusty items he can in no way vanquish Darkness. So Sam decides to set off into the Land of Darkness and retrieve his equipment so that he may finish his quest.Gameplay/PathsPajama Sam, like many Humongous Entertainment games, changes everytime it is played. While the objective remains the same, to find your superhero gear and vanquish Darkness, the location of the items you need to collect changes. This means that in every game different items will need to be collected, different people or things may need to be interacted with, and new characters that wouldn't otherwise make appearance are shown.FlashlightSam attempts to retrieve the flashlight.The flashlight may be located in a section of the mine that is otherwise unaccessable. In order to retrieve the flashlight Sam must find a character capable ofopening the closed mine track. After getting through the player will be required to backtrack in order to find a gear needed for the release mechanism leading to the flashlight.In other playthroughs the flashlight may be located in a shed near the river. In order to open the door a door knob will need to collected and an item that will unrust the hinges. The flashlight is located inside on a top shelf.LunchboxMany times the lunchbox will be located next to the wishing well. Unfortunately the apparent path to the well is block by an immovable thorn bush. In order to retrieve the lunchbox Sam will need to go up through the wishing well. This requires Sam to find a way to get Otto up the rapids located in the cave further down the river.In other playthroughs the lunchbox will be located at the bottom of the river, too far down for Sam to reach. The lunchbox is made of metal so Sam will have to find a magnet capable of pulling the lunchbox out of the river.MaskUsually the mask will be found on Carrot who will only give it up in exchange for assistance in the carrot rebellion. In order to help Carrot Sam will have to provide him with transportation and means of getting into the carrot prison, which is more commonly known as a refridgerator.In other instances the mask will located in the dancing furniture room. While the mask is seemingly free while the furniture is dancing it is later trapped when Sam enters and the furniture suddenly desists into its' original nonfunky form. For Sam to get his mask back he will have to travel deep into Darkness' house to find a secret lab with the means of making him invisible.MinigamesSock CollectingPajama Sam featured a sidequest that involved picking up all of Sam's lost socks. If all twenty are collected during the game the player is treated to slightly different dialogue at the end of the game.Cheese and CrackersCheese and CrackersCheese and Crackers is an aptly named version of Tic Tac Toe played with cheese and crackers. Run by a toaster in the forest near the river the game has no real significance to the storyline. Three different boards are available for play ranging from the basic three by three board to two significantly larger boards. If Sam plays cheese and crackers during the game the dialogue during the ending sequence changes slightly.Wii PortA Wii port, along with Freddi Fish and Spy Fox, was announced by Humongous in March of 2008. It was released the same year on August 26th.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14824">Spy Fox in "Dry Cereal"</game><game id="11177">Putt-Putt Joins the Parade</game><game id="3090">Fatty Bear's Birthday Surprise</game><game id="2373">Freddi Fish and the Case of the Missing Kelp Seeds</game><game id="15666">Freddi Fish 2: The Case of the Haunted School House</game><game id="9720">Freddi Fish 3: The Case of the Stolen Conch Shell</game><game id="10911">Freddi Fish 4: The Case of the Hogfish Rustlers of Briny Gulch</game><game id="15183">Putt-Putt Enters the Race</game><game id="4615">Putt-Putt and Pep's Dog on a Stick</game><game id="13134">Putt-Putt Goes to the Moon</game><game id="931">Putt-Putt Travels Through Time</game><game id="3785">Putt-Putt Saves the Zoo</game><game id="10431">Putt-Putt Joins the Circus</game><game id="7793">Putt-Putt: Pep's Birthday Surprise</game><game id="3136">Putt-Putt and Fatty Bear's Activity Pack</game><game id="13791">Putt-Putt and Pep's Balloon-o-Rama</game><game id="7662">Freddi Fish 5: The Case of the Creature of Coral Cove</game><game id="5449">Freddi Fish and Luther's Water Worries</game><game id="9805">Freddi Fish's One-Stop Fun Shop</game><game id="13067">Freddi Fish &amp; Luther's Maze Madness</game><game id="13465">Spy Fox 2: Some Assembly Required</game><game id="5914">Spy Fox: Operation Ozone</game><game id="18816">Spy Fox in Cheese Chase</game><game id="22727">Spy Fox in: Hold the Mustard</game><game id="19472">Fatty Bear's FunPack</game><game id="11852">Sam &amp; Max Hit the Road</game><game id="5729">The Curse of Monkey Island</game><game id="3019">The Secret of Monkey Island</game><game id="10528">Monkey Island 2:  LeChuck's Revenge</game><game id="6728">Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders</game><game id="14748">Indiana Jones and The Last Crusade: The Graphic Adventure</game><game id="21174">Full Throttle</game><game id="13230">Grim Fandango</game><game id="4372">Maniac Mansion: Day of the Tentacle</game><game id="14743">Blue's 123 Time Activities</game><game id="14412">Blue's Reading Time Activities</game><game id="17810">Blue's Clues: Blue's Art Time Activities</game><game id="11848">Blue's ABC Time Activities</game><game id="5784">Blue's Treasure Hunt</game><game id="16775">Blue's Clues: Blue's Birthday Adventure</game><game id="16132">Moop and Dreadly in the Treasure on Bing Bong Island</game><game id="41631">Finding Teddy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/8884/411549-pajamasam1.jpg</image></root>