<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8480</id><name>All-Pro Football 2K8</name><description>OverviewAll-Pro Football 2K8, developed by Visual Concepts and published by 2K Sports, was released on July 16, 2007 for both the Xbox 360 and Playstation 3. The developers at Visual Concepts had previously worked on their NFL 2K football games until 2005 when Electronic Arts acquired the exclusive rights to publish NFL content. After a couple year hiatus the 2K football team returned with a new idea. Knowing that they couldn't use any of the current NFL content or player likenesses Visual Concepts and 2K Sports decided to go in a new direction by signing the NFLPA's respective Hall-of-Fame to be in the game.The game starts off by having the player create their own team. While creating their team the player gets to customize many attributes including uniforms, team logo, stadium design, and the team's name. After creating the team, the player is then sent to a legend selection screen. The legends are split up into three tiers, gold, silver, and bronze. You are however limited to only two gold, three silver, and six bronze legends per team. All of the non-legend players on your team are automatically filled in by fictional characters.GameplayAPF 2K8 featured gameplay that was very similar to that of its predecessor, ESPN NFL 2K5. The physics engine received a notable upgrade, featuring more fluid motion between animations, and improvements in model collision where now players would slide their arms past or move their foot over another player rather than clipping through them. With the exception of the Xbox 360's bumper integration, controls stayed exactly the same from 2K5.A noticeable change in the mechanics were in regards to turnovers. The frequency of user-induced interceptions and fumbles dropped substantially from that of 2K5, while the frequency of blocked field goals increased.PresentationThe visual presentation of APF 2K8 was greatly improved over NFL 2K5, featuring higher polygon-count models, enhanced facial animations and much more elaborate stadiums.In-game announcers stayed the same from NFL 2K5 (Dan Stevens  Peter O'Keefe), and many recorded lines from 2K5 were reused in APF 2K8. Without the ESPN license, Chris Berman was removed from commenting on half-time and post-game highlight reels, and instead the commentary was replaced by the in-game announcers.APF 2K8 suffers from graphical glitches, such as players seemingly bending their legs at the knee to a 90° degree angle and then proceeding to float a few feet above the ground over players who are lying down in their path. The game also re-renders all plays during highlights and during many post-game highlight reels the coaches can be seen standing in the middle of the highlighted plays as if they were shaking hands after the game.With Electronic Arts holding the publishing rights to NFL-related content, there has been much support of development for unofficial roster updates using NFL characters in APF 2K8. These updates consist of many attributes of actual NFL content, including player names, likenesses, attributes, jerseys and team names. The updates are created by creating a game save on the Xbox 360 in-game, then transferring that save to a computer, using a complex hex-editor to manipulate the game content, and then the save is transferred back to the Xbox 360 hard drive.Legends2K Sports has licensed over 240 retired NFL legends for All-Pro Football 2K8. These legends are as follows:QuarterbacksTroy AikmanSammy BaughJohn ElwayOtto GrahamDan MarinoJoe MontanaWarren MoonRoger StaubachJohnny UnitasSteve YoungRandall CunninghamLen DawsonArchie ManningKen StablerBart StarrJoe TheismannSteve BartkowskiBubby BristerJohn BrodieLynn DickeySteve GroganJim HarbaughJim HartBobby HebertJeff HostetlerTommy KramerDave KriegBernie KosarGreg LandryKen O'BrienNeil O'DonnellMark RypienBill WadeAndre WareJim ZornRunning BacksEarl CampbellRoger CraigLenny MooreWalter PaytonBarry SandersThurman ThomasO.J. SimpsonGale SayersEmmitt SmithMarcus AllenChristian OkoyeCurt WarnerPaul HornungMerril HodgeNatrone MeansDave MeggettJoe PerryBarry FosterHugh McElhennyBilly SimsGreg BellChuck ForemanMike RozierMatt SnellChuck MuncieTom RathmanTony CanadeoReggie CobbRicky WattersIckey WoodsEric BieniemyFloyd LittleFreeman McNeilGeorge McAfeeAbner HaynesCharley TrippiWide Recievers/Tight EndsIrving FryarHerman MooreDrew PearsonAndre ReedJerry RiceFred BiletnikoffDwight ClarkWillie GaultRaghib IsmailWesley WalkerAlvin HarperGary ClarkDon MaynardTony MartinErnest GivinsHenry EllardRicky SandersJohn TaylorCharley TaylorYancey ThigpenRob MooreRick UpchurchSteve TaskerMike DitkaBen CoatesJohn JeffersonTroy DraytonKeith JacksonAnthony CarterJames LoftonTodd ChristensenBrent JonesRaymond BerryDave CasperBilly Joe DupreeBobby MitchellDon HutsonCliff BranchOffensive LinemenAnthony MunozSteve WisniewskiTom MackDwight StephensonGuy McIntyreJim ParkerJesse SapoluRandall McDanielTony BoselliBill CurryRuss GrimmJoe JacobyRoosevelt BrownLou CreekmurDermontti DawsonJoe DeLamielleureRon MixJim OttoMick TinglehoffBill FralicJim LangerLarry LittleRandall McDanielRandy CrossStan JonesBob St. ClairBob BrownBubba ParisJim LacheyKorey StringerRichmond WebbRayfield WrightRon YaryLinebackersBrian BosworthNick BuonicontiDick ButkusMike SingletaryDerrick ThomasChris SpielmanChuck bednarikLamar LathonCarl BanksPepper JohnsonKen Norton Jr.Gary PlummerScott StudwellOtis WilsonJohn OfferdahlBrad Van PeltDave WilcoxJessie TuggleHarry CarsonBrian JonesChuck NollJoe SchmidtGreg LloydJohn AndersonKarl MecklenburgRobert BrazileJack LambertDefensive LinemenReggie WhiteDexter ManleyDeacon JonesRayfield WrightLeon LettBryce PaupDan SaleaumuaHarvey MartinMike GolicMarty LyonsL.C. GreenwoodToo Tall JonesRulon JonesDan HamptonDave ButzLee Roy SelmanElvin BetheaLeslie O'NealRandy WhiteJack YoungbloodTony TolbertJerome BrownGino MarchettiKeith MillardDante LavelliChris DolemanWilliam PerryArt DonovanClyde SimmonsJim MarshallLeonard MarshallBob LillyGreg KragenPete PihosMark GastineauDefensive BacksLem BarneyJoey BrownerWillie WoodLester hayesTerry McDanielJack TatumMark CarrierRonnie LottWillie BrownNolan CromwellEric TurnerRoger WehrliMel RenfroNight Train LaneRod WoodsonAlbert LewisMike HaynesDeron CherryTom BrookshierCliff HarrisEugene RobinsonLeRoy ButlerSolomon WilcotsCharlie WatersDick AndersonFred MarionGeorge McAfeeKickers/PuntersAl Del GrecoJan StenerudLou GrozaJim BakkenRay GuyEddie MurrayJeff JaegerXbox 360 Game InstallationAll Pro Football 2K8 requires 3.7GB of space to install on an Xbox 360 HDD.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="21">Football</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13056">ESPN NFL 2K5</game><game id="805">NFL 2K1</game><game id="4659">NFL 2K</game><game id="10530">NFL 2K3</game><game id="14001">NFL 2K2</game><game id="16585">Madden NFL 07</game><game id="20986">Backbreaker</game><game id="20848">NCAA Football 09</game><game id="20711">Madden NFL 09</game><game id="21413">Madden NFL 08</game><game id="6648">Madden NFL 06</game><game id="4222">Madden NFL 2005</game><game id="11911">Madden NFL 2004</game><game id="15987">Madden NFL 2003</game><game id="10845">Madden NFL 2002</game><game id="8822">Madden NFL 2001</game><game id="12373">Madden NFL 2000</game><game id="13996">Madden NFL 99</game><game id="8679">Madden NFL 98</game><game id="17667">John Madden Football '92</game><game id="1234">John Madden Football</game><game id="17607">John Madden Football II</game><game id="21698">John Madden Duo CD Football</game><game id="21706">NCAA Football 07</game><game id="13671">NCAA Football 06</game><game id="6811">NCAA Football 2005</game><game id="16279">NCAA Football 2004</game><game id="9305">NCAA Football 2003</game><game id="16392">NCAA Football 2002</game><game id="3259">NCAA Football 99</game><game id="21951">NCAA Football 08</game><game id="20920">Blitz: The League II</game><game id="24637">BCFX: The Doug Williams Edition</game><game id="25241">Madden NFL 10</game><game id="25614">NCAA Football 10</game><game id="27692">NFL 2010</game><game id="5898">Jimmy Johnson's VR Football '98</game><game id="33906">Madden NFL 12</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2250668-box_apfb08.png</image></root>