<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8492</id><name>Capcom vs. SNK 2: Mark of the Millennium</name><description>The arcade version.OverviewCapcom vs SNK 2 is the second (and thus far, final) Capcom-produced crossover in the "          SNK vs. Capcom" series. Like the original          Capcom vs. SNK, CvS2 was developed for the Sega Naomi arcade hardware. CvS2 was one of the last fighting games to be fully developed by a Capcom-owned team; all fighting games released after the "death" and subsequent "revival" of Capcom fighters were at least partially outsourced to companies such as         Dimps or        Eighting.  In addition to adding several new characters, CvS2 revamps the Ratio system of the previous game; this allows players to freely choose the strength of each fighter in their one-man, two-man, or three-man team. The game also increases the number of "Grooves" from two to six, incorporating the mechanics and super meter systems of       Street Fighter Alpha 3's fighting styles,      The King of Fighters 98's Advanced and Extra modes, and     Samurai Shodown's Rage meter.CvS2, being a Naomi game, was ported to the Sega Dreamcast. Though the Dreamcast version was not released in North America or Europe, the PS2 port was released internationally only a few months later. The GameCube and Xbox versions, released later, were titled "Capcom vs. SNK 2 EO." These ports included an input mode named "EO-ism," which allows special moves to be performed by simply pointing the C-stick/Right Analog in certain directions. CvS2EO also removes the "Roll Cancel" glitch, a technique that is a key component to CvS2's tournament-level play. The Xbox version of the game notably features online play.GameplayUnlike the first Capcom vs. SNK, which emulated the   Neo Geo's controls by using a four-button system, CvS2 uses the Capcom-standard six button layout; because of this, SNK characters gain all new Medium attacks. Unlike the Marvel vs. series, a match in CvS2 consists of a sequence of up to five 1-on-1 rounds, depending on each team's size. The number of  available "Grooves" have been tripled. A Groove is chosen before selecting characters; they determine the way that a player's super meter works, in addition to determining their offensive and defensive options. Grooves are highlighted in detail below.  New in this game is the "Free Ratio" system. The player is given four points, which can be freely distributed to one, two, or three characters. These points determine their health; for example, a Ratio 1 character's health is much lower than that of a Ratio 3 character. Team possibilities include a single Ratio 4 character, a Ratio 3 character with a Ratio 1 character, two Ratio 2 characters, and two Ratio 1 characters with a Ratio 2 "leader." The console versions also support ratio-free 1-on-1 and 3-on-3 battles. Chun Li (left) uses the P-Groove while Haohmaru (right) uses the K-grooveGrooves C-Groove: Based on         Street Fighter Alpha 3's A-ism style, the super bar is split into three segments. When performing a super combo, the button pressed (weak, medium, or strong) determines whether a Level 1, Level 2, or Level 3 super is used. Level 2 supers, which can only be performed in this groove, can be cancelled into another move.Subsytems: Dash, Roll, Air Guard, Counter Attack, Tactical RecoveryA-Groove: Based on  Street Fighter Alpha 3's V-ism style, the super bar is split into two. The player can only execute Level 1 supers, but can also perform Custom Combos, which allows moves to be freely canceled for a short amount of time or until hit.Subsystems: Dash, Counter attack, Rolling, Safe FallP-Groove: Roughly based on  Street Fighter III and Super Street Fighter II Turbo, the super bar only contains one giant level, which allows the player to perform Level 3 supers.Subsystems: Dash, Small Jump, Tactical Recovery, Parry Sagat (left) uses the C-Groove while Kyo (right) uses the S-Groove.S-Groove: Based on         The King of Fighters '94, the super bar is one level that must be charged manually, allowing for Level 1 supers. The player also gains the ability to use Level 1 supers infinitely at low life, and can use a Level 3 super by having a full gauge at low life.Subsystems: Run, Dodge, Small Jump, Counter Attack, Tactical RecoveryN-Groove: Based on      The King of Fighters '98, the super bar contains three "stocks." Level 1 supers use one stock. One stock can also be used to enter a powered-up state, in which Level 3 supers can be used by giving up another stock.Subsystems: Run, Roll, Small Jump, Counter Movement, Counter Attack, Safe FallK-Groove: A combination of         Samurai Shodown and         Garou: Mark of the Wolves, this gauge fills by taking hits or using Just Defend. When it is full, the character temporarily enters Rage Mode, which powers up all of their attacks and defense and allows them to use Level 3 supers.Subsystems: Run, Small Jump, Safe Fall, Just Defend  SubsystemsDash: By tapping forward twice, the character jumps forward a short distance. Given to all Capcom grooves.Run: By tapping forward twice, the character begins to run.                Morrigan will instead fly into the air at a forward angle. Given to all SNK grooves.Roll: A KOF trademark, Roll allows a character to temporarily become invincible while advancing forward. The infamous Roll Cancel glitch allows this move's invincibility to be transferred to other moves.Dodge: Exclusive to S-Groove, this move causes the character to step into the background. A follow-up attack can be performed by pressing an attack button during the move.Air Guard: Exclusive to C-Groove, this grants the ability to block in the air, like the Street Fighter Alpha games.Counter Attack: This move, like Street Fighter's Alpha Counter and KOF's Guard Cancel Knockdown, allows the character to perform a quick counterattack from a block.Counter Movement: Exclusive to N-Groove, this technique lets the character cancel blockstun into a forward roll.Safe Fall: When knocked down, the character can immediately stand up.Tactical Recovery: When knocked down, the character can extend the amount of time that they stay grounded.Small Jump: A signature SNK movement option, the character will perform a lower, faster hop if the player quickly taps up.Parry: Exclusive to P-Groove, players can negate an opponent's attack by tapping forward in the exact instant that they are about to be struck.Just Defend: Exclusive to K-Groove, players can negate chip damage, build meter, and regain a pixel's worth of life by pressing back right before an attack hits their character. Just Defend can be used in the air, despite K-Groove's lack of air-blocking.Character RosterCapcom CharactersRyu, SNK style.Normal:                  Ryu (Street Fighter)                   Ken (Street Fighter)                   Eagle (Street Fighter)                   Sagat (Street Fighter)                   Chun-Li (Street Fighter II)                   Guile (Street Fighter II)                   Dhalsim (Street Fighter II)                   E. Honda (Street Fighter II)                   Blanka (Street Fighter II)                   Zangief (Street Fighter II)                   Balrog (Street Fighter II)Chun-Li, SNK style.                   Vega (Street Fighter II)                   M. Bison (Street Fighter II)                   Cammy (Super Street Fighter II)                   Akuma (Super Street Fighter II Turbo)                   Dan Hibiki (Street Fighter Alpha)                   Sakura Kasugano (Street Fighter Alpha 2)                   Yun Lee (Street Fighter III)                   Rolento Schugurg (Final Fight)                   Maki Genryusai (Final Fight 2)                   Morrigan Aensland (Darkstalkers)                   Kyosuke Kagami (Rival Schools)   Boss: Shin Akuma (Street Fighter Alpha 2)  Evil Ryu (console only; Street Fighter Alpha 2)  SNK CharactersKyo, Capcom style.Normal:                   Terry Bogard (Fatal Fury)                   Joe Higashi (Fatal Fury)                   Raiden (Fatal Fury)                   Geese Howard (Fatal Fury)                   Mai Shiranui (Fatal Fury 2)                   Kim Kaphwan (Fatal Fury 2)                   Ryuji Yamazaki (Fatal Fury 3)                   Rock Howard (Garou: Mark of the Wolves)                   Ryo Sakazaki (Art of Fighting)                   Yuri Sakazaki (Art of Fighting)                    King (Art of Fighting)                   Ryuhaku Todoh (Art of Fighting)Mai, Capcom style.             Athena Asamiya (Psycho Soldier)              Kyo Kusanagi (The King of Fighters '94)                   Benimaru Nikaido (The King of Fighters '94)                   Chang Koehan and                   Choi Bounge (The King of Fighters '94)                   Rugal Bernstein (The King of Fighters '94)                   Iori Yagami (The King of Fighters '95)                   Vice (The King of Fighters '96)                   Haohmaru (Samurai Shodown)                    Nakoruru (Samurai Shodown)             Hibiki Takane (The Last Blade 2)  Boss:                  Ultimate Rugal (Original)                   Orochi Iori (console only; King of Fighters '97) Cameo AppearancesCapcom Vs SNK 2 feature cameo appearances from other Capcom and SNK characters that appear in the background of some of the stages.Dudley.London Stage                  Dudley (Street Fighter III)                  Elena (Street Fighter III)                  Billy Kane (Fatal Fury)Nairobi Stage                  Alex (Street Fighter III)                  Edward Falcon (Power Stone)                  Clark (Ikari Warriors)                  Leona (King of Fighters '96)Shanghai Stage                  June (Plasma Sword) Useful links                  Official website (Japanese) </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="617">NeoGeo Battle Coliseum</game><game id="18484">Killer Instinct</game><game id="2612">Marvel vs. Capcom 2: New Age of Heroes</game><game id="15728">The King of Fighters 2000</game><game id="16793">Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="11065">Shaman King: Power of Spirit</game><game id="7751">Art of Fighting Anthology</game><game id="22820">Red Earth</game><game id="12125">Capcom Fighting Evolution</game><game id="12903">Marvel Super Heroes</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="9542">Night Warriors: Darkstalkers' Revenge</game><game id="20728">Tatsunoko vs. Capcom: Ultimate All Stars</game><game id="32161">Street Fighter X Tekken</game><game id="30142">The King of Fighters XIII</game><game id="30944">Marvel vs. Capcom 3: Fate of Two Worlds</game><game id="30558">Sunday vs. Magazine: Shuuketsu! Choujou Daikessen</game><game id="34082">Skullgirls</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2179472-box_cvs2.png</image></root>