<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8502</id><name>Power Rangers: Lightspeed Rescue</name><description>OverviewPower Rangers Lightspeed Rescue was developed by many different companies and published by THQ. Each version was completely different and offered many different play styles.Playstation VersionThe Pink Ranger drop kicks an enemy in the PSX version.The Playstation version was developed by Climax and published by THQ. It was released October 30, 2000.It's a standard top down 3D beat em' up where the player can play as all 5 Rangers and, once unlocked, the Titanium Ranger. Each Ranger has his or her own special attack along with the standard assortment of punches and kicks. Not much can be said about the gameplay except the Rangers fight their way to the end of the level and beat a boss. This version of the game can be played co-op.N64 VersionThe N64 version was developed by Mass Media and was also published by THQ. It was released September 28, 2000.Top down shooting level.This version was wildly different from the Playstation version. Instead of it being a top down beat em' up it had four different gameplay types that play like minigames. One type is a top down shooter where a Power Ranger is the playable character, the A button is used to shoot forward and the B button to shoot behind. The player moves around the area collecting coins or saving hostages. The second gameplay type is a 3D sidescrolling mode where the player controls a car. The goal is either to shoot water to put out flaming cars or run over toxic waste to clean it up. The third type is a semi mech game where the player is inside the Lightspeed Megazord and must defeat the enemies on screen. The final game type is sort of a flying game. All that is done is flying around in a hovercraft and collecting boxes. These four gameplay types repeat for 30 levels until the game is eventually completed.GameBoy Color VersionThe GameBoy Color version was developed by Natsume and published by THQ. It was released July 30, 2000.The player goes around saving trapped citizens from peril. The player has to collect items to open doors and stopping fires. It plays out very much like a puzzle game. There are also playable big Megazord battles.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="18">Puzzle</genre><genre id="37">Brawler</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="35038">Ultraman Powered - Kaijū Gekimetsu Sakusen</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2367514-box_prlr.png</image></root>