<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8580</id><name>Jade Empire</name><description>OverviewPublished by Microsoft Game Studios it was the last game developed by BioWare for the original Xbox and was released for the platform on the 12th of April 2005. An announcement on the 10th of May 2006 by BioWare revealed plans for a PC version of the game that would be published by 2K Games. It was released later for the PC on 26th of February 2007 and the Mac OS X version of the game was announced by TransGaming Technologies to be available on the 18th of August 2008.It features an epic adventure for players to enjoy allowing them to pick from various male or female characters to play as before thrusting them into the rich world of the Jade Empire. From there players find they may interact with various NPCs in the game, some of which will join the players team and become a selectable companion to explore with. Others providing a romantic interest for players to pursue.As well as this the game also boasts an intricate combat system that functions in real time with the players actions which allows them to block and/or dodge attacks when appropriate. Combat is focused on learning and developing martial arts styles, magical abilities and weapon techniques. Using aspects of all three groups players can combine them to varying effect from focusing on offensive, defensive or supportive results.GameplayJade Empire follows a tried and true method of RPG gameplay where players choose a character to begin the game with, customizing their initial stats and then proceeding to start the game where they begin in a tutorial environment. As they progress through the story the game become more challenging and the player gains experience from fulfilling quests and killing enemies which allows them to increase their stats and upgrade their fighting styles as they gain more levels.There are three primary stats in the game: Mind, Body and Spirit, which control the secondary stats Chi, Health and Focus as well as the conversation specific stats of Intimidation, Charm and Intuition. Chi is similar to mana as it is used when players heal their character, cast spells or choose to charge up a "Chi Strike" which will deal additional bonus damage when they next attack an enemy. Focus is used for when players primarily opt for utilising weapons in combat instead of martial arts styles that focus on hand to hand techniques. Or when they initiate "Focus Mode" which is very similar to " Bullet Time" slowing down enemy actions and allowing players to attack swiftly dealing extra damage.Focus, Chi and Health can be replenished by collecting orbs that drop from fallen enemies. Or additionally the player can visit any Focus or Chi shrines they can find and replenish themselves from there. Certain companions in a player's group can also help bolster their abilities or replenish their stats if needed.Combat is in real time which allows the player to dodge and/or block incoming attacks as they occur while also attacking enemies when the opportunity presents itself. This also allows the player to switch between various styles of martial arts, cast various spells or equip different weapons during the middle of a fight as the situation calls for it.StoryPlayers begin the game as a student at the Two Rivers academy under the guidance of Master Li who considers the player his most promising student. As the player takes part in a training exercise the local village is attacked by a group of pirates and it is up to the player to protect the local villagers and fend off the attackers. This sets the stage for a tutorial section of the game and allows the player to get acquainted with the controls and combat system early on in the game. After fighting their way to the shore the player finds the ship that the pirates have arrived on and confronts the leader who summons ghosts and spirits to attack the player.However Master Li arrives just in time and defeats the pirate leader who he reveals was a member of the Lotus Assassins who are servants of the Jade Emperor. Master Li explains further that they had come for the player character and a piece of the Dragon Amulet and then goes on to explain that he is in fact a brother to the Emperor and had saved the player when they were a child during the attack on Dirge, the monastery of the Order of Spirit Monks. And that the player is the last Spirit Monk alive.The player is then tasked with retrieving a piece of the Dragon Amulet that's underneath the academy and during their task they are confronted by a vision of the Water Dragon. A mystical entity who was "killed" during the attack on Dirge and her death ended the Long Draught that had fallen over the lands of the Jade Empire back then. But since her death spirits of the dead have begun walking the lands as ghosts causing havoc around the country. As the player retrieves this piece of the amulet their life long friend Dawn Star is kidnapped by a rival student, Gao the lesser, who was earlier exiled from the academy for using deadly magic to fight the player. As the players rescues Dawn Star they also find a new companion, Sagacious Zu, who accompanies the player and Dawn Star back to the village which they find is in flames with Master Li kidnapped and enemies crawling all over the place the trio decide to escape using a flying machine in pursuit of Master Li and his kidnappers who are headed to the Imperial City.However on their way to the Imperial City they crash land at Tien's Landing where they must now find a new flying machine and a wind map to show them the direction. As the player explores the area they locate a new flying machine, the Marvelous Dragonfly, which is located in the middle of the Gao the Greater's base. Gao becomes angry when he hears that his son was killed and the player must kill him as well when it becomes obvious Gao the Greater is working with the Lotus Assassins. Its at this point in the game the player also recruits two new companions, Sky and Kang the Mad.Upon further investigation the player finds the Lotus Assassins are searching some old ruins for another piece of the Dragon Amulet and it is here the player comes into contact with Chai Ka, a celestial demon trapped inside a young girls body sent to protect the player. The adventure takes the player to a great forest where they can either help the cannibals overthrow the Forest Guardian or help the Forest Guardian kill the cannibals. Whichever choice is made the player can then retrieve the wind map they require and the piece of the Dragon Amulet that the Lotus Assassins had found.Using the Marvelous Dragonfly the group finally reaches the Imperial City where they encounter a mysterious woman by the name of Silk Fox who in fact is Princess Lian the Heavenly Lily, daughter of of the Jade Emperor and niece to Master Li. She does not believe her father is the evil man the player says he is but in fact thinks it is Death's Hand, leader of the Lotus Assassins who is the one responsible for the suffering that is occurring throughout the lands of the Jade Empire. The player then infiltrates the Lotus Assassins underground fortress to find the last piece of the Dragon Amulet and they cause the complex to begin collapsing in on itself. After killing Grand Inquisitor Jia the group is confronted by Death's Hand himself and Sagacious Zu sacrifices himself to buy the player and his friends time to escape, both Sagacious Zu and Death's Hand get buried in the rubble of the collapsing fortress.The adventure continues with the player fighting their way into the Emperor's throne room where Silk Fox / Princess Lian finally gets to see her father's true nature and realizes he is the one responsible for the troubles within the Jade Empire. The Emperor however has gone mad with power and knows that the Water Dragon's death has stopped the spirits of the dead from reaching the underworld but doesn't care due to his own insanity. Master Li sits as a prisoner and watches as the player fights the Emperor and defeats him using the Dragon Amulet. However Master Li takes the Emperor's jade heart for himself and uses its power to kill the player who wakes up as a spirit in the underworld.As the player enters the underworld they are confronted again by the Water Dragon who explains that Master Sun Li had planned all along to use the player to defeat the Emperor that is why he saved him/her as a child when the Emperor attacked the Dirge Monastery. It is also revealed that Sun Li and Sun Kin (who is in fact Death's Hand) tried to overthrow Sun Hai, the recently killed Jade Emperor, but when it proved a fatal mistake Sun Li escaped and assumed the identity of the player's guardian and went into hiding. The Player fights their way through the underworld version of Dirge along with Abbot Song and when they come upon the place where the Water Dragon was slain the player must fight their doppelgangers. Once defeating them the player is transported back to the world of the living where their friends fly to Dirge and meet them.Sun Li ever the master strategist raises Death's Hand from the dead and sends his imperial army to Dirge to finally destroy the player and their friends. However, Sky manages to fool Death's Hand into coming alone and the player engages the armor clad warrior in single combat. However even after defeating him Death's Hand continues to rise again and again and eventually the player must use their force of will to break Sun Li's control over his brother's spirit. At this point the player can choose to enslave Death's Hand to his or her own will, set him free or force him to seek redemption for his past sins. Having defeated the army sent to Dirge the player then flies back to the Imperial Palace to finally put an end to Emperor Sun Li's machinations.Upon making their way to confront Sun Li the player and friends encounter the body of the Water Dragon which has been cut up to allow her blood, which is water, to flow into the lands of the Jade Empire and stop any future droughts. At this point the player can decide to destroy her body and allow the spirits of the dead to reach their final resting place in the underworld or control her body for their own use once Sun Li has been defeated. The player then confronts Sun Li who sends constructs to attack the player, once they are defeated he turns the player into stone and tries to break their will by use of mind control. At this point the player is essentially having a battle of wills with Sun Li in their mind and has the support of their friends and companions they've picked up along the adventure.The final fight with Sun Li is now at hand and the player is offered the chance to submit their surrender and be killed quickly so that they may live on in legend for not defying the new Emperor's will. Or the player can choose to refuse and have one final battle with their old master.The Endings *spoilers!*The game has endings for not only the player character but their companions as well.Player Character / StudentAssuming the player chose to destroy the Water Dragon's body then the game ends with the people of the Jade Empire cheering for the player as their hero and savior. This is considered the good ending.Should the player have chosen to corrupt and control the Water Dragon's body then the game ends with the remaining Lotus Assassins bowing and kneeling before the player. This is considered the evil ending.And if the player chose to accept Sun Li's offer to submit and receive a quick death the game ends with a statue being raised in their honor with a group of children sitting around it being told their tale. This is considered a somewhat ambiguous ending, neither good or evil but somewhere in the middle.SkyIf Sky is chosen as the romance option then he and the player character liver together in Tien's Landing. Or if he is not chosen as a romance option he will become the new Death's Hand or use the thieves guild for positive purposes.Silk FoxIf the player character is male and chose her as their romance option then Silk Fox and him rule the Jade Empire together in a firm but fair manner. If the player character is female and chose her as their romance option then the pair rule together in a firm but fair manner with both of them becoming the "Silk Fox". And should the player not have romanced her at all then she will become the sole ruler of the Jade Empire as its Empress.Dawn StarShe lives the rest of her life with the player character, rules alongside the player as Empress and Emperor, lives on her own or disappears on her own should the player have chosen a Closed Fist ending.Chai KaThe celestial demon either stays trapped in the young girls body and she lives the rest of her life insane or he returns to heaven and grants the young girl the gift of eternal life.Black WhirlwindLives the rest of his life roaming the world brawling and cleaving skulls till he eventually goes around the world entirely.Death's HandEither wanders the land seeking redemption for his past sins or becomes even more evil until eventually his armour can no longer hold his new, more evil form.Henpecked HouAfter some minor disasters he starts his own delivery service which gives him the opportunity to escape his demanding wife.Kang the MadContinues his life as an inventor until he is one day killed in a tragic explosion or so it seems as the player receives complex and imaginative machines whenever it is his or her birthday. Or Kang continues to work for the player as a slave if they chose the evil ending until one day Kang escapes into another dimension through some explosion.Ya ZhenAlso known as the toad demon inside Wild Flower, will either serve the player until he/she passes away followed by moving onto bigger plans or serve the player forever and earnestly.Fighting StylesMagicDire FlameIce ShardStone ImmortalTempestMartialIron Palm (exclusive to PC)Legendary StrikeThousand CutsLeaping TigerViper (exclusive to PC)White DemonSupportHeavenly WaveHidden FistParalyzing PalmStorm DragonTransformationHorse DemonJade GolemRed MinisterRhino Demon (exclusive to PC)Toad DemonWeaponCrimson TearsDemon Staff (exclusive to PC)Demon Sword (exclusive to PC)Dragon SwordEyes of the DragonFlawlessFortune's FavoriteGolden StarMirabelleTang's VengeanceTien's Justice (replaces Golden Star in the game's Limited Edition release)OtherDrunken MasterSpirit ThiefTechniquesAlloyed BodyLocation: Two Rivers SchoolEffects: Health 5, Focus -5Balance of NatureLocation: Tien's LandingEffects: Chi 3, Focus -15Belly of IronLocation: Two Rivers SchoolEffects: Health 3, Chi -1Boar's StrengthLocation: Great Southern ForestEffects: Health 7, Focus: -3Bone SplinterLocation: Dirge TempleEffects: Mind 2, Health 15Broken WheelLocation: Dirge TempleEffects: Health 7, Chi 7Chaotic StrainsLocation: Great Southern ForestEffects: Health 5, Chi 5Cleansed Body and MindLocation: Imperial ArenaEffects: Health 15, Focus 5Clear MindLocation: Imperial ArenaEffects: Intimidation -1, Focus 10Communion of the DragonLocation: Dirge TempleEffects: Health 5, Chi 15Communion of the OceanLocation: Dirge TempleEffects: Chi 10Conditioning of the BodyLocation: Tien's LandingEffects: Health 7, Chi -3Craftsman's LitanyLocation: Imperial City Market DistrictEffects: Focus 5Deadened NervesLocation: Lotus Assassin FortressEffects: Health 10, Chi -3Duchess of Ulmsbottom's Rules of EngagementLocation: Imperial City Scholars' GardenEffects: Mind 3Eye of Inner DarknessLocation: Lotus Assassin FortressEffects: Chi 15, Focus 5Fearsome VisageLocation: Lotus Assassin FortressEffects: Charm -1, Intimidation 3Fitness for the Upright GentlemanLocation: Imperial City Scholars' GardenEffects: Body 3Friends in High PlacesLocation: Imperial PalaceEffects: Intuition 2, Chi 5Gaze of the LionLocation: Two Rivers SchoolEffects: Health 2, Focus 2Guardian's StrengthLocation: Wild FlowerEffects: Health 5, Chi 5Hawk's EleganceLocation: Tien's LandingEffects: Health -3, Focus 7Heart of GoldLocation: Two Rivers SchoolEffects: Chi 3, Focus -1Heaven MantraLocation: Imperial Palace Audience ChamberEffects: Chi 10Hunter's SpiritLocation: Great Southern ForestEffects: Chi 15, Focus 3Legacy of Death's HandLocation: Lotus Assassin FortressEffects: Chi 10Legacy of Master LiLocation: Two Rivers SchoolEffects: Focus 7Lessons of the ForgeLocation: Two Rivers SchoolEffects: Health 2Loutish ApprovalLocation: Imperial City Market DistrictEffects: Health 2Manual of TrepanationLocation: Imperial City Scholars' GardenEffects: Spirit 3Mastered EvilLocation: Wild FlowerEffects: Health 5, Focus 5Mind of SteelLocation: Two Rivers SchoolEffects: Health -1, Focus 3Mother's TouchLocation: Pilgrim's Rest InnEffects: Health 5, Chi 5Path of the MonkLocation: Zin BuEffects: Chi 50Path of the ScholarLocation: Zin BuEffects: Focus 50Path of the WarriorLocation: Zin BuEffects: Health 50Perfected WarriorLocation: Imperial ArenaEffects: Health 15, Focus 15Porcelain SkinLocation: Imperial ArenaEffects: Charm 2, Chi -4Predatory IntuitionLocation: Great Southern ForestEffects: Intuition 3, Chi -5Replenishment of the MindLocation: Dirge TempleEffects: Chi 7, Focus 7River of TimeLocation: Dam SiteEffects: Intuition 1, Chi 5Rote of the Endless MindLocation: Black Leopard SchoolEffects: Chi 5, Focus 5Scales of the SerpentLocation: Imperial ArenaEffects: Intimidation 1, Health 7Spiritual SacrificeLocation: The NecropolisEffects: Chi -10Strength of WoodLocation: Pirate Workshop.Effects: Health 2Structured BodyLocation: Spirit CaveEffects: Intimidation 1, Health 3Swallow's GraceLocation: Tien's LandingEffects: Charm 3, Intuition -1Turning WheelLocation: Dirge TempleEffects: Chi 7, Focus 7Theories of MedicineLocation: Imperial City Market DistrictEffects: Intuition 1, Focus 7Tiger MantraLocation: Zin BuEffects: Health 5, Focus 5Tracking EyeLocation: Great Southern ForestEffects: Charm -1, Focus 7Vigorous BodyLocation: Imperial ArenaEffects: Health 10, Chi -2Viper's WitLocation: Swamp CaveEffects: Charm 1, Focus 2Warrior of the Infinite SpiritLocation: Imperial Palace Audience ChamberEffects: Charm 1, Chi 7Warrior of the Inner EyeLocation: Black Leopard SchoolEffects: Intuition 1, Focus 7Warrior of the Unyielding HeartLocation: Zin BuEffects: Health 7Window to the AbyssLocation: Lotus Assassin FortressEffects: Chi 10, Focus -3MinigamesIn addition to the regular gameplay for Jade Empire, there is also two minigames available for players:The first being a simple drinking contest in various tea houses where players can try to out drink regular punters resulting in some witty and drunken dialogue.The other is a top down minigame for the flying machines used in the game. Players must fight their way through waves of enemy flying machines collecting health, chi and weapon drops as they go along before facing a boss at the end of each game.Romance OptionsJade Empire has a number of romance options for players to experience and try out enticing some replay value for the game. This is done through in-game dialogue between the player and their companions, saying or doing certain actions will increase your standing with certain companions resulting in the possibility to romance them.What is notable about the romance options in the game is that there is the choice for heterosexual and homosexual encounters for both Male and Female player characters. The scene for the romance option occurs on the eve before the battle at the temple of Dirge against the Imperial Army. However it should be noted that if the character and their partner are of the same sex the camera pans out before the actual kiss unlike the heterosexual romance scene where the kiss is shown.There is also the possibility for male player characters to romance both Silk Fox and Dawn Star at the same time, although this is rather difficult, and as the dialogue for the romance scene hints at, the player appears to sleep with both of them. Resulting in a threesome.Open Palm  Closed FistJust like many other BioWare games (such as the games of the Knights of the Old Republic and Mass Effect franchises), Jade Empire offers a behavioral spectrum that the player's choices will effect. In Jade Empire, the spectrum exists between the extremes of the Way of the Open Palm and the Way of the Closed Fist. The game stresses that these are not analogues to " good" and " evil" however - the Way of the Open Palm stresses a connection and interdependency between oneself, other people, and the world; the Way of the Closed Fist stresses competition and self-reliance. One's position along the spectrum affects what styles are available to be learned and what quests are available to be completed.ModsUnfortunately Bioware decided not to release any modding tools for Jade Empire. In hindsight it could be speculated that this is one of the reasons - if not the main reason - why the game did not leave the same lasting impression as other Bioware titles. There is no toolset and no source code for most of the game's scripts. The modding community jumped in and ported most of their KotOR tools to Jade Empire - except one: MDLOps. MDLOps made it possible to export KoTORs models to 3d-editors and import them back into the game. Without MDLOps the world of the Jade Empire remained ineditable. It's quite possible that this missing puzzle piece is the reason why the modding activity around this game fizzled rather quickly.There were some smaller mods - most of which are lost now. The majority of these made NPC styles available to PCs. In 2011 however a rather large mod named Jade Empire in Style appeared. This mod more than doubles the number of styles and adds a substantial number of techniques, gems and other items. It also alters the game's rules to give it more replayability.Limited  Special EditionsThe Xbox Limited Edition of the game came with extra content such as a video detailing the making of the game as well as an extra character skin for players to choose from named Monk Zeng. It also came with demos for Forza Motorsport, Conker Live  Reloaded as well as MechAssault 2: Lone Wolf.The PC Special Edition of the game consisted of the following:Monk Zeng characterIncreased resolutions, new special effects, improved textures, ability to import save games.Two extra martial arts styles "Iron Palm" and "Viper" style.New monsters such as the Rhino Demon.More higher level weapons.Improved NPC AI in combat allowing them to take cover and block more often."Jade Master" difficulty setting.New world map interface.Bonus art book and world map.Keyboard  Mouse support.SoundtrackTrackTrack NameLength1The Way of the Open Palm1:372Jade Empire Main Theme2:573Hills and Fields/Dance of the Babbling Brook/Fallow Ground5:134Fist/Test Your Mettle2:495Dawn Star Theme1:126The Tea House1:427Fury, Hammer and Tongs3:058Anthem of the Tyrant2:379Buried Secrets/Whispers3:2110Mischief in the Marsh1:4311Empire at War3:0212Death's Hand Suite3:5413A Night Out1:3714Fires of Chaos1:2715House of Spirits/The Dark Land3:1816Metropolis I and II3:2017Ill Winds2:4718Ballad of the Drunken Revelers1:4719Call to Victory1:3720Into the Fray3:2621The Waterdragon2:3522Last Rites/Internment3:1023Silk Fox Theme1:1424Wine and Women1:3525Lost in the Wilds/The Hunt3:2826Sky Theme1:0827Tribute1:3828Rending of the Flesh2:0529Soaring/Stormclouds2:1130Torment/The Way of the Closed Fist2:4931Sanctuary1:43Xbox OriginalsOn September 22, 2008, Jade Empire became available on the Xbox 360's Xbox Originals download service for 1200 Microsoft Points.</description><genres><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16909">Mass Effect</game><game id="18741">Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic</game><game id="8852">Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic II - The Sith Lords</game><game id="9953">Neverwinter Nights</game><game id="9061">Neverwinter Nights 2</game><game id="2092">Fable: The Lost Chapters</game><game id="3264">Fable</game><game id="7048">Kingdom of Paradise</game><game id="17949">The Elder Scrolls III: Tribunal</game><game id="21590">Mass Effect 2</game><game id="26543">DragonSky</game><game id="19848">Summoner</game><game id="30995">Dragon Age II</game><game id="17533">Deus Ex</game><game id="9883">Deus Ex: Invisible War</game><game id="21198">Shadowrun</game><game id="4505">Vampire: The Masquerade - Redemption</game><game id="16426">Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines</game><game id="29935">Mass Effect 3</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2129484-box_jempire.png</image></root>