<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8605</id><name>Marvel vs. Capcom: Clash of Super Heroes</name><description>OverviewMarvel vs. Capcom: Clash of Super Heroes is a 2D tag-team fighting game developed and released by Capcom for the arcades (under the CPS-2 engine) on January 23, 1998. The third installment of the Marvel vs. Capcom crossover series (and sequel to Marvel Super Heroes vs. Street Fighter), the game adds fighters from various Capcom games (unlike the previous games, which were strictly from Street Fighter Alpha 2) to fight alongside Marvel's superheroes. The installment also adds the concept of "partners" (special assist characters taking the place of the backup character in "assist attacks") and "Duo Team Attack" (a timed event in which the backup character jumps in and both characters are controlled simultaneously, having unlimited use of Super Moves).The game was ported to the Dreamcast on September 30, 1999, adding a new game mode (called Cross Fever), which allows four-player simultaneous gameplay. It was later ported to the PlayStation on January 31, 2000, removing the tag-team mechanics for normal gameplay (restricting it to traditional 1v1 round-based fights, in which "assist attacks" can be performed by either partner characters or secondary characters), while re-adding the Crossover mode from previous ports (in which the tag-team mechanic is brought back, but each player's secondary character is the opposing player's primary character).GameplayRyu unleashing his superMarvel vs. Capcom: Clash of Super Heroes was distinguishable from the rest in the series due to the ability to call upon the help from "assist" characters, as well as the ability to perform a special attack where both of the characters would be in the field at the same time. The game plays quicker than other 2D fighting games at the time. Play focuses heavily on quick reactions, smart team management, and both solo and team super moves.In addition, this game introduced the Duo Team Attack. In the Duo Team Attack, both characters on the team could be controlled simultaneously and had an unlimited use of super moves during the time. In the PlayStation version, the Duo Team Attack worked where the assist character could be summoned repeatedly during this time. The game starts off and the player gets to choose two characters. Then, the fighting starts, with randomly selected pairs of other characters gradually increasing in difficulty until the final boss, Onslaught.CharactersMarvelFightersSpider-Man, one of the key characters in Marvel's assortment of fightersCaptain AmericaGambitHulk (has a secret orange variation)Onslaught (unplayable final boss with two forms)Spider-ManVenom (has a secret variation resembling Carnage)War Machine (has a secret golden variation)WolverineSpecial PartnersColossusCyclopsIcemanJubileeJuggernautMagnetoPsylockeRogueSentinel (hidden, must be inputted via a special codeStormThorU.S. AgentCapcomFightersRyu, one of the key characters in Capcom's assortment of fightersCaptain Commando (from Captain Commando)Chun-Li (from Street Fighter II, has a secret "cyborg" variation, named Shadow Lady)Jin (from Cyberbots: Full Metal Madness)Mega Man (from the classic Mega Man series)Morrigan (from the Darkstalkers series, has a secret variation resembling Lilith)Roll (from the classic Mega Man series, secret character)Ryu (from Street Fighter II, has the ability to switch, in mid-game, between his, Ken's, and Akuma's move sets)Strider Hiryu (from the Strider series)Zangief (from Street Fighter II, has the ability to, in mid-game, transform his body to iron)Special PartnersAnita (from the Darkstalkers series)Arthur (from the Ghosts 'n Goblins series)Devilot (from Cyberbots: Full Metal Madness)Lou  Siva (from Three Wonders, more specifically Midnight Wanderers: Quest for the Chariot)Michelle Heart (from Legendary Wings)Pure  Fur (from Capcom World 2: Adventure Quiz)Saki (from Quiz Nanairo Dreams: Nijiiro-chou no Kiseki)Shadow (hidden "cyborg" variation of Charlie from the Street Fighter Alpha series, must be inputted via a special code)Ton Pooh (from the Strider series)Unknown Soldier (from Forgotten Worlds)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1615">Street Fighter III: 3rd Strike</game><game id="20449">Mortal Kombat vs. DC Universe</game><game id="10574">X-Men: Children of the Atom</game><game id="11156">X-Men vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="16793">Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors</game><game id="1541">Darkstalkers 3</game><game id="13999">Kizuna Encounter: Super Tag Battle</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="19134">Street Fighter Alpha 2</game><game id="22879">Mega Man 2: The Power Fighters</game><game id="22820">Red Earth</game><game id="12125">Capcom Fighting Evolution</game><game id="7527">Marvel Ultimate Alliance</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="18240">The King of Fighters 2003</game><game id="9542">Night Warriors: Darkstalkers' Revenge</game><game id="17743">Super Smash Bros. Melee</game><game id="10126">X-Men: Next Dimension</game><game id="3965">X-Men: Mutant Academy 2</game><game id="16349">Justice League Task Force</game><game id="8899">Marvel Super Heroes in War of the Gems</game><game id="22629">Rage of the Dragons</game><game id="5964">The King of Fighters '99</game><game id="5030">The King of Fighters XI</game><game id="28102">Kabuki Ittou Ryoudan</game><game id="617">NeoGeo Battle Coliseum</game><game id="20728">Tatsunoko vs. Capcom: Ultimate All Stars</game><game id="30399">Spider-Man: Shattered Dimensions</game><game id="30558">Sunday vs. Magazine: Shuuketsu! Choujou Daikessen</game><game id="34082">Skullgirls</game><game id="32161">Street Fighter X Tekken</game><game id="25247">Iron Man 2</game><game id="36051">Ougon Musou Kyoku</game><game id="40803">Street Fighter X Mega Man</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1791299-box_mvc.png</image></root>