<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8612</id><name>Metro Cross</name><description>Overview:You're Winner! You are a contestant on the       futuristic game show:  Metro Cross. In order to win, you must run along an obstacle course, jumping over giant      soda cans and hurdles, as well as avoiding green tiles that will slow you down. Every level has a very strict amount of time to finish with, but whatever time is left over from your first three rounds will carry on to the fourth. Power-ups:Blue soda can- A small, stationary can of soda. Kicking this will give you points, stomping on it will give you a temporary stop on the clock. The points you get depend on how many times you've kicked it.  Green Soda Can-A larger can. Kicking this will give you a temporary burst of speed, and stomping it will stop the clock.  Skateboard-Increases your speed and lets you move freely on green tiles, but jumping or getting hit will lose it. Getting on a skateboard when you're already on one will result in bonus points.  Ramps-Yellow ramp-like trampolines often line the courses. They do almost nothing unless you time your jump as you hit one, launching you several yards forward.  Obstacles:Sentient cans like to mess with you. Red Cola Can-These giant cans will often roll at you in patterns. Jump on them and trip, run into them and get squished.  Green Tiles-Stepping on these will drastically lower your speed. Avoid these.  Hurdles-These are just normal hurdles. Jump over, or avoid them.  Vents-These vents shoot what look like party favors underneath you if you step on it, shooting you up several feet before landing, leaving you to recover for a second before running again.  Mice-Some rounds have green mice that will latch on to you, slowing you down for a bit. They will leave you alone after a while, or you can get hit by something else to scare them away.Red Cube of Terror, relaxing at home.   Giant Red Cube of Terror-This cube will rotate slowly along the Y-axis.   Small Pool-At least that's what it looks like. These glassy, light-blue tiles will swallow you up if you jump in.  Pillars-These pillars move up and down rapidly, making jumps difficult to time.  Bouncy Tires-These tires will bounce at you. Run underneath them.  Time-   Time limits are strict in this game, so stomp the hell out of some cans. Running out of time means     electrocution.  Trivia:In  Metro Cross' only significant contribution to gaming culture, the main screen's theme music was later used as the musical backing to the "theme song" for Namco's 2009 PSN release  Noby Noby Boy.  </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="3">Sports</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="35731">Aero-Cross</game><game id="17616">Seicross</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/3/33870/1095887-metrocrossfront.jpg</image></root>