<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8614</id><name>Wolfenstein: Enemy Territory</name><description>OverviewWolfenstein: Enemy Territory was originally planned to be an expansion pack to Return to Castle Wolfenstein, and later planned to be its own standalone title. There were problems, however, with the single player portion, so rather then fix the problems, id released Enemy Territory as a free multiplayer game. The game was originally released with 6 maps and various game types. Later, the source code for the game was released, which opened the door for vast amounts of user created content. The game was created using a modified RTCW engine, which is related to the Quake III: Arena engine. Today, most ET servers run community generated content.The game later had a spiritual sequel in Quake Wars: Enemy territory.Gameplay  In Wolf: ET the players are split between axis and allies who choose one of five classes and attempt to complete objectives against the defending team. The defending team has 30 minutes to prevent completion of the objective. The game released with 6 maps that spanned 2 campaigns, victory over a campaign was based on winning 2 out of 3 matches, and later, more maps and content were created by the community.Experience and perksThroughout the campaign players earn experience points in 3 areas; light weapons,battle sense, and a unique player skill. This alters the game as the campaign progresses as perks are awarded.The default server settings erase all points and perks at the beginning of a new campaign or upon disconnection with the server. There are modified settings that do allow for XP saves allowing you to carry your skills across multiple campaigns or a preset limit of time. Each skill has 4 levels to obtain in which you earn these rewards, at 20, 50, 90 and 140 experience points. Light Weapons - Rewards all player classes for kills with pistols and other non class specific weapons. Players earn 3 XP per kill with a grenade, a Legshot, an Armshot or a Bodyshot and 5 XP per kill with a Headshot.  Level 1 - Improved use of Light Weapon AmmunitionWhen you respawn, you will have an extra clip of ammunition.Level 2 - Faster ReloadYou reload your weapons 33% faster.Level 3 - Improved Light Weapon HandlingReduces recoil and spread by 50% for pistols and 33% for sub machine guns.Level 4 - Dual-Wield PistolsYou can now dual wield pistols akimbo style, this is not automatically selected for you and you must go into the menu and select it as your weapon.Battle Sense - Players gain ZERO points for each 30 seconds survived while not actively in combat. You'll earn 2XP per 30 seconds while inflicting damage on the other team, 5XP per 30 seconds while inflicting and receiving damage  lastly you earn 8XP if you are actively killing the opposing team and receiving damage.  Level 1 - BinocularsBinoculars which can be used to reconnoiter enemy positions. Covert Ops can use Binoculars to spot Land Mines and alert the rest of the team.Level 2 - Improved Physical FitnessThe benefits of prolonged combat activity enable your Stamina bar to recharge at 160%.Level 3 - Improved HealthYour combat expertise effectively increases your health by 15 points.Level 4 - Trap Awareness You can now sense enemy Land Mines without the aid of Binoculars. Any mines within a certain range will appear as transparent outlines in your field of vision. However only the covert ops class can make the rest of the team aware of mines that you have foundClass specific rewardsHeavy Weapons (Soldier) - 3XP for kills with soldier heavy weapons regardless of splash damage or a direct hit.    Level 1 - Improved Projectile ResourcesPanzerfaust and Mortar will now take 33% less Power than previously.Level 2 - Heavy Weapon ProficiencyEmplaced or Mobile Machine Gun will cool down  at double the normal rate.Level 3 - Improved DexterityLower movement penalty when using heavy weapons.Level 4 - Improved Weapon HandlingYou can now equip an SMG in your pistol slot.First Aid (Medic) - 1 XP for healing using a medpack and 4 xp for reviving using a syringe  Level 1 - Medic AmmoMedics receive an extra ammunition clip and grenade when spawning.Level 2 - Improved ResourcesMedic can have 2 more syringes and gets 2 additional syringes when spawning. Medic pack takes 15% of power bar instead of 25%Level 3 - Full reviveSyringes now return teammates to full healthLevel 4 - Adrenalin selfGives adrenaline needles that you can use on yourself to decrease damage taken by half and Stamina bar will not decrease for 10 seconds Engineering (Engineer):3 XP for repairing a vehicle or MG.5 XP for constructing something that takes 50% of power bar (eg. a MG nest)7.5 XP for constructing something that takes 100% of power bar (eg. a Tank)10 XP for destroying an objective3 XP for Rifle Grenade kill4 XP for a landmine or dynamite kill or defusing a landmine6 XP for defusing enemy dynamite.  Level 1 - Improved use of Explosive ammunationInventory includes 4 extra Rifle Grenades and 4 extra Hand GrenadesLevel 2 - Improved DexterityAllows Engineer to arm and defuse dynamites and land mines in half the timeLevel 3 - Improved Construction and DestructionConstructing and repairing objects and setting dynamites and land mines uses 1/3rd less Power bar than normal.Level 4 - Issued Flak JacketDeflects 50% of the explosive damageSignals (Field Ops):1 XP for giving other players ammo packs3 XP for every enemy player killed using air strike4 XP for every enemy player killed using Artillery5 XP for every objective destoryed by either of these  Level 1 - Improved ResourcesEvery ammo pack will include extra ammo clip and giving them out takes 15% of the power barLevel 2 - Improved SignalsCalling artillery or air strike takes 2/3rd of your power barLevel 3 - Improved Air and Ground supportEach air strike has now 2 aircrafts incoming and artillery is twice as longLevel 4 - Enemy RecognitionPlacing your cross-hairs over an undercover enemy Covert Op gives "Disguised Enemy" message and shows their location on command map. Covert Operations (Covert Ops):Scoped weapons:5 XP for kills using a headshot3 XP for kills using a bodyshot3 XP for spotting landmines5 XP for disgusing themselves using enemy uniform5 XP for every kill using satchel charge7 XP for destroying an objective using satchel charge  Level 1 - Improved use of Scoped Weapon AmmunationEach ammo pack gives extra clip of scoped ammunationLevel 2 - Improved use of Sabotage and MisdirectionPlayer can use satchel charges more often as power bar usage is reduced by 1/3rdLevel 3 - Breath ControlReduces both recoil jump and weapon sway with scoped weapons Level 4 - AssassinAllows to instant kill using any backstabModsBecause source code of the game logic was released in a SDK in early 2004, various mods have been created by the community. Some of the most popular ones are:    Jaymod -Many new features, mostly used in fun servers     ETpub - Mod, which tries to keep original look of the game with no giantic differences from base game     No Quarter - Originally based of ETpub, features higher levels, new guns and many other improvements and bugfixes    ETpro - The mod used for competitions    True Combat Elite - A mod that largely changes the look of the game  ETTVETTV is a special modification that allows other people to spectate matches, allowing people to see matches of, for example, tournaments live in game, using the spectator function ingame. Most of the viewable games are seen on    gamestv.org.Download Wolfenstein: Enemy Territory  Enemy Territory Ultimate Installer is a compilation installer that includes the latest version of ET with the most common modifications and maps.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18883">Enemy Territory: Quake Wars</game><game id="18162">Team Fortress 2</game><game id="7747">John Romero's Daikatana</game><game id="21912">Planetside: Core Combat</game><game id="5274">Battlefield 1942: Secret Weapons of WWII</game><game id="14947">ÜberSoldier</game><game id="21388">Quake Live</game><game id="26694">Brink</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/6805/271947-et_logo_1_.jpg</image></root>