<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8616</id><name>Project I.G.I.: I'm Going In</name><description>OverviewProject IGI: I'm Going In is one of the first computer games to feature realistic weaponry and tactical combat situations. You play as former Special Air Service operative David Llewellyn Jones on a mission to the former Soviet Union to find Russian arms dealer Josef Priboi , and retrieve information on a stolen nuclear warhead. A sequel was released in 2003 called Project IGI 2: Covert Strike.Uniquely among FPS' of the time I.G.I. had no mid mission checkpoint or save system, this combined with the more realistic weapon damage model and open level design made for a very challenging and occasionaly frustrating game.CharactersDavid Llewellyn Jones - The main character of the game, a former British SAS operator, now an agent for I.G.I. (Institute for Geotactical Intelligence).Rebecca Anya - Anya is Jones' radio contact at headquarters.Jach Priboi - Soviet Arms Dealer.Josef Priboi - Jach's Nephew.Ekk - Homicidal Russian woman who intends to destroy Europe by nuclear warfare.Captain Harrison - An ex-Green Beret and the commander of allied troops.PC System RequirementsAs stated by the Eidos Interactive Support Center.Minimum System Requirements:IBM PC or 100% compatibleMicrosoft Windows 95/98Pentium II 300 MHz64 MB System RAM100% DirectX 7.0a-compatible 3d Accelerated Card with 8MB VRAM100% DirectX 7.0a-compatible Sound CardQuad Speed (4X) CD-ROM drive500MB free uncompressed hard drive space100% Windows 95/98 compatible mouse and keyboardRecommended System Requirements:Pentium III equivalent or greater128 MB System RAM100% DirectX 7.0a-compatible 3d Accelerated Card with 16 MB VRAM100% DirectX 7.0a-compatible Sound CardEight-speed (8x) CD-ROM drive or faster500 MB free uncompressed hard drive space</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11364">Project IGI 2: Covert Strike</game><game id="4319">Delta Force</game><game id="12015">Delta Force 2</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/9450/1228287-projectigi.jpg</image></root>