<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8697</id><name>The Simpsons Wrestling</name><description>OverviewThe Simpsons Wrestling is a comedic professional wrestling style game starring the characters from the animated television show. Centered around exaggerated brawls between the cast of characters, the game featured the same voice talent heard in the series.CharactersHomer SimpsonMarge SimpsonBart SimpsonLisa SimpsonMr. Burns and Waylon Smithers - Smithers throws radioactive rods from the side of the ring at the enemy, while Mr. Burns fights.Kang and Kodos - These are the "boss" characters, that must be fought at the end of the game.Apu Nahasapeemapetilon - Throws slushies as their ranged attack.Itchy and Scratchy - Instead of building their TAUNT meter, have an ANVIL meter, which, when full, will drop an anvil on the enemy.Groundskeeper WillieBarney GumbleMoe the BartenderProfessor FrinkBumblebee ManKrusty the ClownNed Flanders - Can 'resurrect' once upon defeat.Gameplay MechanicsWhen the player fills up their TAUNT meter, which is done by collecting various letters from around the ring, then they will become invincible for a certain amount of time. Which usually meant that during this time, the match could be one due to some issues about the length of this. However, when playing as Ned Flanders, you can play, and God will give you a hand to make sure that your opponent takes a lot of damage, which makes this character very hard to unlock.ReceptionBrought out in 2001, this game was mostly given bad reviews, for its bad graphics, audio design, and overly simplistic gameplay.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre><genre id="10">Wrestling</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="12592">WWE SmackDown! vs. RAW 2008</game><game id="15815">WWE SmackDown! Here Comes the Pain</game><game id="3826">WWF Super Wrestlemania</game><game id="18801">WWF War Zone</game><game id="11394">WWF No Mercy</game><game id="17436">WWF SmackDown!</game><game id="4155">WWF Raw</game><game id="7485">WWF In Your House</game><game id="4315">WWE Crush Hour</game><game id="3732">WWE WrestleMania X8</game><game id="23204">Galactic Wrestling: Featuring Ultimate Muscle</game><game id="42353">Popeye 3: WrestleCrazy</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1795751-box_simpwrstl.png</image></root>