<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8733</id><name>Adventures in the Magic Kingdom</name><description>Adventures in the Magic Kingdom is a game revolving around an unknown character who must track down six silver keys by completing stages based on attractions at the Magic Kingdom in Walt Disney World.PremiseMickey Mouse is ready to open the gates of the Magic Kingdom for a big parade, but Goofy accidentally lost an essential key. It is up the player, controlling an unnamed figure in a cowboy hat, to recover the six silver keys.Stages and GameplayThe game is split into five levels based on Disneyland rides and a park wide trivia challenge. The player can chose to tackle the levels in any order they choose. In each of the five levels you can collect stars. These can be spent at almost any time during a game by pressing select and pulling up the star item store. Here you can buy life, ammo, 1-ups and limited invincibility. Correct use of these power up is crucial to winning the game.LEVELS:Space Mountain - This stage pits the player in the role of a spaceship captain docked at Star A, trying to pilot his ship to Star F. The player must match button presses with what is shown on the screen. The arrow keys are used to maneuver the ship, and the A and B buttons are used to fire lasers. Five mismatched or missed button presses will result in a loss. Making it to Star F will win the level and net you a keyAutopia - The player will race against eight computer controlled cars. However you will always win the race, unless you crash or fall off the course or in the river. The player can drive over jumps to cross chasms or jump over other racers. Protip, when given the choice to take any fork right or left, choose the left path. Making it to the finish line in one piece will net the player the key.Big Thunder Mountain - One of the more unique stages, in which the player controls a speeding locomotive making its way down jumbled sets of tracks. The goal is to make it down the mountain to Train Station #2 while avoiding rocks and multiple dead ends. The train can take five rock hits before failing, but one dead end will end the level.Haunted Mansion - The player must traverse the Haunted Mansion to fight The Phantom. This is a standard platforming level where you must make your way through the front yard and four floors of the mansion. Enemies can be fought with thrown candles. The player starts with ten candles but more can be found throughout the level. The third and fourth floors are the hardest, as the player must jump from floating chairs over bottomless pits (even though its been established that you're in a house with floors underneath that you've just traveled through. On the fourth floor is The Phantom, it takes eight candle hit to kill him. After beating The Phantom the player will earn this levels key.Pirates of the Caribbean - The player must save six damsels in distress from pirates who have recently sacked a local port town. The player has 180 seconds to find all six women and light the signal fire at the very end of the level. You can not light the signal fire without the candle found in the underground location under the city. You have no way to fight the pirates and can only jump over them and the barrels they throw at you. Finding all the women and lighting the fire in under 180 seconds will net you the key.Trivia - there are various kids around the park that seem to know where a key is, but want to make sure that they are giving it to the right person. To be sure, each kid, seven in all, will ask you a Disney Trivia question. Answering correctly will result in being told to find the next kid. The last child will ask you two questions. After answering all the questions, you will be presented with the keyThe locations, in order for the children, are..1. The first child is right by Main Street and Sleeping Beauty's castle (middle of map).2. The second child is by Space Mountain (lower left corner).3. The third child is back by the castle again.4. The fourth child is by It's a Small World (upper left corner).5. The fifth child is at the front gate of the park, the starting location of the game.6. The sixth child will be over by Tom Sawyer's island (upper right corner) with Pluto, who has the key. However, after answering the question correctly, Pluto will run away.7. The last child has Pluto and the key outside Autopia (middle left side). To make sure you really deserve the key, you will be asked two questions. Incorrectly answering thesecond one will make you have to answer two new questions.After collecting all six keys, Sleeping Beauty's castle will unlock and the player will get a congratulations screen.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21133">Six Flags Fun Park</game><game id="7434">Universal Studios Theme Park Adventure</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2361119-nes_adventuresinthemagickingdom.jpg</image></root>