<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8743</id><name>Pump It Up : Prex 3</name><description>Song List Novasonic - Empire of the Sun Pink - Let's Get The Party Started Pink - Let's Get The Party Started BanYa - Come To Me Banyo - Come To Me Papa Gonzales - Bambole Papa Gonzales - Bambole BanYa - Bee Banyo - Bee B-Legit, 2Wice,  4Tray - Burning Krypt B-Legit, 2Wice,  4Tray - Burning Krypt 2wice - Can You Feel Dis or Dat 2wice - Can You Feel Dis or Dat Scoop feat. Scoop feat. Joyce Lyle - Clap your hands Joyce Lyle - clap your hands Queen Latin - Conga Queen Latin - Conga BanYa - D Gang Banyo - D Gang Rodney O  Joe Cooley - Dj Nightmare Rodney O  Joe Cooley - Dj Nightmare Mozquito - Eres Para Mi Mozquito - Eres Mi To DJPaula - Fiesta Macarena Pt.1 DJPaula - Fiesta Macarena Pt.1 BanYa - Hello Banyo - Hello Kay Kent - On Your Side Kay Kent - On Your Side Carlos T. Carlos T. Quila - Everybody Quila - Everybody Gans - Join The Party Gans - Join The Party Fresno - Lay It Down Fresno - Lay It Down Lisa Cool  the South Spirit - Let The Sunshine Lisa Cool  the South Spirit - Let The Sunshine Down Lown - Lovething Down Lown - Lovething Mozquito - Mexi Mexi Mozquito - Mexi Mexi Rodney O  Joe Cooley - You don't wanna runup Rodney O  Joe Cooley - You do not want to runup BanYa - Beat Of The War Banyo - Beat Of The War BanYa - Dr. M Banyo - Dr M BanYa - Get Your Groove On Banyo - Get Your Groove On BanYa - Love is a Danger Zone Banyo - Love is a Danger Zone BanYa - Maria Banyo - Maria BanYa - Winter Banyo - Winter BanYa - Will o' The Wisp Banyo - Will o 'The Wisp BanYa - Oy Oy Oy Banyo - Oy Oy Oy To-Ya - Go Away To-Ya - Go Away Hanul - Gotta Be Kidding! Hanul - Gotta Be Kidding! Diva - PERFECT! Diva - PERFECT! BanYa - Vook Banyo - Vook BanYa - Csikos Post Banyo - Csiki Post Crying Nut - Circus Magic Crying Nut - Circus Magic DUKE - Starian DUKE - Starian BanYa - Chicken Wing Banyo - Chicken Wing BanYa - Radezky Can Can Banyo - Radezky Can Can TTMa - Loner TTMa - Loner E-Paksa - Monkey Magic E-Paks - Monkey Magic Lee Hyun Do - Pierrot Lee Hyun Do - Pierrot BanYa - Final Audition Ep.1 Banyo - Final Audition Ep.1 BanYa - Pump Jump Banyo - Pump Jump BanYa - Rolling Christmas Banyo - Rolling Christmas BanYa - Beethoven Virus Banyo - Beethoven Virus BanYa - All I Want for Xmas Banyo - All I Want for Xmas Deux - Come Back To Me Deux - Come Back To Me Kim Sung Jae - As I Told U Kim Sung Jae - As I Told U Novasonic - Slam Novasonic - Slam E-Paksa - Space Fantasy E-Paks - Space Fantasy BanYa - Oh! Banyo - Oh! Rosa Pink BanYa - First Love Banyo - First Love BanYa - Betrayer Banyo - Betrayer  BanYa - Solitary Banyo - Solitary BanYa - Mr. Larpus Banyo - Mr. Larpus Novasonic - Run! Novasonic - Run! DJ.Doc - Run To You DJ.Doc - Run To You BanYa - Final Audition 2 Banyo - Final Audition 2 BanYa - Naissance Banyo - naissance Banya - Turkey March Banyo - Turkey March BanYa - An Interesting View Banyo - An Interesting View   BanYa - Nightmare Banyo - Nightmare BanYa - She Likes Pizza Banyo - She Likes Pizza BanYa - Pumping Up Banyo - Pumping Up Tashannie - Don't Bother Me Tashannie - Do not bother me Deux - We Are Deux - We Are BanYa - Hate Banyo - Hate BanYa - Koul Banyo - Koul BanYa - Final Audition Banyo - Final Audition BanYa - Extravaganza Banyo - Extravaganza Sechskies - Com' Back Sechskies - With 'Back BanYa - Ignition Starts! Banyo - Ignition Starts! BanYa - Hypnosis Banyo - Hypnosis Yoo Seung Jun - Passion Yoo Seung Jun - Passion Clon - Come To Me Clon - Come To Me Clon - Funky Tonight Clon - Funky Tonight Novasonic - Another Truth Novasonic - Another Truth </description><genres><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="19">Music/Rhythm</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11694">Dance Dance Revolution SuperNOVA</game><game id="7010">StepMania</game><game id="21746">Dance Dance Revolution SuperNOVA 2</game><game id="25024">Dance ManiaX 2nd MIX</game><game id="29418">Dance Dance Revolution</game><game id="31119">Dance Dance Revolution USA</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/15228/856906-piu.jpg</image></root>