<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8768</id><name>Capcom vs. SNK: Millennium Fight 2000</name><description>OverviewCapcom vs SNK: Millennium Fight 2000 is a 2D fighting game developed and distributed by Capcom for the arcades in 2000 (and later released by Capcom for the Dreamcast on November 9, 2000). Developed for the Sega NAOMI arcade hardware, the game pits characters from Capcom and SNK fighting game franchises in a massive team-based martial arts tournament. Playing like a traditional fighting game, Capcom vs SNK: Millennium Fight 2000 includes a "Ratio" system, in which variable-sized teams are built from characters of different strengths, and a "Groove" system, in which players can choose between two variations of super meters.The game was updated a year later in Capcom vs SNK: Millennium Fight 2000 Pro, making use of the GD-ROM upgrade for the Sega NAOMI while adding new characters (Dan Hibiki and Joe Higashi) and new moves for existing characters. This version was released for the Dreamcast (only in Japan) and was later ported and released worldwide to the PlayStation. A sequel was later developed, called Capcom vs SNK 2: Mark of the Millennium 2001, which builds upon the "Ratio" and "Groove" systems while adding new characters and game mechanics. SNK's entry into the crossover fighting game series, SNK Vs. Capcom: Chaos, was planned to be released at the same time as this game, but was delayed for years after the company went bankrupt.GameplayBasic MovesThe gameplay and basic moves in the game are more towards the SNK fighting games. The game uses four buttons instead of six - Light Punch, Hard Punch, Light Kick, Hard Kick.- and other technique can be done using combination of those four buttons.Capcom VS SNK has a couple of basic moves. The First is the Roll mechanic which is done by pressing the Light punch and Light kick simultaneously. It makes the player's character invincible and it's also good for evading all attacks. Other basic moves in the game that there is the Throw and Tech Throw; the Throw is done by pressing forward or back on the D-Pad or Joystick and pressing Hard punch or Hard kick simultaneously. The Tech Throw is a cancel Throw that is done by pressing forward or back when the player is about to be thrown. The other basic moves in the game is dashing or running that the player can choose to use in the options menu. The Dash is done tapping forward or back on the Joystick or D-Pad and same thing for the run.The Sakazaki stage.PresentationAll of the SNK characters are fully redrawn for the game and some of the Capcom characters as well. But as for the rest of the characters have not been redrawn; their sprites have been taken from where they originated - Street Fighter Alpha and DarkStalkers. 3D visual have been used for the projectiles attacks and other effects to give the game a unique look.The stages have special intros for all the stages - which is a bit of a nod to some of the SNK fighting games. Some of the stages have neat little effects; for example, in the Sakazaki stage, when a character gets slam into the ground the roof comes crashing down little by lillte.Another way to earn VS points.Secret ShopSecret Shop is a mode in the game were the player goes to unlock all the secrets in the game. All the secrets in the Secret Shop contains more characters, more colors for the character's outfits, stages, EX versions of some of the characters, game modes, music, and many more. The way the player unlocks the secrets is by spending "VS points" that the player can earn in the arcade mode or the training mode. One cool feature that player can do is hook up their Neo-Geo pocket with a copy of SNK VS Capcom to transfer more points to Capcom VS SNK.EX VersionOnce unlock from the Secret Shop, the player has the option to choose an "EX" version of some of the characters. What EX does is it change up the moves-set - specials and super moves.Color Edit Mode.Color Edit ModeColor edit is a feature in the game that allows the player to edit the colors of the a character's outfit.Ratio SystemBefore a match, the roster is broking up into four Ratio teirs; each character is place in the Ratio teirs in terms of their offense and defense. The player is giving four "points" and spents those points by picking their characters; for example, characters like Ryu  Kyo are in the Ratio two teirs. So the player can spent all four points by picking Ryu  Kyo and have a team of two. Or can have a team four if the player decides to pick just the Ratio one characters like Sakura  Yuri.Ratio 1: Weak Offense, Weak DefenseRatio 2: Average Offense, Average DefenseRatio 3: Strong Offense, Strong DefenseRatio 4: Strongest Offense, Strongest DefenseThe Grooves.GroovesThe game features two "Grooves" that the player can select before he or she picks her characters. Each Grooves determinds how the special meters are used during a fight.Capcom Groove: The Capcom groove is similar to the Street Fighter Alpha super meter were the players is given three levels of super.SNK Groove: The SNK groove, based on the super meter in The King of Fighters '94, is used by charging up the character by pressing the Hard punch and Hard kick button simutaneously. The other feature of the SNK groove is when the player's health bar gets decrease at a certain point where it's blinking, the player can perform unlimted amounts of super moves.CharactersThe game includes 33 playable fighters, split up into four ratios.CapcomRatio 1 (Weak)BlankaCammyDhalsimSakuraRatio 2 (Normal)BalrogChun-LiE. HondaGuileKenMorrigan (unlockable)RyuZangiefRatio 3 (Strong)M. Bison (boss)SagatVegaRatio 4 (Strongest)Akuma (hidden)Evil Ryu (hidden)SNKRatio 1 (Weak)BenimaruKingViceYuriRatio 2 (Normal)IoriKimKyoMaiNakoruru (unlockable)RaidenRyoTerryRatio 3 (Strong)Geese (boss)RugalYamazakiRatio 4 (Strongest)Wild Iori (hidden)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1615">Street Fighter III: 3rd Strike</game><game id="16793">Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="32161">Street Fighter X Tekken</game><game id="30558">Sunday vs. Magazine: Shuuketsu! Choujou Daikessen</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2179471-box_cvs.png</image></root>