<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8844</id><name>Need for Speed: Carbon</name><description>OverviewNeed for Speed: Carbon is a racing game and the tenth game in the       Need for Speed franchise .It is a direct sequel to       Need for Speed: Most Wanted and is the first Need for Speed to be released on all seventh generation consoles.PlotThe game begins after the events of Most Wanted with the player on the road back into  Palmont City after having left some time ago. While driving the player flashes back to the events that happened on the night the player left but the player's flashback is rudely interrupted by former Sergeant turned bounty hunter Cross, who rams the player's car and chases the player until he wrecks his BMW. Cross corners the player but before he can detain him, Darius, a former ally, shows up with his crew and your ex-girlfriend Nikki (Emanuelle Vaugier) and pays him off. Darius leaves Nikki to update the player on the current situation in Palmont City. The player is then tasked with regaining his lost reputation by winning races, acquiring territories and beating the bosses of the resident street racing crews (Kenji, Angie and Wolf). As the crews are defeated, various former members come forward and offer further details about the night the player left.Once the player owns all three districts, Darius asks the player to meet him, where he reveals that he was just using the player to gain territory and leaves the player to be arrested. However, Nikki shows up to rescue the player and reveal the whole story behind the night the player left. It was actually Darius that framed the player by switching the bag containing the money and allowing the player to escape the police raid. Nikki finally agrees to team up with the player to take over Silverton and take down Darius and his Stacked Deck crew. Before the player can take on Darius in the Canyon, they must defeat the previous three bosses.Once the player has defeated Darius, Darius hands the player the keys to his Audi Le Mans Quattro and agrees to leave Palmont City. He leaves the player a final warning - "Enjoy it while it lasts. There's always someone out there who's a little faster than you are. And sooner or later, they're going to catch up". Gameplay Screenshot from the Xbox 360 version.In Need for Speed: Carbon you race against rival       street racing crews in a quest to conquer territories and districts. The player is in charge of its own crew and can hire specialists that can provide the player with much needed help both during and off races.  Race types        Drift - Drift racing makes a return in Carbon, a mode that was made popular i n       Need for Speed: Undergroundand       Need for Speed: Underground 2 but was cut out of Carbon's predecessor       Need for Speed: Most Wanted.  Canyon Racing - This mode involves four different type of races, Canyon Duel, Canyon Race, Canyon       Checkpoint and Canyon Drift. Checkpoint - Similar to the Toolboth races in Need for Speed: Most Wanted. Sprint   Circuit  Race wars   CustomizationCarbon introduced a more robust car customization to the series and included a feature called "Autosculpt" where you could adjust sliders to different parts and they would morph freely from one size/design to another, allowing for seemingly unlimited control over exactly how you wanted something to look - getting away from a set list of defined choices in previous games.  Parts from real world manufacturers were also included and could in most cases be "sculpted" as well.  The inclusion of an improved layers system called "vinyls" allowed the player to further customize the car with various shapes and characters, allowing some skilled players to make wildly complex designs using primitives as the building blocks - something that would become a major feature of later games in the genre. Car List  Muscle Cars     1967 Chevrolet Camaro SS     1970 Chevrolet Chevelle SS 454     2005 Chrysler 300C SRT-8           1971 Dodge Challenger     1969 Dodge Charger R/T     2006 Dodge Charger SRT-8     2006 Ford Mustang GT     1969 Plymouth Road Runner     2006 Pontiac GTO     2005 Vauxhall Monaro VXR           2006 Chevrolet Camaro Concept     2006 Chevrolet Corvette Z06     2008 Dodge Challenger     2006 Dodge Viper SRT-10     1967 Ford Mustang Shelby GT500     2007 Ford Mustang Shelby GT500     1970 Plymouth Barracuda     2005 Ford GTTuner Cars     2004 Lexus IS300     2007 Mazda 3 MPS     2003 Mazda RX-8     1992 Nissan 240 SX       1999 Mazda RX-7     1999 Mitsubishi Eclipse GSX     2006 Mitsubishi Eclipse GT     2005 Renault Clio V6     1986 Toyota Corolla GT-S (AE86)     1992 Toyota MR2     2006 Volkswagen Golf R32         2004 Infiniti G35     2006 Mitsubishi Lancer EVO IX MR     2006 Nissan 350Z     1999 Nissan Skyline R34 GT-R     2006 Subaru Impreza WRX STI     1999 Toyota SupraExotic Cars     2006 Alfa Romeo Brera     2005 Mercedes-Benz CLK500          2004 Aston Martin DB9     2007 Jaguar XK     2004 Lotus Elise 111R     2006 Lotus Europa S     2005 Mercedes-Benz SL65 AMG     2006 Porsche Cayman S         2007 Audi R8/LeMans Quattro     2003 BMW M3 GTR     2006 Koenigsegg CCX     2006 Lamborghini Gallardo     2004 Lamborghini Murciélago     2006 Lamborghini Murciélago LP640     2004 Mercedes-Benz SLR McLaren     2006 Pagani Zonda F     2006 Porsche 911 GT3 RS     2006 Porsche 911 Turbo S     2004 Porsche Carrera GT     2005 Ford GT LocationThe game is set in the fictional city of Palmont and in 3 canyons that surround the city, East, West and Carbon. The city is divied into 4 main   parts. These are Fortura, Downtown, Silverton and Kempton.Versions The PC, Xbox 360 and PS3 versions of the game features an online racing mode that can only be seen in these versions, named "Be the Cop".PS2 Canyon Duel.The  Wii version lacks online play but makes use of the innovative motion controls of the Wii Remote. Soundtrack   Dynamite MC - After PartyEagles Of Death Metal - Don’t Speak (I Came to Make A Bang!)Ekstrak feat. Know-1 - Hard DriversEvery Move A Picture - Signs Of LifeGary Numan/Tubeway Army - Are ‘Friends’ ElectricGrandmaster Flash And The Furious Five - ScorpioGoldfrapp Ride A White Horse (Serge Santiago Remix)-Kyuss - HurricaneLady Sovereign - Luv Me Or Hate MeLadytron - Sugar (Jagz Kooner Remix)Ladytron - Fighting In Built Up Areasmelody. - FEEL THE RUSH (Junkie XL Remix)Metro Riots - Thee Small FacesPart 2 feat. Fallacy - One Of Dem Days (Remix)Pharrell feat. Lauren - Skateboard P Presents: Show You How To HustlePriestess - I Am The Night, Colour Me BlackRoots Manuva - No LoveSpank Rock - What It Look LikeSway - Hype BoysThe Bronx - Around The HornThe Presets - SteamworksThe Vacation - I’m No GoodTiga - Good As GoldTigarah - Girl Fight (Mr. D Hyphy Mix)Tomas Andersson - Washing Up (Tiga Remix)Valient Thorr - HeatseekerVitalic - My Friend DarioWolfmother - Joker And The ThiefYonderboi - People Always Talk About The Weather (Junkie XL Remix)</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5881">Forza Motorsport 2</game><game id="18095">Need for Speed: ProStreet</game><game id="6582">Test Drive Unlimited</game><game id="9651">Need for Speed Underground 2</game><game id="20729">GRID</game><game id="19809">Project Gotham Racing 3</game><game id="7777">Juiced</game><game id="5977">Need for Speed III: Hot Pursuit</game><game id="788">The Fast and the Furious</game><game id="252">Tokyo Xtreme Racer Zero</game><game id="10403">Tokyo Xtreme Racer 3</game><game id="5648">Burnout Paradise</game><game id="14975">Import Tuner Challenge</game><game id="21307">Juiced 2: Hot Import Nights</game><game id="11055">NASCAR 08</game><game id="20038">NASCAR: Dirt to Daytona</game><game id="20927">Midnight Club: Los Angeles</game><game id="1101">Ridge Racer 7</game><game id="941">Project Gotham Racing</game><game id="2279">Project Gotham Racing 2</game><game id="8437">TOCA 2: Touring Car Challenge</game><game id="7019">Ridge Racer V</game><game id="16276">Ford Bold Moves Street Racing</game><game id="20919">Ford Racing: Off Road</game><game id="7431">Ford Racing</game><game id="12950">Gran Turismo 3 A-Spec</game><game id="10124">Midnight Club: Street Racing</game><game id="284">NASCAR 2005: Chase for the Cup</game><game id="17872">TOCA Race Driver 3 Challenge</game><game id="8438">NASCAR 06: Total Team Control</game><game id="21657">Initial D: Extreme Stage</game><game id="23461">FUEL</game><game id="21689">Wangan Midnight</game><game id="20418">Midnight Club II</game><game id="1052">Super PickUps</game><game id="20957">Pure</game><game id="3916">DiRT</game><game id="5819">Speed Devils</game><game id="26956">Wangan Midnight Maximum Tune</game><game id="25485">Test Drive Unlimited 2</game><game id="25226">Need for Speed World</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1897544-box_nfsc.png</image></root>