<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8867</id><name>Art of Fighting 3: The Path of The Warrior</name><description>Overview Art of Fighting 3: The Path of the Warrior (known in Japan as Art of Fighting: Ryuuko no Ken Gaiden) is a fighting game developed and published by SNK for the                  Neo Geo. The game uses a new engine with smoother animation and gameplay mechanics built around special "command moves". This game is often compared to                    Street Fighter III: New Generation (released a year later) for its similarities. (Brand new character roster with the exception of the two main characters, parrying, smoother animation)  The game was not as well-known as the previous Art of Fighting games. The game was later released in the                   Neo Geo CD platform with improved music. The game was also released for the                 PlayStation 2 in the                Art of Fighting Anthology compilation.  The story follows Robert Garcia, who meets an old childhood friend in GlassHill,               Mexico. Other characters have stories of their own, such as           Ryo (who is searching for the whereabouts of Robert) and          Kasumi Todoh (who is searching for a battle with Ryo). Gameplay The mechanics in this game are similar to previous Art of Fighting games. The first two buttons are punch and kick, which can be combined with joystick presses to form special "command moves", each with varying strength and utility. The third button is a utility button that allows for strong attacks, throws, and                       parries. (The first fighting game ever to include the concept of parrying) The fourth button is used for taunting. The player can dash forwards and backwards by tapping the joystick in either direction twice. The player can also attack downed opponents through the "pursuit" command move.  Like the previous Art of Fighting games, this game includes the concept of the "spirit gauge", which determines the effectiveness of special moves. The gauge lowers after the player performs a special move. It also depletes when the opponent performs a taunt. The gauge can be recharged by holding down any button. Unlike the previous games, the gauge slowly recharges automatically.  This game has no bonus stages and the player's life and spirit gauges are equal to the opponent's. The player no longer needs to learn super moves in Story mode. "Desperation" moves still exist in this game, which can only be executed when the character itself flashes red (20% life or less). When you finish an opponent with a desperation move and that opponent has 10% life or less, it counts as an "Ultimate K.O.". An Ultimate KO leads to the win of the entire match, even on the first round.Characters                         Robert Garcia                        Ryo Sakazaki                       Kasumi Todoh       Wang Koh San      Karman Cole     Rody Birts     Lenny Creston    Jin Fu-Ha   Sinclair (sub-boss) Wyler (boss)</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8680">Street Fighter Alpha 3 MAX</game><game id="3185">ClayFighter 63 1/3</game><game id="243">Street Fighter II: The World Warrior</game><game id="21344">Hokuto no Ken: Shinpan no Sousousei Kengou Retsuden</game><game id="14929">Real Bout Fatal Fury 2: The Newcomers</game><game id="10827">World Heroes Perfect</game><game id="16064">World Heroes 2 JET</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="16793">Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="21519">The King of Fighters XII</game><game id="22629">Rage of the Dragons</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5822/282162-aof3.jpg</image></root>