<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8881</id><name>The Legend of Zelda: Link's Awakening DX</name><description>OverviewTitle ScreenThe Legend of Zelda: Link's Awakening DX is an enhanced re-release of The Legend of Zelda: Link's Awakening. The game was released for the Game Boy Color in 1998 and features Link getting stranded on Koholint Island where he discovers that he must awaken the Wind Fish if he ever wants to go home.In order to awaken the Wind Fish and get off of Koholint Island, Link has to battle his way through eight dungeons and collect eight Instruments of the Sirens. In each temple there are many enemies, one or more sub-bosses and one main boss (in this game called Nightmares); each Nightmare can be defeated with the aid of a specific item located in the associated dungeon.When Link has acquired all the instruments, he must climb up to the peak of Tal Tal Mountain and play the "Ballad of the Wind Fish" in order to awaken the Wind Fish.Version DifferencesThe new color dungeon.The cartridge is black instead of grey signifying that it is compatible with both the original Game Boy and the Game Boy Color.A color palette has been added.A new color dungeon has been added. If the game is being played on the original Game Boy then two skeleton guards will block the player from entering.The Photo Shop and the photography side quest have been added.The title screen has been changed - the Wind Fish's Egg is now surrounded by clouds.The Stone Slabs and Stone Slab Fragments in dungeons have been replaced by Owl Statues and Stone Beaks. This allows multiple statues (and therefore hints) in a single dungeon.The Start Menu has been altered to show the different tunics if the Select button is pressed.The secret ending has been changed - it now shows a portrait of Marin changing into a seagull instead of her sprite flying across the screen with wings.A Super Game Boy background has been added.Additional dialogue has been added, such as when the player obtains the Seashell Sword or the second boss giving a more specific hint as to his weakness.The genie boss now throws his fireballs more slowly.The infamous hint from the second dungeon has been altered so it describes the enemies instead of naming them (the names were in the original's Japanese manual, but not the other versions').Players can no longer skip all of a character's dialogue by pressing the B button.Fade in/out effects are less exaggerated, such as using a bomb or a dungeon warp.The Select screen jump glitch no longer works.The Photo ShopOne of the major additions to The Legend of Zelda: Link's Awakening DX is the photo shop side quest. In northern Ukuku Prairie is the photo shop, where Link can have his photo taken. Once this has happened, the photo will be placed in the player's very own photo album, entitled "The Travels of Link." From then on the photographer will appear to take photos of various events throughout the game, each of which will be added to the album. These photographs can then be printed off using the Game Boy Printer.There are a total of thirteen photographs in the game, however only twelve can be collected in a given playthrough as the first photograph contains a choice depending on whether or not Link is a willing participant in the photograph. As some of the photographs are of specific scripted events or have specific prerequisites, they can be missed entirely if the player has not obtained the photo album yet, e.g. the photo of Link opening the gate to Kanalet Castle.Virtual Console releaseOn 7th/8th May 2011 (the year of Zelda's 25th anniversary), Link's Awakening DX was released on the 3DS eshop as part of it's Virtual Console range. As with all Virtual Console releases, this is an exact, complete version of the original cart with no added content or 3D enhancements. The single added feature is a quick-save button, allowing the player to quickly leave the game and restore where they left off. Link's Awakening DX is priced at $5.99 in the US, £5.40 in the UK and $9 in AU. The Game Boy Printer does not work with this version however.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9971">Final Fantasy Adventure</game><game id="5570">Alundra</game><game id="2388">StarTropics</game><game id="17335">Zoda's Revenge: Star Tropics II</game><game id="211">Beyond Oasis</game><game id="1320">Klonoa Heroes: Densetsu no Star Medal</game><game id="21554">Star Ocean: Blue Sphere</game><game id="24675">Bomberman Quest</game><game id="12945">Lagoon</game><game id="31363">Xena: Warrior Princess</game><game id="39255">Gheldia</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/82063/2267398-929090-lozlinksawakeningdxus.jpg</image></root>