<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8885</id><name>NES Open Tournament Golf</name><description>OverviewNES Open Tournament Golf is a golf game released on September 1, 1991. While similar in many ways to Golf U.S. Course released on the Famicom Disk System, It features only 3 courses, as opposed to the 5 courses that were featured in the Famicom version. The included Courses are America, Japan and United Kingdom. It is thought that the two cut courses from the Famicom version were removed due to the difficulty. There are also some changes in music between the two versions.GameplayThe first player plays as Mario while an optional second player can play as Luigi. There are also appearances by Princess Peach and Princess Daisy as Caddies. In the game there are four modes that a player can choose from.Stroke Play-Stroke play is a leveling system that can be played to raise between ranks. They start out as a beginner and then move up to ameature, semi-pro and professional.Match Play- Is a versus mode against AI opponents that increases in difficulty as they progress.Tournament- Tournament mode allows players to play for position against AI players. After every round they are sent to a higher difficulty player. The player also earns in game money than can be bet against an AI player as you play one hole and compete for the lowest score.Clubhouse-is an options menu that allows you to view varios stats such as money earned, choose clubs and clear saved game data.CoursesNorth American CoursesUS CourseUK CourseJapan courseJapanese versionJapan courseAustralia CourseFrance CourseHawaii CourseUK CourseExtra CourseBetween some version the holes of courses change and are located on different courses, such as hole 1 in the Australia course is hole 9 on the US course. Player RosterBarryBillyBruceCarrieColleenDayvDeniseDonEarlElizabethFredGloriaJeffJimJohnKimLeslieLynnMarkMaryPaulaPeteSteveTinaTonyMikiIwataHiroNakajimaOnozukaMishimaTsuchiyamaMiyamotoShirotaTodoriUemuraThe players on the roster are the people that Mario and Luigi compete against.  Player 27-36 are all named after Nintendo employees that worked on the game. ReleasesThe game was first released on September 1, 1991 for the Nintendo Entertainment System. It was re-released on the Wii Shop in the spring and summer of 2007 in Japan, Europe and North America. NES Open Tournament Golf was again released on the 3DS as part of the Ambassador Program as a way to thank early adopters of the Nintendo 3DS handheld system. It was later released to the general public at a price of $4.99.</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21837">Bandai Golf: Challenge Pebble Beach</game><game id="22096">Golf</game><game id="19044">Lee Trevino's Fighting Golf</game><game id="25353">Golf Grand Slam</game><game id="33868">Golf: U.S. Course</game><game id="28372">Namco Open</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/9/93770/2362082-nes_nesopenturnamentgolf_gb.jpg</image></root>