<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8930</id><name>Rage Racer</name><description>OverviewRage Racer was released by Namco for the Playstation. It was the first game to have Reiko Nagase officially announced in the game as she is now the "face" of the Ridge Racer series.Rage Racer is the first Ridge Racer title ever where new cars must be purchased using credits won from races. It is also the first Ridge Racer title where the players can use credits to upgrade the performance of their vehicles. Rage Racer has an almost RPG-like progresson system, as a player can choose to re-enter races in order to earn more credits, or instead attempt more challenging racing classes without upgrading or purchasing a new vehicle first.Even today these elements are relatively rare for the Ridge Racer series, where cars are typically awarded for free or unlocked, and the speed level of each is always the same, or purely dependent on whatever course or racing class you've selected.TracksStadard GP info for track names, length, GP name and prize money for each class in GP Mode.Mythical CoastLength: 4641mClass 1: Calme GP - 1st 400eg, 2nd 160eg, 3rd 80egClass 2: Brise GP - 1st 2400eg, 2nd 1000eg, 3rd 500egClass 3: Rafale GP - 1st 12000eg, 2nd 5000eg, 3rd 2500egClass 4: Mistral GP - 1st 60000eg, 2nd 25000, 3rd 12500egClass 5: Tempete GP - 1st 375000eg, 2nd 125000eg, 3rd 62500egOver Pass CityLength: 6640mClass 1: Calme GP - 1st 550eg, 2nd 240eg, 3rd 120egClass 2: Brise GP - 1st 3400eg, 2nd 1500eg, 3rd 750egClass 3: Rafale GP - 1st 18000eg, 2nd 7500eg, 3rd 3750egClass 4: Mistral GP - 1st 85000eg, 2nd 37500, 3rd 18750egClass 5: Tempete GP - 1st 420000eg, 2nd 187500, 3rd 93750egLakeside GateLength: 6237mClass 1: Calme GP - 1st 500eg, 2nd 220eg, 3rd 110egClass 2: Brise GP - 1st 3200eg, 2nd 1400eg, 3rd 700egClass 3: Rafale GP - 1st 16000eg, 2nd 7000eg, 3rd 3500egClass 4: Mistral GP - 1st 80000eg, 2nd 35000, 3rd 17500egClass 5: Tempete GP - 1st 400000eg, 2nd 175000eg, 3rd 87500egThe Extreme OvalLength: 3074mClass 3: Rafale GP - 1st 22000eg, 2nd 6000eg, 3rd 3000egClass 4: Mistral GP - 1st 90000eg, 2nd 30000, 3rd 15000egClass 5: Tempete GP - 1st 300000eg, 2nd 150000eg, 3rd 75000egThere is also an unlockable Class 6 and an Extra GP mode.CarsList of cars available in standard GP mode of the game with price and other information.Each time a car is tuned up it goes into the next grade up.The cars stats are shown in each grade.Grade 1GnadeEsperanzaMax Power: 70 PS / 5200 rpmMax Torque: 8.3 kgm / 3200 rpmCost: You start off with this carGrade 2AgeErrisoMax Power: 80 PS / 6200 rpmMax Torque: 7.1kgm / 2600 rpmCost: 2600egLizzardAcceronMax Power: 150 PS / 5000 rpmMax Torque: 36.2 kgm / 2800 rpmCost: 4000egGrade 3AgeAbeilleMax Power: 99 PS / 6700 rpmMax Torque: 9.8 kgm / 3500 rpmCost: 14500egLizardBayonetMax Power: 200 PS / 5000 rpmMax Torque: 38.1 kgm / 3600 rpmCost: 15200egAssolutoFatalitaMax Power: 255 PS / 8000 rpmMax Torque: 28.6 kgm / 6600 rpmCost: 20000egGrade 4AgePegaseMax Power: 160 PS / 7200 rpmMax Torque: 15.2 kgm / 6600 rpmCost: 143300egMaunal Transmission onlyLizardHijackMax Power: 340 PS / 5700 rpmMax Torque: 42.6 kgm / 4500 rpmCost: 136700egMaunal Transmission onlyAssolutoIstanteMax Power: 380 PS / 7500 rpmMax Torque: 47.1 kgm / 7000 rpmCost: 151600egMaunal Transmission onlyGrade 5AssolutoGhepardoMax Power: 650 PS / 9000 rpmMax Torque: 60 kgm / 6200 rpmCost: 695900Maunal Transmission onlySoundtrackThough the soundtrack is widely credited to "Namco Sound Team," the principle members (Shinji Hosoe and Ayako Saso, collectively known as SamplingMasters) of that team left Namco to pursue other projects before development of the soundtrack for Rage Racer began. This allowed up-and-comers Tetsukazu Nakanishi and Hiroshi Okubou to shine, producing what can be considered one of the best soundtracks in the series.The game used Redbook audio and as such, could be put into normal CD players to enjoy the game's great music outside of the game.1. [Game Data]2. Story3. Rage Racer4. Mathemabeat5. Lightning Luge6. Industria7. Hurricane Hub8. Mech Monster9. Silver Stream10. Stimulation11. Volcano Vehicle12. Grand Prix Replay13. Time Trial Replay14. High Score Screen15. Game Over16. Victory17. Deep Drive (In the game, this song is unlocked once the player has all the Gold Trophies)There were only a few songs that used Sony's proprietary PlayStation streaming formats or soundchip-produced songs:Attract (Played during Rage Racer's video introduction)Menu (Played in game's menu screens)Ending (Played during Rage Racer's video ending)</description><genres><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="225">Daytona USA</game><game id="4246">Daytona USA: Championship Circuit Edition</game><game id="453">Need for Speed: High Stakes</game><game id="42324">Ridge Racer Driftopia</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1839030-box_rracer3.png</image></root>