<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>8979</id><name>EverQuest: Lost Dungeons of Norrath</name><description>Overview    Wayfarer Camp Butcherblock MtnsThe sixth expansion to EverQuest brought about several new concepts to the game.  Like The Legacy of Ykesha before it, Lost Dungeons of Norrath was available via download, but SOE placed an incentive to buy the retail version by including a metal keychain and an exclusive in-game item and for those who took that route in purchasing the expansion.  Highlights of the sixth expansion include: Instanced Zones: The dungeons of the new expansion are instanced, meaning groups do not have to compete with each over content.48 New Zones: Touted as the more than any previous expansion, there were 5 different dungeon themes with 8-10 variations each.Augments: Adventurers can now customize weapons and armor with augments.Variable Missions: Groups could choose what missions they wanted to pursue in the dungeons as well as select the difficulty.  Completing the adventures earns points used to purchase items, spells, or augments.Scaling Mobs: A group of level 65's and a group of level 30's can separately do the same adventure and be equally challenged.Interactive Environments: The dungeons are littered with chests, coffins, vases and other items that can be unlocked, smashed, or opened in various ways by those with proficient skills.   Wayfarers Brotherhood    Wayfarer Camp  Everfrost PeaksThe Lost Dungeons of Norrath introduced a new faction of adventurers to the world of Norrath.  The Wayfarers would become an integral part of the game's storyline throughout the next several expansions.  The group, led by a rogue named Morden Rasp, have discovered five lucrative dungeons located in Everfrost Peaks, Northern Desert of Ro, Oasis of Marr, Guk, and Lesser Faydark.  Rasp is credited with the discovery augmentations, revolutionizing the use of weaponry and armor throughout Norrath.  The magi of the Brotherhood have also changed the world with their discovery of Farstone Magic, giving them the ability to translocate themselves and others quickly between the other Wayfarers' camps.  Adventurers can accept missions and tasks from the members of the Brotherhood at the various camps located in Everfrost Peaks, East Commonlands, Northern Desert of Ro, Southern Desert of Ro, and Butcherblock Mountains.  Each camp offers eight to ten different adventures, each with variable difficulty.  The missions can be one of four specific types including: Assassination - The group must kill one specific enemy, who will only appear after 60% of the dungeon is cleared.Collection - The group must find a specific number of a certain item randomly dropped by enemies in the dungeon.Rescue - The group must find a particular person and escort them out of the dungeon.Slaughter - Every living creature in the dungeon must be exterminated.  To add another layer of difficulty to the task, there are time limits involved.  The Wayfarers will give adventurers 30 minutes to find the dungeon, then 90 minutes to complete the given task and return to camp.  Completing these missions for the Wayfarers will earn points that can be spent to purchase unique weapons, armor, or augments from the treasure hoard of the Brotherhood.  The Wayfarers also keep track of those who contribute the most often and most efficiently to their cause and post these statistics for all to see.   DungeonsThere are five different dungeon themes.  Each feature between eight and ten different adventures.  Deepest Guk Deepest GukLower Guk has always been a popular destination for adventurers seeking fortune, but little did they know that an even darker, scarier system of caverns lie beneath them.  The undead Frogloks in Deepest Guk have been left undisturbed for a very long time.  Surviving in this festering cess pool of undeath will prove quite challenging.  Adventures in Deepest Guk are distributed by Selephra Giztral in the Southern Desert of Ro. The Cauldron of Lost SoulsThe Drowning CryptThe Ancient AqueductsThe Mushroom GroveThe Foreboding PrisonThe Chapel of the WitnessesThe Root GardenThe Accursed Sanctuary   Miragul's Menagerie Miragul's MenagerieBeneath the frozen tundra of the Everfrost Peaks, an Erudite man named Miragul once gathered artifacts and practiced his evil sorcery.  For Miragul was the original Heretic, the leader of the faction of Erudites that abandoned the teachings of Erud and established their own city of Paineel where they could study the ways of necromancy without ridicule.  Paladins had discovered through their quest for the Fiery Avenger that Miragul had secluded himself in the frozen north, but it was the Wayfarers who uncovered the menagerie itself along with its powerful magical creatures residing within its icy walls.  Adventures in Miragul's Menagerie are handed out by Teria Grinntli in Everfrost.The Silent GalleryThe Maw of the MenagerieThe Spider DenThe Hushed BanquetThe Frosted HallsThe Forgotten WastesThe Heart of the MenagerieThe Morbid LibraryThe Theater of Imprisoned HorrorsThe Grand Library  Mistmoore Catacombs    Mistmoore CatacombsAll residents of Faydwer know to stay far away from the castle belonging to the legendary Mayong Mistmoore.  His vampiric minions have wreaked havoc upon the Elves, Dwarves, and Gnomes of the region ever since their arrival on the continent.  Unbeknown to Faydwer though, is that Castle Mistmoore is only the tip of the iceberg.  Twisted and turning caverns sprawl across the continent beneath the surface.  Adventurers in the Mistmoore Catacombs can be obtained from Vual Stoutest in Butcherblock Mountains. The Forlorn CavernsThe Dreary GrottoThe Asylum of Invoked StoneThe Chambers of Eternal AfflictionThe Sepulcher of the DamnedThe Ritualistic Summoning GroundsThe Cesspits of PutrescenceThe Aisles of BloodThe Halls of Sanguinary RitesThe Internal Sanctuary  Rujarkian Hills    Rujarkian HillsStories have been heard in the taverns of Freeport for decades about a tribe of orcs who mysteriously disappeared from Norrath.  Their clan was known as Rujark, and the legend states that these orcs were direct descendants of the first orcs created by The Warlord, Rallos Zek.  The Rujarkian orcs are believed to be the smartest and yet most savage in the history of Norrath.  The old wives tales of orcs capturing and enslaving citizens of Freeport that wander too far into the Desert of Ro have turned out to be true.  Adventures in the Rujarkian Hills are issued by Barstre Songweaver in East Commonlands tunnel. The Bloodied QuarriesThe Halls of WarThe Wind BridgesThe Gladiator PitsThe Drudge HollowsThe Fortified Lair of the TaskmastersThe Hidden ValeThe Blazing ForgeThe Arena of ChanceThe Barracks of War  Ruins of Takish-Hiz    Ruins of Takish-HizCenturies ago, the Elves lived in a lush forest that existed where what is now the Desert of Ro.  The sun god, Solusek Ro, laid waste to the forest by burning it to the ground, which forced the Elves to flee to Faydwer, where they established Felwithe and Kelethin in the Faydark.  Remnants of their lost civilization peak out above the sands to this day, but the Wayfarers have discovered a path to a portion of the Elves' capital city of Takish-Hiz that remains somewhat in tact.  What priceless artifacts and mysteries could lie beneath the sand?  Adventures in the Ruins of Takish-Hiz can be obtained from Ruanya Windleaf in the Northern Desert of Ro. The Sunken LibraryThe Shifting TowerThe Fading TempleThe Royal ObservatoryThe River of RecollectionThe Sandfall CorridorsThe Balancing ChambersThe Sweeping TidesThe Antiquated PalaceThe Prismatic Corridors</description><genres><genre id="16">MMORPG</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/1/17724/874826-eqlostdungeons.png</image></root>