<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9031</id><name>NHL 2K6</name><description>NHL 2K6 was the first game in the NHL 2K series to hit next gen consoles when it was released as a launch title on the Xbox360 on November 16, 2005. Marty Turco of the Dallas Stars was featured on the cover in the United States, with Mats Sundin gracing the game's cover in Canada.  Classic TeamsNHL 2K6 includes 59 classic NHL, international, and all-decade teams for play.  2002 Olympics Canada2001-02 Detroit Red Wings2001-02 San Jose Sharks2000-01 Colorado Avalanche2000-01 Pittsburgh Penguins1998-99 Buffalo Sabres1998-99 Dallas Stars1997-98 Washington Capitals1996-97 Detroit Red Wings1996-97 New York Rangers1996-97 Philadelphia Flyers1996 World Cup USA1995-96 Colorado Avalanche1995-96 Florida Panthers1995 New Jersey Devils1994 Olympics Sweden1993-94 New York Rangers1993-94 San Jose Sharks1993-94 Vancouver Canucks1992-93 Buffalo Sabres1992-93  Los Angeles Kings 1992-93 Montreal Canadiens1992-93  New York Islanders 1992-93 Quebec Nordiques 1992-93 St. Louis Blues1992-93 Toronto Maple Leafs 1992-93 Winnipeg Jets1991-92 Chicago Blackhawks1991 World Championships Czechoslovakia1990-91 Minnesota North Stars1990-91 Pittsburgh Penguins1989-90 Boston Bruins1989-90 Edmonton Oilers1988-89 Calgary Flames1987 Canada Cup Canada1987 Canada Cup USSR1986-87 Edmonton Oilers1986-87 Philadelphia Flyers1985-86 Montreal Canadiens1981-82 Los Angeles Kings1981-82 New York Islanders1980 Olympics USA1980 Olympics USSR1976-77 Montreal Canadiens1974-75 Buffalo Sabres1974-75 Philadelphia Flyers1971-72 Boston Bruins1971-72 New York Rangers1972 Summit Series Canada1972 Summit Series USSR1970-71 Chicago Black Hawks1967-68 Montreal Canadiens1962-63 Toronto Maple Leafs1955-56 Montreal Canadiens1951-52 Detroit Red Wings1990's1980's1970's1960's</description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="39">Hockey</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11698">NHL 06</game><game id="21784">Gretzky NHL 06</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2222539-box_nhl2k6.png</image></root>