<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9085</id><name>Vampire Rain</name><description>GameplayWhen you get the shotgun, its on!Vampire Rain is a                            Japanese                             Xbox 360 title. The main concept of the game is                          stealth. You have to sneak around a city avoiding                         vampires that can rough you up and kill you in a flash. Whenever you start a mission you are given weak weapons that won't do much to save you if you are spotted. But you do have a pair of goggles that have                           night vision and necro vision which allows you to see who is a vampire and who is just a                        human. There are some levels where you have to sneak around and not get caught, while others may force you to sneak around and then get a powerful weapon to shoot all the vampires with.                       Shotguns really tear up vampires and kills in one shot depending on how far away they are.                      Snipers with a well place shot is also a     one hit kill. But most of the time you have to    sneak and not fight.VampiresA vampire As you may have guessed these aren't normal                     vampires. They do not come into your bedroom, suck your blood, and then turn into a bat and fly away. No these modern Vampires have taken a                    Metal Gear Solid                   Genom Soldier/gangster approach by chilling out on sidewalks waiting for people to come by, but only have a limited range of vision. When the player does get spotted, they don't call for help or anything because one is more than a match if you're not prepared. The game does give a warning of some sort that a vampire has spotted someone but isn't certain of it yet. That gives the player a chance to      hide to avoid detection. But if you fail to do so, the vampire(s) will bum rush the player. Then they will swipe at the player which will take away most of the player's       health. That swipe knocks you over and once that happens its        game over because they will hit the player while he is on the ground. FailureMost                 Japanese                  Xbox 360 games from small companies have always had poor sales. This game continues that trend. It also did not make a big splash in               America as it wanted to. This was mainly due to the fact that the demo was only released on the Japanese marketplace.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="16140">Metal Gear Solid</game><game id="12780">Darkwatch</game><game id="22537">Vampire Rain: Altered Species</game><game id="23924">Spy Fiction</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2151949-box_vrain.png</image></root>