<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9170</id><name>Dementium: The Ward</name><description>GameplayDementium: The Ward uses full 3D environments with touch screen controls much like in  Metroid Prime: Hunters. It also borrows some elements from other notable horror games to create it is own creepy concept where the player has to use a flashlight to guide their way out from the darkness and use weapons to fight their way through a horde of hideous creatures. The game also provide users a notepad for jotting down notes to solve puzzles.PlotIn Dementium, you play as an amnesiac man with no clue of his identity, his whereabouts, or his current situation. He finds himself waking up in a bed in  Redmoor Hospital and discovers that the hallways, rooms and wards are swarming with hideous, murderous creatures. The man must search for clues to his identity as well as weapons he can use to defend himself against the abominations roaming the ward while he desperately looks for a way to escape.WeaponsFlashlight - While not exactly a weapon, but it's used to light you path from the dark hallways and also to spot hidden enemies.Nightstick - A wooden baton used by security guards. Useful at first but useless later on unless you are out of ammo.Pistol - A standard 9mm handgun. Not exactly powerful but it's a better substitution to replace the nightstick.Shotgun - A more powerful weapon than the pistol.Electric Buzz-Saw - A close range weapon to replace the nightstick. Makes a lot of noise.Machine gun - An automatic which is useful for killing a horde of enemies. Packs a lot of recoils too.Revolver - The magnum is an effective choice of weapon but kind of slow.Sniper Rifle - It's equipped with a zooming scope and a night vision scope.ChaptersChapter 1: The AdmittanceChapter 2: The RooftopChapter 3: The Infant WardChapter 4: The CleaverChapter 5: The CourtyardChapter 6: The Electric Buzz-SawChapter 7: The Main Security RoomChapter 8: The FlashbackChapter 9: The Hole In The WallChapter 10: The Torn PhotographChapter 11: The Guard TowerChapter 12: The Cleaver's ReturnChapter 13: The Door with No HandleChapter 14: The Wheelchair's ReturnChapter 15: The First EncounterChapter 16: The Final EncounterReceptionDementium: The Ward received generally favourable reviews for pushing the  Nintendo DS' capabilities with its outstanding visuals and lighting textures. However, Dementium was criticized for its short length and lack of replayability. After finishing the game, there isn't any score results or unlocked features. You see the credits and it's back to the main menu.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21507">Moon</game><game id="4312">Silent Hill</game><game id="25713">C.O.R.E.</game><game id="15848">Resident Evil: Survivor</game><game id="42032">Cult County</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2314061-box_dtw.png</image></root>