<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9203</id><name>Shadowgrounds</name><description>OverviewShadowgrounds is a top-down shooter developed for the PC where you are a simple engineer of a space colony on Ganymede, one of Jupiter's Moons. Developed by Frozenbyte, the game features many similarities to Doom 3, in that both concepts involve the invasion of a space colony of some sort by aliens/monsters, with the player defending using a decent selection of  weapons. The atmosphere is also similar, in that they both heavily use lighting to create a tense and nervous environment where it is not always easy to see and shadows are cast by dynamic lights to create creepy moments where you can see the shadow of a creature bot not the creature itself.Shadowgrounds takes place from a top-down perspective reminiscent of older shooters and the monsters come at the player very fast which is also another old-school element, these both make the game fast-paced and accessible but also mean there is not a whole lot of depth. As you progress through the game and kill more monsters, you have many opportunities to upgrade your arsenal such as a damage upgrade, rate of fire adjustments and other beneficial enhancements. Although the core of the game is definitely pushing through the environments as you mow down wave after wave of monsters, the game does again share elemnents with Doom 3, as there are PDAs and computer stations situated all over the environments which provide some back-story and plot clues, although not enough to explain everything.PlotThe story in Shadowgrounds revolves around the Ganymede colonies and the main character Wesley Tyler who is controlled by the player. When the game starts out, Wesley is just a regular wrench monkey working on the repair base when he is called to check out an electrical malfunction. Soon after, unknown lifeforms start swarming the base and Wesley is forced to fend for himself.GameplayShadowgrounds is an extremely action-focused game with a top-down view of the player. It is at it's core a corridor crawl through the Ganymede bases and surounding environments mowing down monsters. The gameplay has been compared to the likes of the Alien Breed franchise for it's fast, action-heavy style, and also Doom 3 because of the setting, the use of darkness, monsters and so on. The use of a flashlight is also similar to that of Doom 3, and the game even features an  Aliens-style radar movement tracker that lets you know where enemies are in your vicinity.As the player kills more and more monsters they can pick up upradge tokens to upgrade their weapons throughout the game, each weapon having 3 possible upgrades, the better ones requiring more upgrade pieces.For the most part the player will be running from point a to point b, dispatching of  monsters along the way, although sometimes the player will be asked to repair broken electronics, defend a base sector with other NPC's and shut down barriers to allow the player to progress.The game features several Boss battles, some more memorable than others but all offering a reasonable challenge.WeaponsPistol Pulse Rifle Shotgun Flamer Laser Rifle Minigun Grenade Launcher Rocket Launcher Railgun Electric Gun  PC System Requirements  Minimum:  Processor speed: 1.3 GHZ or Equivalent Memory: 384 MB RAM Video: GeForce 4 Ti 4200* or ATi Radeon 9000 or better HDD: 1 GB free hard drive space OS: Windows 2000/XP/Vista/7 Recommended:  Processor speed: 2.0 GHz Memory: 512 MB RAM Video: GeForce FX 5900 Ultra or ATi Radeon 9500 Pro or better * Please note that Shadowgrounds does not run on GeForce 4 MX cards.    </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="11">Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="4719">Alien Breed</game><game id="15149">Alien Breed: Tower Assault</game><game id="16238">Alien Shooter 2</game><game id="17293">Alien Shooter</game><game id="31479">Alien Breed: Impact</game><game id="32098">Alien Swarm</game><game id="33182">Alien Breed 3: Descent</game><game id="34896">Ikki Online</game><game id="32071">Alien Breed 2: Assault</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/1987/659099-shadowgrounds_pc.jpg</image></root>