<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9209</id><name>Yu-Gi-Oh! Duelists of the Roses</name><description>This is an RPG game where the player is a "ROSE DUELIST". The player is summoned by a druid named Simon to the past days of dueling so that he can help the young prince Yu-Gi Moto. Only before Simon can fully convince the player to join forces with the "Yorkist" (Yu-Gi's side) a man named Seto Kiaba appears. Seto is the leader of the Rose Crusaders which believe that they should summon one of the old kings which helped create the dueling game. After a lengthy discussion of both Simon and Seto attempting to get the player to join their sides Seto proposes a compromise. Seto explains that both the Yorkist and the Crusaders have eight of the sixteen "Rose Cards". Seto explains to the player that neither side is winning so it is fair game. The player is then given a choice to take the White Rose Card and fight for Seto and the Crusaders or to choose the Red Rose Card and fight for Yu-Gi and the Yorkist. (The Rose Crusaders is intentionally easier such as choosing the Dark Side in the Star Wars Video games.) The Rose Cruesaders    If the player chooses the White Rose Card then Simon is wisk away and the player goes with Seto. Seto explains that the player needs to go into the Yorkist country and destroy all of their duelist so he can retrieve all of the Red Rose Cards. The player battles through players such as Mya, Tristian, Joey, Grandpa, and finally Yu-Gi himself. After the player retrieves all of the Red Rose Cards he takes them to Seto where Seto makes an attempt to summon the former king and succeeds. Only things do not go as planned as the king becomes upset that he was awoken from his slumber and claims to be disturber by the way that the human race has "tainted" the way of dueling. The king promises to take over again and return  "order" to the way of dueling. Seto calls on the player to battle the king because the prophecy states that only the Rose Duelist would be able to defeat the king.  Card Codes  After you have completed either sides campaign you are rewarded with a password to obtain a card. But you can only get two different codes for each campaign. If you wish to receive another then you must start the game over with a new file.  Ancient Tree Of Enlightenment - EKJHQ109 Aqua Dragon - JXCB6FU7 Barrel Dragon - GTJXSBJ7 Beast King Of The Swamp - QXNTQPAX Birdface - N54T4TY5 Blast Sphere - CZN5GD2X Change Of Heart - SBYDQM8B Crush Card - SRA7L5YR Dark Hole - UMJ10MQB Dragonseeker - 81EZCH8B Earthshaker - Y34PN1SV Elf's Light - E5G3NRAD Exodia's Head - 37689434 Fairy King Trusdale - YF07QVEZ Fairy's Gift - NVE7A3EZ Goblin Fan - 92886423 Gravity Bind - 0HNFG9WX Greenkappa - YBJMCD6Z Harpy's Feather Sweep - 8HJHQPNP Horn Of The Unicorn - S14FGKQ1 Left Arm Of Exodia - A5CF6HSH Magician Of Faith - GME1S3UM Meteor Dragon - 86985631 Mimicat - 69YDQM85 Mirror Wall - 53297534 Mystical Capture Chains - N1NDJMQ3 Robotic Knight - S5S7NKNH Royal Decree - 8TETQHE1 Seiyaryu - 2H4D85J7 Serpentine Princess - UMQ3WZUZ Slate Warrior - 73153736 Swordsman From A Foreign Land - CZ81UVGR Swordstalker - AH0PSHEB Tactical warrior - 054TC727</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="13">Card Game</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9600">Metal Gear Ac!d</game><game id="8702">Metal Gear Ac!d 2</game><game id="1213">Baten Kaitos Origins</game><game id="7958">Baten Kaitos: Eternal Wings and the Lost Ocean</game><game id="5134">SNK vs. Capcom: Card Fighter's Clash - SNK &amp; Capcom Version</game><game id="10489">Pokémon Trading Card Game</game><game id="19085">Dragon Ball Z: Collectible Card Game</game><game id="3210">Marvel Trading Card Game</game><game id="36372">Pokémon Card Game: How To Play DS</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2210239-box_ygotdotr.png</image></root>