<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9238</id><name>Animal Crossing: Wild World</name><description>Overview  Look! TWO PEOPLE!Animal Crossing: Wild World for the                                                     Nintendo DS is a simulation game developed by                                             Nintendo EAD as a sequel to the                                                     Nintendo GameCube title                                       Animal Crossing.  The game's premise is simple, and follows in the footsteps of the original: the player moves to a new town, immediately gets in debt and has to pay it off while fishing, catching bugs, planting and picking fruit, and socializing with the myriad of neighbors. The game's clock is set with the system clock, thus allowing night in the "real world" to translate to night in the game, as well as certain season effects (snow in the winter, leaves turning red and orange in the fall).   Wild World improves on the original by adding a barber shop, new furniture, expanding the potential size of the player's home, and adding strong support through the                                                     Nintendo Wi-Fi system, including the ability for players to visit other players' towns after friend codes have been exchanged. The acre-system of movement was removed in favor of a rolling effect. For use of the DS's extra screen, the bottom is the main screen, while the top usually shows either the sky or the ceiling of the building you're in. In addition, the game is controllable by both touchscreen command and standard button-input. Specific holidays, such as Christmas and                                            Halloween, have been either eliminated or replaced, with Christmas in particular being replaced by the very similar "Toy Day." The game has its own special holidays and events, though, so the loss of these is felt less since there are still events to celebrate.Gameplay  This person likes pink.The player begins the game in a taxi cab in which the driver,                                                     Kapp'n, asks a series of questions that determine the appearance of the character, as well as making sure that the internal clock on the Nintendo DS is the correct time. After the dialogue sequence, the player arrives in a randomly-generated town and is greeted by                                                     Tom Nook, the town shopkeeper, who offers the player a house of residence. However, in order to retain and start paying off the house, the player must perform a series of jobs that serve as a type of tutorial to the game's basic socializing mechanics. After these are completed, the player is free to experience the game at their leisure, though it is encourage that players earn bells, the game's currency, in order to pay off and upgrade their home.  The upgrades for the home are the following:       First House Expansion Pay off 19,800 Bells in the Town hall   Second House Expansion Pay off 120,000 Bells in the Town hall  Upstairs Room Pay off 298,000 Bells in the Town hall  Left Room Pay off 598,000 Bells in the Town hall  Right Room Pay off 720,000 Bells in the Town hall  Back Room Pay off 848,000 Bells in the Town hall While up to four human players may reside in a single game file, unlike with the original Animal Crossing's four separate houses, these players all live in the same house. The very top floor of each how is set as the player's bedroom, and as more players are added, more beds are added to the room. If you find a bed you like more than the one they give you to start with, you can go up to the bedroom and replace it (even things like a workout bench work). Fishing  in the ocean. Earning Money The principle element of Wild World is the monetary system and the collection of bells. Bells are used not only to pay off           Tom Nook for home upgrades, but also for various furniture pieces and items that he sells within his store. Likewise, as more goods are purchased, the store upgrades to offer larger selections. The most common means of earning bells include:  Fishing - Perhaps the most popular method of earning bells, a Fishing Rod costs 500 bells to start with, but begins to pay itself off right away. Shadows in the water (pond, river or ocean) are used to show where fish reside, and specific fish reside in specific areas-some netting as little as 100 bells, others netting close to 20,000. Upon catching, the player has the option of keeping the fish at home, selling it, or donating to the museum (for no monetary reward, though it's said donated fish become more populous).  Bug catching with a villager.Bug Catching - Similarly, bugs can also be caught using a 500 bell net. Bugs are traditionally less common and sell for less bells than fish, but they are typically very common during summer months. They tend to be harder to catch, as you must sneak up on them or find them underground, too. Once caught, the player has the same options as with fish-keep, sell or donate.   Digging - Small X-shaped holes in the ground mark places where the player can dig and find either a                                                     Gyroid or a                                           fossil. Fossils can be identified by                                                     Blathers in the museum, and can then be either donated or sold. There are 3 fossils each day, and they tend to sell for large sums of bells. Gyroids are much more rare, tending to appear after a rain, and sell for around 800 bells each (and who'd sell them? They're adorable). Tasks - When you talk to your neighbors, after their little spiel about eating or catching buts or something, they give you the option to ask for a task from them. Most of the tasks are pretty simple, where they give you some sort of item to deliver to someone, or a letter to give (unless you want to be bad and read it). Retrieving an item can take the longest, though, since neighbors tend to loan the things they don't own to other people. It can go through a chain of about 6 people before you get it back at times. It's also possible to fail at returning an item, specifically if the neighbor in question moves away. You don't get a reward if that happens. On that note, rewards tend to be furniture, carpets, shirts, or small sums of bells. Various tree pots and an orange.Fruit Harvesting -  Each town is assigned a specific fruit (Apple, Peach, Cherry, Pear, Orange) which can be sold for 100 bells a piece, or can be planted in the grown to grow a tree bearing that fruit (each tree holds three pieces of fruit, which grow back every three days if taken down). If the player sells a "foreign fruit"--that is, any fruit besides the specific "native fruit" of the town--the player will receive 500 bells. By planting several trees bearing foreign fruit, the player can make approximately 1500 bells per tree, allowing for a quick monetary reward. Coconut trees can also be planted near the beach area, but these trees bear only two fruits, and are sold for 150 bells each. It's not guaranteed that a planted fruit will grow into a tree, but to aid in your chances, plant a tree where a weed was just plucked from.   Selling items - During your stay in whatever you name your town, you're going to start collecting a lot of rather useless items. There's a few ways to get rid of these: you can gift them to neighbors (they gift back), put them in the lost and found, or sell them for quick cash to Tom Nook. They never sell for large amounts, but an authentic painting or rare item can fetch a very good price and clear up some inventory space for all those fish.  Tools of the Trade Fishing Rod The fishing rod is just that-a normal fishing rod that uses a bobbing lure. You can tap A or the touch screen to use it. In the river or ocean, the bob will float with the current, making it better to throw out the line ahead of the fish and let it float down there. Most fish will nibble a few times, but there's a definite splash sound and graphic to let you know when it's actually sunk its teeth in. Getting every single fish in the game will get you the Golden Fishing Rod. However, this is mostly for bragging rights, though it does have a lure that makes fish easier to catch.  Bug Catching Net A simple net, it's quite effective at making sure you never have to handle some of the grosser of more dangerous bugs with your bare hands. Holding down on the screen or the button will let you sneak-most bugs are very finicky and will run away at the slightest provocation. Sneaking up is the best way to catch them. You can also hit the townspeople on the head with it, but they'll get very angry and yell at you if you do. Getting every bug gets you the Golden Net, which is twice as big, allowing easier catches.  Axe The axe is used for chopping down trees. There's really very little reason to do this in the game- you can't sell chopped wood and the fruit drops off after the first hit. After that, you still have to dig the stump out anyways. The best reason to do this is to plant a new tree where that one had been-preferably fruit to help get a harvest. The Golden Axe is one of the most infinitely useful items in the game, though. Where the axe will chip away and be destroyed, the Golden Axe will last forever. However, getting it requires you to buy a Red Turnip. When Wendell comes to town, you give him the Turnip and he'll give you the Turban or Country Guitar. The guitar is a dead end, but give the Turban to Sahara and she'll give you a Red Vase or a Massage Chair. The vase is the bust this time around, and the Massage Chair goes to                                          Tortimer. He'll give you a Scallop that goes to Pascal who, if you're lucky, will give you the Golden Axe.  Slingshot With the top screen comes a view of presents hanging from balloons, floating across the sky. That, or a UFO, or possibly even just the mail man. Hitting any of them with this mischief maker will cause them to fall to the bottom screen, allowing you to talk to the person involved or collect the present. Hitting 15 presents will get you the Golden Slingshot, a useful tool that shoots 3 stones at once.  Shovel Well...A shovel is used for digging. In true Indiana Jones fashion, X always marks the spot, and digging will find you Gyroids, random items/bells, and fossils. You can also dig spots to plant trees and fruit, or just bother a friend by digging a lot of holes around them. The Golden Shovel is received by planting a shovel and digging it up the next day. It lets the player grow money trees-though they only bloom once.  Watering Can To grow a plant, you need some water, and no better way than a watering can! Just sprinkle a bit of water and bloom, bloom, bloom. Keeping your town garbage free and happy for 16 days will get one of the people in the Town Hall give the Golden Watering Can to you when you talk to them, which nurses withered black roses back to life as Golden Roses. Main Characters NameDescriptionPicture Villager The villager is the human character in the game, and can be either male  or female. As mentioned, the appearance of this character is based on  the answers to the questions posed by             Kapp'n in the taxi cab  at the beginning of the game. Things like hairstyle and clothing don't  matter, since they can be changed as part of the game (hairstyle based  on questions in the barber shop). Unsurprisingly, you can name your  character whatever you want and get to earning them bells in a jiffy.                                       Male Villager                                 Tom Nook  Tom Nook is a raccoon who provides the house at the start of the game,  and is also the town shopkeeper. To pay off his debt, the player must  perform various tasks such as delivering purchases to customers,  planting flowers, and advertising his store-at first. After finishing  the work, the player is free to explore the game, although they're  encouraged to pay off the remaining loan (STRONGLY ENCOURAGED). After  paying it off, the player can ask Tom Nook to upgrade his or her house,  which can be done several times to increase size, add a new floor, and  finish of with adding extra rooms. Tom Nook's main job, though, is  managing his shop, which sells furniture, carpeting, wallpaper, paint,  tools, stationary, and medicine (for bee stings). His shop starts as the  tiny, brilliantly-named "Nook's Cranny" and, in the end, evolves into  Nookingtons, which has a second floor and barber shop.                                                 Tommy and Timmy Nook run the furniture department, where as the barber shop is run by a poodle named Harriet.                                   K.K. Slider  K.K. Slider is a guitar playing dog who visits your village every  Saturday night (around 8 PM) at the Café.  He will play a song for you  and also takes requests if there is something in particular you want to  hear.  After his performance he provides you with an 'aircheck' (tape)  to play in your house. The songs in the Cafe have a very simple  sound-just an acoustic guitar and his voice- whereas the airchecks have a  much more professionally-produced sound.                              Mr. Resetti  Mr. Resetti is an angry mole that will visit the village if the  player attempts to turn off or reset the game without saving, which is  considered cheating. The game attempts to simulate real life, and  resetting is not  possible in real life, according to Mr. Resetti (and he's right). Mr.  Resetti punishes the player by not. Shutting. Up. At times he even has  the player type his words in exactly as he spells them out (punctuation  marks and everything). Attempting to shut him up by turning off the game  is seen by all as a mistake.                               Blathers  Blathers is the curator of the local museum. In addition to identifying  fossils and determining whether paintings are authentic or not, Blathers  will gladly take fish, bugs, and the aforementioned paintings and  fossils. He is known for his love of fish (slobbering over them and  offering his favourite way to cook them), his extreme fear of insects,  and for getting "frightfully tired" during the day (to where you have to  wake him every few minutes). The more that is donated to the museum,  the happier Blathers becomes toward the player- not that he's ever sad  to see you!  Mayor Tortimer  Tortimer is the mayor of your town.  He can be seen 'working' in the  back of the town office year round and comes out of the office for  special events such as New Year's Eve. He often gives out free items  such as Roman Candles and Firecrackers, and weird statues and trophies.  He also hosts events such as the Bug-Off and the Fishing Tourney.  It is  highly suspected that Tortimer is also Cornimer, the leader of the  Acorn Festival that lasts a week in October.                          Mabel Able  One of the Able Sisters, Mabel is the more personal of the sisters who's  in charge of running the store. She is the person you talk to in order  to create custom design patters, and will also shine compliments upon  the player after each piece of clothing he or she puts on in an attempt  to make a sale.                         Sable Able  The other Able sister, Sable is very shy and spends most of her time  doing the sewing for the store. It's possible to win her over, but only  after saying hello to her for a number of days in a row can the player  begin to talk to her more at length.                      Brewster  Brewster is a pigeon who runs the coffee shop under the museum. He's           there 24/7, and will quietly serve you a hot cup for about 200  bells. He offers light conversation, but keep talking to him over a few  days and he'll start opening up more, even offering to put special  ingredients in your coffee. Just remember: coffee is meant to be drank  while it's hot!   LyleLyle is a weasel in both the literal and figurative meanings. He would  have to be though, seeing as he's an insurance salesman. Every Saturday  he shows up and begins to hound you, following you when you walk out of  your house. The first policy he offers you covers bee stings and you  tripping, which will get you 100 bells of compensation each time, and  the second protects you from the forged paintings Redd sells...by paying  100 bells for them. Redd and he obviously have a good scam going, and  talking to him will allow you to change the day that Redd comes to town.      Celeste On the DS, with the upper screen showing the sky, at night you may  notice the stars coming out. Talking to Celeste, who runs the second  story of the museum, will allow you to search the skies for  constellations, which means making custom constellations wherever you  see fit. It also lets you delete constellations, since going to other  people's towns or having them visit may import some of theirs. It's up  to you to keep the sky beautiful!                         Booker                  CopperThe lovable police dogs from the Gamecube original make a return as town                  guards, keeping the gate shut and all but approved  members of the Wi-Fi world out of your town. On top of that, talking to  Copper will also change the town's flag to a design of your choice, and  they still run the lost and found that you can still totally go in and  jack all the fresh stuff that's not yours. They're in charge of you  going to places, too, so you'll be talking to them a lot if you're a  rather social person.  Booker    Special Characters   NameDescriptionPictureCrazy Redd  Redd is the leader of the local Black Market. Once a week (determined by  the player) he sets up a tent in Town. In order to get into his tent  the player must obtain a password, which can be obtained by talking to  other villagers or by getting on Redd's mailing list. He sells rare  items and paintings at extremely marked up prices (up to double), though  his paintings are quite often forgeries and unaccepted for display by  Blathers in the museum. It is possible to get a good deal from him, but  it takes a sharp eye and a lot of patience.   Joan  Buy low, sell high-the rule governing both the stock market and the  turnip trade. Turnips are sold every Sunday from 6 a.m. to noon by the  wandering boar Joan in bunches of 10, 50, or 100. After buying turnips  the player may sell them to Tom Nook on any day of that week (except  Sunday). His prices vary from day to day, thus allowing for either great  profit or great loss from the selling of the turnips, which will spoil  and sell for nothing after one week. In addition, Joan will sell a red  turnip, which must be watered daily or else it wilts. This can be traded  at a later time, on a trading path that will eventually net you the  Golden Axe.  Saharah  Saharah makes her living selling rare and exotic carpets from far away  lands. Like most of the game's other special characters, Saharah sells  items that can't be found anywhere else. She does, however, have a  different way of doing business- through a barter system. In order to  obtain one of her carpets, the player must trade in one of his or her  carpets along with some money. Her prices go up each time a carpet is  bought on one visit.    Wendell  Wendell is a wandering walrus. His role has shifted quite strongly from  the Gamecube predecessor, where he gave out wallpapers. In this version,  he will instead give you special patterns if you bring him a fish (he's  quite hungry). Though certain fish (especially more rare ones) will net  you specific patterns, the majority will just see you rewarded with a  random pattern. Aside from the fish, his service is otherwise free.   Dr. Shrunk  Given the greater lean on being social with other people in Wild World,  it's         only fitting that there should be emotions in the game.  When Dr. Shrunk comes to town, if you find him, he will try to teach you  a new emotion, starting with shyness. It's basically a timing based  exercise, so when he says "go", you tap the screen and emote, and you'll  have your new emotion. You can only hold so many, so there may come a  time when you have to delete one for another. There are about 30  emotions in the game total.    Gracie  There's something wonderful about the idea of a giraffe who works as a  fashionista, and Gracie delivers that in spades. Driving from town to  town, she's one of the more complicated characters to get something  special from. First, she gives you a quiz and a normal shirt, but if you  bother her, she'll ask for 5,000 bells in order to give you a makeover.  If you do, you get a special shirt and new accessory, but if you spurn  her, she'll give you a moldy shirt. Stylish!   Blanca  Blanca is an interesting character who only appears after you've connected          with someone over Wi-Fi. She was born with a very unfortunate  problem-Blanca has no face, and she wants you to give her one. She'll  then be unleashed into a database and can wind up in someone else's  town- and you'll wind up your own awesome designs from other people if  you're not careful.    Katie  Kaitlin   Similar to Blanca in that they only appear after visiting another town,  Katie and Kaitlin are two cats who come to visit your town; only t he  problem is that they're separated! If the player has the mother, then  she will tell them the name of another town where she last saw Katie.  The owner of that town must then guide Katie over to your town over the  Wi-Fi Connection. It's a bit of a gyp, but only the player who guides  Katie to her mother will get a reward-but it's something quite rare and  special indeed!      Katrina  Yet another cat who visits your town, Katrina tells fortunes.  Startlingly              accurate fortunes. However, they merely go down  to whether or not you will have good luck or bad luck for the rest of  the day. If it's good luck, you'll find more stuff, get more presents,  and there will be more balloons to shoot down. Bad luck, though, will  make you start tripping a lot and could cause some of your neighbors to  begin acting a bit distant towards you. For 10,000 bells she can cleanse  this bad spirit from you, but for the price of free, you could just  stop playing until the next day- your luck wears off at midnight.   Pascal  Pascal is, like, kinda out there, you know, maaaan? Talking like an  ex-hippie and about as spaced as The Dude, Pascal the Otter will show up  on your beach, staring out into the distance like he's looking past it  all (man). Talking to him gets a fat load of philosophizing dropped on  your chest, but once he's done with that, he gives you a piece of Pirate  furniture and disappears off into the ocean again. If you've been doing  the trading route for the Red Turnip, then it ends here: the fabled  Golden Axe will be yours if you give the right item to Pascal.   Gulliver  Gulliver is a traveler. But not some simple, namby-pamby boat or car or  anything. Gulliver travels through space. He's no alien though- he's an  astronaut, and when he appears, flying over the top of your screen, it's  your duty to shoot him down with your slingshot. He'll be OK. And to  thank you, he'll give you an extremely, extra rare (we're talking a  purple here) item. Then, it's back into his ship and who knows when  you'll see him again!    Fishing IndexBelow you will find every fish, with it's appropriate price, location, and season.   Key: Morning = 4:00 AM - 9:00 AM, Noon = 9:00 AM - 4:00 PM. Evening = 4:00 PM - 8:00 PM, Night = 8:00 PM - 4:00 AM Fish NameValue (To Tom Nook)LocationAvailable Peak Availability RarityBitterling      900 BellsRiver  November - February (All Day)           None Common    Pale Chub        200 BellsRiver All Year (Noon)  April - June, September - October (Noon) CommonCrucian Carp   120 BellsRiverAll Year (All Day)October - April (Night)  CommonDace  200 BellsRiver All Year (Morning, Evening,  Night) December - February (Morning, Evening, Night)  CommonBarbel Steed      200 BellsRiver All Year (All Day) October - April (Night)  Common    Carp 300 BellsRiver All Year (All Day) April - May, Oct - Nov (Morning, Evening, Night)  Common   KoiDa  2000 BellsRiver All Year (Morning, Evening, Night) None  RareGoldfish  1300 BellsRiver All Year (All Day) None  RarePopeyed Goldfish      1300 BellsRiver All Year (Noon) None  Rare Killifish 300 BellsHolding Pond April - August (All Day) None  RareCrawfish  250 BellsHolding Pond April - September None  Common Frog 120 BellsHolding Pond May - August (All Day)  None CommonFreshwater Goby   300 BellsRiver All Year (Morning, Evening, Night) None Rare Leach 300 BellsRiver March - May (All Day) None  Common Catfish     800 BellsPond May - October (Morning, Evening, Night)June - September (Night)  Common Eel     2000 BellsRiver June - September (Morning, Evening, Night)July - August (Morning, Evening, Night) Common Snakehead      5500 BellsPond July - August (Noon) None Common  Bluegill     120 BellsRiver All Year (Noon) May - November (Noon) Common  Yellow Perch     240 BellsRiver October - March (All Day) November - February (Morning, Noon, Evening) Common  Black Bass  300 BellsRiver All Year (All Day) May - November (Morning, Evening, Night) Common Pond Smelt  300 BellsPond December - February (All Day) None Common  Sweetfish 900 BellsRiver July - September (All Day) July - August (Morning, Noon, Evening) Common  Cherry Salmon     1000 BellsRiver March - June, September - November (Morning, Evening) March, April, September, October (Morning, Evening) Common Char  3800 BellsWaterfall March - June, September - November (Morning, Evening) None Common  Rainbow Trout 800 BellsRiver March - June, September - November (Morning, Evening) March, April, October (Morning, Evening) Common Stringfish  15000 BellsRiver December - February (Morning, Evening, Night) None Rare  Salmon     700 BellsRiver September (All Day) None Common          King Salmon 1800 BellsRiver September (All Day) None Rare     Guppy 1300 BellsRiver April - November (Noon)None  Rare Angelfish 3000 BellsRiver May - October (Morning, Evening, Night) None Rare  Piranha 2500 BellsRiver June - September (Noon, Night) None Rare Arowana      10000 BellsRiver June - September (Morning, Evening, Night) None Rare Dorado      15000 BellsRiver June - September (Morning, Evening, Night) None Rare     Gar 6000 BellsPond June - September (Morning, Evening, Night) None Rare  Arapaima     10000 BellsRiver July - September (Morning, Evening, Night) None Rare    Sea Butterfly  1000 BellsOcean December - February (All Day) None Common Jellyfish      100 BellsOcean August (All Day) None Common Seahorse  1300 BellsOcean April - August (All Day) May - September (Noon) Common Clownfish      650 BellsOcean April - September (All Day) May - August (Noon) Common Zebra Turkeyfish      400 BellsOcean April - November (all Day) May - September (noon)  Common    Puffer Fish 240 BellsOcean July - September (All Day) August (All Day) Common Horse Mackerel  150 BellsOcean All Year (All Day) None Common Barred Knifejaw  5000 BellsOcean March - November (All Day) None Rare Sea Bass      160 Bells     Ocean All Year (All Day) None Absurdly Common     Red Snapper 3000 Bells Ocean     All Year (All Day) April - July (All Day) Common Dab      300 Bells Ocean     October - April (All Day) None Common    Olive Flounder  800 Bells Ocean     All Year (All Day) December - February (All Day) Rare Squid      400 Bells Ocean     December - August (All Day) February - June (Night) Common Octopus  500 Bells Ocean     September - January, March - July (All Day) October - December, April - June (Morning, Evening, Night) Common Football Fish  2500 Bells Ocean     November - March (Morning, Evening, Night) None Rare  Tuna 7000 Bells Ocean     November - March (All Day) None Rare Blue Marlin 10000 Bells Ocean     July - September (All Day) None RareOcean Sunfish  4000 BellsOcean August - September (Morning, Evening, Night) None Rare Hammerhead Shark 8000 BellsOcean June - September (All Day) None Rare Shark  15000 BellsOcean June - September (Morning, Evening, Night) None Rare Coelacanth  15000 BellsOcean During Snow Or Rain, All Year (Morning, Evening, Night) None Absurdly Rare     Bug Index Animal Crossing: Wild World offers a variety of offerings in terms of bugs.  Below you will find the complete list of bugs in the game.  Bug NameValue (To Tom Nook)LocationAvailablePeak AvailabilityRarity    Common Butterfly 90 Bells Near Flowers March - September (Morning, Noon) April - June (Noon) Common          Yellow Butterfly 90 Bells Near Flowers March - September (Morning, Noon) April - June (Noon) Common Tiger Butterfly      160 Bells Near Red and Pink Flowers March - September (Morning, Noon) May - June (Noon) Common  Peacock 220 Bells Near Blue, Purple, or Black Flowers March - September (Morning, Noon) May - June (Noon) Common Monarch  140 Bells Near Flowers September - November (Noon)None Common Emperor      2,500 Bells Near Flowers June - September (Noon)None Rare    Agrias Butterfly  3,000 Bells Near Flowers June - September (Noon) None Rare    Birdwing  3,000 Bells Near Flowers June - September (Noon) None Rare    Moth  60 Bells Near Lighting (Outdoor) May - September (Night) June - August (Night) Common Oak Silk Moth      1,200 Bells On Trees June - September (Night) None Rare  Honeybee     100 Bells Near Flowers  March - August (Noon)March - June (Noon) Common  Long Locust     200 Bells Grass August - November (Noon) September - October (Noon) Common  Mantis 430 Bells On Flowers August - November (Noon)  September - November (Noon)Common    Migratory Locust  600 Bells Grass September - November (Noon) September - October (Noon) Common Orchid Mantis      2,400 Bells On Flowers August - November (Noon) September - November (Noon) Common    Brown Cicada  200 Bells On Trees July - August (Noon) None Common Robust Cicada      300 Bells On Trees July - August (Noon) None Common  Walker Cicada     400 Bells On Trees July - August (Noon) None Rare Evening Cicada      550 Bells On Trees July - August (Morning, Evening) None Common  Lantern Fly     1,800 BellsOn Trees June - September (Evening, Night)None Rare Red Dragonfly      80 Bells Airborne September - October (Evening) None Common Darner Dragonfly      200 Bells Airborne June - August (Noon) June (Noon) Common Banded Dragonfly      4,500 Bells Airborne July - August (Noon) None Rare Ant  80 Bells Ground Year Round (Morning, Night) None Commom  Pond Skater     130 Bells On Ponds and Holding Ponds June - September (Noon) None Rare  Snail     250 Bells On Flowers April - September (All Day) None Rare Cricket      130 Bells Grass September - November ( Evening, Night) September - October (Evening, Night) Common Bell Cricket      430 Bells Grass September - October (Evening, Night) None Common Grasshopper      160 Bells Grass July - September (Noon) September (Noon) Common Mole Cricket  280 Bells Underground November - May (Morning, Night) None Rare Walkingstick      600 Bells On Trees July - November (Morning, Noon) None Rare Ladybug      200 Bells On Flowers March - June, October (Noon) March - May (Noon) Common Fruit Beetle      100 Bells On Trees July - September (Morning, Night) July - August (Night) Common      6,000 Bells On Trees July - August (Night) None Rare Dung Beetle      800 Bells Near Snowballs December - February (Evening, Night) None Rare Goliath Beetle      6,000 Bells On Coconut Palm Trees June - August (Night) None Rare  Firefly     300 Bells Near Fresh Water June (Night)NoneCommon Jewel Beetle      2,400 Bells On Trees July - August (Noon)None Rare Longhorn Beetle      260 Bells On Trees June - August (Noon)  NoneRare Saw Stag Beetle      2,000 Bells On Trees July - August (Morning, Night) July - August (Night) Rare Stag Beetle      2,000 Bells On Trees June - August (Night) July - August (Night) Rare  Giant Beetle     10,000 Bells On Trees July - August (Night) None Rare  Rainbow Stag     10,000 Bells On Trees June - September (Night) None Rare Dynastid Beetle      1,350 Bells On Trees July - August (Night) None Common Atlas Beetle  8,000 Bells On Coconut Palm Trees July - August (Night) None Rare Elephant Beetle  8,000 Bells On Coconut Palm Trees July - August (Night) None Rare  Hercules Beetle 12,000 Bells On Coconut Palm Trees July - August (Night) None Rare  Flea 70 Bells On your Neighbor March - November (Morning, Night) None Rare  Pillbug 250 Bells Under Rocks Year Round (Morning, Night) None Common  Mosquito 130 Bells Airborne June - September (Evening, Night) June - August (Evening, Night) Common  Fly 60 Bells Rafflesia, Rotten Turnips, or Garbage Year Round (Morning, Night) None Common  Cockroach 5 Bells On Trees Year Round (Morning, Night) None Rare Spider  300 Bells In Trees March - November (Morning, Night) None Common Tarantula      8,000 Bells On Ground July - August (Night)None Rare  Scorpion     8,000 Bells On Ground July - September None Rare Fossil IndexThis index lists each one of the complete fossils, and it's components.  Ptera Fossil Fossil NameValue at Nook's Store Ptera Skull4,000 Bells  Ptera Right Wing4,500 Bells  Ptera Left Wing4,500 Bells  Ptera Body4,000 Bells  Seismo Fossil  Fossil NameValue at Nook's Store Seismo Skull5,000 Bells  Seismo Chest4,500 Bells  Seismo Hip4,000 Bells  Seismo Tail4,500 Bells   Ankylo Fossil Fossil NameValue at Nook's Store Ankylo Skull3,500 Bells Ankylo Torso3,000 Bells  Ankylo Tail2,500 Bells  Apato Fossil   Fossil NameValue at Nook's Store Apato Skull5,000 Bells  Apato Torso4,500 Bells  Apato Tail4,000 Bells   Dimetrodon Fossil  Fossil NameValue at Nook's Store Dimetrodon Skull5,500 Bells  Dimetrodon Torso3,500 Bells  Dimetrodon Tail4,500 Bells  Iguanodon Fossil  Fossil NameValue at Nook's Store Iguanodon Skull4,000 Bells  Iguanodon Torso3,500 Bells  Iguanodon Tail3,000 Bells   Mammoth Fossil Fossil NameValue at Nook's Store Mammoth Skull3,000 Bells  Mammoth Torso2,500 Bells   Pachy Fossil Fossil NameValue at Nook's Store Pachy Skull 4,000 Bells Pachy Torso3,500 Bells  Pachy Tail3,000 Bells Parasaur Fossil  Fossil NameValue at Nook's Store Parasaur Skull3,500 Bells  Parasaur Torso3,000 Bells  Parasaur Tail2,500 Bells   Sabertooth Fossil  Fossil NameValue at Nook's Store Sabertooth Skull2,500 Bells  Sabertooth Torso2,000 Bells  Stego Fossil Fossil NameValue at Nook's Store Stego Skull5,000 Bells  Stego Torso4,500 Bells  Stego Tail4,000 Bells Plesio Fossil   Fossil NameValue at Nook's Store  Plesio Skull4,500 Bells  Plesio Neck4,500 Bells  Plesio Torso4,500 Bells   T-Rex Fossil Fossil NameValue at Nook's Store T-Rex Skull6,000 Bells  T-Rex Torso5,500 Bells  T-Rex Tail5,000 Bells    Tricera Fossil Fossil NameValue at Nook's Store Tricera Skull5,500 Bells  Tricera Torso5,000 Bells  Tricera Tail4,500 Bells  Miscellaneous Fossils   Fossil NameValue at Nook's Store Amber1,200 Bells  Ammonite1,100 Bells  Dino Droppings1,100 Bells  Dinosaur Egg1,400 Bells  Fern Fossil1,000 Bells  Dinosaur Track1,000 Bells  Archaeopteryx1,300 Bells  Pecking Man1,100 Bells  Shark Tooth1,000 Bells  Trilobite1,300 Bells  Places Town HallThe player in Town Hall The player may check what the other villagers think about the environment, change the Town Tune (which plays every time a villager is talked to and every hour that passes), donate Bells to the poor people of a foreign town called Boondox, or move out of the town (that is to say, delete a character from the card). One can also mail letters at the Post Office to the right area of the Town Hall, save and/or withdraw Bells into a bank account (which accrues interest), save a letter, and pay off Tom Nook for the house. The last thing on the Town Hall is the Recycling Bin, which is emptied Mondays and Thursdays at 6 a.m and will occasionally hold random items.   Tom Nook's StoreConcept art for Nook's CrannyAt the beginning, Nook's "store" is actually only a wooden shack, featuring an extremely limited amount of items to choose from. Tom Nook changes his stock daily, offering different furniture piece and tools each day, though rarely anything too rare. As the player buys and sells more items from Nook, the store will expand and grow larger. Here's a brief explanation of the expansions:  Nook's Cranny: Available from the start. It's a wooden shack with a very limited amount of items for sale. Nook n' Go: The first expansion of the store. It looks more like a mini-market and has a fair selection of items to choose from. The store will expand to this once you pay Nook 25,000 Bells or get the same amount of money from him by selling. Nookway: A supermarket with a good selection of items to buy. This expansion will be done when you've paid Nook around 90,000 Bells and/or have received from Nook 90,000 Bells. Nookingtons: The final store upgrade, with a huge selection of items, two floors full of goodies, and a barber shop. Tom Nook takes care of needs on the first floor, while his two nephews, Timmy and Tommy, take over on the second. Available after spending/selling 240,000 bells worth of stuff and having a friend from a different town shop at the store. Another thing that makes Nook's store different than a regular one is the PTM system, a machine in the corner of the store that gives points every time an item is bought. For every 100 bells, 1 point is added. After reaching 300 points, the player acquires Membership Status, which earns a model of Nook's Cranny. At 5,000 points a 5% discount is offered for every item bought and the Nook n' Go model is rewarded, at 10,000 points a 10% discount is offered and the Nookway model is rewarded, and at 20,000 points a 20% discount is offered and the Nookington's model is rewarded.The Able Sisters This store is right next to Tom Nook's. It's clothing-orientated, so you'll only visit the shop to buy new clothes and accessories like a cool hat or sunglasses, etc. You can also design a pattern of your own for 360 Bells, and you can use that pattern as your clothing, your hat, a floor/wall decoration, or the town flag. You can also have one of your patterns displayed in the store, allowing you to double the amount of patterns you have, and allowing villagers to buy a copy of it for themselves. You can sell stuff in this store as well, but only clothing-orientated items and for competitive prices. The shop is run by two hedgehog sisters, Mabel and Sable, listed above. Speaking with BlathersMuseum This museum is completely empty at the beginning, with only Blathers the Owl at the entry hall, sitting alone and waiting for guests. After speaking with Blathers, the player can donate fish, insects, fossils or paintings (paintings are only found on Crazy Redd's store). You can also gain information on the museum, identify a fossil and, of course, look at the exhibits. At the beginning Blathers says he's rather ashamed that there's next to nothing in the museum, but as the player donates more he becomes quite proud of the progress.Observatory - Located in the Museum building, the Observatory is run by Celeste, the owl sister of Blathers. Here the player can gaze at the stars through the telescope or create constellations in the sky, which will be shown at night on the top screen of the DS. After creating a constellation, Celeste asks for a name, and a time in which it can best be seen.Coffee Shop - The Coffee Shop is also located in the Museum building. The owner of the Coffee Shop (The Roost) is a pigeon named Brewster, who is initially not very friendly nor open to others. The asking price for a cup of coffee is 200 bells, and at the beginning he will only say "it might be a tad expensive but it's worth it" and "thanks..." As the player visits his shop more often and drinks coffee from him, he'll warm up, start talking more, and ask if he can put pigeon milk into the coffee. Several other NPCs hang around the Roost at specific times, including Kapp'n, Pelly, Phyllis, Ressetti, Rover and other people. On Saturday evenings at 8 p.m., K.K. Slider performs. Town GateOne of the most important areas in town is the Town Gate. To someone who doesn't play this game with friends, the town gate makes almost no difference to them. However, this is the gateway to the outside world: through this gate, one can visit another town or have others visit them. In addition, this is where you manage your town flag and use the lost and found. K.K. Slider Songs Agent K.K.Aloha K.K. Café K.K.  Comrade K.K. DJ K.K.Forest LifeGo K.K. RiderI Love YouImperial K.K.K.K. AriaK.K. BalladK.K. BluesK.K. BossaK.K. CalypsoK.K. CasbahK.K. ChoraleK.K. CondorK.K. CountryK.K. Cruisin'K.K. D  BK.K. DirgeK.K. DixieK.K. EtudeK.K. FaireK.K. FolkK.K. FusionK.K. GumboK.K. JazzK.K. LamentK.K. Love SongK.K. LullabyK.K. MamboK.K. MarathonK.K. MarchK.K. MetalK.K. RagtimeK.K. RallyK.K. ReggaeK.K. RockK.K. RockabilityK.K. SafariK.K. SalsaK.K. SambaK.K. SkaK.K. SongK.K. SoulK.K. SteppeK.K. SwingK.K. TangoK.K. TechnopopK.K. WaltzK.K. WesternKing K.K.Lucky K.K.Marine Song 2001Mountain SongMr. K.K.My PlaceNeapolitanOnly MePonderingRockin' K.K.Señor K.K.Soulful K.K.Steep HillSurfin' K.K.The K. FunkTo the EdgeTwo Days Ago</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21257">Harvest Moon: Magical Melody</game><game id="18673">Pokémon Yellow: Special Pikachu Edition</game><game id="17463">The Sims</game><game id="15926">Harvest Moon: Friends of Mineral Town</game><game id="21401">MySims Kingdom</game><game id="2168">Viva Piñata</game><game id="21631">Little King's Story</game><game id="3105">Harvest Moon: A Wonderful Life</game><game id="20682">Viva Piñata: Trouble in Paradise</game><game id="21062">Viva Piñata: Pocket Paradise</game><game id="12003">Viva Piñata: Party Animals</game><game id="503">Giftpia</game><game id="6913">Harvest Moon: Back to Nature</game><game id="23920">Harvest Moon: Welcome to the Wind Bazaar</game><game id="24354">Magician’s Quest: Mysterious Times</game><game id="2473">The Sims 2</game><game id="7682">MySims</game><game id="12573">Harvest Moon DS</game><game id="22437">Harvest Moon DS Cute</game><game id="21055">Harvest Moon: Island of Happiness</game><game id="23982">Tomodachi Collection</game><game id="20581">The Sims 3</game><game id="24244">Atelier Annie: Alchemists of Sera Island</game><game id="27199">Rune Factory 3: A Fantasy Harvest Moon</game><game id="28216">Lina no Atelier: Strahl no Renkinjutsushi</game><game id="1842">The Urbz: Sims in the City</game><game id="26917">My Friends</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2097995-box_acww.png</image></root>