<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9255</id><name>Fatal Frame II: Crimson Butterfly</name><description>OverviewFatal Frame II: Crimson Butterfly is the second game in the Fatal Frame (Project Zero in Europe, Zero in Japan) survival horror franchise. The game was first released for the Playstation 2 in 2003, and then for Xbox in 2004 as a Director's Cut version with exclusive content. The game was later remade for the Nintendo Wii, but this version was only released in Japan and Europe.StoryTwin sisters Mio and Mayu Amakura wander through the woods one day when they find themselves in a lost village. Mio, who feels protective of her sister due to Mayu having suffered a childhood injury that's left her with a permanent limp, finds a Camera Obscura, and must use it to defend herself and her sister from ghosts that haunt the abandoned homes and other buildings. But before they're able to leave, Mayu disappears, and Mio must find her before they become the latest victims in an ancient sacrificial ritual involving twin sisters.GameplayThe basic gameplay mechanics are largely identical to the first game. The player must explore the lost village from a third-perspective with fixed camera angles to uncover secrets, solve puzzles, and evade ghosts. When using the Camera Obscura, the game switches to a first-person view. The Xbox Director's Cut version features an exclusive mode in which the entire game can be played from a first-person perspective.To defeat ghosts, the player must use the Camera Obscure to snap photographs of them. The better the photograph, the more damage inflicted. while you take pictures of ghosts to harm them.</description><genres><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2842">Haunting Ground</game><game id="22605">Cursed Mountain</game><game id="10369">Silent Hill 3</game><game id="6328">Silent Hill 4: The Room</game><game id="10780">Silent Hill 2</game><game id="4312">Silent Hill</game><game id="17962">Clock Tower 3</game><game id="25707">Silent Hill: Shattered Memories</game><game id="26599">Ghostwire</game><game id="25888">Ju-On: The Grudge</game><game id="9418">Resident Evil 2</game><game id="29295">Phase Paradox</game><game id="15099">Kuon</game><game id="42171">DreadOut</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1867804-box_fframe2.png</image></root>