<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9259</id><name>Twisted Metal: Head-On</name><description>OverviewTwisted Metal: Head-On is a vehicular combat game and also part of the Twisted Metal series. Head-On is the first game in the series to go portable. The game is widely considered to be the true sequel to Twisted Metal 2, despite there already being a Twisted Metal III. The story is akin to its predecessors where a mysterious man named Calypso holds a tournament called Twisted Metal, where the victor is granted a single wish. The story continues the "be careful what you wish for" theme laid down by its predecessors where Calypso tends to twist the wish of the victor making them worse off than before.GameplayThe gameplay continues the traditional formula of its predecessors. Players use a variety of weapons such as bullets and missiles to destroy the vehicles of their opponents. In Twisted Metal: Head-On each vehicle also has its own unique ability, such as Twister's ability to create a tornado that sucks up enemy vehicles in its range.VehiclesGrasshopper Mr.  Grimm Outlaw Roadkill Shadow Spectre Sweet Tooth Thumper Twister Warthog ATV Axel Cousin Eddy Crimson Fury Dark Tooth Hammerhead Mr. Slam Tower Tooth  LevelsBig Blue Stadium Los Angeles Paris Egypt Roman Ruins Russia Greece Monaco Tokyo Streets Tokyo Rooftop </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="38">Vehicular Combat</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6426">Twisted Metal: Black</game><game id="14769">Twisted Metal Small Brawl</game><game id="205">Pursuit Force</game><game id="689">Jak X: Combat Racing</game><game id="4315">WWE Crush Hour</game><game id="14204">Mashed: Drive to Survive</game><game id="23277">Vigilante 8 Arcade</game><game id="12364">Battle Cars</game><game id="23527">Hardware 2</game><game id="16728">Powerslide</game><game id="25512">Clutch</game><game id="23930">Wild Metal</game><game id="5917">Cyber Sled</game><game id="7242">1NSANE</game><game id="12975">Super Chase H.Q.</game><game id="9461">Critical Depth</game><game id="37266">Smash 'n' Survive</game><game id="28960">Metal Drift</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2011584-box_tmetalho.png</image></root>