<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9365</id><name>Touch Detective</name><description>OverviewTouch detective is a point-and-click adventure game for the Nintendo DS, developed by Beeworks released in October 24, 2006. It is known as Osawari Tantei: Ozawa Rina in Japan, and Mystery Detective in Europe outside of France. It was published in Japan by Success Corp, later brought to America by Atlus USA, and in Europe by 505 Games. It was released for iOS in 2011 and Android in late 2012, with the first chapter being free to download.GameplayYou play as detective Mackenzie, solving mysteries in the town of Osawari. The game is controlled by using the touch screen, searching for clues, and talking to characters in town. Mackenzie has a pet mushroom named Funghi, which can be used for hints, or to help out in puzzles. The game contains a touch notebook, which lists major items that have been touched by the player.Mobile VersionOutside of the Nintendo DS version also exists iPhone and Android versions of the games. The main app is downloaded for free and comes with the entirety of chapter 1 and part one of chapter 2. and additional episodes are provided via additional purchases made within the app.Funghi Breaks Out!In addition to the main game, the mobile versions also feature a new game mode called "Funghi Breaks Out!" You can only play this if you have purchased it from within the app.In this game you play as Funghi where you are set within different areas and must escape by utilizing the items found in the environment. Mackenzie and Cromwell are both missing as well, and it's up to you to look for them.Purchasable Items[Chapter 2, Part 2  Chapter 3, Part 1][Chapter 3, Part 2 Chapter 4, Part 1][Chapter 4, Part 2  Funghi Breaks Out!][Purchase All Scenarios + Funghi Breaks Out!]If episodes are purchased individually, you have to buy them in order.</description><genres><genre id="4">Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1159">Hotel Dusk: Room 215</game><game id="19409">Phoenix Wright: Ace Attorney</game><game id="21807">Unsolved Crimes</game><game id="21826">Defenders of Law Inc: Crime in Willburg</game><game id="17990">Trace Memory</game><game id="23075">Ikatan: Ikamono Tantei</game><game id="8676">Touch Detective 2 1/2</game><game id="24237">Again</game><game id="17544">Broken Sword: The Shadow of the Templars</game><game id="25340">Tokyo Twilight Busters</game><game id="22330">Jake Hunter: Detective Chronicles</game><game id="21052">Time Hollow</game><game id="21578">Ace Attorney Investigations: Miles Edgeworth</game><game id="24071">So Blonde</game><game id="28435">Agatha Christie: The ABC Murders</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2478705-box_td.png</image></root>