<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>939</id><name>Real Bout Fatal Fury</name><description>Overview Real Bout Fatal Fury (known in Japan as Real Bout Garou Densetsu) is a fighting game developed and published by                    SNK for the                     Neo Geo. The character roster and game engine return from                   Fatal Fury 3, with some new additions. The boss characters from Fatal Fury 3 are now playable, as well as the return of                  Kim Kaphwan,                 Billy Kane, and                Duck King.               Geese Howard reprises his role as the game's boss, organizing another "King of Fighters" tournament. This game marks the canonical death of Geese Howard, as he falls from Geese Tower after refusing help from              Terry Bogard. (Shown in the introduction to             Garou: Mark of the Wolves)  The game was ported to the            Neo Geo CD,           Sega Saturn, and          PlayStation (only in Japan and PAL regions). The original Neo Geo version was also released in the         Fatal Fury Battle Archives Volume 2 compilation for the        PlayStation 2. Gameplay Although much of the control mechanics in this game return from Fatal Fury 3, there are big differences. Each player now has three attack buttons (punch, kick, and strong attack) and one button to control the "oversway" system. Real Bout Fatal Fury also revamps the desperation move system and introduces a power gauge, which allows the player to use one of three special techniques: guard cancels (when the gauge is half full), desperation moves (when the gauge is filled), and hidden desperation moves. Players who have a full power gauge and less than half of his life gauge will trigger "P. Power" mode, where the power gauge will gradually drain and allow the player to execute as much guard cancels and desperation moves as he likes, as well as execute the hidden desperation move. Guard cancels do not use up any portion of the power gauge.  Real Bout Fatal Fury is the only game in the Fatal Fury series to feature the concept of ring-outs. When the player performs certain attacks on their opponent while the opponent is next to certain boundaries, those barriers would eventually break, causing an instant lose for the player that falls off the boundary. Characters                                  Terry Bogard                                Andy Bogard                               Joe Higashi                              Mai Shiranui                             Kim Kaphwan                            Billy Kane                           Duck King                          Blue Mary                         Ryuji Yamazaki                        Jin Chonshu                       Jin Chonrei     Sokaku Mochizuki                      Bob Wilson   Hon-Fu  Franco Bash                     Geese Howard</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8680">Street Fighter Alpha 3 MAX</game><game id="10674">Garou: Mark of the Wolves</game><game id="11156">X-Men vs. Street Fighter</game><game id="7111">Savage Reign</game><game id="14669">Virtua Fighter Animation</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="10486">Fighter's History</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1408741-rbfatalfury_box.jpg</image></root>