<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9423</id><name>Ticket to Ride</name><description>OverviewTicket to Ride is a Xbox Live Arcade conversion of the titular board game, designed by Alan R. Moon. It was developed by Next Level Games and published by Playful Entertainment. The game was released on Xbox Live Arcade on June 25th, 2008, costing 800 Microsoft Points. You can play single player against AIs with up to 3 different level setting or go online on Xbox Live to have a 5 player game; in addition, there is a hot-seat multiplayer where you can have 4 players play locally on the same console.GameplayGameplay screenshotPlayers use two types of cards to complete the game: Destination Tickets, which show two cities that need to be connected to earn points, and train cards, which are colored based on what type of cargo they are carrying. At the start of the game, players receive three randomly drawn destination cards and must keep at least two; they are also given four train cards and forty five train pieces, which are used to mark claimed routes on the board.Each turn, players can choose to do one of three things: draw more train cards, which are needed to claim routes; draw new Destination Tickets, if they have already competed the Destination Tickets they own; or claim a route. Routes claimed must be the same color as the train cards they are hold their hand. For example, if a route has five yellow cars on it, the player must give up five of his yellow cars he had in his hand. There are also locomotive cards that serve as wild-cards, which can be used as a substitute for any color. Players earn points both by claiming routes and by completing destination cards.When one of the players has depleted his/her trains, the game goes into the final round in which all players get one last turn. If a player still has Destination Tickets that have not been completed, the points on the ticket are subtracted from the player's final score. The player with the longest continuous route at the end of the game receives bonus points.Downloadable ContentEuropeEuropean continentThe Europe Downloadable Content for TTR was released on August 1st, 2008, costing 600 Microsoft Points. The new continent adds several new elements to the game. You not only have the choice of claiming normal routes, but you also have tunnels and ferries. When you claim a tunnel section three cards will be drawn at random and for each that matches the color of the route you will need to spend one more train card of that color. If you don't have enough cards of that color you will have to end your turn without claiming the tunnel. Ferries require the use of the locomotives. The other new element is that you are able to build train stations on cities and share another players route into or out of that city. This is handy since it seems to be a lot easier to have people fighting for the same routesUSA 1910USA 1910 uses the same North America map from the base game but adds 35 new Destination Tickets and a new Bonus Card. The new Bonus Card is called "Globetrotter" and is won by completing the most tickets during a game. With the new tickets and bonus card the add-on introduced three new types of gameplay:1910: Play with only the new Destination Tickets and the new "Globetrotter" Bonus Card.Big Cities: Play with Destination Tickets that all connects to one of the following cities: Chicago, Dallas, Houston, Los Angeles, Miami, New York and Seattle. No bonus card is used. Players will be dealt 4 Destination Tickets at the start of a game and must keep 2. When new Destination Tickets are drawn players must choose 1 out of 4 drawn tickets.Mega Game: Play with all 65 Destination Tickets and both bonus cards. Players will be dealt 5 Destination Tickets at the start of a game and must keep 3. When new Destination Tickets are drawn players must choose 1 out of 4 drawn tickets.PC System RequirementsOS: Windows XP, Windows Vista, Windows 7Processor: Dual Core 1.6 GHz or betterMemory: 1GB (XP), 2GB (Vista), 2GB (Windows 7)Hard Disk Space: 140 MB Free SpaceVideo Card: OpenGL 1.4 or higherSound: Windows supported Sound Card</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="14">Trivia/Board Game</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17086">Carcassonne</game><game id="21010">Catan</game><game id="20764">Lost Cities</game><game id="23813">Domino Master</game><game id="25343">Tide of Iron</game><game id="25753">Penguins &amp; Friends: Hey! That's My Fish!</game><game id="29748">RISK: Factions</game><game id="40025">Carcassonne</game><game id="40216">Super Momotarou Dentetsu II</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1858021-box_ttr.png</image></root>