<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9439</id><name>Wii Play</name><description>OverviewWii Play (Hajimete No Wii in japan) is a minigame collection that comes packaged with a Wii Remote. It is available for only a small price more than a single Wii remote on it's own, and this is often attributed as the reason for its success. It consists of nine simple minigames, all of which can be played by one player or two. The 9 games are Shooting Range, Find Mii, Table Tennis, Pose Mii, Laser Hockey, Fishing, Billiards, Charge!, and Tanks!.GameShooting RangeShooting RangeIn shooting range, players try to destroy as many targets as possible, using the Wii remote as a pointer and shooting with A or B. Targets include balloons, targets, clay pigeons, cans and UFO's. Occasionally targets with the face of the player's Mii will appear. Points will be lost for shooting targets displaying their own mii, but gained for shooting targets displaying their opponents Mii. Also, in homage to the classic NES game Duck Hunt, between rounds ducks will fly across the screen, and points will be gained for shooting them.Find MiiFind MiiFind Mii displays a selection of Mii's to the player, in various situations, from just standing around, to walking across a road and even swimming. The player will be asked to find a certain Mii, or a group of Mii's. For example, the player might be asked to find 5 identical Mii's, or the player's Mii, or even a Mii that is travelling faster than the other ones.Table TennisTable TennisTable tennis is a very basic game of table tennis. By pointing the Wii remote at the screen the player controls the position of his paddle. To hit the ball, the player must put the paddle in line with the ball. There is no swinging of the Wii remote required.Pose MiiPose MiiBy pointing their Wii remote at the screen, the player can control the position of their Mii. The Mii's pose can also be changed by pressing the A or B button. Bubbles containing a silhouette of the Mii will float down onto the screen. The player must match the Mii in the exact position of the silhouette, which will make the bubble burst. If three bubbles are not burst, and reach the bottom of the screen the game will end.Laser HockeyLaser HockeyLaser hockey is a brightly colored version of air hockey, in which the player controls a paddle which he must use to defend his goal, and score in the opponents goal. In single player the game lasts two minutes. The winner is whoever has most points after two minutes. In a two player game, the game has no time limit, the winner is the first to score eight goalsFishingFishingIn Fishing, you use the pointer to move your rod around and into the pond, and score points according to the type of fish you catch.BilliardsBilliardsBilliards is a pretty standard game of 9 ball pool.Charge!Charge!Charge!, as strange as it may sound, is a race on cowback. That's right, you ride a cow and score points for knocking down scarecrows and arriving to the finish first.Tanks!Tanks!Finally, Tanks!, the only game that supports nunchuk is about moving a toy tank around a world made out of cubes and trying to destroy the enemy tanks.Other Info1-2 playersNunchuk compatible</description><genres><genre id="17">Minigame Collection</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="13328">Wii Sports</game><game id="20913">Sports Party</game><game id="20503">Wii Fit</game><game id="21824">Cooking Mama: World Kitchen</game><game id="21099">Wii Music</game><game id="6406">Battle City</game><game id="29716">Deca Sports DS</game><game id="29758">Family Party: 30 Great Games Winter Fun</game><game id="31897">Tron Evolution: Battle Grids</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5150/811185-wii_play.jpg</image></root>