<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9446</id><name>Dominions 3: The Awakening</name><description> Dominions 3 plays out on a randomly generatedmap (although campaign maps are included) which resemble the basic riskformula. You can see the countries, unit and city information, the borders and so forth. From this map you can deploy your troops, recruit troops, look for treasure, upgrade the cities, in short - build up your empire in a turn-basedmanner. The game's core is similar to other empire building games such as Master of Magic. Yet, the strategic depth does not lie in micromanagement of towns, with only half a dozen buildings available, but in the units. With hundreds of different units at your disposal, you will spend some time in building and configuring your armies, which include heroes, who themselves can level up and find artifacts etc. The game also features a deep magic system with various magic schools. Your avatar (the in-game representation of your divinity) and your race are highly customizable. The game changes drastically depending on which avatar, school of magic and race you choose. There are many races in the game which are based on various inspirations, including mythology(Greek mythology etc.), Literature ( Lovecraftiannations) or history (Roman Empire). The game comes with an extensive and elaborate Manual. The graphics of the game are not the focal point of the game, the battles can be reviewed in retrospective to analyze the outcome in more detail.System RequirementsPCOS: Windows XP/Vista/7 Processor: 1 GHz Memory: 512 MB RAM Graphics: OpenGL capable graphics card Hard Drive: 350 MB available spaceMacOS: 10.3 or later Processor: Any PowerPC or Intel cpu Memory: 512 MB RAM Hard Drive: 350 MB available spaceLinuxOS: Any GNU/Linux distribution Processor: x86, 32 or 64 bit, 1 GHz or faster Memory: 512 MB RAM Graphics: OpenGL capable graphics card Hard Drive: 350 MB available space</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="18279">Age of Wonders: Shadow Magic</game><game id="13989">Heroes of Might and Magic III: The Restoration of Erathia</game><game id="13076">Age of Mythology</game><game id="18327">Fantasy Empires</game><game id="18414">Age of Wonders</game><game id="15976">Age of Wonders II: The Wizard's Throne</game><game id="1370">Age of Mythology: The Titans</game><game id="1915">Heroes of Might and Magic V</game><game id="10692">Heroes of Might and Magic IV</game><game id="14391">Heroes of Might and Magic: A Strategic Quest</game><game id="12466">Heroes of Might and Magic II: The Succession Wars</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/2891/814508-dominions_box.jpg</image></root>