<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9459</id><name>Culdcept</name><description>OverviewCuldcept is part of long-running hybrid digital board and card game series. Players take the role of an inexperienced Cepter whose task it is to collect the wayward fragments of Culdcept, the book of creation. These fragments take the form of cards which Cepters have the unique ability to use in summoning monsters and magical powers. Goligan, a servant of the Goddess Culdra, is sent to guide the player's character and offer advice and wisdom.Functionally, it has been compared to a bizarre fusion of Magic: The Gathering and Monopoly and has some basis on another Japanese digital board game, Fortune Street.The original title was released in 1997 for the Sega Saturn in Japan. In 2000 a revised edition, Culdcept Expansion, was released on the Japanese market for the Playstation. 2008's Japan-only Culdcept DS was released for the series' 10th Anniversary with even more cards, a modernized ruleset and a robust set of online features including free maps and exclusive cards.Its 2001 sequel, Culdcept Second, originally debuted on the Japanese Dreamcast. Its revised edition, Culdcept Second Expansion, was released in 2002 for the Playstation 2 in Japan. In the year 2003 Culdcept Second Expansion received a North American release retitled as simply 'Culdcept' in an effort to confuse as many people as possible.ts combination of collecting cards along with fun strategy elements is highly addictive by most people who pick up the game for the first time, even if the english translation is often questionable on some of the cards.GameplayThe players control a character each called a Cepter, and each Cepter have a custom-made "book" (or rather, deck of cards) consisting of 50 cards. Players can customize their books before or after battles, but once a player have picked 50 cards and started a battle they can only use those cards they chose. New cards to choose from is mostly random rewards after battles, and it can be somewhat overwhelming to collect all the cards available. As players build up their roster of cards they must carefully decide what 50 cards they want to include in their book, as there are 7 different card-types to choose from: Neutral monsters, Fire monsters, Air monsters, Water monsters, Earth monsters, Items and Spells.A typical Culdcept map.The maps, that looks like traditional gameboards, are constructed so the players move in laps. As suggested by the different colours of monsters, there are several different coloured areas on the board, and placing a monster on its colour boosts its powers. Every turn the player roll a die and move so many squares as the die say, and then have to make an action depending on where they land. It can be placing out a monster from their book, or if the space is occupied by another player's monster they can attack or pay tribute straight away, among several other actions. Just like Monopoly players can later upgrade the squares they have populated by their monsters, so the unfortunate opponent that land there have to pay more tribute in case they can't beat the monster that occupies the space.CardsEvery monster have special statistics, which are:ST: Strength, how much damage the monster does each attack.HP: Health, how much health the monster currently have.MHP: Maximum Health, how much health the monster have when it comes into play. Everytime a player makes a full lap around the board, all monsters regain 20% MHP.G: How much it costs to place a monster on the board.Neutral Monsters (Gray)Amber MosquitoAmber MosquitoST:0 HP:40 MHP:40 G:10Item Limit: ScrollsIn Battle: Transforms into Tyrannosaurus or Giant Rat.ArchbishopArchbishopST:30 HP:30 MHP:30 G:60Territory (50G): Removes Enchantment effects from target creature (territory). / Immune to Destroy Item and Steal Item effects.BaldandersBaldandersST:0 HP:30 MHP:30 G:10In Battle: Transforms into a random creature.BanditBanditST:20 HP:20 MHP:20 G:20Support / Attack Bonus: Steals (damage dealt x2G) magic from opponent.Basalt IdolBasalt IdolST:0 HP:20 MHP:20 G:50Item Limit: Weapons ScrollsDefensive / Global Ability: All creatures cannot use abilities that trigger at Battle End or Upon Defeat.Battle Gear AlphaBattle Gear AlphaST:40 HP:20 MHP:20 G:60Item Limit: ScrollsSupport / Transforms into Bundlegear if Battle Gear Beta is used as Support. / Cannot be targeted by spells or territory abilities.Battle Gear BetaBattle Gear BetaST:20 HP:40 MHP:40 G:60Item Limit: ScrollsSupport / Transforms into Bundlegear if Battle Gear Alpha is used as Support. / Neutralizes: Scroll attacks.BerserkerBerserkerST:40 HP:50 MHP:50 G:50Attack Bonus: Confusion (to itself)BorgessBorgessST:30 HP:30 MHP:30 G:50Boost: HP 20 to Neutral creatures.Brass IdolBrass IdolST:0 HP:20 MHP:20 G:40Item Limit: Weapons ScrollsDefensive / Global Ability: All Cepters draw two cards when drawing instead of one.BundlegearBundlegearST:60 HP:70 MHP:70 G:250Item Limit: ScrollsNeutralizes: Scroll attacks. / Cannot be targeted by spells or territory abilities.ClericClericST:10 HP:30 MHP:30 G:55Support / Instant Death: 80% against Neutral creatures.Clockwork OwlClockwork OwlST:0 HP:20 MHP:20 G:10Item Limit: Weapons ArmorTerritory (30G): Target Cepter can choose movement direction next turn.ColossusColossusST:70 HP:70 MHP:70 G:120Item Limit: Weapons Armor Tools ScrollsDoes not receive lap recovery. / Cannot be targeted by Enchantment spells or Enchantment territory abilities.Cray IdolCray IdolST:0 HP:20 MHP:20 G:60Item Limit: Weapons ScrollsDefensive / Global Ability: Damage to all creatures from spells and territory abilities is reduced by 10.CyclopsCyclopsST:50 HP:50 MHP:50 G:60Attacks LastDancing DollDancing DollST:20 HP:20 MHP:20 G:30Territory (70G): Lowers the value of all symbols by 20%.DecoyDecoyST:0 HP:10 MHP:10 G:40 []Item Limit: Weapons ArmorReflects: All attacks (except scroll attacks)DoppelgangerDoppelgangerST:0 HP:30 MHP:30 G:10 []In Battle: Transforms into same creature as opponent.Ebony IdolEbony IdolST:0 HP:20 MHP:20 G:40Item Limit: Weapons ScrollsDefensive / Global Ability: All creatures cannot use territory abilities.FighterFighterST:40 HP:40 MHP:40 G:40Giant RatGiant RatST:20 HP:10 MHP:10 G:0Item Limit: ScrollsAttacks FirstGoblinGoblinST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:0Golden TotemGolden TotemST:0 HP:30 MHP:30 G:0Item Limit: WeaponsDefensive / Territory (0G): Gives its user 300G, then is destroyedGold IdolGold IdolST:0 HP:20 MHP:20 G:70Item Limit: Weapons ScrollsDefensive / Global Ability: Requirements for summoning creatures other than magic cost are ignored.Granite IdolGranite IdolST:0 HP:20 MHP:20 G:60Item Limit: Weapons ScrollsDefensive / Global Ability: All Cepters cannot be targeted by Flash spells or Flash territory abilities (except those that dispel Enchantment effects).Horned ChameleonHorned ChameleonST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:40Item Limit: ScrollsReceives land effect from lands of any element.Iron IdolIron IdolST:0 HP:20 MHP:20 G:40Item Limit: Weapons ScrollsDefensive / Global ability: Die yields only 4-6 when rolled normally.Ivory IdolIvory IdolST:0 HP:20 MHP:20 G:60Item Limit: Weapons ScrollsDefensive / Global Ability: Cards of rarity S require 1.5x magic to use. Cards of rarity R and E require double.Jade IdolJade IdolST:0 HP:20 MHP:20 G:50Item Limit: Weapons ScrollsDefensive / Global Ability: All territories are prevented from undergoing land transformation via spells or territory abilities and are immune to effects that lower land levels.Little GrayLittle GrayST:10 HP:20 MHP:20 G:50 []Attack Bonus: Moves opposing creature to random vacant land.Living ShieldLiving ShieldST:0 HP:30 MHP:30 G:40Item Limit: Weapons Armor ScrollsItem CreatureLiving SpearLiving SpearST:20 HP:20 MHP:20 G:50Item Limit: Weapons Armor ScrollsItem CreatureLiving SwordLiving SwordST:30 HP:1 MHP:1 G:30Item Limit: Weapons Armor ScrollsItem CreatureLunatic HareLunatic HareST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:20Battle End: Swaps opponent's ST and HP values.Marble IdolMarble IdolST:0 HP:20 MHP:20 G:70Item Limit: Weapons ScrollsDefensive / Global Ability: Creatures of the same type as those already in play cannot be summoned.MigoalMigoalST:40 HP:40 MHP:40 G:80 []Critical Hit: Water Earth / Neutralizes: Fire AirMystic EggMystic EggST:0 HP:30 MHP:30 G:0In Battle: Transforms into a different creature based on the item used.NinjaNinjaST:40 HP:40 MHP:40 G:80Attacks First / Scroll Critical HitSamuraiSamuraiST:50 HP:30 MHP:30 G:80Instant Death: 60% vs. creatures with MHP of 30 and under.Sanctum GuardSanctum GuardST:40 HP:40 MHP:40 G:70Attacks First / Upon Victory: User gains 5 symbols of same element as battle territory.Silver IdolSilver IdolST:0 HP:20 MHP:20 G:50Item Limit: Weapons ScrollsDefensive / Global Ability: In battle, all defending creatures gain Attacks First ability.SkeletonSkeletonST:30 HP:40 MHP:40 G:30Item Limit: ScrollsRegenerates.SquonkSquonkST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:0Support / Upon Victory: Returns to user's hand.StatueStatueST:0 HP:50 MHP:50 G:20Item Limit: Weapons ScrollsDefensive / Does not receive lap recovery.Steam GearSteam GearST:50 HP:50 MHP:50 G:60Item Limit: ScrollsClaims 1/2 the standard toll value.ThiefThiefST:20 HP:40 MHP:40 G:30Battle Start: Steals opponent's item if using no items of your own.Trojan HorseTrojan HorseST:0 HP:30 MHP:30 G:50Item Limit: Weapons Armor ScrollsPenetrates / SupportTyrannosaurusTyrannosaurusST:50 HP:60 MHP:60 G:80 []Item Limit: Armor ScrollsWerewolfWerewolfST:30 HP:30 MHP:30 G:30Attack Bonus: Transform opposing creature into Wolf (60%)WolfWolfST:20 HP:40 MHP:40 G:10Item Limit: ScrollsWonder WallWonder WallST:0 HP:30 MHP:30 G:30 []Item Limit: Weapons ArmorDefensive / Neutralizes: Fire Water Earth AirWraithWraithST:10 HP:30 MHP:30 G:40 []Item Limit: ArmorInstant Death: 50% / Battle End: Is destroyed.ZombieZombieST:20 HP:50 MHP:50 G:20Item Limit: ScrollsBattle End: HP-20Fire Monsters (Red)AresAresST:50 HP:60 MHP:60 G:90 RRLand Limit: WaterBoost: ST 20 to invading creatures.Ba=AlBa=AlST:50 HP:50 MHP:50 G:80 R []Attacks First / Battle End: Destroys a random card from user's hand.BardBardST:30 HP:30 MHP:30 G:30Battle End: Moves to a random vacant land when the opposing creature could not be destroyed.Barrow WightBarrow WightST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:30 R []Attack Bonus: SleepBoggartBoggartST:10 HP:30 MHP:30 G:40Item Limit: ArmorClaims double the standard toll value. Returns to user's hand if destroyed by spell or territory ability.Cait SithCait SithST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:60Land Limit: WaterCannot be targeted by spells or territory abilities. / Neutralizes: Attacks from creatures with ST of 40 and up.CatoblepasCatoblepasST:20 HP:50 MHP:50 G:80 RIn Battle: When not using an item, ST=(opposing creature's ST)ChimeraChimeraST:30 HP:50 MHP:50 G:80 RItem Limit: ScrollsAttacks First / ST 10 each time user receives a lap bonus (up to a maximum of 80).ConjurerConjurerST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:40Item Limit: WeaponsTerritory (80G): Summons Ba=Al to vacant land of user's choice, then is destroyed. / Scroll Critical HitDomovikhaDomovikhaST:10 HP:20 MHP:20 G:10Territory (70G): Adds Land Protection to target territory.DomovoiDomovoiST:20 HP:20 MHP:20 G:10Territory (30G): Adds Phantasm to target territory.DragonDragonST:40 HP:60 MHP:60 G:90 RRLand Limit: WaterItem Limit: ArmorIn Battle: ST 20, HP-20 when invading.DragonflyDragonflyST:30 HP:20 MHP:20 G:20Item Limit: ScrollsAttacks FirstEfreetEfreetST:40 HP:60 MHP:60 G:60 RLand Limit: WaterAttacks Last / In Battle: Performs a scroll attack of its base ST value if not equipped with an item / Battle End: User loses G=(amount of own remaining base HP)ExecutorExecutorST:70 HP:20 MHP:20 G:60 []Item Limit: WeaponsFanaticFanaticST:20 HP:20 MHP:20 G:25 RTerritory (60): Decreases its own HP by 20, and does 20 damage to the target creature.Fire GiantFire GiantST:50 HP:50 MHP:50 G:100 RCritical Hit: WaterFlame LordFlame LordST:70 HP:70 MHP:70 G:140 RR []Land Limit: WaterBoost: HP 10 to Fire creatures. / Battle End: User loses 100G magic.Gas CloudGas CloudST:30 HP:30 MHP:30 G:70Item Limit: ArmorNeutralizes: 1/2 of damage received (excludes scroll attacks).GladiatorGladiatorST:40 HP:40 MHP:40 G:70Item Limit: Armor Tools ScrollsCritical Hit: Fire Water Earth AirGolemGolemST:40 HP:50 MHP:50 G:60Battle End: Base ST  Base HP-10Heat ImpHeat ImpST:20 HP:20 MHP:20 G:10 []Territory (50G): Reduces target Cepter's most numerous symbol by 40%, then is destroyed.Hell HoundHell HoundST:50 HP:40 MHP:40 G:80Deals only 1/2 damage to Water creatures.KoboldKoboldST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:20LarvaeLarvaeST:30 HP:50 MHP:50 G:75 []In Battle: ST 20, HP 20 if user holds 3 more cards than the opposing CepterLava WormLava WormST:40 HP:50 MHP:50 G:90 RItem Limit: ArmorPenetrates: WaterManesManesST:30 HP:40 MHP:40 G:50Land Limit: WaterIn Battle: HP 20 if battle territory has an Enchantment upon it.ManticoreManticoreST:0 HP:50 MHP:50 G:70 RIn Battle: ST  HP= (number of cards in user's hand x10).MephistophelesMephistophelesST:40 HP:30 MHP:30 G:50 []Attacking Cepter loses 200G if destroyed by spell or territory ability.MinotaurMinotaurST:40 HP:40 MHP:40 G:70Old WillowOld WillowST:20 HP:40 MHP:40 G:40 RRItem Limit: Weapons ScrollsDefensive / Stops all passing Cepters other than user when placed on a Fire land.PeriPeriST:30 HP:30 MHP:30 G:50 RCannot be targeted by spells or territory abilities. / In Battle: ST  HP 20 when user's book has 3 fewer remaining cards than opponent's book.PhoenixPhoenixST:30 HP:30 MHP:30 G:40Item Limit: ScrollsUpon Defeat: Returns to user's hand.Pillar of FlamePillar of FlameST:30 HP:50 MHP:50 G:30Land Limit: WaterItem Limit: Armor ScrollsDefensivePyrallisPyrallisST:30 HP:40 MHP:40 G:50Land Limit: WaterItem Limit: ScrollsIn Battle: ST=(# of user's Fire territories x10). If user has Water territory, HP-20.Pyro DrakePyro DrakeST:30 HP:40 MHP:40 G:80Land Limit: WaterItem Limit: ArmorIn Battle: ST 20, HP 20 if an item is not used.SalamanderSalamanderST:40 HP:50 MHP:50 G:80 RLand Limit: WaterItem Limit: ArmorHP increases for every point of damage received from Fire creatures (excludes scroll attacks).SharazadSharazadST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:55Support / Territory (30G): Clears all Cepters of Enchantments.Son AsceticSon AsceticST:0 HP:30 MHP:30 G:60Support (Uses abilities of the supporting creature)SorcererSorcererST:0 HP:30 MHP:30 G:40Item Limit: WeaponsScroll Critical Hit / In Battle: Performs a scroll attack of ST=20 if not equipped with an item.Sulfurous BalloonSulfurous BalloonST:10 HP:30 MHP:30 G:15 RItem Limit: ScrollsUpon Defeat: HP-30 to opponent's base HP.ValkyriaValkyriaST:30 HP:30 MHP:30 G:70 RAttacks First / Support / Upon Victory: ST 10 (up to a maximum of 80).Will O' the WispWill O' the WispST:10 HP:50 MHP:50 G:60Item Limit: WeaponsAttacks Last / Attack Bonus: Steals (own remaining base HP x2G) magic from opponent Cepter.Air Monsters (Yellow)ArcherArcherST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:40Item Limit: WeaponsTerritory (30G): Deals 10 damage to target creature.BeelzebubBeelzebubST:70 HP:70 MHP:70 G:140 YY []Land Limit: EarthBoost: HP 10 to Air creatures. / Battle End: User loses 100G magic.CentaurCentaurST:30 HP:40 MHP:40 G:80Attacks First / Battle End: Items equipped recycle to user's book.ChonchonChonchonST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:40In Battle: HP 20 if not equipped with an item. / Battle End: Adds Anti-Element to defending creature if not equipped with an item.CornfolkCornfolkST:30 HP:40 MHP:40 G:70Upon Defeat: User gains 200G magic. / User gains 200G magic if destroyed by spell or territory ability.DhampirDhampirST:40 HP:40 MHP:40 G:80 YNeutralizes: Earth / Instant Death: 60% to Earth creatures.ElfElfST:40 HP:30 MHP:30 G:70 YAttacks First / Critical Hit: EarthGiant BatGiant BatST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:20Item Limit: ScrollsGiant RattlerGiant RattlerST:40 HP:40 MHP:40 G:70Item Limit: ScrollsBattle End: Adds Disease to defending creature if not equipped with an item.GoudaGoudaST:0 HP:40 MHP:40 G:60 YYLand Limit: EarthIn Battle: ST  HP= (number of Air creatures in play x10).GremlinGremlinST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:70Item Limit: ScrollsBattle Start: Destroys opponent's item.GriffonGriffonST:50 HP:50 MHP:50 G:90Land Limit: EarthItem Limit: ScrollsHarpyHarpyST:30 HP:30 MHP:30 G:60Attacks FirstHoly LlamaHoly LlamaST:20 HP:40 MHP:40 G:60Item Limit: ScrollsTerritory (30G): Adds Holy Word 6 to target Cepter. / Can move to any vacant Air land in the area.HornetHornetST:40 HP:30 MHP:30 G:60Item Limit: ScrollsAttack Bonus: PoisonHurricaneHurricaneST:20 HP:50 MHP:50 G:50Land Limit: EarthItem Limit: Armor ScrollsAttacks First / DefensiveIgneous FatuiIgneous FatuiST:10 HP:30 MHP:30 G:10 YY []Land Limit: Fire WaterAttacks Last / Instant Death: 80%KnightKnightST:50 HP:40 MHP:40 G:90Critical Hit: Creatures with MHP of 50 and up.LeprechaunLeprechaunST:20 HP:20 MHP:20 G:40 Y []Battle Start: Gives opponent its own item and forces them to use it.LevelerLevelerST:40 HP:60 MHP:60 G:100 Y []Item Limit: ScrollsBattle End: Lowers level of battle territory by 1 unless it's an Air land.Master MonkMaster MonkST:20 HP:50 MHP:50 G:80Attacks First / In Battle: ST 30, HP-30 if not equipped with an item.MermecoleoMermecoleoST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:60Land Limit: EarthItem Limit: ScrollsAttacks Last / Upon Defeat: Evolves into Dragonfly.Night FiendNight FiendST:0 HP:40 MHP:40 G:70 YYLand Limit: WaterItem Limit: Weapons ArmorAttacks First / In Battle: ST (level of battle territory x20).NightmareNightmareST:30 HP:30 MHP:30 G:50 YPenetratesNikeNikeST:30 HP:30 MHP:30 G:60 YItem Limit: ArmorAttacks First / Attack Bonus: ParalysisNueNueST:40 HP:50 MHP:50 G:80 YLand Limit: EarthBoost: ST-10 to invading creatures.PaladinPaladinST:50 HP:50 MHP:50 G:90 YLand Limit: EarthCritical Hit: Neutral / RegeneratesPegasusPegasusST:30 HP:20 MHP:20 G:60Item Limit: ScrollsAttacks First / Cannot be targeted by spells or territory abilities / Neutralizes: Scroll attacks.Powder EaterPowder EaterST:1 HP:1 MHP:1 G:0Item Limit: ScrollsMultiplies when moving, leaving copies in both former and new locations.PushpullPushpullST:0 HP:40 MHP:40 G:70Item Limit: ScrollsAttacks twice.QuetzalcoatlQuetzalcoatlST:30 HP:50 MHP:50 G:80 YItem Limit: ArmorBoost: ST 10 to Attacks First creatures, Attacks First ability is removed.RoadrunnerRoadrunnerST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:60Item Limit: ScrollsAttacks First / Moves 2 spaces.Soul CollectorSoul CollectorST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:60 []In Battle: ST (number of creatures destroyed thus far x5).SpectreSpectreST:0 HP:30 MHP:30 G:30In Battle: ST  HP= (random value between 10 and 70).SphinxSphinxST:40 HP:50 MHP:50 G:80 Y []Land Limit: EarthAttack Bonus: Confusion / Boost: HP-10 to Earth creatures.SpriteSpriteST:20 HP:20 MHP:20 G:10Land Limit: EarthNeutralizes: Attacks from creatures with MHP of 40 and up.SuccubusSuccubusST:40 HP:40 MHP:40 G:50 []Land Limit: EarthAttack Bonus: Opponent's ST=0.Trample WeedTrample WeedST:20 HP:60 MHP:60 G:30 YItem Limit: Weapons ScrollsDefensive / Level of occupied land cannot be changed.VirusVirusST:10 HP:10 MHP:10 G:0 YLand Limit: EarthItem Limit: Weapons Armor ScrollsBoost: HP-10 to all creatures.WendigoWendigoST:30 HP:50 MHP:50 G:70Battle End: Adds Fog to defending creature if Wendigo is not equipped with an item.Wind ImpWind ImpST:20 HP:20 MHP:20 G:10 []Territory (50G): Target enemy Cepter's G is reduced by 50%, then is destroyed.WitchWitchST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:50Item Limit: WeaponsTerritory (30G): Steals (number of spell and item cards in target enemy Cepter's hand x20G) magic. / Scroll Critical HitWyvernWyvernST:40 HP:40 MHP:40 G:80 YLand Limit: EarthItem Limit: ArmorAttacks First / Can move to any vacant Air land in the area.Earth Monsters (Green)AngosturaAngosturaST:20 HP:60 MHP:60 G:80Item Limit: Weapons ScrollsDefensive / Instant Death: 80% against creatures with MHP of 30 and under.ArmadilloArmadilloST:20 HP:50 MHP:50 G:40Item Limit: ScrollsIn Battle: In an odd-numbered round, HP=60. In an even-numbered round, HP=30.BarometzBarometzST:0 HP:30 MHP:30 G:20Land Limit: FireItem Limit: Weapons ScrollsDefensive / Territory (0G): User gains (lap number x30G) magic.BasiliskBasiliskST:30 HP:40 MHP:40 G:50 GGItem Limit: ArmorInstant Death: 50% / Battle End: Lowers level of battle territory by 1.BlynxBlynxST:20 HP:20 MHP:20 G:40Item Limit: ScrollsCan move to any vacant land within the area. / Cannot be targeted by spells or territory abilities.CarbuncleCarbuncleST:20 HP:20 MHP:20 G:20Support / Reflects: Scroll attacks.CarbunflyCarbunflyST:40 HP:40 MHP:40 G:100 RRItem Limit: ScrollsAttacks First / Reflects: Scroll attacks. / Upon Defeat: Evolves into Carbuncle.CerberusCerberusST:20 HP:40 MHP:40 G:50 GLand Limit: AirItem Limit: ScrollsAttacks twice.CoatiCoatiST:30 HP:30 MHP:30 G:60In Battle: ST (number of Earth creatures in play x5).CockatriceCockatriceST:30 HP:40 MHP:40 G:60 GItem Limit: ScrollsAttack Bonus: Transforms opponent into Wall of Stone.Dark ElfDark ElfST:40 HP:30 MHP:30 G:70 GAttacks First / Critical Hit: AirDark MasterDark MasterST:60 HP:80 MHP:80 G:140 GG []Land Limit: AirBoost: HP 10 to Earth creatures. / Battle End: User loses 100G magic.Death GazeDeath GazeST:50 HP:30 MHP:30 G:70 GLand Limit: AirNeutralizes: Scroll attacks. / Upon Victory: Destroys any cards identical to defeated creature in opponent Cepter's book and hand. (80% chance)Dragon ZombieDragon ZombieST:40 HP:60 MHP:60 G:100Land Limit: AirItem Limit: ArmorDryadDryadST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:60Land Limit: AirItem Limit: WeaponsSupport / Can move to any vacant Earth land within the area.DwarfDwarfST:30 HP:50 MHP:50 G:70GargoyleGargoyleST:30 HP:50 MHP:50 G:90 GAttacks First / In Battle: ST=50 when defending.GhoulGhoulST:40 HP:30 MHP:30 G:50 []Attack Bonus: Paralysis / Upon Victory: RegeneratesGigantheriumGigantheriumST:50 HP:60 MHP:60 G:90 GItem Limit: ScrollsIn Battle: HP-20 if battle territory has an Enchantment upon it.GnomeGnomeST:20 HP:40 MHP:40 G:60Toll value for occupied territory becomes 1.5x.GoobaGoobaST:0 HP:10 MHP:10 G:0Item Limit: ScrollsGooba QueenGooba QueenST:10 HP:40 MHP:40 G:30 GGItem Limit: WeaponsTerritory (20G): Summons Gooba to vacant land of user's choice.Green MoldGreen MoldST:10 HP:50 MHP:50 G:45Item Limit: Weapons ScrollsDefensive / RegeneratesGrimalkinGrimalkinST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:60 GSupport / Cannot be targeted by spells or territory abilities.HealerHealerST:10 HP:40 MHP:40 G:50Regenerates / Territory (20G): Recovers target creature's HP by 30.Huge SpiderHuge SpiderST:30 HP:40 MHP:40 G:70Item Limit: ScrollsAttack Bonus: ParalysisHunbabaHunbabaST:50 HP:40 MHP:40 G:80 G []Land Limit: AirAttack Bonus: Poison / Boost: ST-10 to Air creatures.LeshyLeshyST:30 HP:40 MHP:40 G:50Defensive / Battle End: Raises level of battle territory by 1.MandrakeMandrakeST:10 HP:50 MHP:50 G:55 GLand Limit: AirBattle End: If user's creature's HP is 20 or under, both it and opponent's creature are destroyed.MudmanMudmanST:20 HP:40 MHP:40 G:65Land Limit: AirItem Limit: ArmorIn Battle: HP (number of Earth creatures in play x5).MummyMummyST:20 HP:50 MHP:50 G:40Item Limit: WeaponsDefensive / Upon Defeat: User gains (lap number x50G) magic.OdradekOdradekST:20 HP:20 MHP:20 G:40Support / HP  MHP cannot be altered by spells or territory abilities.PanPanST:30 HP:40 MHP:40 G:60Attack Bonus: ConfusionQuake BeastQuake BeastST:50 HP:30 MHP:30 G:40 GGItem Limit: ArmorTerritory (60G): Lowers adjacent lands one level, then is destroyed.RaksasRaksasST:50 HP:30 MHP:30 G:70 GUpon Victory: Opponent Cepter loses 30% of their most numerous symbol.SageSageST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:70Support / Immune to Destroy Item and Steal Item effects.Spitting CobraSpitting CobraST:40 HP:40 MHP:40 G:70Item Limit: ScrollsTerritory (0G): Adds Poison to target creature.T'ao T'iehT'ao T'iehST:40 HP:40 MHP:40 G:70 GLand Limit: AirUpon Victory: ST  MHP 10 (up to a maximum of 80).Tiger BeetleTiger BeetleST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:20Item Limit: ScrollsTrench WormTrench WormST:40 HP:50 MHP:50 G:90 GItem Limit: ArmorPenetrates: AirTrollTrollST:40 HP:40 MHP:40 G:70Land Limit: Fire AirRegeneratesVampireVampireST:40 HP:40 MHP:40 G:80 GLand Limit: Water AirItem Limit: ArmorAttacks First / Attack Bonus: HP (damage dealt to opponent).Wall of StoneWall of StoneST:0 HP:60 MHP:60 G:30Land Limit: AirItem Limit: Armor ScrollsDefensiveWereboarWereboarST:20 HP:40 MHP:40 G:80In Battle: ST 30 when invading.WoodfolkWoodfolkST:30 HP:30 MHP:30 G:60Item Limit: WeaponsSupportWater Monsters (Blue)Alga SphereAlga SphereST:10 HP:40 MHP:40 G:30Item Limit: Weapons ScrollsDefensive / Territory Ability (30G): MHP 10 (up to a maximum of 80).AmazonAmazonST:40 HP:40 MHP:40 G:80Attack Bonus: Steals (user's lap number x20G) magic from opponent Cepter if not equipped with an item.AnubiasAnubiasST:30 HP:50 MHP:50 G:70 BLand Limit: FireIn Battle: HP= (number of creatures destroyed thus far x5).BansheeBansheeST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:20 BBItem Limit: WeaponsTerritory (60G): Deals (25% of MHP) damage to all creatures.BehemothBehemothST:60 HP:60 MHP:60 G:90 BLand Limit: FireItem Limit: Armor ScrollsAttacks Last / Battle End: Destroys a single card at random from user's hand.Bloody PuddingBloody PuddingST:20 HP:20 MHP:20 G:30Item Limit: ScrollsSupport / Battle Start: MHP (supporting creature's MHP). (Up to a maximum of 80).Book WormBook WormST:10 HP:20 MHP:20 G:10 BItem Limit: ScrollsTerritory (40G): User chooses a card from target enemy Cepter's hand and destroys it.BunyipBunyipST:50 HP:40 MHP:40 G:90Item Limit: ArmorNeutralizes: PenetratesCharonCharonST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:70 BItem Limit: ArmorNeutralizes: All non-scroll attacks. / User pays (amount of neutralized damage x2G) magic.DagonDagonST:60 HP:80 MHP:80 G:140 BB []Land Limit: FireBoost: HP 10 to Water creatures. / Battle End: User loses 100G magic.DroolDroolST:0 HP:40 MHP:40 G:70Item Limit: Weapons ScrollsPenetrates / In Battle: ST= (number of user's Water territories x10).FateFateST:30 HP:40 MHP:40 G:60Territory (40G): User draws a card. / Upon Defeat: User draws a card.FungonoidFungonoidST:30 HP:40 MHP:40 G:60Item Limit: ScrollsBattle End: MHP 10 (up to a maximum of 80).Giant AmoebaGiant AmoebaST:30 HP:30 MHP:30 G:50Item Limit: Armor ScrollsNeutralizes: Fire EarthGrendelGrendelST:50 HP:50 MHP:50 G:110 BCritical Hit: Creatures with ST of 20 and under.GrindylowGrindylowST:20 HP:40 MHP:40 G:60Neutralizes: Attacks from creatures with ST of 30 or less.HydeHydeST:30 HP:30 MHP:30 G:50 BLand Limit: FireTerritory (50G): Adds Paralysis to target creature.HydraHydraST:40 HP:50 MHP:50 G:90 BItem Limit: ArmorRegenerates: Except when on Fire land.KelpieKelpieST:30 HP:30 MHP:30 G:70 BItem Limit: ScrollsStops all passing Cepters other than user when placed on a Water land.King TortoiseKing TortoiseST:10 HP:50 MHP:50 G:45Item Limit: ScrollsAttacks LastKrakenKrakenST:50 HP:50 MHP:50 G:80 BLand Limit: FireItem Limit: ScrollsNeutralizes: Neutral / In Battle: If user has Fire territory, HP-20.LeviathanLeviathanST:30 HP:60 MHP:60 G:120 BBItem Limit: ArmorUpon Victory: Battle territory becomes Water.LilithLilithST:0 HP:30 MHP:30 G:80Item Limit: ArmorAttacks First / In Battle: ST= (number of cards in user's hand x10).LizardmanLizardmanST:30 HP:40 MHP:40 G:70Attacks FirstLungLungST:0 HP:30 MHP:30 G:50 BBLand Limit: FireItem Limit: Weapons ArmorIn Battle: ST  HP= (number of Water symbols owned by user).Mad ClownMad ClownST:10 HP:20 MHP:20 G:10 B []Boost: HP 10 to user's creatures.MarfolkMarfolkST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:20MedusaMedusaST:30 HP:30 MHP:30 G:50 []Attack Bonus: Transforms opponent into Statue.MegarodonMegarodonST:50 HP:50 MHP:50 G:70Land Limit: Neutral Fire Earth AirItem Limit: ScrollsMujinaMujinaST:0 HP:30 MHP:30 G:50 BIn Battle: ST  HP= (number of opponent's cards in hand x10).NymphNymphST:10 HP:30 MHP:30 G:50 BLand Limit: Fire AirNeutralizes: Fire / Attack Bonus: If opposing creature has HP = 30, it is added to user's hand (40%)PiratePirateST:10 HP:30 MHP:30 G:45SupportRemoraRemoraST:20 HP:40 MHP:40 G:40Land Limit: Fire AirItem Limit: ScrollsAttack Bonus: Destroys a card at random from opponent Cepter's hand.Sea BonzeSea BonzeST:20 HP:40 MHP:40 G:70Land Limit: Fire EarthDefensive / In Battle: No effects or abilities can be used during battle.Shell CreeperShell CreeperST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:50Item Limit: ScrollsNeutralizes: Fire AirStorm GiantStorm GiantST:40 HP:60 MHP:60 G:110 BCritical Hit: FireSuikoSuikoST:20 HP:30 MHP:30 G:0 []Land Limit: FireBattle End: Adds Vitality to defending creature.UndineUndineST:30 HP:30 MHP:30 G:60Item Limit: ArmorIn Battle: HP= (number of user's Water territories x20). / Neutralizes: WaterVisionVisionST:40 HP:50 MHP:50 G:80In Battle: HP=30 / Neutralizes: AirVodyanoiVodyanoiST:40 HP:40 MHP:40 G:90 B []Attacks First / Instant Death: 80% if on defense.Wall of IceWall of IceST:0 HP:40 MHP:40 G:40Land Limit: FireItem Limit: Armor ScrollsDefensive / In Battle: HP 30WizardWizardST:0 HP:30 MHP:30 G:45Item Limit: WeaponsSupport / Scroll Critical HitYetiYetiST:40 HP:40 MHP:40 G:80 BItem Limit: ScrollsNeutralizes: Fire / Instant Death: 60% against Fire creatures.ItemsAir Slasher (Weapon)G:10ST 20 / Critical Hit: AirAmber Ring (Tool)G:30ST 20 / Penetrates: AirAura Blade (Weapon)G:40ST (MHP value).Bandit's Glove (Tool)G:0Attack Bonus: Steals (damage dealt x2G) magic from opponent.Battering Ram (Weapon)G:30ST 20 / Attack Bonus: 100% Instant Death against Defensive creatures.Battle Axe (Weapon)G:30ST 40Bell of Chaos (Tool)G:50Battle Start: Destroys all cards identical to opponent's item in all Cepters' books and hands. / Immune to Destroy Item and Steal Item effects.Bell of Law (Tool)G:10Battle Start: Destroys the card with the highest cost in the opposing Cepter's hand. / Battle End: Recycles to BookBlack Orb (Tool)G:30Equipped creature ignores opponent creature's Neutralizes or Reflects ability.Boomerang (Weapon)G:40ST 20 / HP 10 / Battle End: Recycles to HandBuckler (Armor)G:30Neutralizes: Attacks from creatures with ST of 30 and under.Catapult (Weapon)G:90ST 30 / HP 30Chain Mail (Armor)G:10HP 30Chameleon Armor (Armor)G:30HP= (level of battle territory x20).Changing Salve (Tool)G:0Swaps equipped creature's ST and HP values.Claw of the Ghoul (Tool)G:10Attack Bonus: ParalysisClaymore (Weapon)G:60ST 50Coin of Piety (Tool)G:0Upon Victory: User gains 10 symbols of same element as battle territory.Counter Amulet (Tool)G:100ST=0 / Reflects: All non-scroll attacks.Crossbow (Weapon)G:70ST 30 / HP 20Dagger of Mite (Weapon)G:40ST (current standing x20).Death (Scroll)G:80Scroll Attack: Instant Death: 60% / Battle End: Equipped creature is destroyed (40%).Diamond Armor (Armor)G:60Attacks Last / ST-30 / HP 60Dynamite (Tool)G:50ST 60 / Battle End: Equipped creature is destroyed.Earth Amulet (Tool)G:30ST 10 / Attacks First / Critical Hit: When equipped creature is EarthEarth Shield (Armor)G:25Neutralizes: Earth / Neutralizes all non-scroll attack damage when equipped by a Earth creature.Emerald Ring (Tool)G:30ST 20 / Penetrates: EarthFire Amulet (Tool)G:30ST 20 / HP 10 / Regenerates / Critical Hit: When equipped creature is FireFire Bolt (Scroll)G:40Scroll Attack: ST=30 / Scroll Critical Hit: WaterFire Shield (Armor)G:25Neutralizes: Fire / Neutralizes all non-scroll attack damage when equipped by a Fire creature.Flame Tongue (Weapon)G:10ST 20 / Critical Hit: WaterFreeze (Scroll)G:40Scroll Attack: ST=30 / Scroll Critical Hit: FireGaseous Form (Tool)G:70ST=0 / Neutralizes: All non-scroll attacks.Gem of Life (Tool)G:20Battle End: If user's creature's HP is 20 or under, both it and opponent's creature are destroyed.Glaive (Weapon)G:40ST 20 / HP 20Golden Goose (Tool)G:0Upon Defeat: User gains G= (MHP x10G)Gremlin Amulet (Tool)G:70Battle Start: Destroys opponent's item.Heart Fibula (Tool)G:30Upon Victory: ST 20 / MHP 20 (up to a maximum of 80).Hell Blaze (Scroll)G:80Scroll Attack: ST=40 / Scroll Critical Hit: Creatures with 20ST or less.Holy Grail (Tool)G:80Neutralizes: All non-scroll attacks. / User pays (amount of neutralized damage x2G) magic.Hourglass (Tool)G:10Attacks First / Disables opponent creature's Attacks First ability.Icicle (Weapon)G:10ST 20 / Critical Hit: FireIksear (Tool)G:50HP (number of user's Water territories x20). / Immune to Destroy Item and Steal Item effects.Knight Shield (Armor)G:40Neutralizes: Attacks from creatures with ST of 40 and up.Kris (Weapon)G:50ST 30 / Immune to Destroy Item and Steal Item effects.Lance of Odin (Weapon)G:80ST 50 / HP 10Leather Armor (Armor)G:0HP 20Long Sword (Weapon)G:10ST 30Luna Stone (Tool)G:50Battle End: Swaps opponent's ST and HP values.Mace (Weapon)G:0ST 20Magic Shield (Armor)G:10HP 20 / Neutralizes: Scroll attacks.Magus's Mirror (Armor)G:40HP 20 / Reflects: Scroll attacks.Marker Flag (Tool)G:30Battle End: Invading Cepter can use Territory commands or invade again.Masamune (Weapon)G:50ST 50 / HP-10Morning Star (Weapon)G:40ST 30 / HP 10Mujina Mask (Tool)G:30HP (number of opponent's cards in hand x10).Necro Scarab (Tool)G:60Upon Defeat: Transforms equipped creature into Zombie.Neutral Amulet (Tool)G:10Equipped creature becomes Neutral. / Battle End: Recycles to BookNuclear Fusion (Scroll)G:120Scroll Attack: ST=50Nunchaku (Weapon)G:0ST 30 / HP-10Offering Doll (Tool)G:0Upon Victory: Symbol value of same element as equipped creature is increased 30%.Petrify Stone (Tool)G:50ST=0 / HP=80Phoenix Amulet (Tool)G:20Upon Defeat: Returns to user's hand.Plate Mail (Armor)G:60HP 50Power Bracelet (Tool)G:30STx2Prismatic Wand (Weapon)G:80If the element of user's creature is different from the enemy's, the user's creature gains ST/HP 40.Protean Ring (Tool)G:0Transforms equipped creature into a random different creature.Rainbow Piece (Tool)G:50HP 40 / Neutralizes: Scroll attacks. / Battle End: Removes Enchantment from battle territory.Rat Hunter (Tool)G:50Attack Bonus: Transforms opponent into Giant Rat.Ring of the Succubus (Tool)G:30Attacks First / Attack Bonus: Opponent's base ST=0.Ring of the Vampire (Tool)G:30Attacks First / Attack Bonus: HP (damage dealt to opponent).Rock Biter (Weapon)G:10ST 20 / Critical Hit: EarthRuby Ring (Tool)G:30ST 20 / Penetrates: FireSapphire Ring (Tool)G:30ST 20 / Penetrates: WaterScale Armor (Armor)G:30HP 40Shadow Armor (Armor)G:30HP ((7- battle territory level) x10).Silver Plow (Tool)G:100Battle End: Raises level of battle territory by 1.Sleep (Scroll)G:50Scroll Attack: Adds Sleep to opponent.Sling (Tool)G:40Attacks First / ST 10 / HP 10Smoke Torch (Tool)G:30Neutralizes: Scroll attacks and Penetrates ability.Spear (Weapon)G:20ST 20 / HP 10Spike Shield (Armor)G:60Reflects: 1/2 of damage received (excluded scroll attacks).Stink Bottle (Tool)G:20Battle Start: Destroys opponent's tool or supporting creature / Battle End: Recycles to BookStone Hail (Scroll)G:40Scroll Attack: ST=30 / Scroll Critical Hit: AirStorm Causer (Weapon)G:60ST 60 / HP-30Sword of the Falcon (Weapon)G:30Attacks First / ST 20Tearing Halo (Scroll)G:80Scroll Attack: ST=30 / Scroll Critical Hit: Unless equipped creature is Neutral / Immune to Destroy Item and Steal Item effects.Terrair (Tool)G:50ST (number of user's Air territories x20). / Immune to Destroy Item and Steal Item effects.The Hand (Tool)G:80Battle Start: Steals opponent's item and uses it.Tower Shield (Armor)G:40Neutralizes: 1/2 of damage received (excludes scroll attacks).Trapezon (Tool)G:20Transforms equipped creature into Ba=Al.Trident (Weapon)G:70ST 40 / HP 10Venom (Tool)G:20Battle End: Deals damage equal to 50% of opponent's base HP.Vestment (Armor)G:50HP 30 / Immune to Destroy Item and Steal Item effects.Vorpal Sword (Weapon)G:40ST 30 / Critical Hit: Creatures with MHP of 40 and up.Water Amulet (Tool)G:30ST 30 / Critical Hit: When equipped creature is WaterWater Shield (Armor)G:25Neutralizes: Water / Neutralizes all non-scroll attack damage when equipped by a Water creature.Wind Amulet (Tool)G:30ST 10 / HP 10 / Critical Hit: When equipped creature is Air / Upon Victory: MHP 10 (up to a maximum of 80).Wind Cutter (Scroll)G:40Scroll Attack: ST=30 / Scroll Critical Hit: EarthWind Shield (Armor)G:25Neutralizes: Air / Neutralizes all non-scroll attack damage when equipped by an Air creature.Winged Boots (Tool)G:10Attacks First / Battle End: Recycles to BookSpellsAcid Rain (Multi-Flash)G:70Deals 30 damage to all Defensive creatures.Anti Element (Single-Enchant)G:60Target creature cannot receive land effect.Anti-Magic (Single-Enchant)G:50Neutralizes the next spell or territory ability that targets target Cepter (except those that dispel Enchantments).Aports (Multi-Flash)G:60Moves all Cepters to user's location that are on land matching the user's. User cannot roll the die this turn.Aurora (Multi-Flash)G:50Raises the value of all symbols by 20%.Avalanche (Multi-Flash)G:150Deals 30 damage to all creatures in level 5 territories.Babble (Single-Enchant)G:30Target Cepter cannot use Fortune Teller and Temple for 3 rounds.Backward (Single-Enchant)G:20Target Cepter moves backward instead of forward upon rolling the die.Banishing Ray (Single-Flash)G:70Destroys target Neutral creature.Barricade (Single-Enchant)G:10Toll value for target territory is increased 30% for 3 rounds.Barrier (Single-Enchant)G:30Target Cepter cannot be targeted by spells or territory abilities (except those that dispel Enchantments) for 5 rounds.Bind (Single-Enchant)G:60Target Cepter cannot move for 1 round.Binding Mist (Single-Enchant)G:30Adds Paralysis to target creature.Bistair (Single-Flash)G:80Deals damage= (# of user's Fire territories x10) to target enemy creature.Black Out (Single-Enchant)G:40Target enemy Cepter cannot claim tolls for 2 rounds.Camouflage (Single-Enchant)G:40Target creature receives land effect from lands of any element.Catastrophe (Multi-Flash)G:300 []HP=1/2 to all creatures.Changeling (Single-Flash)G:100Transforms 2 of the cards remaining in target enemy Cepter's book into Goblins.Chaos Panic (Multi-Flash)G:90All Cepters travel in the opposite direction next turn.Chariot (Single-Flash)G:50Moves target creature belonging to user 2 spaces. / Recycles to Book.Corruption (Single-Flash)G:90Target enemy Cepter loses (number of symbols owned x10G) magic.Cramp (Multi-Flash)G:60ST-20 to all creatures in target area.Cure (Single-Flash)G:10Fully recovers target creature's HP.Death Cloud (Multi-Flash)G:80Deals 20 damage to all Air creatures.Demonic Trade (Multi-Flash)G:200 []Transforms all of the creatures in user's territories into Goblins. / User gains G= (# of Goblins placed x100G magic).Desert Storm (Multi-Enchant)G:80Prevents changing of levels in any territories in the target area for 2 rounds.Despair (Single-Enchant)G:70Target enemy Cepter discards cards drawn for 2 rounds.Dimension Door (Single-Flash)G:20Moves target Cepter to a random territory. User cannot roll the die this turn.Disbelief (Multi-Flash)G:90All Cepters lose (number of symbols owned x5G) magic.Disease (Single-Enchant)G:40In battle, ST  HP-20 to target creature.Dispel Magic (Single-Flash)G:10Removes Enchantment from target Cepter.Drain Magic (Single-Flash)G:80User steals 30% of target enemy Cepter's magic.Dream Terrain (Single-Enchant)G:40User gains 50% of tolls collected by other Cepters until user reaches the castle.Drought (Single-Enchant)G:50Level of target territory cannot be changed.Dullness (Single-Enchant)G:30No items or supporting creatures can be used during battle on the target territory.Earth Shaker (Multi-Flash)G:300 []Level of all territories is lowered by 1.Echo (Single-Flash)G:80Sets user's magic to 50% of target enemy Cepter's magic.Eclipse (Single-Flash)G:60Target Cepter loses 20 of most numerous symbol. / Target Cepter gains 200G magic.Elemental Rage (Multi-Flash)G:80Lowers HP of all creatures whose elements differ from the territories they inhabit by 1/2.Erasure (Multi-Flash)G:50Clears all Cepters and creatures of Enchantments.Escape (Single-Flash)G:20Transports user to nearest vacant land within the area. User cannot roll the die this turn.Evil Blast (Single-Flash)G:120Deals 30 damage to target enemy creature.Exile (Single-Flash)G:100Returns 1 creature with Enchantment to owner's hand.Exorcism (Multi-Flash)G:60Clears all creatures of Enchantments in the target area. / MHP 10 to affected creatures.Fairy Light (Single-Enchant)G:60Every round, target Cepter gains (number of cards in hand x10G) magic. Effect ends when target reaches the castle.Feast (Multi-Flash)G:20All Cepters gain (number of territories in their possession x50G) magic.Find (Single-Flash)G:40User draws 1 card. / Adds Find to hand.Fire Explosion (Multi-Flash)G:80All creatures in an area take damage=30% of MHPFly (Single-Flash)G:20User rolls two dice this turn.Fog (Single-Enchant)G:50Decreases target territory's toll value by 1/2.Foresight (Single-Flash)G:40User views the top 6 cards in their book, then selects 1 to place in their hand.Forest Leap (Single-Flash)G:20Transports user to nearest Earth land within the area. User cannot roll the die this turn.Goblin's Lair (Single-Flash)G:10 []Places Goblin on land occupied by user if it is currently empty. / Adds Goblin's Lair to hand.Grace (Single-Flash)G:30Caster gains 15% of the total value of target Cepter's symbols in magical powers.Gravity (Multi-Enchant)G:50All Cepters' next die roll yields a 1.Greed (Single-Enchant)G:20Raises target territory's toll value to 1.5x. / In Battle: HP-10Growth Body (Single-Flash)G:20MHP 10 to target creature.Haste (Single-Enchant)G:50Locks target Cepter's die roll to 6-8 for 2 rounds.Haunt (Single-Enchant)G:70The computer controls the target Cepter for 2 rounds.Holy Word 0 (Single-Enchant)G:30Target Cepter's next die roll yields a 0.Holy Word 1 (Single-Enchant)G:20Target Cepter's next die roll yields a 1.Holy Word 2 (Single-Enchant)G:10Target Cepter's next die roll yields a 2.Holy Word 3 (Single-Enchant)G:10Target Cepter's next die roll yields a 3.Holy Word 6 (Single-Enchant)G:10Target Cepter's next die roll yields a 6.Holy Word X (Single-Enchant)G:30Target Cepter's next die roll yields a 10.Ice Storm (Multi-Flash)G:80Deals 20 damage to all Fire creatures.Incineration (Multi-Flash)G:10User gains (number of creatures destroyed thus far x20G) magic, then number is reset.Influence (Single-Flash)G:80Transforms target territory into its owner's most numerous land type.Insect Swarm (Multi-Flash)G:80Deals 20 damage to all creatures in target area that have already taken damage.Invisibility (Single-Enchant)G:60User's territories cannot be targeted by spells or territory abilities (except those that dispel Enchantments). Effect ends if user casts a spell.Judgment (Single-Flash)G:100The target Cepter (67%) or user (33%) will lose 80% of their G.Lake Leap (Single-Flash)G:20Transports user to nearest Water land within the area. User cannot roll the die this turn.Land Protection (Single-Enchant)G:70Target territory cannot be targeted by spells or territory abilities (except those that dispel Enchantments).Land Transfer (Single-Flash)G:20Releases target territory from user's control and reverts it to magic. / Recycles to Book.Life Force (Single-Enchant)G:70 []Target Cepter can use creatures and items for 1/2 normal G cost but will be unable to use spells for 3 rounds.Life Stream (Multi-Flash)G:50Fully recovers HP of all creatures owned by user.Locust (Single-Flash)G:80Lowers target territory's level by 1.Magic Bolt (Single-Flash)G:50Deals 20 damage to target enemy creature.Magic Fountain (Single-Enchant)G:20The Cepter that stops first in target territory gains 400G magic.Manna (Single-Flash)G:0User gains (lap number x50G) magic.Mass Growth (Multi-Flash)G:30MHP 5 to all creatures (up to a maximum of 80).Mass Phantasm (Multi-Enchant)G:100Adds Phantasm to all creatures in target area.Mesmerize (Single-Flash)G:100 []User chooses a card from target enemy Cepter's hand and uses it (other than Mesmerize).Meteor (Single-Flash)G:200 []Target territory's level becomes 1.Mind Seeker (Single-Flash)G:20User selects 1 of 6 cards in target enemy Cepter's book to destroy (without seeing it).Mine (Single-Enchant)G:10The Cepter that stops first in target territory loses 50% of their magic.Mistletoe (Single-Enchant)G:20User gains 50G magic each time a Cepter rolls a 5-7 for 2 rounds.Mountain Leap (Single-Flash)G:20Transports user to nearest Fire land within the area. User cannot roll the die this turn.Mutation (Single-Enchant)G:40MHP 20 to target creature (up to a maximum of 80). / Adds Poison.Pain (Single-Flash)G:20Target enemy Cepter loses 100G magic.Parasite (Single-Enchant)G:50Target creature's owner loses 100G magic at the end of battle.Peace (Single-Enchant)G:70Target territory cannot be invaded. / Target territory's toll value becomes 0.Permission (Single-Flash)G:80User gets clearance from all forts.Phantasm (Single-Enchant)G:30Target creature's HP and MHP cannot be altered by spells or territory abilities.Plague (Multi-Enchant)G:100Adds Poison to all creatures in target area.Plain Leap (Single-Flash)G:20Transports user to nearest Air land within the area. User cannot roll the die this turn.Pressure (Multi-Flash)G:70Lowers the value of all symbols by 30%.Prophecy (Single-Flash)G:40User draws 1 card of specified type from their book.Punisher (Multi-Flash)G:100Deals 20 damage to all creatures in territories with Enchantments.Quicksand (Single-Enchant)G:100Forces any Cepter that steps onto target territory to stop. Effect ends when triggered or after 2 rounds.Quintessence (Single-Flash)G:60Transforms target territory into a Multi-Element land.Raise Dead (Single-Flash)G:30Returns last destroyed creature to hand. / Recycles to Book.Ray of Law (Multi-Flash)G:80Destroys all cards of magic 100G and up from all Cepters' hands.Regeneration (Single-Enchant)G:40In battle, HP 20 and Regenerates to target creature.Reincarnation (Single-Flash)G:50User discards all cards from current hand and draws an equal number of new cards from their book.Reinforce (Multi-Flash)G:60ST 10 to all creatures in target area (up to a maximum of 80).Relief (Single-Flash)G:30Exchanges creatures in 2 of user's territories. / Recycles to Book.Remove Curse (Single-Flash)G:10Removes Enchantment from target creature (territory).Replace (Single-Flash)G:120Exchanges target creature with another from its owner's hand.Revelation (Single-Enchant)G:50Adds Enlightenment to user for 2 rounds.Revival (Single-Flash)G:70 []Target Cepter's book is reverted to the state it was in when the game began.Ruin (Single-Flash)G:80Destroys all spell cards in the target enemy Cepter's hand and the user's.Rust (Single-Flash)G:80 []Destroys all item cards in the target enemy Cepter's hand.Scourge (Multi-Flash)G:80Decreases magic of all Cepters with Enchantments by 30%.Sculpture (Multi-Flash)G:150 []Transforms all creatures in target area with MHP of 30 and under into Statues.Selenear (Single-Flash)G:50User gains G= (# of user's Earth territories x100G) magic.Senility (Single-Enchant)G:100Target creature is destroyed at Battle End.Shatter (Single-Flash)G:20User chooses a non-creature card from target enemy Cepter's hand and destroys it.Shine (Single-Enchant)G:150Raises the value of all symbols by 50% for 2 rounds.Shrink (Single-Flash)G:30MHP-10 to target enemy creature.Silence (Single-Enchant)G:70Prevents target enemy Cepter from using creature cards for 2 rounds.Simulacrum (Single-Enchant)G:40Target creature neutralizes all non-scroll attack damage in battle. User loses (amount of neutralized damage x3G) magic.Sink (Single-Flash)G:150Transforms target territory into a Water land.Slow (Single-Enchant)G:20Locks target Cepter's die roll to 1-3 for 2 rounds.Soltis (Single-Flash)G:80User chooses 1 effect among 7 possible choices.Sonic Wave (Multi-Flash)G:70Deals 20 damage to all creatures with Attacks First ability.Soul Hunt (Single-Enchant)G:10User gains (target creature's MHP x5G) magic if target creature is destroyed by a spell or territory ability.Soul Steal (Single-Enchant)G:10User gains G= (# of destroyed creatures x50G) magic for 3 rounds.Spartoi (Single-Flash)G:40 []Places a Skeleton on a random vacant land.Spirit Walk (Single-Enchant)G:20Target creature can travel to any vacant land within the area when moving.Squeeze (Single-Flash)G:50User chooses a card from target Cepter's hand and destroys it. / Target Cepter gains 150G magic.Subsidence (Single-Flash)G:120Lowers level of target enemy Cepter's highest-level territory by 1.Suppression (Single-Flash)G:100User selects one spell card from target Cepter's hand, then destroys all instances of this card in all Cepters' hands and books.Telegnosis (Single-Enchant)G:60Adds Enlightenment to user until next round. / Recycles to Book.Telekinesis (Single-Flash)G:100Moves target creature 1 space.Teleport (Single-Flash)G:10Transports target Cepter to nearest special land (fort, temple, etc.). User cannot roll the die this turn.Temperance (Single-Flash)G:70MHP=30 to target creature.Tempest (Multi-Flash)G:200 []Deals 20 damage to all creatures.Thorn Fetter (Single-Enchant)G:50Target creature cannot be moved normally. / Battle End: HP-20.Thunder Storm (Multi-Flash)G:80Deals 20 damage to all Earth creatures.Torture (Single-Enchant)G:50Every round, target Cepter loses (number of spell cards in hand x20G) magic. Effect ends when target reaches the castle.Triumph (Single-Enchant)G:20User's next lap bonus is increased to 1.5x. Effect ends when user reaches the castle.Turn to the Wall (Single-Flash)G:80Transforms target creature into a predetermined Defensive creature of the same element.Upheaval (Single-Flash)G:150Transforms target territory into a Fire land.Vitality (Single-Enchant)G:40In battle, ST  HP 20 to target creature.Vortex (Single-Enchant)G:40No effects or abilities can be used during battle on the target territory.Waste (Single-Enchant)G:70Target enemy Cepter's creature and item cards cost double magic until target reaches the castle.Weakness (Single-Flash)G:10ST=0 to target creature.Weathering (Single-Flash)G:150Transforms target territory into a Air land.Wild Growth (Single-Flash)G:150Transforms target territory into a Earth land.Wind of Hope (Single-Flash)G:40User draws 2 card from their book.Wing (Single-Enchant)G:40In battle, target creature ST 20 and Attacks First.Wizard Eye (Single-Flash)G:0User views the top 6 cards in target Cepter's book. / Adds Wizard Eye to hand.Word of Recall (Single-Flash)G:80 []Transports target Cepter straight to castle. User cannot roll the die this turn.Medal RewardsAstral QueenAstral Queen (Neutral)ST:30 HP:40 MHP:40 G:70 []Territory (60G): Adds Camouflage to all creatures. / In Battle: HP (number of Neutral creatures in play x5).DarkcraftDarkcraft (Multi-Flash)G:70The Cepter possessing the most symbols loses 30% of their most numerous symbol.Dragon HelmDragon Helm (Tool)G:70Critical Hit: Fire Air / Neutralizes: Water Earth / Immune to Destroy Item and Steal Item effects.Energy FlashEnergy Flash (Multi-Flash)G:100 []Destroys all creatures on level 1 territories.LeoknightLeoknight (Neutral)ST:0 HP:40 MHP:40 G:100Item Limit: ScrollsIn Battle: ST=(number of territories opponent owns x10). HP=(number of territories user owns x10).LightcraftLightcraft (Multi-Flash)G:50All Cepters' books are reverted to the state they were in when the game began. / All Cepters discard all cards from current hand and draw 5 new cards.PolymorphPolymorph (Single-Flash)G:80 []Transforms target creature into a random different creature.TalismanTalisman (Tool)G:100Battle Start: Destroys opponent's item. / Neutralizes: All non-scroll attacks. / Battle End: Adds Land Protection to defending creature.TetramorphTetramorph (Neutral)ST:30 HP:50 MHP:50 G:80 []Defensive / Boost: HP-20 to invading creatures. / Territory (50G): Deals 50 damage to target enemy creature whose element differs from its territory.FollowupIn 2008 the Culdcept franchise took a leap over to the next generation, and released Culdcept Saga for the Xbox 360. Just like Culdcept for Playstation 2 it was only released in North America and Japan, leaving fans in other regions hungry for more.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="13">Card Game</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="2958">Monopoly</game><game id="3000">Magic: The Gathering</game><game id="22891">Godzilla Trading Battle</game><game id="15133">Phantom Dust</game><game id="9600">Metal Gear Ac!d</game><game id="34411">Magic: The Gathering - Duels of the Planeswalkers 2012</game><game id="35610">Fortune Street</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2117017-box_culdcept.png</image></root>