<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9473</id><name>Homeworld 2</name><description>OverviewDeveloped by Relic Entertainment and published by Sierra Entertainment in 2003, Homeworld 2 is the second follow-up to 1999's Homeworld and the first to be headed by Relic itself, the creator of the series. Like the previous games in the franchise, it is a PC real-time strategy game set in space, with an emphasis on full freedom of ship movement. Homeworld 2 sees the return of the Hiigaran faction as a playable race, called Kushan in the original game, after being absent from Barking Dog Studios' stand-alone expansion, Cataclysm. It also introduces a completely new faction, the Vaygr, who act as antagonists during the game's single-player campaign. The game's graphical presentation is heavily upgraded over previous installments, and numerous adjustments and additions to Homeworld's gameplay and interface have been made as well.PlotSet 115 years after the events of the first game and 100 years after the events of Cataclysm, Homeworld 2 revisits the fate of the Hiigarans as a new power arises to threaten them. It is established early on that the Hyperspace Core found in the deserts of Kharak long ago and used by the Kushan to build the original Mothership is one of only three such devices known to exist. The first was found by the Bentusi, and with them both they and the Hiigarans possess the ability to Far Jump, that is, to cross great distances of space almost instantaneously. More recently, the third and final Hyperspace Core was discovered by the Vaygr, a nomadic race from the Eastern Galactic Fringe, and it is used by their warlord Makaan to quickly take control of a large swath of the galaxy. Believing himself to be the Sajuuk-Khar (literally, the Chosen of He Whose Hand Shapes What Is), a messianic figure foretold to combine the three Hyperspace Cores and unite the galaxy, Makaan sets out to obtain the other two Cores. He is aided by his own Core, which allows him to divine the location of the others.The Pride of Hiigara, a second iteration of the famous Hiigaran Mothership, is commissioned in secret at the Tanis Shipyards.Sensing that war with the Vaygr is on the horizon, the Hiigarans secretly commission a new Mothership, the Pride of Hiigara, and Fleet Command responsibilities are taken over by the hero of the Homeworld War, Karan S'jet. During this time the Vaygr further strengthen themselves by allying with the Hiigaran's old enemies, the Taiidani, and despite the clandestine construction of the Mothership, it is ultimately discovered by the Vaygr, whose arrival at the Tanis Shipyards barely gives the Hiigarans time to escape. Upon returning to Hiigara with the Mothership it is revealed that the Vaygr have begun a mass offensive against the planet in an effort to force Hiigara to relinquish the Hyperspace Core. Unable to oppose Makaan's forces in its current state, the Mothership travels to Shipyard Naabal in order to bolster the fleet. After protecting Naabal and augmenting their own numbers, the Hiigarans are contacted by the Bentusi, who inform them of Makaan's plans and the prophesy of the End Times, which the unification of the three Cores is said to bring about. The Bentusi advise them to seek out the Oracle, a Progenitor relic that may have more information.But retrieving the Oracle from the asteroid fields of Gehenna, located deep within the Vaygr Reaches, would be no easy feat. The Hiigaran fleet is forced to use dust clouds to hide their presence and engage the Vaygr on their own terms. Eventually, the Oracle is found and linked with the Mothership's Hyperspace Core, though it unexpectedly forces the ship to hyperspace jump to the Karos Graveyard. After the jump, the Mothership is attacked by and made to defend itself against Progenitor ships known as Movers, though in time the Oracle releases control of the ship's Hyperspace Core. Within the Graveyard the Hiigarans come across the bridge section of a much larger Progenitor ship, and in examining it they find information that suggests the remains of the ship are strewn across the entire Karos sector. They also learn that the aft section of the ship housed a powerful Dreadnaught ship called the Gatekeeper of Sajuuk, and with telemetry data gathered from the derelict they attempt a hyperspace jump to the Dreadnaught's location.The Bentusi periodically come to the aid of the Hiigarans, as they did many years ago, though the war has reduced them to a single ship, the Bentus (seen above).Their jump is interrupted before they can reach the Dreadnaught, however, and upon further inspection it is found that quantum wave form irregularities emanating from the wreckage of the Progenitor ship's engineering section are preventing the Mothership from entering hyperspace. As they endeavor to clear the Progenitor debris so the fleet can continue on its journey, the Hiigarans find Vaygr ships hidden among the irradiated wreckage, forcing a confrontation between the two. The Vaygr underestimate the renewed strength of the Hiigaran military, and before long the area is cleared both of the Vaygr and disruptive ship detritus. The Mothership makes a second attempt to hyperspace jump to the Dreadnaught's location, this time successfully, although a large hostile Progenitor craft called the Keeper of Sajuuk is found within the area also. The Hiigarans are able to salvage the Dreadnaught and also destroy the Keeper before leaving the system. Though the acquisition of a Dreadnaught is a major victory for the Hiigarans, it is not enough to ensure their victory, as S'jet is certain that Makaan has found one as well.With additional firepower at their disposal, the Hiigaran fleet decides to go on the offensive by attacking a Vaygr assembly plant in the Shining Hinterlands. Their newly-salvaged Dreadnaught shows signs of promise, even destroying a Vaygr Battlecruiser with a single shot, but due to a misfire of its Phased Cannon Array it is prematurely retired from the battle, leaving the Hiigarans to try frantically to repair it as a second wave of Vaygr arrives. Without the Gatekeeper of Sajuuk, the Hiigarans are only able to survive by eliminating Vaygr Hyperspace Gates, which slows their assault. Once reinforcements arrive, repair of the Dreadnaught is shifted to Shipyard Naabal, and though the Vaygr attempt to destroy Naabal before the Progentior ship can be restored, they are unsuccessful, and the renewed Gatekeeper ultimately leads to their defeat. Captain Soban is captured during the battle, however, and, knowing the fate that awaits him, the Mothership and its crew decide to follow his tracking beacon in order to rescue him.The Mothership is once again pulled from hyperspace before it reaches its destination, and the Hiigarans soon come under fire from multiple Progenitor Keepers looking to recover the Gatekeeper of Sajuuk. Even with the Dreadnaught, the Hiigaran fleet is unable to destroy the Keepers; unexpectedly, the last Bentusi ship, the Bentus, jumps into the area, offering to perform modifications on the Dreadnaught which would allow it to operate at peak capacity. As they perform repairs, the Bentusi come under attack by the Keepers, forcing the Hiigarans to defend the Bentus. Even with the upgraded Dreadnaught, the Progenitor ships prove to be too strong, and as a last resort the Bentusi decide to scuttle their ship, warning the Mothership to leave the system moments beforehand. They warp to a point outside the blast radius in order to recover the shattered pieces of the Bentusi Hyperspace Core, and while the Vaygr quickly arrive hoping to do the same, the combined might of the Hiigaran fleet and the Gatekeeper of Sajuuk allow the Hiigarans to fully recover the Core.Makaan, self-styled Sajuuk-Khar and warlord of the Vaygr peopleNow with two Hyperspace Cores in their possession, the Hiigarans jump to Thaddis Sabbah where Captain Soban is suspected to be held. A fierce battle ensues, and Makaan himself takes to the field against the Mothership for the first time, but the fully operational Dreadnaught proves to be enough to hold the Vaygr at bay. All traces of Vaygr presence within the area are destroyed, and Captain Soban is rescued, though Makaan is able to leave the system safely. Soban informs Fleet Command that Makaan intends to pass through the Balcora Gate, a Progenitor device that allows access to Sajuuk, Makaan's ultimate desire. The Mothership arrives at the outskirts of Balcora just as Makaan enters the Gate, leaving much of his fleet behind to prevent the Hiigarans from following. Though the Vaygr attempt to destroy the Balcora Gate to deny the Hiigarans access to it, the firepower amassed by the Hiigaran fleet over the course of their journey is too much for them to hold back, and, using the Gatekeeper of Sajuuk, the Mothership is able to enter the Gate.Within Balcora the Sajuuk is revealed to be a massive Progenitor starship which can only be activated when all three Hyperspace Cores are combined. Knowing that neither of them can leave unless the other is destroyed, the Hiigarans and the Vaygr fight a pitched battle over the fate of the Cores and Sajuuk. Eventually, Makaan's Flagship falls, though in his dying moments the Vaygr warlord seems content in the knowledge that Hiigara will be destroyed. Now with the means to activate Sajuuk, the Hiigarans abandon their Mothership in favor of the Progenitor craft, quickly warping to their home system thereafter. Not long after their arrival, three massive Planet Killer ships, each capable of decimating the entire planet's population, begin to bombard Hiigara. While other ships have no effect, the Sajuuk proves to be capable of destroying the Planet Killers, and soon all Vaygr presence is driven from the Hiigaran system. With the threat of war over, the Sajuuk eventually finds and activates the Eye of Aarran, a galaxy-wide hyperspace network that revolutionizes space travel.GameplayHomeworld 2 shares many of the traits of its forebears, Homeworld and Cataclysm, and like them one of its most notable features is the ability of ships to move in all three axes, thus making gameplay fully three-dimensional. As a real-time strategy game, much of Homeworld 2 revolves around gathering resources, known in-game as Resource Units, in order to build new vessels and research new technologies. Ships are primarily produced through the Mothership, the game's central unit, and though there is no base building in the traditional sense, the Mothership and a select few other craft can be upgraded with additional subsystems. Homeworld 2 does not have an overarching unit cap like the original game or a secondary Supply Unit resource to restrict unit production like Cataclysm; rather, each individual ship class has its own unit cap, which may not be exceeded. In single-player, missions will typically end if and when the player loses their Mothership, while in multiplayer scenarios victory conditions usually require that all production ships be destroyed.The Sensors Manager allows a larger view of the battlefield. At bottom, the taskbar can be seen.The game is controlled through both mouse and keyboard, and movement commands can be issued by right clicking, with z-axis movement bound to the left mouse button; this can also be done by hitting the M key or holding the Shift key for z-axis movement. The player can focus on any currently-selected unit or units by hitting the F key and can move the camera around its focal point by holding the right mouse button while moving the mouse; zooming the camera in or out can be done either by scrolling the mouse wheel or by holding the left and right mouse button while moving the mouse forward or backward. Units can be ordered to assume passive, defensive, or aggressive tactics with hotkeys or through an in-game taskbar, and large gatherings of units can also be saved as strike groups at any time by Control-clicking while they are selected. Strike groups may also be issued formations, and with Homeworld 2's environments offering little or no exploitable terrain advantages, success in battle can often be influenced through tactical decisions such as employing flanking maneuvers and diversionary stratagems.Like all other games in the series, ships in Homeworld 2 are divided into discrete categories, with the major offensive varieties being, in order of size, Fighters, Corvettes, Frigate, and Capital Ships. Larger ships tend to be more dangerous and more heavily armored than smaller ones, though this comes at the expense of speed and maneuverability. Furthermore, each ship type comes with its own strengths and weaknesses, leading to disparate capabilities even within the same class; Ion Cannon Frigates, for instance, are very susceptible to Bombers, whereas Flak Frigates can easily dispatch them. In addition to the intrinsic ship designs each faction possesses, certain ships have the ability to subvert and repurpose enemy vessels, and new units can be acquired in other ways as well during single-player. With very few exceptions, ships within a certain class can only be built once the appropriate production facility has been constructed on the Mothership (or other available production facilities), and more advanced ships may also require additional research before they can be built.The single-player campaign incorporates a wide number of objectives and overarching mission goals, though in all cases heavy combat is to be expected. Much like past iterations, resources and units are carried forward from mission to mission. The adjustable difficulty settings introduced in Cataclysm's campaign are not adopted in Homeworld 2, which instead opts for a system more akin to the original game, where difficulty is adjusted dynamically based on the number of units the player starts each mission with. Any ungathered resources left on the map at the end of a scenario are automatically credited to the player, which prevents players from having to continue mining once the mission proper has ended (as was often required in the previous games). In keeping with series tradition, Homeworld 2's story is told through a combination of black-and-white inter-mission cutscenes, cinematic in-game cutscenes, and extensive voice over during missions.Hiigaran ShipsThe Hiigaran faction is the only playable race during Homeworld 2's single-player campaign, and one of two available for multiplayer and skirmish battles. As opposed to the Vaygr, their ships are somewhat broader in focus, with more of their vessels being able to tackle multiple roles or fight effectively against multiple enemy types. They are also well-known for their wide variety of Frigates, and in fact Frigates represent their largest single ship category. Hiigaran craft tend to be more defensive than those of the Vaygr, and a well-fortified line of Hiigaran Capital ships can be hard to break. Perhaps due to their focus on defensive ability, Hiigaran ships can sometimes be slower than others.Fighter ClassHiigaran ScoutScoutRole: Reconnaissance FighterCost: 350 RUsBuild Time: 20 secondsDamage Per Second: 9Armor: 90 (30 per ship)Max. Velocity: 480 m/sStrong Against: NoneWeak Against: Fighters, Corvettes, Frigates, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: NoneUpgrade Tech: EMP Pulse, Enhanced SensorsOf the three Fighter craft available to the Hiigarans, the Scout is the least suitable for battle, as it features modest offense and a smaller-than-average squadron size (three ships). Despite this, they can be useful vessels for a number of reasons. Most importantly, Scouts are natural reconnaissance ships with a far greater sensor range than most units. They can also be upgraded with the ability to ping distant locations for intel and deliver EMP blasts that temporarily disable ships, leaving them without defense for a short period of time.Hiigaran InterceptorInterceptorRole: Fighter InterceptorCost: 500 RUsBuild Time: 35 secondsDamage Per Second: 36Armor: 150 (30 per ship)Max. Velocity: 325 m/sStrong Against: FightersWeak Against: Corvettes, Frigates, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: Fighter FacilityUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2Both cheap to purchase and quick to produce, the Interceptor squadron is the most basic attack force in the Hiigaran fleet. A single formation consists of five ships, and they are at their best when used against other ships within the Fighter category or in harassing non-combat craft like Resource Collectors. In general, Interceptors fare poorly against ships in larger classes, though there are a few exceptions to this rule. They are also canny defensive units for larger vessels that may not have the means to fend off fast, agile Strike ships.Hiigaran BomberBomberRole: Anti-Capital Ship FighterCost: 550 RUsBuild Time: 45 secondsDamage Per Second: 439Armor: 150 (30 per ship)Max. Velocity: 260 m/sStrong Against: Frigates, Capital Ships, SubsystemsWeak Against: Fighters, Corvettes, Anti-Fighter FrigatesRequired Tech: Fighter FacilityUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Improved BombersThe Hiigaran Bomber is designed to attack ships much larger than itself, namely those of Frigate class or higher. Produced in squadrons of five, Bombers unleash highly destructive plasma bombs that are ideally suited for tearing through the thick armor plating of Capital ships. Once upgraded, these bombs cause even greater damage when targeting subsystems, opening up further strategic options for ship assaults. The trade-off for this increased firepower is an almost total inability to defend itself against other Strike ships.Corvette ClassHiigaran GunshipGunshipRole: Anti-Fighter CorvetteCost: 625 RUsBuild Time: 45 secondsDamage Per Second: 56Armor: 1,200 (400 per ship)Max. Velocity: 215 m/sStrong Against: FightersWeak Against: Corvettes, Frigates, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: Corvette FacilityUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2The Hiigaran Gunship is built for one purpose and one purpose only: the decimation of all opposing Fighter ships. To this end, each vessel is equipped with two turret-mounted kinetic guns that offer a great degree of targeting flexibility when tackling smaller, faster ships. A squadron of three Gunships can in most circumstances make short work of an enemy Fighter squadron without sustaining serious damage in the process. Relatively modest damage values keep it from being much of a threat to anything outside of this class, however.Hiigaran Pulsar GunshipPulsar GunshipRole: Anti-Corvette ShipCost: 625 RUsBuild Time: 45 secondsDamage Per Second: 54Armor: 1,200 (400 per ship)Max. Velocity: 215 m/sStrong Against: Corvettes, FrigatesWeak Against: Capital ShipsRequired Tech: Corvette FacilityUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2Wielding a weapon known as the Pulsar, a type of short-range ion cannon, the Pulsar Gunship is similar to the standard Gunship in many respects, including its price, weapon coverage, squadron size, and durability. The nature of its weapon makes it much more effective against Corvette-class ships and even Frigates when produced in greater numbers. Though not quite as useful against Fighters as a Gunship squadron, they make for excellent defense for Fighter ships and solid front line attackers in a full-scale Capital ship assault.Hiigaran Minelayer CorvetteMinelayer CorvetteRole: Utility CorvetteCost: 800 RUsBuild Time: 45 secondsDamage Per Second: 48Armor: 400Max. Velocity: 215 m/sStrong Against: Capital ShipsWeak Against: Corvettes, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: Corvette Facility, Advanced Research Module, Minelaying TechnologyUpgrade Tech: NoneFeaturing very little in the way of direct offense, the Minelayer Corvette is a highly specialized craft that can lay down static defenses in the form of magnetic mines. These devices, once laid, seek out nearby enemy ships and explode, causing tremendous damage. The Minelayer's ability has a number of applications, such as protecting resource fields with a grid of explosives, though, once the fighting starts in earnest, it is best kept away from the action, as it has very little to contribute outside of its signature minelaying functionality.Frigate ClassHiigaran Torpedo FrigateTorpedo FrigateRole: Anti-Corvette, Anti-Capital Ship FrigateCost: 700 RUsBuild Time: 55 secondsDamage Per Second: 305Armor: 12,000Max. Velocity: 161 m/sStrong Against: Corvettes, FrigatesWeak Against: Bombers, DestroyersRequired Tech: Frigate FacilityUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2, Improved TorpedoesThe Torpedo Frigate is a long-range mobile bombardment platform that houses two torpedo launchers. Initially, these are useful primarily against incoming Strike ships, which can be fired upon from well outside of their own weapon range. With upgrades, its torpedoes becomes significantly stronger when targeting Capital ships, allowing it to take on a larger, more versatile role in the fleet. Of the ships in its class, the Torpedo Frigate is the least well-protected, which, when combined with its optimum range, makes it an attractive rear line ship.Hiigaran Flak FrigateFlak FrigateRole: Anti-Fighter FrigateCost: 700 RUsBuild Time: 55 secondsDamage Per Second: 50Armor: 16,000Max. Velocity: 161 m/sStrong Against: FightersWeak Against: Capital ShipsRequired Tech: Frigate Facility, Advanced Research ModuleUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2The Hiigaran Flak Frigate is uniquely equipped to handle Fighters and, to a somewhat lesser extent, Corvettes. Each one is fitted with a number of flak cannons that produce area-of-effect explosions capable of hitting multiple ships at once. These cannons are particularly deadly against tightly-packed Strike ship squadrons, though Corvettes, with their heavier armor, are less susceptible to them. Flak Frigates also lose a large amount of efficacy against Capital ships due to their short range and the comparatively slight damage they cause.Hiigaran Ion Cannon FrigateIon Cannon FrigateRole: Anti-Capital Ship FrigateCost: 700 RUsBuild Time: 45 secondsDamage Per Second: 315Armor: 16,000Max. Velocity: 150 m/sStrong Against: Frigates, Capital ShipsWeak Against: Bombers, DestroyersRequired Tech: Frigate Facility, Advanced Research ModuleUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2One of the oldest designs in the Hiigaran fleet, the Ion Cannon Frigate behaves much like it did in the original game. The entire length of the Frigate houses but a single armament, though this ion beam causes considerable damage to any ship of Frigate level or higher. Like its predecessor, its main drawback is the unwieldy nature of the weapon it supports. The ion cannon has a slow rate of fire and can only target enemies directly in front of the vessel, making the Ion Cannon Frigate vulnerable to fast-moving, agile ships, especially Bombers.Hiigaran Marine FrigateMarine FrigateRole: Boarding FrigateCost: 700 RUsBuild Time: 55 secondsDamage Per Second: 80Armor: 18,000Max. Velocity: 230 m/sStrong Against: Capital ShipsWeak Against: Bombers, FrigatesRequired Tech: Frigate Facility, Advanced Research ModuleUpgrade Tech: NoneThe spiritual successor to Homeworld's Salvage Corvettes, the Marine Frigate carries with it a squad of military servicemen trained in the art of infiltration. Once close enough to its target, the Marine Frigate can insert this squad onto an enemy ship, and with enough time they will subdue its personnel and completely commandeer the vessel. While it has some defensive capability and fairly thick armor, it is nonetheless unwise to deploy a Marine Frigate without an escort, as, without aid, it is only able to turn back very small-scale attacks.Hiigaran Defense Field FrigateDefense Field FrigateRole: Capital Ship Defense FrigateCost: 1,250 RUsBuild Time: 1 minute, 10 secondsDamage Per Second: 17Armor: 18,000Max. Velocity: 161 m/sStrong Against: N/AWeak Against: Bombers, CorvettesRequired Tech: Frigate Facility, Advanced Research Module, Defense Field TechnologyUpgrade Tech: Enhanced Defense FieldApparently inspired by the Taiidani vessel of the same name, the Defense Field Frigate is a non-combat ship that can project a defensive barrier around itself, shielding any craft within its radius. The Hiigaran version emits a much stronger field than the Taiidani's original design, though it can only do so for a little over three minutes at a time, after which it must recharge for an equal duration. It has a single mass driver turret, which serves a mostly superficial role, as the Defense Field Frigate should not be mistaken for an offensive unit.Capital ClassHiigaran DestroyerDestroyerRole: Anti-Frigate Capital ShipCost: 2,000 RUsBuild Time: 2 minutes, 45 secondsDamage Per Second: 1,034Armor: 85,000Max. Velocity: 115 m/sStrong Against: Frigates, Capital ShipsWeak Against: Bombers, BattlecruisersRequired Tech: Capital Ship Facility, Research Module, Destroyer ChassisUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2With four heavy mass driver turrets and a single twin torpedo launcher, the Destroyer is well-girded to attack and subdue most types of Capital ships, especially those without strong options against other large vessels. Destroyers have a few notable weaknesses, though, including a near-complete inability to ward off Strike ships, which makes them quite susceptible to Bomber attacks if not adequately protected. In addition, they are outclassed by the Battlecruisers, and should not attack one without a clear numerical advantage.Hiigaran BattlecruiserBattlecruiserRole: Anti-Capital Ship CruiserCost: 4,000 RUsBuild Time: 4 minutes, 40 secondsDamage Per Second: 5,200Armor: 240,000Max. Velocity: 69 m/sStrong Against: Frigates, Capital ShipsWeak Against: BombersRequired Tech: Shipyard Capital Ship Facility, Advanced Research Module, Battlecruiser ChassisUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2The pinnacle of the Hiigaran's military might, the Battlecruiser is in fact so massive that it can only be commissioned from a Shipyard. In return for the significant investment required to build one, the player is rewarded with a Super Capital class ship several times the strength of the Destroyer, its closest analogue in terms of power. It is large enough that it can service Strike ships, repairing them in the field without a Carrier or Mothership. This can be a symbiotic relationship, as these ships can in turn defend the Cruiser against Bombers.Hiigaran CarrierCarrierRole: Capital Class Production ShipCost: 2,800 RUsBuild Time: 1 minute, 5 secondsDamage Per Second: 40Armor: 80,000Max. Velocity: 75 m/sStrong Against: NoneWeak Against: Bombers, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: Capital Ship FacilityUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2, Improved ManufacturingThe Hiigaran Carrier is essentially the Mothership in miniature. It is able to assume many of the same responsibilities, such as producing ships up to and including Frigate class, docking with Resource Collectors in order to receive Resource Units, and repairing Fighters and Corvettes. It has three slots for production subsystems, two for modules, and one for sensors; it can also store and launch up to ten Strike squadrons. It is not suitable for use in open warfare, but can be a vital supporter for both combat and non-combat operations.Mothership ClassHiigaran MothershipMothershipRole: Mothership Class Production ShipCost: 8,000 RUsBuild Time: 1 secondDamage Per Second: 120Armor: 200,000Max. Velocity: 40 m/sStrong Against: NoneWeak Against: Bombers, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: N/A (not constructable)Upgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2, Hyperdrive Lvl. 1, Hyperdrive Lvl. 2, Anti-Mover Weaponry, Improved ManufacturingDubbed the "Pride of Hiigara" during single-player, the Mothership is the Hiigaran's main means of production, able to construct every Hiigaran ship save for the Battlecruiser and the Shipyard. In addition, it is a resource drop-off point, and repair station, and a docking platform for Strike ships. Its subsystem potential includes space for four production facilities, four modules, and one sensor subsystem. Though fairly durable, the Mothership is extremely slow and nearly defenseless, so it should ideally be kept as far from enemies as possible.Hiigaran ShipyardShipyardRole: Mothership Class Production ShipCost: 3,500 RUsBuild Time: 1 minute, 15 secondsDamage Per Second: 120Armor: 150,000Max. Velocity: 15 m/sStrong Against: NoneWeak Against: Bombers, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: Research Module, Hyperspace ModuleUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2, Improved ManufacturingThe only Hiigaran ship that arrives by hyperspace rather than being constructed on-site, the Shipyard is the ultimate production platform, and the only vessel capable of building the immense Battlecruiser. Aside from this, it operates more or less like other production ships, though it also features two more module subsystem slots than the Mothership. Like the Mothership and the Carrier, it is slow and not adequately equipped for operation while under duress, so considerations should be made to ensure that it does not see heavy combat.Platform ClassHiigaran Gun PlatformGun PlatformRole: Anti-Fighter Weapon PlatformCost: 300 RUsBuild Time: 20 secondsDamage Per Second: 32Armor: 5,000Max. Velocity: 125 m/sStrong Against: FightersWeak Against: Frigates, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: Platform Control ModuleUpgrade Tech: Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2Once constructed, the Hiigaran Gun Platform can be moved only once, after which it becomes a stationary defensive unit. Using two long-range mass driver cannons, it can act as an effective deterrent for smaller craft, with an emphasis on Fighters, while larger vessels will likely not find themselves hindered by it overmuch. For the cost, it features a large amount of armor, and if not immediately issued a movement order, it will automatically follow the production ship that constructed it, which allows it to act as a mobile base defender of sorts.Hiigaran Ion PlatformIon PlatformRole: Anti-Capital Ship Weapon PlatformCost: 300 RUsBuild Time: 20 secondsDamage Per Second: 167Armor: 5,000Max. Velocity: 125 m/sStrong Against: Frigates, Capital ShipsWeak Against: Fighters, CorvettesRequired Tech: Platform Control Module, Research Module, Platform Ion WeaponryUpgrade Tech: Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2The Ion Platform is akin to the Gun Platform in most respects, including its one-time-use engine, though in place of mass drivers it features two twin ion cannon turrets. These gun emplacements can tear through Frigate and Capital Ship armor, though they are too slow to seriously deter Fighter and Corvette class ships. While the Ion Platform's weaponry is less potent than that of the Ion Cannon Frigate, and the unit's overall utility is more limited, it is perhaps one of the best means of restricting the movement of enemy Capital ships.Vaygr ShipsThe Vaygr differ from Hiigarans in that their ships are oftentimes more heavily specialized, thus requiring a heavier emphasis on using multiple ship types in conjunction. This is not to say that they are entirely different, however, as most Hiigaran ships do have a roughly analogous doppelganger within the Vaygr fleet. Since they are built upon divergent technological backgrounds, Vaygr ships may at times use different means to achieve the same ends, such as outfitting Frigates with flechette launchers instead of flak cannons for anti-Fighter purposes. As they are the main antagonists during the single-player game, the Vaygr can only be used online or in skirmish mode.Fighter ClassVaygr Survey ScoutSurvey ScoutRole: Reconnaissance FighterCost: 350 RUsBuild Time: 20 secondsDamage Per Second: 9Armor: 90 (30 per ship)Max. Velocity: 420 m/sStrong Against: NoneWeak Against: Fighters, Corvettes, Frigates, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: NoneUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, EMP PulseLike its Hiigaran equivalent, the Vaygr Survey Scout, while technically a combat unit, is unable to hold its own in most dogfights, let alone excel. In practice, it is more useful to think of it as a mobile version of the Probe than as a true Fighter ship, as it has enhanced sensor range and enough speed to get itself out of trouble should the situation turn hostile. Its speed can be upgraded to surpass that of the Hiigaran Scout, however it does not have the same ability to ping remote locations for intelligence, nor can it be upgraded to do so.Vaygr Assault FighterAssault FighterRole: Fighter InterceptorCost: 500 RUsBuild Time: 35 secondsDamage Per Second: 30Armor: 210 (30 per ship)Max. Velocity: 325 m/sStrong Against: FightersWeak Against: Corvettes, Frigates, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: Fighter FacilityUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2The Assault Fighter is the Vaygr's basic superiority Strike squadron, being comparable to the Hiigaran Interceptor. The most noticeable difference between the two, aside from appearance, is the number of ships in each squadron. While the Hiigarans field five ships per squadron, the Vaygr typically construct seven. Though this would seem at first to give the Vaygr an edge over their foes, Assault Fighters are no more powerful individually than Interceptors, and furthermore the Hiigarans enjoy greater range with their weaponry.Vaygr BomberBomberRole: Anti-Capital Ship FighterCost: 550 RUsBuild Time: 40 secondsDamage Per Second: 332Armor: 180 (30 per ship)Max. Velocity: 260 m/sStrong Against: Frigates, Capital Ships, SubsystemsWeak Against: Fighters, Corvettes, Anti-Fighter FrigatesRequired Tech: Fighter Facility, Research Module, Fusion BombUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2With six ships per squadron (as opposed to the Hiigaran's five), the Vaygr Bomber has the potential to establish a slightly larger numerical presence on the battlefield than its direct competitor, though as with the Assault Fighter, this distinction in numbers is not quite as significant an advantage as it might appear to be. Perhaps the biggest equalizer is the difference in firepower; Vaygr Bombers do slightly less damage on a per ship basis. Still, the Vaygr Bomber has slightly better survivability, though this is hard to exploit in practice.Vaygr Lance FighterLance FighterRole: Anti-Corvette FighterCost: 500 RUsBuild Time: 35 secondsDamage Per Second: 43Armor: 150 (30 per ship)Max. Velocity: 260 m/sStrong Against: CorvettesWeak Against: Fighters, Anti-Fighter FrigatesRequired Tech: Fighter Facility, Research Module, Lance BeamUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2The Vaygr Lance Fighter rounds out the Fighter category by complementing the anti-Fighter focus of the Assault Fighter and the anti-Capital ship emphasis of the Bomber with an attack squadron specifically designed to destroy Corvettes. Each Lance Fighter is mounted with a single plasma lance, a beam weapon that can cut through more heavily armored Strike ships. They can also have limited success against larger vessels provided they don't have anti-Fighter capability, though for about the same price, Bombers will perform better.Corvette ClassVaygr Missile CorvetteMissile CorvetteRole: Anti-Corvette, Anti-Frigate ShipCost: 625 RUsBuild Time: 45 secondsDamage Per Second: 26Armor: 1,600 (400 per ship)Max. Velocity: 215 m/sStrong Against: Corvettes, FrigatesWeak Against: Capital ShipsRequired Tech: Corvette FacilityUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2The Vaygr Missile Corvette squadron, deployed in groups of four, is known for its high-yield concussion missile launchers, whose missiles are adept at damaging large Strike craft and Frigates. They are particularly proficient at dispatching the former, making the Missile Corvette one of the best Corvette-killers in the game. Its efficacy against Frigates comes with a few caveats, though, as any Frigate with dedicated anti-Strike weaponry, such as Torpedo and Flak Frigates, will be able to return fire with a significant degree of success.Vaygr Laser CorvetteLaser CorvetteRole: Anti-Capital Ship CorvetteCost: 650 RUsBuild Time: 45 secondsDamage Per Second: 350Armor: 1,600 (400 per ship)Max. Velocity: 215 m/sStrong Against: Frigates, Capital ShipsWeak Against: Corvettes, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: Corvette Facility, Research Module, Corvette LaserUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2Produced in squadrons of four, the Vaygr Laser Corvette is an anti-Capital ship Corvette similar to the Hiigaran Pulsar Gunship, though with a few significant differences. Unlike the Pulsar, which features turrets, the Laser Corvette can only fire forward. This is not much of an issue when fighting Frigates and Capital ships, and in fact the power of its beam weaponry more than makes up for its reduced coverage area, however the lack of turrets makes it much less survivable when faced with dogfight situations with other Strike ships.Vaygr Command CorvetteCommand CorvetteRole: Utility CorvetteCost: 400 RUsBuild Time: 30 secondsDamage Per Second: 0Armor: 600Max. Velocity: 215 m/sStrong Against: N/AWeak Against: Corvettes, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: Corvette Facility, Research Module, Command Corvette SystemsUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2Occupied by high-ranking military officials and various other dignitaries, the Vaygr Command Corvette is a unique non-offensive unit that offers passive benefits to any ship within a certain radius of itself. All ships affected by it will perform their duties more efficiently, which is reflected in-game as a noticeable boost in the damage they deliver. In addition, the Command Corvette is built with cutting-edge technology that gives it superior sensor capability. The only thing it lacks is weaponry, though it is much tougher than most Corvettes.Vaygr Minelayer CorvetteMinelayer CorvetteRole: Utility CorvetteCost: 800 RUsBuild Time: 45 secondsDamage Per Second: 48Armor: 400Max. Velocity: 215 m/sStrong Against: Capital ShipsWeak Against: Corvettes, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: Corvette Facility, Research Module, Minelaying TechnologyUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2The Vaygr Minelayer Corvette is, for all intents and purposes, identical to the Hiigaran version of the unit. It possesses a payload of magnetic mines which it can be directed to lay at whatever position it currently occupies as well as a single mass driver cannon that does little to protect it in the event of an actual firefight. Like other iterations on the same design, the Vaygr Minelayer is best used to protect strategic assets, such as rich resource fields and vulnerable ship production sites, without venturing too far into dangerous enemy territory.Frigate ClassVaygr Heavy Missile FrigateHeavy Missile FrigateRole: Anti-Capital Ship FrigateCost: 700 RUsBuild Time: 45 secondsDamage Per Second: 351Armor: 16,000Max. Velocity: 150 m/sStrong Against: Frigates, Capital ShipsWeak Against: Bombers, DestroyersRequired Tech: Frigate FacilityUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2Able to unleash swarms of concussion missiles and torpedoes, the Vaygr Heavy Missile Frigate is deadly to both Capital ships and Frigates, though moreso in the case of the latter. While it loses some of the range of the Torpedo Frigate, its Hiigaran analogue, it is significantly more durable, making it a more versatile vessel overall. Its missiles are fairly inept at destroying Strike ships since they cannot adequately track fast-moving targets, and furthermore there are certain large Capital Ships that are simply too strong for the Missile Frigate.Vaygr Assault FrigateAssault FrigateRole: Anti-Strike FrigateCost: 650 RUsBuild Time: 45 secondsDamage Per Second: 127Armor: 16,000Max. Velocity: 161 m/sStrong Against: FightersWeak Against: Bombers, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: Frigate Facility, Research Module, Assault Frigate ChassisUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2The Vagyr counterpart to the Hiigaran Flak Frigate, the Assault Frigate is primarily geared toward anti-Strike detail. While unified in purpose, though, it differs significantly in the nature of its weaponry. Whereas the Flak Frigate focuses on damaging multiple targets at once, the Assault Frigate targets individual ships with three separate flechette cannon turrets. With its heavy emphasis on small ships, its biggest weakness is predictably larger vessels, in particular those intended for use against sluggish Capital ships, like the Ion Cannon Frigate.Vaygr Infiltrator FrigateInfiltrator FrigateRole: Boarding FrigateCost: 800 RUsBuild Time: 55 secondsDamage Per Second: 53Armor: 18,000Max. Velocity: 230 m/sStrong Against: Capital ShipsWeak Against: Bombers, FrigatesRequired Tech: Frigate Facility, Research Module, Infiltration PodsUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2The Vaygr Infiltrator Frigate is built for the express purpose of facilitating the infiltration and subversion of Capital class enemy ships, and in this respect it is much like the Hiigaran's Marine Frigate. Its method for achieving this end is somewhat different, though, as Infiltrator Frigates insert their crew by way of drop pods rather than beaming them directly onboard their target. This gives Vaygr boarding parties somewhat greater incentive to complete their mission, as the odds of surviving in the event of an abortive takeover are slim to none.Capital ClassVaygr DestroyerDestroyerRole: Anti-Frigate Capital ShipCost: 2,000 RUsBuild Time: 2 minutes, 45 secondsDamage Per Second: 1,100Armor: 85,000Max. Velocity: 115 m/sStrong Against: Frigates, Capital ShipsWeak Against: Bombers, BattlecruisersRequired Tech: Capital Ship Facility, Research Module, Destroyer ChassisUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2While still primarily an anti-Frigate ship, the Vaygr Destroyer also incorporates a number of anti-Strike weapon systems that make it slightly more well-rounded than the Hiigaran vessel of the same name. This includes two twin flechette cannons that allow targeting at a distance and four hull defense turrets that protect it against any Fighters that manage to get in close. Against larger spacecraft, the Destroyer's main offense is a battery of four fusion missile launchers which spell almost certain death when focused on a single Frigate.Vaygr BattlecruiserBattlecruiserRole: Anti-Capital Ship CruiserCost: 4,000 RUsBuild Time: 4 minutes, 40 secondsDamage Per Second: 5,404Armor: 240,000Max. Velocity: 69 m/sStrong Against: Frigates, Capital ShipsWeak Against: BombersRequired Tech: Shipyard Capital Ship Facility, Research Module, Battlecruiser ChassisUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2Though its payload is somewhat less well-rounded than the Hiigaran Battlecruiser, the Vaygr's ultimate warship makes up for this deficit in sheer focused firepower, as even a Destroyer will be close to destruction after a single salvo from its forward-facing triple pulse cannon. A small repair bay is also included to support any protective detail the ship might have, and two empty hardpoints allow for later modular upgrades. As with all ships of its size, maneuverability is something of an issue, so players should be mindful of flanking.Vaygr CarrierCarrierRole: Capital Class Production ShipCost: 1,700 RUsBuild Time: 40 secondsDamage Per Second: 200Armor: 55,000Max. Velocity: 75 m/sStrong Against: NoneWeak Against: Bombers, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: Capital Ship FacilityUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2, Improved ManufacturingThe Vaygr Carrier is noticeably cheaper and quicker to build than the Hiigaran Carrier, though it is not hard to see why. While the Hiigaran Carrier can house up to three production systems, the Vaygr variant supports only one, making it less viable as an alternative production site. In addition, it has much lighter armor than its Hiigaran counterpart, although it is better able to defend itself thanks to its greater firepower. In other respects the two ships remain largely the same, and their overall purpose is similar regardless of the differences.Mothership ClassVaygr FlagshipFlagshipRole: Mothership Class Production ShipCost: 8,000 RUsBuild Time: 1 secondDamage Per Second: 120Armor: 200,000Max. Velocity: 40 m/sStrong Against: NoneWeak Against: Bombers, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: N/A (not constructable)Upgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2, Improved ManufacturingWith four slots for production, four for modules, and one for sensors, the Vagyr Flagship is identical to the Hiigaran Mothership in terms of its subsystem capacity. In other areas as well it remains largely the same, serving simultaneously as a resource collection point, ship production facility, research center, and Strike ship storehouse. Even at a statistical level, there is very little to differentiate the two ships. It is the most important vessel in the Vaygr fleet, serving both as its primary production facility and Makaan's personal stronghold.Vaygr ShipyardShipyardRole: Mothership Class Production ShipCost: 4,000 RUsBuild Time: 1 minute, 25 secondsDamage Per Second: 550Armor: 160,000Max. Velocity: 15 m/sStrong Against: NoneWeak Against: Bombers, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: Research Module, Hyperspace Gate Generator, Hyperspace ModuleUpgrade Tech: Engine Lvl. 1, Engine Lvl. 2, Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2, Improved ManufacturingLike the Flagship, the Vaygr Shipyard is more or less a carbon copy of the functionality of its Hiigaran counterpart. It is a little tougher and somewhat better equipped to defend itself, though still quite vulnerable. Expansion hardpoints are all directly comparable, and, like the Hiigaran Shipyard, it is the only vessel within its faction capable of constructing the massive Battlecruiser. Being too large and unwieldy to be built on-location, the Shipyard is instead assembled elsewhere before being hyperspaced to the front lines to fulfill its duties.Platform ClassVaygr Gun PlatformGun PlatformRole: Anti-Fighter Weapon PlatformCost: 300 RUsBuild Time: 20 secondsDamage Per Second: 32Armor: 5,000Max. Velocity: 125 m/sStrong Against: FightersWeak Against: Frigates, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: Platform Control ModuleUpgrade Tech: Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2Designed to repel Strike ships, the Vaygr Gun Platform can be set to defend a specific area, attacking any target within the range of its two mass driver turrets. Like its equivalent on the Hiigaran side, it is progressively less useful against larger ships, as it doesn't inflict much damage with each shot. Vulnerable outfits like deep space mining operations or Shipyards are prime candidates for Gun Platform protection. The single-use engine restriction of the Gun Platform can also be manipulated by leaving it in parade formation once built.Vaygr Missile PlatformMissile PlatformRole: Anti-Capital Ship Weapon PlatformCost: 300 RUsBuild Time: 20 secondsDamage Per Second: 127Armor: 5,000Max. Velocity: 125 m/sStrong Against: Frigates, Capital ShipsWeak Against: Fighters, CorvettesRequired Tech: Platform Control Module, Research Module, Platform MissilesUpgrade Tech: Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2By firing salvos of fusion missiles that ably track down less maneuverable craft, the Missile Platform establishes itself as a firm defensive unit against Frigates and Capital Ships. Like all other defensive Platform class ships, only one movement order is allowed before it becomes completely stationary, thus it is of the utmost importance to place it correctly the first time around. The fusion missiles of the Missile Platform do greater damage individually than the ion beams of the Ion Platform, though this is evened out by their slower recharge rate.Vaygr Hyperspace GateHyperspace GateRole: Hyperspace Generator PlatformCost: 750 RUsBuild Time: 45 secondsDamage Per Second: 0Armor: 16,000Max. Velocity: 600 m/sStrong Against: NoneWeak Against: Fighters, Corvettes, Frigates, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: Platform Control Module, Research Module, Hyperspace Gate GeneratorUpgrade Tech: Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2The Hyperspace Gate is a unique Vaygr creation that allows fast travel between two points. This is accomplished by placing one Gate at the location of the player's fleet and another at the desired exit point. As a Platform class ship, the Hyperspace Gate's engine can be used only once, so it is imperative that they be placed in useful positions. Without weaponry, it is also easy for them to be destroyed or captured. Thus, if a Gate is placed within enemy territory, allied ships must be warped in fairly quickly so that its utility is not wasted.Utility ShipsShips in the Utility class are available to both factions, and usually differ from each other in appearance more than anything else. These non-combat vessels are either classified as resource ships or probes, with the former being related to the collection of Resource Units, the raw materials used to produce ships, and the latter being designed to either augment allied sensor capability or interfere with enemy sensors. Technically speaking, not all utility ships belong to the same weight class, but they are all unified by their complete lack of weaponry.Hiigaran AppearanceVaygr AppearanceStatistics  DescriptionHiigaran Resource CollectorVaygr Resource CollectorResource CollectorRole: Resource GathererCost: 300 RUsBuild Time: 30 secondsDamage Per Second: 0Armor: 2,000Max. Velocity: 276 m/sStrong Against: NoneWeak Against: Fighters, Corvettes, Frigates, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: NoneUpgrade Tech: Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2, RepairThe lifeblood of both the Hiigaran and Vaygr fleets, Resource Collectors are tasked with gathering and delivering resource deposits to any nearby resource collector. In addition, when upgraded, they can assume other duties, namely the repair and maintenance of Frigate and Capital class ships. As the only unit in the game that can gather Resource Units, they are also an attractive target for raiding parties looking to cripple an enemy.Hiigaran Mobile RefineryVaygr Mobile RefineryMobile RefineryRole: Mobile Resource CollectorCost: 800 RUsBuild Time: 45 seconds / 40 secondsDamage Per Second: 80Armor: 18,000Max. Velocity: 225 m/sStrong Against: NoneWeak Against: Fighters, Corvettes, Frigates, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: NoneUpgrade Tech: Armor Lvl. 1, Armor Lvl. 2Mobile Refineries are essentially moveable drop-off points for Resource Collectors, offering two docking points per vessel. While there are several other ships that can receive Resource Units, such as Motherships, Shipyards, and Carriers, the Mobile Refinery is the cheapest and most maneuverable option for resource support, allowing distant mineral deposits to be mined efficiently without establishing a large presence in the area.Hiigaran ProbeVaygr ProbeProbeRole: Single-Use Reconnaissance DeviceCost: 150 RUsBuild Time: 15 secondsDamage Per Second: 0Armor: 100 / 50Max. Velocity: 600 m/sStrong Against: NoneWeak Against: Fighters, Corvettes, Frigates, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: NoneUpgrade Tech: NoneThe lowly Probe is the cheapest vessel to produce in either the Hiigaran or Vaygr faction. Upon completion, it can be issued a single movement order, after which it will simply remain at its directed location, providing constant intelligence until such time as it is destroyed. To assist in its reconnaissance efforts, it is gifted with better sensor capability than most ships, although this does not include the detection of cloaked ships.Hiigaran Proximity SensorVaygr Proximity SensorProximity SensorRole: Single-Use Reconnaissance DeviceCost: 250 RUsBuild Time: 15 seconds / 25 secondsDamage Per Second: 0Armor: 100 / 50Max. Velocity: 600 m/sStrong Against: NoneWeak Against: Fighters, Corvettes, Frigates, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: Research Module, Proximity SensorUpgrade Tech: NoneThe Proximity Sensor Probe is an upgraded version of the standard Probe that requires more Resource Units and prior research into Proximity Sensor technology before it can be built. It can be deployed only once, moving to a proscribed location in order to gather information about the surrounding area. Its range is actually smaller than that of its cheaper predecessor, but it comes with the added benefit of cloak field detection.Hiigaran Distortion ProbeVaygr Distortion ProbeDistortion ProbeRole:Cost: 600 RUs / 500 RUsBuild Time: 30 seconds / 15 secondsDamage Per Second: 0Armor: 100 / 50Max. Velocity: 600 m/sStrong Against: NoneWeak Against: Fighters, Corvettes, Frigates, Capital ShipsRequired Tech: Research Module, Sensor Distortion ProbeUpgrade Tech: NoneUnlike other Probe varieties, the Sensor Distortion Probe is intended primarily to affect enemy sensors. It is utilized in the same manner as other devices of its kind, that is to say by moving it into a location before its single-use engine expires. Once there, they emit false sensor signatures that are meant to confuse and disrupt enemy activity. Though fairly expensive for a Probe, when used in an assault the results can be quite noticeable.ReceptionHomeworld 2's critical reception was overwhelmingly positive in tone, and it maintains a review average within the eightieth percentile on both Metacritic and GameRankings. Reviewers often made mention of a strong audio and visual presentation, engaging gameplay, and a compelling single-player campaign when speaking of the game. It is worth noting though that, while it scored very well overall, it did not score as highly as the original game, and many critics cited a belief that Homeworld 2 represented an incremental rather than fundamental improvement on the Homeworld formula. Nevertheless, most reviewers came to the conclusion that, while it was not as revolutionary as its forebear, Homeworld 2 was ultimately a worthwhile experience, especially for existing fans of the franchise.PC System requirementsProcessor: 1 GHz CPUMemory: 256 MB RAMGraphics: 32 MB TL capable video cardHD: 750 MB free hard drive space</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="11658">Gateway 2: Homeworld</game><game id="9115">Sins of a Solar Empire</game><game id="24092">Sins of a Solar Empire: Entrenchment</game><game id="5244">Far Gate</game><game id="1523">Nexus: The Jupiter Incident</game><game id="26939">Light of Altair</game><game id="29556">Sins of a Solar Empire: Diplomacy</game><game id="19600">Star Wolves</game><game id="36300">Nexus 2</game><game id="2577">O.R.B.: Off-World Resource Base</game><game id="980">Hegemonia: Legions of Iron</game><game id="9962">Hegemonia: The Solon Heritage</game><game id="38867">Total War: Rome II</game><game id="42153">Homeworld: Shipbreakers</game><game id="34294">Sins of a Solar Empire: Rebellion</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/5370/1452190-hw2_us.jpg</image></root>