<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9479</id><name>Sonic Rush</name><description>OverviewSonic goes down a water slideDeveloped by Dimps and overseen by Sonic Team, Sonic Rush is a very classic Sonic game in appearance. Similar to the early Sonic the Hedgehog games and the Sonic Advance games, Sonic Rush plays along a 2Dimensional plain. Each screen of the DS is used entirely for game play, as the player will stay centered in the center of one of the screens. After ascending of descending far enough, however, the player will switch from one screen to the next.Sonic Rush allows players to play as both Sonic the Hedgehog and a new character, Blaze the Cat.PlotBlaze going up a loop!Blaze, a cat-like creature from another dimension, has mysteriously landed in Sonic's Dimension. Sonic and Blaze's dimensions each seem to share certain similarities with each other, such as Doctor Eggman and Eggman Nega being after each dimensions emeralds, the Chaos and Sol Emeralds. Blaze discovers that Doctor Eggman has the Sol Emeralds in his possession and works on getting them back. Blaze runs in to Cream the Rabbit and, despite normally being a reserved individual, she befriends Cream as she travels through the unfamiliar territory.Meanwhile, Sonic is on a similar quest to get the Chaos Emeralds, and is facing a familiar but different foe, Eggman Nega. Similar in appearance to Doctor Eggman, Eggman Nega is the alternative to him from Blaze's dimension. After Tails discovers that the dimensions are beginning to merge, Sonic starts to pursue Blaze, who he became suspicious of when they met earlier in the game.Players are able to follow the story of either character, with the other protagonist and their companions showing up at points in the game. The levels played by each character are the same, but they appear in a different order, and their soundtracks with each stage a different between them.GameplayThe moves available to the player are similar to the earlier Sonic games, with the exception of being able to dash in mid-air and perform tricks while in the air or on rails. Levels are centered around running quickly through them, rather than exact platforming, which is a good fit for the series and plays to it's strength. The player must avoid traps throughout the level, whilst navigating through the levels and their multiple paths.Sonic riding a floating device.Each of the characters performs similar moves. These often differ in appearance only, as their moves have the exact same effect. For example, pressing down on the control pad whilst running with Sonic will cause him to roll, whilst Blaze will spin round and round on a point.Tension GaugeThe Tension Gauge is used for super boost within the game and is situated at the left hand side of the screen. To be able to super boost, the Tension Gauge needs to be charged and this can be done in many ways. Whenever you perform trick actions or defeat an enemy the Tension Gauge will charge a little bit. The Tension Gauge will change color from blue, to orange and then red, indicating the amount of energy you have earned. When the red gauge is completely filled and the star icon on top of the gauge is spinning, the boost action can be used freely. However the Tension Gauge will decrease with time or if you have been hit by an enemy and take damage.The StagesThe game has a total of seven levels, two acts and a boss fight at the end of each level.Leaf Storm: Like most other 2-D Sonic games, you start off in a nice hilly grassland filled with ring loops. This level is fairly easy especially since it's the first level in the game.Water Palace: Obligatory water level. Lots of ways to drown but, this stage is much more forgiving with allowing you to stay above the water.Mirage Road: This level can be described as confusing. This is the desert level of Sonic Rush which has more puzzles than the other levels.Night Carnival: Casino level once again returns. If you played Sonic 2 or 3 this will be very familiar to you.Huge Crisis: A stage of metal and steam. This level is so straight forward yet the easiest to get lost in an endless loop.Altitude Limit: A stage in the sky. Try not to fall...there a few hang gliders up here to keep you safe.Dead Line: The final level of the game. Prepare for riding rockets and gravity changing gameplay as you walk on the ceiling and and have to adjust to the controls.The SoundtrackIf the music in this game sounds a little bit more say upbeat and a Jet Set Radio feel to it than usualSoundtrack coverThat's because it was composed by Hidedki Naganuma. The person responsible for most of the songs in the Jet Set Radio series. People that also helped composed the OST are Teruhiko Nakagawa and Yukifumi Makino.Track List01Right There, Ride On2:3602Back 2 Back2:4503What U Need2:4704Jeh Jeh Rocket2:5105Ska Cha Cha2:5106Vela-Nova3:0007Wrapped in Black3:0008A New Day2:2109What U Need is Remix1:3810Right There, Right On1:3811Right There, Right On (Blazy Mix)1:5112Groove Rush #10:0813Ska Cha Cha2:0714Ska Cha Cha (Blazy Mix)2:1815Enemy or Friend ?0:1116Ethno Circus2:0717Ethno Circus (Blazy Mix)2:1518Metal Scratchin'1:3619Metal Scratchin' (Part 2)0:3220Groove Rush #30:0821Back 2 Back1:3122Back 2 Back (Blazy Mix)2:0823I Wanna Breathe0:1224Just a Breath ! (SE)0:0525Jeh Jeh Rocket2:1226Jeh Jeh Rocket (Blazy Mix)2:2227Groove Rush #70:1028Get Edgy1:3629Get Edgy (Blazy Mix)1:5930A New Day (Intermission)0:2331What U Need2:0532What U Need (Blazy Mix)2:1633Vela-Nova2:0834Vela-Nova (Part 2)0:3635Groove Rush #20:0936Groove Rush #80:0537Bomber Barbara2:0838Bomber Barbara (Part 2)0:3939Groove Rush #40:0940Raisin' Me Up (Prologue)0:5441Wrapped in Black2:3542Wrapped in Black (Part 2)1:0443Groove Rush #50:0944Raisin' Me Up3:5145Medley Rush #23:32Disc length: 73:38CreditsSonic - Jason GriffithBlaze - Berra HudsonMiles "Tails" Prower - Amy PalantCream - Rebbecca HonigEggman/ Eggman Nega - Mike PollockKnuckles the Echidna - Dan GreenAmy Rose - Lisa OrtizExecutive Producer - Hisao OguchiProducer - Yuji NakaRecording Director - Julie RathRecording Engineer - Jason CushingRecording Coordinator - Kristen ThormeCreative Director - Matthew Woodley</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="8224">New Super Mario Bros.</game><game id="10347">Yoshi's Island DS</game><game id="10299">Super Mario Bros. 3</game><game id="9233">Kirby Super Star</game><game id="15890">Kirby's Adventure</game><game id="2866">Super Mario World 2: Yoshi's Island</game><game id="4237">Contra 4</game><game id="9882">Super Princess Peach</game><game id="12778">Sonic Rush Adventure</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1803668-box_sonicrush.png</image></root>