<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9491</id><name>Cold Winter</name><description>CampaignPlotAndrew Sterling an MI6 agent is captured while on a deniable covert operation in China. After weeks of internment, and with MI6 seemingly disavowing Andrew, he is rescued by an old friend 'Kim'. He finds that he has been freed at the behest of his old associate Danny Parish. To repay this debt and at loose ends with his status, ex-Mi6 agent, Andrew agrees to assist Parish's on a new mission his private security firm is running in Africa. Andrew arrives in Egypt to investigate Amenkoht Ali-Salah, a corrupt Egyptian businessman who's corporation, Setech Industries is involved with illegal arms dealers. Andrew get's to Salah and his compatriots, but learns that his arms dealing is connected to deeper plot involving a post WWII secret society, GreyWings, bent on destroying the world to save it. Andrew and Kim set out to save the world from this secrete society called Greywings.LevelsChang PrisonChang Prison CourtyardsQattara Old TownQattara New TownQattara CompoundSalah's Den (Warehouse)Salah's Den (Distribution)Salah's Den (Perimeter)Setech Industries QuarrySetech Industries LabsSetech Industries SublevelsBlack Market ApproachBlack Market ValleyWinterlong Monitoring SystemWinterlong Supply Depot B-16Winterlong CoreGameplay - Striking FeaturesCold Winter's environments are interactive for a 2005 era PS2 title. Most tables can be tipped over to create cover, toilets flush and faucets spill water. You can also drag big items like rickshaws, desks, beds and dumpsters, and small items like chairs, baskets, pots  pans, can be picked up and thrown.A rudimentary cover mechanic is integrated into game play. Although cover is usually unnecessary, an overturned table or desk proved useful in some fights in nothing more as something to do to confound the passable enemy AI. Playing at higher difficulty levels shows off an adequate AI system often missed on lower levels where enemies act far more realistically in cover.Items looted from enemies and the environment can be combined metal shards, wire cutters, alarm clocks, rags, glue, motion sensor and plastique to create improved weapons (bombs, grenades, traps).The game offers what it calls 'Zone specific' rag-doll death  body damage effects which amounts of blood splatter  drip effects, limbs spawn when blown off, player drips blood when critically hit. The ragdoll is satisfying, but primitive with many enemies falling without flourish but sometimes cart wheeling away a bit too limply.Health is distributed through a syringe of adrenaline you carry with you at all times. It can be used at any time, but must be strategically employed since it requires a seven second animation that if interrupted by the player or enemies must be restarted.An after mission ranking system was included in the game. Rank was based on how many secondary objectives , shooting accuracy, the percentage of enemies killed, number of weapons found, the number of combinable items found, and the number of intelligence items found. Much of this system was unexplained in the game and manual so they system was very controversial since it seem arbitrary and harsh without explanation of how to improve.Voice ActorsThe shadowy anatomist of John Grey was voiced by British character actor Tom Baker, best known as the fourth incarnation of The Doctor, in Doctor Who. Royal Shakespeare Company (RSC) actor Nathaniel Parker played the protagonist Andrew Sterling, he is best know from his role as the timid Edward Rochester in film Wild Sargasso Sea. Rounding out the cast was Kristy Wu who played Kim, she is best known from the reoccurring role of comic-foil Chao-Ahn from Buffy The Vampire Slayer (the potential slayer who only spoke Cantonese)WritersCold Winter was written as a collaboration of Julian Widdows with Warren Ellis.Multiplayer (Competitive, Team Oriented)Offline: 4 player (split screen w/ AI bots)Deathmatch, King Of The Hill, Flag Tag (capture the flag), Last Man Standing, Domination and Headmatch (keep-away a dismembered head for points).Online: - 8 player broadbandDeathmatch, King Of The Hill, Flag Tag (capture the flag), Last Man Standing, Domination and Headmatch (keep-away a dismembered head for points).Maps12 online that feature friendly fire toggles  player handicapsOnline Player FeaturesPlayers can set a profile where they choose from 30 skins.Guns[HANDGUNS]PSU 9mm Suppressed288 9mmAMT Longslide HardballerB93 Burst (Beretta Model 93r)288 Special (scope attached)[SUBMACHINE GUNS]M-320K53P5K SMG9mm TMP SMGP5K SuppressedP90 SMG[ASSAULT RIFLES]AKS47Stur ARGM4A1G11 Assault Rifle[SHOTGUNS]Pump Action ShotgunSawn-Off Shotgun (double-barreled 12-gauge)Hammer (Jackhammer 12-gauge automatic shotgun)[SNIPER RIFLES]Dragunov Sniper RiflePS1 Sniper RifleL50 (Barrett M82A1 Light Fifty)L96AW (PM L96A1 sniper rifle)[HEAVY MACHINEGUNS]Browning (mounted .50 caliber heavy machine gun)PK-S Medium Machine Gun (Russian 7.62mm light machine gun)[HEAVY WEAPONS]40mm Grenade Launcher (HK HK79A1)RPG LauncherKV-8 Dragon FlamethrowerLAW ( M-72 light antitank weapon)[GRENADES/EXPLOSIVES  CREATED IMPROVISED WEAPON]Fragmentation GrenadeSmoke GrenadeMolotov Cocktail (Materials Needed: Empty Bottle, Fuel Can, Strip of Cloth)Timed Explosive (Materials Needed: Plastique, Alarm Clock)Sticky Timed Explosive (Materials Needed: Plastique, Alarm Clock, Tin of Glue)Motion Sensitive Explosive (Materials Needed: Plastique, Motion Sensor)Sticky Motion Sensitive Explosive (Materials Needed: Plastique, Motion Sensor, Tin of GlueFire Bomb (Materials Needed: Fuel Can, Plastique, Alarm Clock)Motion Sensitive Fire Bomb (Materials Needed: Fuel Can, Plastique, Motion Sensor)SoundtrackArtist: Mark WillotAlbum: Cold Winter- Original Game Music ScoreLabel: Universal Music Production Library ℗ 2004 Swordfish Studios LimitedReleased: Nov 14, 2006Duration: 1:42 minutes1. Cold Winter Front End2. Sterlings Story3. Kimfiltration4. Fight in the Prison Courtyard5. Helicopter Attack6. China Escape7. Parish Flashback8. The Golden Narghile9. Mystery Bombers10. Conflict Outside the Biomine11. Fight at the BioMine Reactor12. Fight With Salah13. Kims Story14. Fight in Fariqs Warehouse15. Fight on the Rooftops16. John in the Lab17. Market Garden18. Sweden19. The Spitfire20. The War Room21. The Wedding22. Johns Assassination23. Winterlong Barracks24. The Array25. The Cable Car26. Fight in the Lobby27. Cold Winter Credits</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="14123">GoldenEye: Rogue Agent</game><game id="16559">007: Agent Under Fire</game><game id="6647">007: Nightfire</game><game id="8632">Soldier of Fortune: Payback</game><game id="4745">Soldier of Fortune II: Double Helix</game><game id="8369">Black</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/4865/810055-914739_60855_front.jpg</image></root>