<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9532</id><name>Disgaea: Afternoon of Darkness</name><description>Known in Japan as Disgaea portable, Disgaea: Afternoon of Darkness is the English name for the psp remake of the first game in the Disgaea series, Hour of Darkness, which appeared on the Playstation 2.Disgaea: Afternoon of Darkness boxart Afternoon of Darkness features a number of changes including an "Etna" mode where Etna accidently kills Laharl waking him at the beginning of the game and is instead the main character. There are extra boss battles including a battle with some of the  characters from Disgaea 2, as well as multiplayer modes (Battle, Capture the Flag and Defeat the Leader), a first for the Disgaea series.There is also a music shop and a stats keeper, neither of which featured in Disgaea 1.Afternoon of Darkness was converted to a 16:9 format (from the originals 4:3) to take advantage of the PSP's widescreen.In addition, Afternoon of Darkness includes a complete dual language option (English and the original Japanese) and the option to turn off battle animations. Most of the silent Japanese cut scenes now include voice acting. However, when set to English, the scenes that were originally silent in the PS2 release are still silent. To reflect the change in Etna's voice actor, her lines have been re-recorded to match Michelle Ruff's portrayal of Etna in Disgaea 2</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20593">Jeanne d'Arc</game><game id="8721">Final Fantasy Tactics Advance</game><game id="12719">Advance Wars</game><game id="21924">Dragoneer's Aria</game><game id="12050">Eternal Eyes</game><game id="21961">Wild Arms XF</game><game id="21355">Soul Nomad &amp; the World Eaters</game><game id="17905">PoPoLoCrois</game><game id="23082">Super Robot Wars R</game><game id="21996">Dungeons and Dragons Tactics</game><game id="23083">Super Robot Wars D</game><game id="22607">Super Robot Wars Alpha 2</game><game id="21244">Super Robot Wars W</game><game id="7259">Arc the Lad</game><game id="22722">Disgaea DS</game><game id="9600">Metal Gear Ac!d</game><game id="8702">Metal Gear Ac!d 2</game><game id="7281">Astonishia Story</game><game id="3731">Phantom Brave</game><game id="24220">Fire Emblem: Shadow Dragon</game><game id="27388">Valkyria Chronicles II</game><game id="24212">Growlanser</game><game id="27861">Shin Megami Tensei: Persona 3 Portable</game><game id="29245">Queen's Blade: Spiral Chaos</game><game id="29281">Akatsuki no Amaneka to Aoi Kyojin: Pashiate Bunmei Kenkyuukai Koubouki</game><game id="13936">Warhammer 40,000: Squad Command</game><game id="19864">Final Fantasy Tactics</game><game id="27994">Final Fantasy Tactics: The War of the Lions</game><game id="21286">Final Fantasy Tactics A2: Grimoire of the Rift</game><game id="33448">Vantage Master</game><game id="29872">Dokapon DX</game><game id="11771">Brave Story: New Traveler</game><game id="36104">Card Hunter</game><game id="37059">Aselia the Eternal</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1832916-box_disgaeapsp.png</image></root>