<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9542</id><name>Night Warriors: Darkstalkers' Revenge</name><description>OverviewNight Warriors: Darkstalkers' Revenge (known in Japan as Vampire Hunter: Darkstalkers' Revenge) is a 2D Gothic horror-themed fighting game developed and released by Capcom for arcades (using the CPS-2 hardware) on March 1995. The second installment of the Darkstalkers franchise (and the sequel to Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors), Night Warriors: Darkstalkers' Revenge refines the gameplay (including adding the ability to stock up on multiple super meters) while adding two new characters (the dhampir Donovan Baine and the jiangshi Hsien-Ko) and refines the story (involving the invasion of Earth by the alien Pyron, and the two new characters' goal to hunt the other "darkstalkers").The game was ported to the Saturn on February 22, 1996, featuring an "Appendix Mode" that allows players to switch between this game's version and the Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors version for certain background stages, character palette, and background music.GameplayScreen Shot Showing the New Energy Bar.While keeping the basic fighting mechanics from the first game including Chain Combos, Crouch walking and air blocking, several refinements and, balance tweaks were made.The energy meter system from the previous game was replaced with a more traditional "stock" system similar to that of Street Fighter Alpha. This system allows you to save up energy to use at a later time.Also introduced in this game were recovery rolls and pursuit attacks. Pursuit attacks allowed a player to attack a downed opponent. While the recovery roll could be used to counter this new mechanic and "roll" out of the way of the attack ether towards or away from the opponent.Chain Combos where heavily modified, and now where called "Hunter Combos". This is a specific kind of chain combo where the player starts by hitting weak attacks and progress up to stronger ones of the same type. This same combo mechanic was later used in the newer Marvel vs franchise.Hardware and PortsNorth American Sega Saturn Box ArtJust like the first installment of the Darkstalkers series, Night Warrors: Darkstalker Revenge ran on Capcoms CPSII hardware. The arcade controls and button layout was the same as previous games in the series, using Capcoms standard 6 button control panel layout.Night Warrors: Darkstalkers Revenge has been ported a total of four times to various hardware. Both Playstation and Saturn received versions of the game, adding options menus and different game modes.The Saturn version featured a unique appendix mode that allowed for the music and art assets to be swapped from the original Darkstalkers game, however the assets where not always accurate to the original sometimes just being recoloring of Night Warriors assets.The game has also been released as part of a larger compilation, Darkstalkers Chronicle: The Chaos Tower, for PSP, and The Vampire Collection for PS2. Both the Playstation and Playstation 2 ports of the game have never been released outside of Japan.The game will be remastered in HD as part of Darkstalkers Resurrection for XBLA and PSN (alongside Darkstalkers 3).CharactersThe Updated Character Select ScreenNight Warriors: Darkstalker Revenge features 14 playable characters based on popular monster movie villains or myth. The characters in Night Warriors are fighting from around the world much like Street fighter, however nearly all the country's in the Darkstalker series are different than the Street Fighter games. Much like Street Fighter 2 Turbo, all of the default character colors where changed to there alternate. All of the previous characters return from the first iteration as well all making the boss characters playable. As with the previous version, the two final matches are against Huitzil and Pyron respectively.Returning Playable CharactersCharacterMonsterCountryAnakarisMummyEgyptBishamonSamurai GhostJapanDemitri MaximoffVampireRomainaFeliciaCatwomanUnited StatesJon TalbainWarewolfEnglandLord RaptorZombieAustraliaMorrigan AenslandSuccubusScotlandRikuoMermanBrazilSasquatchSasquatchCanadaVictor Von GerdenheimFrankenstien MonsterGermanyNew Playable CharactersCharacterMonsterPyroAlienPlanet HelstormHuitzilAlien RobotMexicoDonovanDemon HunterUnknownHsien-KoChinese ZombieChina</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="6295">Darkstalkers Chronicle: The Chaos Tower</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="243">Street Fighter II: The World Warrior</game><game id="20456">Street Fighter IV</game><game id="1615">Street Fighter III: 3rd Strike</game><game id="1328">Street Fighter Alpha 3</game><game id="1096">Street Fighter II': Champion Edition</game><game id="8161">Street Fighter II Turbo: Hyper Fighting</game><game id="1235">Street Fighter</game><game id="20616">Super Street Fighter II Turbo HD Remix</game><game id="22820">Red Earth</game><game id="12903">Marvel Super Heroes</game><game id="10574">X-Men: Children of the Atom</game><game id="2612">Marvel vs. Capcom 2: New Age of Heroes</game><game id="8492">Capcom vs. SNK 2: Mark of the Millennium</game><game id="8605">Marvel vs. Capcom: Clash of Super Heroes</game><game id="20728">Tatsunoko vs. Capcom: Ultimate All Stars</game><game id="12125">Capcom Fighting Evolution</game><game id="9369">Namco x Capcom</game><game id="2457">Iron &amp; Blood: Warriors of Ravenloft</game><game id="379">Waku Waku 7</game><game id="18647">JoJo's Bizarre Adventure</game><game id="23535">Samurai Shodown VI</game><game id="20292">Astra Superstars</game><game id="34082">Skullgirls</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2339537-box_nwdr.png</image></root>