<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9578</id><name>Zoo Tycoon 2: Endangered Species</name><description>Endangered Species is an expansion for Microsoft's Zoo Tycoon 2 PC game, and was the first of three released. Like all expansions, Endangered Species requires the original Zoo Tycoon 2 game installed. The expansion adds extra campaigns, items, and animals. Endangered Species contains 20 new animals, which vary in rarity.  Graphical PatchesEndangered Species included multiple patches for the graphics of the game on the disc, and these were generally welcomed by PC gamers as the original game graphics were regarded as being somewhat poor. Should the PC being used be able to handle 'Very High' settings for water detail, the water became transparent, rather than a solid color. On top of this,  all 2D objects contained in the original Zoo Tycoon 2 were upgraded into 3D with the Endangered Species expansion pack.  New AnimalsEndangered Species boosted the roster of animals present in the game by 20, and as the name would suggest, focuses entirely on endangered species of animal, such as the orangutan. As well as adding new animals, Endangered Species reworked the AI of animals that were included in the original game, and allowed them to be herded more easily amongst other things. Below is a list of all the animals added:  Latin NameCommon Name Lycaon Pictus African Wild Dog Bison Bison American Bison Tapirus Bairdii Baird's Tapir Rangifer Tarandus Groenlandicus Caribou Hylobates Concolor Crested Gibbon Vulpes Zerda Fennec Fox Puma Concolor Coryi Florida Panther Hippotragus Niger Variani Giant Sable Antelope Geochelone Niger Porteri Galapagos Giant Tortoise Canis Lupus Lyacon Grey Wolf Rhinoceros Sondaicus Javan Rhino Phascolarctos Cinerus Koala Vanarus Komodoenisis Komodo Dragon Capra Falconeri Markhor Pongo Pygmaeus Orangutan Equus Ferus Przewalskii  Przewalskii's Horse Oryx Dammah Scimitar Horned Oryx Lynx Pardinius Spanish Lynx Tremarctos Omatus Speckled Bear Gulo Gulo WolverineDespite the fact that these animals were all added to the game before Zoo Tycoon 2 for the Nintendo DS was released, the only Endangered Species animals to appear in the DS version of the game are the Spanish Lynx, Orangutan and Koala.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre><genre id="8">Educational</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="1022">Jurassic Park III: Park Builder</game><game id="11069">Jurassic Park: Operation Genesis</game><game id="42908">Zoo Tycoon</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/56/668351-928190_67228_front.jpg</image></root>