<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9598</id><name>Astral Tournament</name><description>Astral Tournament is a card game where mages duel each other using spells and summoned creatures. The game does not feature any deck customization, but attempts to offset the random element this introduces by having players choose specializations at the start of a match. This idea has been iterated upon in the game's sequel, Spectromancer.GameplayPlayers start a match with a random set of cards, and 50 life points. The object of the game is to reduce your opponent's life points to 0. Each card has an elemental level associated with it. The 5 elements the game uses are Air, Earth, Fire, Water and Death. Cards can only be used if the player using it is of a high enough level with the corresponding element. Players gain a level in each element at the start of their turn, and are given a starting bonus to one element based on the specialization they choose at the beginning of a match. Using a card drains the caster of the number of levels that the card is rated as in the associated element.In addition to casting spells, creatures can be summoned to help in battle. There are 5 creature slots on each side of the battlefield. If a creature is placed next to a creature of the opposing side, it will attack that creature. If a creature is placed on a slot without an enemy creature next to it, the creature will damage the opponent. Creatures have independent life and attack ratings.Mage Specializations Battle Mage - Specializes in Fire MagicDruid - Specializes in Earth MagicNecromancer - Specializes in Death MagicStorm Mage - Specializes in Water MagicThunder Mage - Specializes in Air MagicWizard - Balanced in all elementsGame ModesDuel Game - Allows for one-on-one duels between 2 players, or with an AI. Both online and hotseat multiplayer are supported.Tournament Game - Players move through several leagues of AI controlled opponents. Each league consists of 8 rounds against AI opponents, while other matches between AI opponents are simulated to generate a ranking for the player at the end of 8 rounds. There is a progression of leagues for the player to ascend, with new abilities being given along the way.</description><genres><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="13">Card Game</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="25488">Spectromancer</game></similar_games><image>NONE</image></root>