<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9600</id><name>Metal Gear Ac!d</name><description>Launching alongside the  PSP, Metal Gear Acid made several changes to the well-established  Metal Gear franchise. Rather than being an Action game, Acid is a Turn Based Strategy and  Collectible Card game, a huge departure from the previous titles. But while the method of playing the game had changed, the fundamental gameplay had not. Players were still expected to use whatever means necessary to avoid enemy detection and complete their objectives all the while encountering over the top  bosses, unravel a complex plot and stop the latest iteration of  Metal Gear.Metal Gear Acid allows players to construct decks out of the cards they have collected, either from a completing a mission or buying a booster pack, that enable Snake to do various moves prior to any mission. With over 200 cards to collect, players have many options when it comes to constructing a deck. The cards themselves are organized into different sets, that have different themes spanning the entirety of the Metal Gear universe as well as some other games  Kojima has produced over the years.  Each card has a different effect: some conjure the images of past bosses and  allies, such as  Gray Fox or  Metal Gear REX to help defeat your foes, while others heal Snake, like the trusty  Ration card. Many of the cards represent the many weapons seen in the  Metal Gear franchise, including the  SOCOM from  Metal Gear Solid or the  Mosin-Nagant from  Metal Gear Solid 3: Snake Eater. Metal Gear Ac!d was followed up by  Metal Gear Ac!d 2 (also on the PSP), but it's not a direct continuation of the original.SoundtrackDisc 1      Soundtrack          METAL GEAR ACID (0:52)      Intermission (0:57)      Conspiracy (1:49)      NEKAL Commercial (0:08)      On Alert (0:59)      Leone (1:36)      Briefing (1:05)      Elsie  Francis (1:36)      First Mission (1:23)      Undercover Action (1:38)      Control Office (1:28)      Egersis (1:55)      Minette (1:07)      Dream Land (1:46)      BRC (1:29)      Ritual of the Swarm (1:32)      Leone Forces (1:36)      Residential Quarters (1:24)      Power House (1:51)      Interval of Dark (1:44)      Niko2 (1:36)      FAR (1:29)      La Clown (1:52)      Death of SwallowTail (1:09)      Frission (1:37)      Metal Gear!? (1:29)      Vs. Metal Gear (3:37)      Alice (1:33)      Roger's Confession (1:58)      End Title (3:41)      MGS1 Pack (0:23)      MGS2 Pack (0:29)      MGS3 Pack (0:34)      Chronicle Pack (0:32)      Link Battle (1:47)      Link Battle Rush (0:42)      Sweeties (0:40)      Mission Start (0:07)      Mission Failed (0:07)      Mission Complete(0:07)      Metal Gear -Remix-(1:59)      Bonus Track -Sound Effects- (3:02)     </description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="13">Card Game</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="9209">Yu-Gi-Oh! Duelists of the Roses</game><game id="15039">Lost Kingdoms II</game><game id="14922">Yu-Gi-Oh! Capsule Monster Coliseum</game><game id="8702">Metal Gear Ac!d 2</game><game id="9532">Disgaea: Afternoon of Darkness</game><game id="20593">Jeanne d'Arc</game><game id="4563">Field Commander</game><game id="13936">Warhammer 40,000: Squad Command</game><game id="21529">Aedis Eclipse: Generation of Chaos</game><game id="5219">The Lord of the Rings: Tactics</game><game id="24967">Disgaea 2: Dark Hero Days</game><game id="15133">Phantom Dust</game><game id="20786">Culdcept Saga</game><game id="24070">Culdcept DS</game><game id="9459">Culdcept</game><game id="27388">Valkyria Chronicles II</game><game id="24212">Growlanser</game><game id="29245">Queen's Blade: Spiral Chaos</game><game id="29281">Akatsuki no Amaneka to Aoi Kyojin: Pashiate Bunmei Kenkyuukai Koubouki</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1789933-box_mgacid.png</image></root>