<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9603</id><name>Star Wars: Masters of Teräs Käsi</name><description>OverviewStar Wars: Masters of Teräs Käsi is a fighting game based in the Star Wars universe that takes place during the original trilogy that was released on the Playstation in 1997. The game offers characters ranging from Luke Skywalker to Boba Fett and Darth Vader. Various locations from the films can be found in the fighting arenas including Hoth and Cloud City. The name "Teräs Käsi" originates from the Finnish language and translates to "steel hand".WeaponsTeräs Käsi was a fairly unique fighting game because of its implementation of weapons. Most characters could pull out a weapon with the push of a button. These weapons were unique to each character and ranged from a blaster for Han Solo, to a lightsaber for Luke Skywalker, Mara Jade, and Darth Vader. Arden Lyn and Thok were unique in that they could not choose between hand to hand combat and using a weapon. Thok's weapon of choice was a battle ax, and it could not be put away. Arden Lyn had no weapon to choose from.Mara Jade was first made a playable character in Star Wars: Master of Teras KasiEaster EggsTeräs Käsi, like most games set in the star wars universe had a number of nods to the expansive Star Wars universe. Players could unlock the scout trooper from Return of the Jedi. They could unlock Princess Leia's slave girl outfit. Also, the developers of Teräs Käsi made characters from the extended universe playable as well. Mara jade, the popular character from Timothy Zahn's Thrawn trilogy makes an appearance, as well as the Boba Fett lookalike, Jodo Kast.Playable Characters Arden Lyn, a master of Teräs Käsi hired by the Emperor Boba Fett Chewbacca Darth Vader  Han Solo Hoar, a Tusken Raider Jodo Kast Luke Skywalker Mara Jade Princess Leia Organa Thok, a Gamorrean guard Stormtrooper</description><genres><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="41">Virtua Fighter 2</game><game id="12411">Soulcalibur</game><game id="11822">Soulcalibur II</game><game id="9855">Soulcalibur III</game><game id="20678">Soulcalibur IV</game><game id="10081">Tekken</game><game id="10387">Tekken 2</game><game id="11189">Tekken 3</game><game id="14684">Tekken 4</game><game id="18753">Tekken 5</game><game id="6153">Soul Blade</game><game id="1480">Star Gladiator Episode 1: Final Crusade</game><game id="6421">Mortal Kombat 4</game><game id="617">NeoGeo Battle Coliseum</game><game id="20728">Tatsunoko vs. Capcom: Ultimate All Stars</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/1787606-box_swmotk.png</image></root>