<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9609</id><name>Grand Prix 2</name><description>OverviewGrand Prix 2, also known as "GP2", is a racing simulator released by      MicroProse in 1995 and designed by     Geoff Crammond. The game held an official FIA license that featured the Formula One 1994 season in its entirety: all of the circuits, teams, drivers (except for    Ayrton Senna and Roland Ratzenberger who where both killed in separate racing incidents during the 1994 season) and cars were present in the game.Grand Prix 2 was one of the first games with 3D texture mapping and SVGA graphics, as well as an early but realistic physics engine. Grand Prix 2 is recognised as one of the definitive racing simulations of all times.  A large community of GP2 enthusiasts formed quickly and still exists today. One of the reasons for this is the easy ability to modify the cars and tracks. Editing tools sprung up on websites that allowed people to design their own cars and change almost every aspect of the game. One particularly hilarious modification allowed the player to change how bouncy the cars were, leading to particularly interesting race starts.   The introduction video feature a slide show of photographs from real Formula One interspersed with a flying, 3D, "Grand Prix 2" logo.FeaturesVGA graphics will full texture and light sourcing.Start of a race at the Monaco Grand Prix. All sixteen circuits from the 1994 season. State-of-the-art 3D engine. Full race strategy planning. Multi-player capability over LAN or Dial Up. Superb realism with pitching, banking, rolling, crashes and spins. Full lap replay from real TV camera positions. Team, Tracks, Drivers and Sponsors identical to the real sport.A brilliant implementation of instant replay (one button press) that very few racing games do well even today.  System RequirementsMinimum Requirements: Processor: 486 DX4 100MHz Operating System: DOS 5.0 or higher / Windows 95 or 98 RAM Memory: 16 MB Graphics Card: 256 VGA Graphics Audio Card: Soundblaster Sound Card or 100 Compatible   Recommended Requirements:Processor: Pentium 90 MHzOperating System: DOS 5.0 or higher / Windows 95 or 98RAM Memory: 32 MB Graphics Card: Super VGA Card with 1MB Ram Audio Card: Soundblaster Sound Card or 100 Compatible </description><genres><genre id="3">Sports</genre><genre id="6">Driving/Racing</genre><genre id="7">Simulation</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="5615">Grand Prix Simulator</game><game id="6455">F-1 World Grand Prix</game><game id="6347">Grand Prix Legends</game><game id="5890">CART Precision Racing</game><game id="8360">F1 World Championship Edition</game><game id="25985">F1 2010</game><game id="14919">Grand Prix Challenge</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/6/62890/1533272-grand_prix_2.jpg</image></root>