<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9676</id><name>NiGHTS into Dreams...</name><description>OverviewNiGHTS was born out of a simple concept: capturing the sensation of flight. Released the same month as Super Mario 64, some viewed it as Sega's answer to Nintendo's mascot superstar. In reality, NiGHTS into Dreams, much like the Sonic titles, shares more in common with a traditional arcade game, complete with high score tables displayed at the end of each level and a score multiplier awarded depending on how well you perform during the boss encounter.Elliot at the Ideya PalaceAfter choosing between playing as Elliot Edwards (the boy) or Claris Sinclair (the girl), you are dropped in to a fully 3D environment where your most immediate task is to reclaim the four "Ideya Spheres" that have been stolen from you and hidden within the level. While you can go searching for them on foot, you are incredibly super vulnerable in your human form, so your best bet is to approach and enter the Ideya Palace and transform in to the flying purple jester known as NiGHTS.The gameplay shifts between 3D and 2.5 D. As Elliot and Claris the game offers a fully developed 3D landscape, as Nights however the game changes to a side scroling perspective with Nights locked into one of four possible paths. The game is essentially lap based with each lap consisting of a different path. The only way to switch paths it to collect 20 blue chips and bring them to an Ideya Spheare. Doing this and completing a lap will cause the path to alternate in which you must do the same thing again. After completing all 4 paths the game swithches to a boss leveAs Nights you are essentially invincible with the only penalty for being hit being loss of time. Time however is a very valuable resource in this game with players only being given a limited amount of time as Nights before being turned back to human form. Failing to complete the all the paths in a regular level before time is up. means that you will have to collect all 20 blue chips and return them to an Ideya shphere before being allowed to become Nights again. On foot you can die with one hit. Futhermore an alarm clock relentlessly tracks you while on foot, which will also kill you if it catches you.In the boss levels there are no humans allowed. Running out of times in these will lead to an immediate game over.Other versionsChristmas NightsFor Christmas of 1996, SonicTeam and Sega released a special extended demo called Christmas NiGHTS which includes its own content (reskinned graphics, the ability to play as Sonic, and more) and even an entire level (sans boss) not found in the full game.Playstation 2 portIn 2007, eleven years after the original NiGHTS was released, Sega remade NiGHTS for the Playstation 2, with enhanced graphics and bonus extras.Xbox Live. Playstation Network ports.In October 2012, Sega released a version of Nights into Dreams for the Xbox 360 and Playstation Network. This port is based on the Playetation 2 port.PlotNiGHTS and ClarisThe evil Wizeman, King of the Nightmaren, is no longer satisfied with simply controlling the dream world of Nightopia. He seeks more! Wizeman hatches a plot to use Ideya Dream Energy to shake off the shackles of the dream world and enter our reality, where his power to shape and create nightmares will leave him unstoppable. To help him accomplish this task, he crafts two special first-class Nightmaren: a pair of jesters by the names of NiGHTS and Reala. He commands the pair to seek out and capture any Ideya they can find, especially the rare red Ideya, representing the emotion of Bravery.Ungrateful to its creator, NiGHTS rebels against Wizeman's orders. As punishment, Wizeman seals NiGHTS in an Ideya Prison; the only way he can be freed is if somebody uses their Ideya energy to temporarily unlock his cage, and with his Nightmaren collecting all the Ideya for themselves, it is not likely NiGHTS will ever be released. However, two special dreamers - a pair of children named Elliot Edwards and Claris Sinclair - have an abundance of Red Ideya energy and find themselves very near NiGHTS' holding cell...LevelsClarisSpring Valley ~the IDEAL~ (Boss: Gilwing)Mystic Forest ~the POSSIBILITY~ (Boss: Gulpo)Soft Museum ~the CONFUSION~ (Boss: Jackle)Twin Seeds ~the GROWTH~ (Boss: Wizeman)ElliotSplash Garden ~the AFFECTION~ (Boss: Puffy)Frozen Bell ~the CONSCIOUSNESS~ (Boss: Clawz)Stick Canyon ~the REVIVAL~ (Boss: Reala)Twin Seeds ~the GROWTH~ (Boss: Wizeman)Playstation 2 Re-Release"Brand New Dream" modeNiGHTS: into Dreams... was released for the Playstation 2 exclusively in Japan in 2007. Initially thought to be part of Sega's " Sega Ages 2500" releases, it did not bear the budget line's branding and was instead a full-priced product. The Playstation 2 version of NiGHTS features all of the content from the original Sega Saturn release as well as a visually remastered "Brand New Dream" mode. A number of bonus features from Christmas NiGHTS were also incorporated, including image galleries, the Nightopian viewer, and the Christmas version of Spring Valley. However, other features, like Link Attack, Karaoke Mode, and Sonic into Dreams remain exclusive to the Sega Saturn version of Christmas NiGHTS. The Playstation 2 version of NiGHTS also adds four new calendar-related events, which imbue Claris and Elliot with special bonus costumes:July 20th: Play Splash Garden as Claris in a summer outfit.August 31st: Play Splash Garden as Elliot in a summer outfit.October 1st-30th: Play Mystic Forest as Claris in a witch costume.October 31st: Play Mystic Forest as Elliot in a vampire costume.SoundtrackNiGHTS Original SoundtrackMusic for NiGHTS was composed by Naofumi Hataya, Tomoko Sasaki, and Fumie Kumatani. The soundtrack was released in Japan by PolyGram on July 10, 1996. The game contains one vocal track, with two variations: one version is sung by children (presumably Claris and Elliot themselves), with a second version playing over the credits as a reward for completing the game with all A ranks.NiGHTS Original SoundtrackTotal length: 57:30NiGHTSGate of Your DreamPaternal HornThe Dragon Gave a Loud ScreamTake the Snow TrainThe MantleMessage from NightopiaGloom of the N.H.C.E-LE-KI SparkleThe Amazing WaterDeep it LiesDreams Dreams ~In Silent Memory~Suburban MuseumShe Had Long EarsUnder ConstructionNights and RealaGrowing WingsNights and Reala ~Theme of a Tregedic Revenge~D'Force MasterAfter the DreamKnow Thyself!Sowing SeedsDREAMS DREAMSFragmented NightsDevelopment HistoryShortly after completing work on Sonic the Hedgehog 2, future Sonic Team president Yuji Naka had a flash of inspiration on the plane ride back to Japan: What if a game captured the thrilling sensation of flight? This idea was shelved for many years as he continued work on games in the Sonic the Hedgehog franchise. After completing Sonic  Knuckles, the team revisited the concept of flight for Sega's new Saturn game console, hoping technology had advanced to the point where a game based around the concept would be feasible and enjoyable.Initial concepts involved a newborn baby bird who was just learning how to fly; over the course of the game, this character would grow stronger and learn how to fly more gracefully. This concept was scrapped after deciding it somehow resembled Sonic the Hedgehog too much. Eventually the concept of a graceful jester called NiGHTS in the dream world of Nightopia was decided upon. Hundreds of animations were created to convey the acrobatic sense of grace NiGHTS had, easily gliding through the air, defying the laws of gravity. To help control NiGHTS, SonicTeam simultaneously launched a new Sega Saturn analog joystick with NiGHTS into Dreams..., allowing players full control over NiGHTS' speed and direction.To flesh out Nightopia, Sonic Team designers actually studied dream psychology for many weeks, reading and comparing the works of psychologists like Carl Jung and Frederick Holtz for inspiration. Each level in NiGHTS was carefully constructed to reflect the apparent memories and emotions both the main characters had growing up.Yuji Naka frequently likened his feelings about NiGHTS: Into Dreams... to Steven Spielberg's own regarding E.T.: The Extra Terrestrial - that it is his "perfect" game. Much like Spielberg's aversion to making a sequel to E.T., Yuji Naka repeatedly stated that it would be difficult if not impossible to improve on the game's formula without tarnishing what made the original NiGHTS so unique and special. He maintained this position all the way up until quitting Sonic Team in 2006 to go start PROPE. Within less than a year of Naka's departure, Sonic Team announced they would be developing a sequel, called NiGHTS: Journey of Dreams.TriviaThe genders of NiGHTS and its evil twin Reala are never openly mentioned; they are purposely left androgynous.A boss fight against a character called "Selph" was cut. Reportedly, Selph would be a mirror image of NiGHTS. The unused orchestral track "Know Thyself!" on the official NiGHTS Soundtrack is said to be the music for the deleted Selph boss.Despite NiGHTS existing only in a singular Sega Saturn game for many years, Sonic Team made damn sure nobody could forget the character: NiGHTS had a cameo in nearly every Sonic Team game produced following the release of the original Sega Saturn title, with appearances in Sonic Adventure, Sonic Adventure 2, Phantasy Star Online, Sonic Shuffle, Billy Hatcher and the Giant Egg, and more.NiGHTS was the debut of Sonic Team's ill-fated "Artificial Life" (A-Life for short) system. Each level in NiGHTS is inhabited by small pixie-like creatures called Pians. Pians freely move about the level, doing various activities on their own accord; singing, socializing, and generally having fun. NiGHTS can interact with Pians one of several ways: Killing them (which makes all Pians witness to the event very upset), or helping them to mate: by touching a Nightmaren, Pians lay special eggs, and from these eggs hatch hybrid Pians with characteristics of the enemy their parent contacted. Pians also have a secondary function: Depending on their mood, the tone of the music for that given level will change, with 20 total music variations present for each level in the game. If undisturbed, Pians naturally grow happy over time. However, if a Pian witnesses another being killed, they grow sad or angry.Many of the concepts included in Christmas NiGHTS were intended for this version of the game, and numerous features in Christmas NiGHTS can be used to analyze save files from the full version.A sequel known as "Air NiGHTS" was planned for the Dreamcast, but never came to fruition. Reportedly, the game would have used a gyroscopic motion sensor that slotted in to the Dreamcast's VMU port.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="4">Adventure</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre><genre id="43">Action-Adventure</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="33890">Rodea the Sky Soldier</game><game id="4161">NiGHTS: Journey of Dreams</game><game id="17085">Magic Carpet</game><game id="26839">Super Mario Galaxy 2</game><game id="16094">Super Mario Galaxy</game><game id="8139">Christmas NiGHTS into Dreams...</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2115069-box_nid.png</image></root>