<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9722</id><name>Donkey Kong Land 2</name><description>Donkey Kong Land 2 is the second game in the series starring              Diddy Kong and             Dixie Kong for the Nintendo Game Boy. Compared to the first            DKL title, DKL2 shares more in common to           Donkey Kong Country 2; it keeps the same storyline, worlds and level names, although the design and structure of the levels themselves has been changed so the game is not just a watered down port. The team-up mechanic which was introduced in DKC2 is missing here due to the Game Boy's limitations, but the Kongs' signature moves like Diddy's cartwheel and Dixie's helicopter spin have still been included, as have their animal buddies which still retain their charge-up "super moves" introduced in Donkey Kong Country 2.    Compared to the original, Donkey Kong Land 2 has smoother control and better proportioned sprites, but the level of detail with the visuals has been cut down, particularly with the sprites which seem to tear every now and then while playing. Playable StagesGangplank Galleon  Pirate PanicMainbrace MayhemGangplank GalleyLockjaw's LockerTopsail TroubleKrow's Nest (Boss) Krem Cauldron  Hot Head HopKannon's KlaimLava LagoonRedhot RideSquawks's ShaftBarrel BayouGlimmer's GalleonKrockhead KlamberRattle BattleSlime ClimbKleaver's Kiln (Boss) Krazy Kremland Hornet HoleTarget TerrorBramble BlastRickety RaceBramble ScrambleMudhole MarshRambi RumbleKing Zing Sting (Boss)Gloomy Gulch Ghostly GroveKrazy KoasterGusty GladeParrot Chute PanicWeb WoodsKreepy Krow (Boss)K.Rool's Keep Arctic AbyssWindy WellDungeon DangerClapper's CavernChain Link ChamberToxic TowerStronghold ShowdownThe Flying Krock  Screech's SprintK. Rool Duel (Boss)The Lost World (Klubba's Kiosk) Jungle JinxBlack Ice BattleFiery FurnaceKlobber KarnageAnimal AnticsKrocodile Kore (Boss)Differences to Donkey Kong Country 2 Overworld map has been flipped, as have most of the individual world maps.          Crocodile Cauldron and         Krem Quay have been joined together to create Krem Cauldron; some of their levels have been transfered to Krazy Kremland. As a result the boss of Krem Quay in DKC2,        Kudgel, does not make an appearance in this game.Lost World is accessed as an entire world from the overworld map, instead of having individual levels accessed from each of the worlds via Klubba's Kiosk.Removal of Swanky and       Cranky,      Wrinkly no longer gives out hintsNo team-up mechanic presentCharacters always transform into Animal buddies and cannot ride themDixie's ponytail whirl now allows the player to hit B in the air at any time before hitting the peak of their jumpWhile stages may have the same name as their SNES console counterparts, the level layout (and sometimes mechanics) are completely differentEnd of a level is marked by a stand-alone target with no prizes for good timingStages with water in them do not have dynamic water which raises and falls anymoreNot all music has been ported over, as such many of the different level archtypes share the same musicMusic has been remixed by     Grant Kirkhope (composer for Banjo-Kazooie and Viva Pinata) rather than by original composer    David WiseNo bonus stages are accessed via cannons with cannon balls, or by breaking through secret walls. All are found in bonus barrels.Only 47 Bonus or Krem Coins to collect instead of 75Cat O' Nine Tails enemy has been removedGlimmer's Galleon no longer features the angler fish Glimmer; instead you must touch various barrels to light up the stage for youIt's possible to complete the Rattle Battle stage without using Rattly the snake at allSlime Climb features toxic slime which hurts you upon touching it instead of containing a dangerous piranha (Snapjaw in Donkey Kong Country 2)Kleaver's Kiln fight utilises Krockheads that the player must use to cross to the other side of the battlefield instead of hooksHaunted Hall in  Gloomy Gulch has been replaced by a regular rollercoaster level called Krazy KoasterOnly need to scale one set of rigging ropes in Kreepy Krow fightIn King Zing Sting fight, King Zing never shoots barbs at you. It doesn't matter where you hit him with   Squawks the Parrot's nuts, and he won't make a barricade of Zingers around himself, only leave a trail of them behind him later in the fight instead.Animal Antics is now entirely a jungle level. K. Rool Duel is now set in a castle level, whereas Krocodile Kore fight is now set in a lava level</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre></genres><similar_games /><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/0/3948/1167190-197138_27868_front.jpg</image></root>