<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9761</id><name>Shadow Dancer: The Secret of Shinobi</name><description>Overview~ (Genesis/Megadrive)After bringing down the Neo Zeed organization. Joe Musashi found his skills weren't needed anymore. He went to New York city and spent some time with Kato, his former martial arts student.Musashi returned to his native land, refreshed and relaxed. Kato, meanwhile, heard that some nasty characters had taken over a local elementary school, and were holding the children as hostages. Naturally, he went to try and help the kids. What he found was shocking.Kato was severely wounded at the school, and was not expected to survive. When he got the news, Musashi raced back to New York. But before he could get to the hospital, Kato passed away, leaving nothing but memories and his faithful dog, Yamato. Overcome with grief and rage, Joe Musashi promised Kato's mother that he would avenge her son's death.Kato perished at the hands of one of the many Ninja warriors belonging to Union Lizard, a frighteningly vast and powerful group that took orders from a hideous, gigantic reptilian form. Since it could not communicate through words, the reptile's instinct guided it and many soldiers on a path that would result in world domination -- if no one stopped them. They've taken over New York, and are holding many terrified people hostage. Can you guide Joe Musashi and Yamato, the shinobi dog, through the ring of fire and triumph over this evil force?~Passage from the game manual.Yamato~ Musashi's Best Friend.Yamato, once the pet of Musashi's late friend Kato, now gives his loyalty to our hero. Yamato isn't just a spectator -- He'll lay down his very life for you!~Description of Yamato from the manual.Times when Yamato can't attack:-When there are no enemies on the screen.When Yamato and the enemies are on different floors.When an enemy Yamato was planning to assault suddenly jumps up or down to a different level. In this case, Yamato charges straight ahead, and after seeing that there's no one there, returns to his master's side.Levels~ (Genesis/Megadrive)Burning Down town- 1This level is set in Brooklyn, the boss of the level is; 'The Stomper!'.Battle on the Railway-2Set in a railway station, the boss of this level is; 'The Mirage!'.Statue of Liberty-3Set in the Liberty Statue, the boss of this level is; The Blade!'.In the Darkness-4Set in a terrifying cavern, the boss of this level is; 'The Wheel of FIre!'.The Reptile Sauros-5The lair of the game's ultimate protagonist 'Sauros'. Before fighting him though, you will have to pass a little test.NinjutsuThe three types of spells available:Fire - Columns of fire cook your enemies.Tornadoes - Two tornadoes join forces to blow your foes away!Meteorites - Meteorites fall from the sky like a killer rain.TriviaIn the original Japanese version, the protagonist was Joe's son Hayate. Western versions changed him to Joe for some reason.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="41">Platformer</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="3353">Rolling Thunder</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2412939-box_sdtsos.png</image></root>