<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9855</id><name>Soulcalibur III</name><description>Some old facesSoulcalibur III is the third installment in       Namco's       Soulcalibur fighting series. It's the only game to be exclusive for the Playstation 2. The game does not support online play, which many players had hoped for. You no longer get the character       Heihachi, who exclusively appeared in the Playstation 2 version of the previous game. This game was the first in the series to feature the ability to create your own custom characters. The game also has the largest character roster; 24 characters playable in the "Tales of Souls" mode, and an additional 18 playable in all other modes, and the largest battle stage selection in the series. The game also features a new RTS mode, which is also a first for the series.Playable Characters Starting Characters:       Zasalamel          Cassandra        Taki        Mitsurugi        Siegfried        Nightmare        Ivy        Astaroth        Voldo        Tira        Kilik        Xianghua        Maxi        Seung Mina         Yun-seong        Talim        Raphael        Setsuka  Unlockable Characters:        Yoshimitsu        Rock        Sophitia        Olcadan        Cervantes        Lizardman         Abyss  Bonus Characters:        Hwang         Amy        Li Long        Arthur        Revenant    Greed        Miser        Valeria        Hualin        Lynette        Abelia    Luna        Girardot        Chester        Demuth        Aurelia        Strife        Olcadan  Character Creation Create classes from Pirates to Ninjas.   Character Creation, known as Create-A-Soul, allows you to create a very customizable character. Everything down to the lip color is fully customizable. Your character can have a personality, a voice, a fighting style, and it will all be yours to come up with. The only thing missing from this is body build, which was not added due to hit detection complications.  After you choose a gender, you choose an occupation.   The character you create will have an occupation that you choose, which has a large role in what the character is like. Each occupation determines the different weapons and fighting styles that character will be able to choose, so choose the style you like best! More styles are unlockable later.  Occupations:  Barbarian A warrior from the frontier who refuses to rely on modern technology. Crushes the enemy with brute physical strength garnered from nature and a raw instinct for survival.     Monk An ascetic who fights with a body hardened from intense training under strict discipline. Has an iron will that refuses to back down from protecting their beliefs and path.   Thief Dweller of the night who travels the world in search of treasure. Fearless in pursuit of their objective, yet ever so cautious. Prefers to take the enemy by surprise.   Dancer A beautiful and graceful charmer who enchants the hearts of all. A body lithe from adventure and continuous training will turn even a battleground into a stage.   Saint A devotee of God who does not question good or evil of any deed under God's name. This otherwise gentle soul will bring down divine judgment on all heathens and blasphemers without mercy.   Ninja A shadow warrior from Japan who carries out the master's bidding with deadly precision. Ready to die in order to complete the master's mission.   Gladiator A fighter who descends into the heat of battle for fortune and glory. Overcomes all enemies with the power and fortitude cultivated in combat.   Pirate A fearless warrior of the sea. The power and cunningness that has won countless battles and vast riches over treacherous waters will lure all enemies to their underwater graves.   Samurai A warrior from Japan who has vowed fealty to the feudal master. Values faith and loyalty more than life. Proficient with marshal arts, and excels in sword fighting.   Assassin A hired killer who stalks in the night, willing to take a friend's life for the right price. The sheer artistry of the killings will entrall even the intended targets.  Several more such as Swordmaster and Sage are there too!Options: Here are the options you are able to customize:   All (selects from some preset options)  Head  Hair  Mask  Chin  Lower Torso  Mid Torso  Upper Torso  Arms  Shoulders  Neck  Waist  Lower Legs  Upper Legs  Socks  Feet  Face  Eyebrows  Lips  Eyes  Skin  Underwear   Voice  All of these options are fully customizable using one of 192 colors.  Original Character Customization:You can also customize original characters as well.   There are three, sometimes four, customizable parts per character. Which parts they are depend upon who they are. Each part's color can be changed to any of the 192 available colors. Don't like Cassandra with blond hair? Okay, make her a redhead!Tale of SoulsThe cutscenes look great!  SC2's one player Arcade mode had almost no story, except for the ending of each character's mode (which was done with a few illustrations and text.) There was one outcome, and no story while you were playing. All you did was fight people over and over until you beat the last one.  SC3's Tales of Souls mode, however, is nothing like this. It is a vast improvement. Every character gets a unique storyline, and you get to see where they go and how they get wrapped up into the main plot. Everybody's plot is all going on at once, so what you're doing is seeing the story from a different perspective; you're seeing where the character you chose went and what they did.  The adventure will follow the Soul Edge and Soulcalibur, the evil and good swords. During this adventure, there are many interactive cutscenes. These cutscenes will show your character's personality more. It will show how all the characters interact, meet, become friends, or become enemies. Also, this mode is not linear. If you play as the same character twice, different things will occur and the ending may change. For example, you may have to quickly input commands during the cut-scenes, like in Resident Evil 4. These events could alter the storyline.  There are also be a variety of challenges that give you one shot to beat a specific event, which could unlock some cool stuff. What's best about this is that you could play through the same character's game multiple times and see different things. This, combined with how many characters there are, allows you to have a great experience.Chronicles of the Sword  Introduction: This is the first Soul Calibur to feature an RTS element.   Chronicles of the Sword mode is a brand new mode for Soulcalibur III. It is a real time strategy mode that also has the classic Soulcalibur fighting added with it. You play as your own CAS character (or others the game gives you), and use strategy to defeat the opposing armies and to clear your objectives.    As you keep playing your character gains more experience and gets more powerful. You choose how to direct your men (and women) into combat. You can make units. Not only are you playing in a brand new story, but the classic characters, such as Mitsurugi, can show up as well here and there.  Story:   This is yet another tale of souls and swords...Player Devolopment     Once, there existed on a great continent three countries--    The Grandall Empire, the Kingdom of Dalkia, and the Halteese Republic.    The Kingdom of Dalkia and the Halteese Republic waged a great war against one another for countless years. The Grandall Empire stayed out of the   conflict, amassing their army quietly. Then, the impasse was suddenly broken as the Dalkian Kingdom declared war on Grandall Empire. Amidst the conflict and conspiracy, a new republic, Maletta, emerged...    At the time, the great tactician Chester, who instigated the conflict which later came to be known as the Mantis War, had no yet appeared in the annals of history. And the individual who was to be a key figure in the war was a mere cadet in the Grandall army...        Prologue  Chosen by history, a man becomes a hero.  Engraved into history, a hero becomes a legend.  --14th century troubadour song   Transcending history and the world, a tale of souls and swords, eternally retold.  --A story from the end of the Middle Ages, author unknown  Some call it the ultimate sword. Some described it as a demon sword in which a powerful spiritual power dwelt. Some said it was the sword of heroes, the savior of kingdoms... Numerous rumors and legends surrounded Soul Edge, but its true nature was that of a cursed sword that devoured human souls.   It was originally a single sword created by the hand of man. It was merely a warrior's tool, possessing no will of its own. But the sword bathed in the blood and hatred of countless battles throughout its dark history, and eventually came to emit an evil aura. It learned to devour souls as it rest the flesh of men, and its power steadily increased. In one age, a hero acquired Soul Edge. With his iron will, he controlled the sword freely and brought peace to the violent land. He was revered as a king. In any age, however, there are those who resent great men. The one who took Soul Edge out of envy was none other than the king's own son. Sadly, his soul stolen, he became a puppet to the sword's dark will. The king fought against his son. At the end of their fearsome battle, the king's desperate blow shattered Soul Edge, but also took the life of his son.  When the chaos subsided, the source of the conflict, Soul Edge, had disappeared. The king was tormented by remorse. Most would have submitted to the overwhelming grief, but the king did no such thing. The abominable Soul Edge would certainly appear again, bringing tragedy with it. This ill omen steeled the king's resolve. For the sake of the world as well as his own redemption, he vowed to create a holy sword that could fight against the evil blade's powers. With the aid of the greatest sage of the era, the king began work on his grand plan. Purifying fragments of the cursed sword that he still had, the king finally succeeded in creating the holy sword, Soul Calibur. But it cost him his life. A sect of guardians was created to carry out the late king's will. These guardians lived in seclusion, passing down the sword secretly from generation to generation in preparation for the day when Soul Edge would unleash its fury. Each time the sword fell back into the hands of powerful warriors and those with evil intentions, Soul Calibur appeared to prevent the cursed weapon from committing unspeakable atrocities. Stories of the never-ending struggle between the two swords were passed on from one generation to another, giving birth to countless legends and fairly tales.  Time passed, and it was now the end of the sixteenth century.  Over the long years, the two swords had increased their power. Now, they had appeared once again upon the stage of history. During the course of their conflict, Soul Edge was shattered and Soul Calibur was contaminated with evil energy. The will of the cursed sword appeared to have burned out, but in reality, it had merely been reduced to a smoldering ember. The life of the holy sword, too, was thought to have withered and died, but it was quietly burbling like a spring at the bottom of a deep abyss. Even now, the ancient swords were awaiting the change to regain their true power. There was a young knight who had been controlled not merely once but several times by the evil sword. When he broke that curse and stabbed through the heart of the cursed weapon with the holy sword, the gears of fate began to creak into motion. A new page would soon be written in the tale of the two swords, opposite in power and bound by destiny... Hear with your ears the best things; look upon them with clear-seeing thought, for decision between the two Beliefs, each man for himself before the Great sonummation, bethinking you that it be accomplished to our pleasure. SoundtrackDisc One  1. "Hour of Destiny"   運命の満つる時へ 3:50   2. "Lorekeeper"   伝承は語る 1:24   3. "History Reckons"   歴史の舞台へのいざない 1:33   4. "Fearless Eyes"   その瞳に恐れの色なし 2:33   5. "Call of the Ancients"   古の呼び声 2:20   6. "Time Marches"   刻まれゆく時の果て 2:23   7. "Wings of Despair"   翼持つ死の遣い 1:40   8. "The Blade Seeker"   死線を征く者 3:01   9. "Pure Breeze"   穢れ無き風の調べ 2:07   10. "Face Your Fate"   目を逸らさずに 2:14   11. "Confrontation"   対決 2:30   12. "The Evil Moon"   禍月の夜 2:35   13. "Bred from the Gap"   狭間より湧き出でし者 1:49   14. "Sail Over the Storm"   荒海を超えて 2:44   15. "Blind Loyalty"   迷い無き忠誠 2:36   16. "The Cursed Image"   呪われし心象 2:13   17. "The New Legend"   新たなる伝説 2:10   18. "Labyrinth of Moonlight"   月光の迷宮 3:36   19. "Through Molten Caves"   灼熱の地脈を抜けて 2:34   20. "No Regrets"   悔いることなき道行き 3:08   21. "Ephemeral Dream"   儚く散るが故に 2:18   22. "Endless Warfare"   果て知らぬ野望 2:32   23. "Water Dance"   たゆたう水の舞 2:53   24. "Courage Ablaze"   炎より勇なる者 2:12   25. "Beyond the Horizon"   地平線の果てに 2:40   26. "If There Were Any Other Way"   非情なる運命の絆 1:51   27. "Forsaken Sanctuary"   忘れられし約束の地 2:05   28. "Catastrophe"   滅びの宴 2:08   29. "World Distortion"   歪み崩れゆく世界 2:10 Disc Two  1. "Tales of Souls"   ある魂の遍歴 1:25   2. "Eternal Wayfarer"   広大なる世界を巡り 1:27   3. "The Ordeal"   試練の旅路 1:21   4. "The Intruder"   聖域侵犯 1:21   5. "Under a Black Curse"   黒き呪詛を辿って 2:43   6. "Tenderness"   ぬくもりの記憶 0:45   7. "The Oath"   明日への誓い 1:00   8. "Teardrops"   哀しみの雫 0:46   9. "Gaze from Hell"   煉獄の凝視 0:46   10. "Crisis"   迫り来る危機 0:31   11. "Frailty, Thy Name Is..."   弱き者、汝の名は… 2:38   12. "Fatal Chain"   断ち切れぬ鎖 0:57   13. "Tiptoe"   抜き足差し足 0:31   14. "Peaceful Days"   安らぎの中に 2:46   15. "Memento"   想い出の欠片 0:52   16. "Armed with Valor"   その身に纏うは武勇の装束 1:27   17. "Battle for the Crown"   栄冠を求めて 1:35   18. "The Gemstones"   英雄の原石たち 0:56   19. "Radiant Souls"   煌めく魂の諸相 1:45   20. "The Lost Chronicle"   失われた年代記 1:06   21. "The Die is Cast"   賽は投げられた 1:58   22. "Approaching Tempest"   争嵐の予兆――出撃 1:23   23. "Symphony of Swords"   剣たちの奏でる戦律 2:47   24. "Nameless Calamity"   名も無き戦火 4:55   25. "Upon My Soul"   この宿命に誓って 3:08   26. "Crimson Feast"   血戦 4:43   27. "The Hollow Delusion"   虚妄の帳 3:26   28. "Value of Tranquility"   平和の価値 1:12   29. "Path of Destiny"   運命は己が胸の内に 6:31   30. "Healing Winds"   戦士を癒す風 3:25   31. "Peaceful Days (Piano Version)"   安らぎの中に（ピアノバージョン） 2:58   32. "The Oath (Guitar Version)"   明日への誓い 0:57   33. "Healing Winds: Reprise"   戦士を癒す風 2:00</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="2">Strategy</genre><genre id="9">Fighting</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="21375">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja 3</game><game id="10162">Tekken Tag Tournament</game><game id="2895">Battle Arena Toshinden 3</game><game id="11958">EOE: Eve of Extinction</game><game id="3839">Dead or Alive</game><game id="5238">Battle Arena Toshinden</game><game id="9603">Star Wars: Masters of Teräs Käsi</game><game id="19043">Fighters Megamix</game><game id="22292">Dead or Alive 2: Hardcore</game><game id="7792">Dead or Alive 4</game><game id="3744">Def Jam: Fight for NY</game><game id="18288">Last Bronx</game><game id="16110">Resurrection: Rise 2</game><game id="721">Ehrgeiz: God Bless the Ring</game><game id="16842">Street Fighter: Anniversary Collection</game><game id="13753">Dead or Alive Ultimate</game><game id="16172">Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</game><game id="12411">Soulcalibur</game><game id="8673">Fighter Destiny 2</game><game id="23220">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja</game><game id="23007">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja Heroes</game><game id="21582">Naruto Shippuuden: Gekitou Ninja Taisen! EX 2</game><game id="707">Virtua Fighter 5</game><game id="4891">Virtua Fighter 4: Evolution</game><game id="4313">Virtua Fighter 4</game><game id="20689">Tekken 6</game><game id="11189">Tekken 3</game><game id="10387">Tekken 2</game><game id="14684">Tekken 4</game><game id="18753">Tekken 5</game><game id="11606">Tekken: Dark Resurrection</game><game id="11822">Soulcalibur II</game><game id="16690">Def Jam: Icon</game><game id="2410">Def Jam: Vendetta</game><game id="10476">War Gods</game><game id="21195">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai Tenkaichi 3</game><game id="22305">Street Fighter III: 2nd Impact</game><game id="21948">Street Fighter III: New Generation</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2126450-box_sc3.png</image></root>