<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9989</id><name>Hellgate: London</name><description>OverviewHellgate: London is a 3rd-person dungeon crawler with randomly generated areas. Hellgate gives you access to a wide arsenal of futuristic weaponry, including machine guns, rocket launchers, and sniper rifles, in addition to the usual assortment of swords, magic, and minion summoning, to utilize to free London from the grasp of Satan.The game was developed by Flagship Studios, a company founded by Bill Roper, Max and Erich Schaefer, and David Brevik which were the core executive team from Blizzard North, the company that produced the original Diablo game. The game was several year in development and very hyped when it was released, not the least by the company itself. And although it wasn't a bad game according to the critics, it was generally accepted that it didn't live up to the expectations and was therefore a failure. It also led to the demise of Flagship Studios.GameplayIn Hellgate: London you can play three classes:Templar; a melee oriented characterCabalist: the modern version of the mageHunter: the rangerEach of these classes could evolve into a further specialized class which gave you additional skills and bonuses.The game could be played in either 3rd-person view for all classes or first-person view for the Cabalist and Hunter classes. The game consists of 6 mayor area's to play (acts in the game) and each act takes more than 20 hours to complete.The battleground of the game is London, both underground and in the streets of London. Well known metro stations act as safe area's and in which the character can pick up missions. The player has then to travel through the tubes to other stations or streetlevel to accomplish these quests that most of the time consists of 'slay x monsters' or 'pick up x at y'.Loot is one of the key gameplay features of Hellgate London, and you will be gathering a lot of it. In the metro stations all kind of stores are willing to buy your loot and sell other equipment and upgrades. Later in the game you can access upgrade stations to enhance your weapons: the modern version of socketing.Free To PlayHellgate: London has gone free to play in 2010 and is avalible in Korea as well as the US. General gameplay is free for anyone that makes an account, and can purchase the publishers MTX (Micro Transaction) currency Tcoins at a going rate of $1 USD for 1000 Tcoins.In game premium purchases involving Tcoins include thing like higher percentage of XP gain for a set amount of time, extra inventory space, access to later chapters of the storyline, and other bonuses that player who do not pay extra for cannot obtain.PatchesBefore it was disbanded Flagship released many small bug fixing and balancing related patches but they also released a downloadable content expansion named the Stonehedge Chronicles. Hanbitsoft has released other patches for Hellgate: London. Until 2010, patches were only available in Korea.Legal Issues and DissolutionIn 2008, financial issues at Flagship Studios led to the firing of most employees at the studio. Development of Flagship's then-upcoming Action-RPG, Mythos, was discontinued and delayed any updates that would be coming to Hellgate: London. Korean company, Hanbitsoft took over development of Hellgate: London and as of 2010 possess the rights for distribution in the United States and Europe.SoundtrackThe music for the game was done by Cris Velasco and Sascha Dikiciyan and released on CD format.Into the RiftFight for the CryptsRespiteThe Dawn of WarBedlamInto the DepthsClosing InLostAmbushRemember the DeadThe Covent GardensFor the LivingHellgate LondonPC System RequirementsMinimum:Windows XP/Vista1GB RAM7.0GB Hard Disk SpaceDirectX 9.0c128MB ATI Radeon 9000/Nvidia GeForce 6200 Video CardDirectX 9.0c Compatible Sound Card8X DVD-ROM Drive</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="5">Role-Playing</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="17494">Guild Wars</game><game id="1119">Diablo II</game><game id="5985">Diablo</game><game id="20803">Diablo III</game><game id="15589">Diablo II: Lord of Destruction</game><game id="20499">Too Human</game><game id="11082">Guild Wars: Nightfall</game><game id="20612">Space Siege</game><game id="20900">The Agency</game><game id="500">The Thing</game><game id="20532">Legendary</game><game id="20690">Left 4 Dead</game><game id="12134">Wasteland</game><game id="10746">Shadow Man</game><game id="8638">Titan Quest</game><game id="13762">Titan Quest: Immortal Throne</game><game id="1727">Dungeon Siege II</game><game id="2059">Dungeon Siege</game><game id="9953">Neverwinter Nights</game><game id="9061">Neverwinter Nights 2</game><game id="20989">CrimeCraft</game><game id="24057">Demon's Souls</game><game id="23275">Fallen Earth</game><game id="29717">E.Y.E: Divine Cybermancy</game><game id="32580">Firefall</game><game id="34531">Mission Europa</game><game id="36055">Borderlands 2</game><game id="35560">Warrior's Lair</game><game id="29339">Hellgate: Tokyo</game><game id="31832">Konung III: Ties of the Dynasty</game><game id="20487">Borderlands</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2098000-box_hellgatel.png</image></root>