<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><id>9993</id><name>Halo 3</name><description>OverviewMaster Chief, ready to "finish the fight".Halo 3 is a sci-fi first-person shooter developed by Bungie and published by Microsoft for the Xbox 360 on September 25, 2007 (later re-released through Games on Demand on April 20, 2010). The third game in the Halo franchise (and the last in the original Halo trilogy, after Halo 2), Halo 3 continues the story of the SPARTAN-II super-soldier known as Master Chief and concludes the events of the Human-Covenant War.After escaping the Flood-infested Covenant space station High Charity via boarding the ancient ship (the Forerunner Dreadnaught) of the main antagonist (the Prophet of Truth), the Master Chief disembarks from the ship as it lands in eastern Africa. With the help of both the United Nations Space Command (mainly by Sergeant Major Avery Johnson, Commander Miranda Keyes, and Fleet Admiral Terrence Hood) and the Sangheili (mainly by The Arbiter), Master Chief must defend Earth from the remaining forces of the Prophet of Truth while both preventing Truth from activating the entire Halo array and figuring out how to end the Flood infestation, once and for all.Halo 3 has brought various additions and changes to Halo 2's gameplay mechanics. The MA5-series Assault Rifle makes a return as the Master Chief's weapon of choice (while players can also use the powerful Spartan Laser, and various new Jiralhanae weapons, such as the Spike and Firebomb Grenades, the close-ranged Gravity Hammer, the Mauler, and the Spike Rifle). Players can now use separate buttons (defaulting to the "bumper" buttons) to reload each dual-wielded weapon (in which the secondary reload button doubles as switching grenades, if the player is not dual-wielding). Players can also carry and deploy (using the button originally used to reload) special portable "equipment" (including trip mines, gravitational lifts, and bubble shield generators). Players can also now detach stationary turrets for portable use (albeit slower movement speeds and forced third-person perspective). The game also includes new vehicles, including the UNSC's mobile transport Mongoose and the Brute's attack motorbike Chopper.The game also includes various improvements to Halo 2's multiplayer aspect. Players can now customize the armor permutations (including helmet, shoulders, and torso) for both their Spartan and Elite soldiers (each of which must be earned by completing goals and achievements throughout the game). Players can now be easily identified by their allies in-game through a custom Service Tag (composed of a letter followed by two numbers). Halo 3 includes a more robust matchmaking system with the TrueSkill ranking system, a new experience system (with a special ranking system in which players can earn different "grades" depending on their TrueSkill rank and experience points), special playlists (including playlists that grant double experience points), and the option to veto the first given map/gametype combination. The game now includes a special Theater Mode (where players can watch game replays and crop them into smaller film clips or take screenshots) and Forge Mode (a unique in-game map editor where players can alter the placement of any weapon, spawn, item, or structure on any map) While the clan system from Halo 2 was removed, Halo 3 includes a new File Share system, in which players can upload custom gametype variants, film clips, screenshots, and "Forged" map variants into Bungie's servers, so that they can be downloaded by other players.Bungie later created a standalone campaign, running on a heavily modified Halo 3 engine, titled Halo 3: ODST. Players play as an Orbital Drop Shock Trooper known as The Rookie, who must investigate the whereabouts of his squad in the dark, dead city of New Mombasa (shortly after the events of Halo 2). Along with several new gameplay mechanics (including the VISR night-vision visor, silenced weapons, an open-world hub level, a new "stamina" system, and the introduction of the co-operative wave-based survival mode known as Firefight), the game also includes a bonus disc containing the entire multiplayer component of Halo 3 (featuring all downloadable maps, including three time-exclusive maps known as the Mythic II Map Pack). Players who completed all seven Vidmaster achievements (from both games) received a special piece of multiplayer armor: the Recon Armor (formerly given by Bungie to exceptional community players, given to all players regardless of achievement progress after March 29, 2012).GameplayMechanicsOne of tens of thousands of multiplayer armour permutations.The gameplay in Halo 3 has undergone some significant changes compared to its predecessors, including simple tweaks to make it more cohesive. You may now carry "equipment," which can range from a portable gravity lift, allowing the player to lift himself into the air, to a bubble-shield, which will spawn a clear, protective bubble around whoever decides to throw it down, as well as deployable cover, which projects a small blue defense shield, as well as many others. Bungie has assigned these special abilities to the "X" button, which was previously used to reload. Players now use the RB (right bumper) to reload the main weapon and LB for the secondary weapon if they are dual-wielding, although they can decide to use one of several other pre-made control schemes.The Load-OutA player brandishing the Recon Armor, formerly given to exceptional community members.Bungie has added a different version of the original Assault Rifle (it has about half the clip size of the version in Halo: Combat Evolved, but it deals a little more damage and has better accuracy), strengthened the Needler (though it can no longer be dual-wielded), and also included some new weapons like the Spikers (Brute sub-machine guns) and the Gravity Hammer (the Brute counterpart of the Elite Energy Sword). There are also 2 new grenade classes: The Spike Grenade and the Incendiary Grenade (AKA the firebomb grenade). The former is a Brute-made grenade that sticks to objects before sending razor-sharp spikes flying in the direction of the blast, and the latter a UNSC weapon especially useful against the zombie-like Flood. Bungie also reduced the load-out on each grenade from the previous four, to two, allowing players to carry a total of eight grenades and switch between the types with the left bumper (when not dual-wielding). A player may also pick up turrets and flamethrowers, but by using them he/she will switch into a 3rd person view, in which movement will be slightly restricted and ammo will become limited. There are also a few new vehicles like the Mongoose, a quadbike with two seats, the Hornet, which is the human equivalent to the Banshee, and the Chopper, which resembles the Ghost in that it has only one seat and can fire front-mounted cannons. One final new vehicle, the Elephant, is an enormous, invincible mobile base armed with two turrets. The Elephant appears only in the multiplayer level 'Sand Trap', and serves as each team's flag base in Capture the Flag mode, allowing players to actually move their flag around the level, albeit at a painfully slow pace.MultiplayerMultiplayer gameplay on the Mythic map, "Assembly"Halo 3's campaign can be played co-operatively, locally, through System Link, and online on Xbox Live with up to four players, although only two players may play on a single Xbox 360. Unlike previous games, which just doubled the primary character, each player in Halo 3 is given a unique character; player one controls the Master Chief, player two controls the Arbiter (with small changes to the dialogue and cutscenes to reflect the fact that the Arbiter never leaves the Chief) and players three and four controlling unique Elites, who never speak and do not show up in cutscenes, though Bungie has named them N'tho 'Sraom and Usze 'Taham, respectively. In addition, Halo 3 can also be played competitively through a matchmaking service or in custom, user-created games. In matchmaking, players are matched with up to fifteen other players based on their rank and skill level in the individual "playlists", which are categorized into two groups depending on their overall purpose. Ranked playlists are used to match players based on their Trueskill rating. Social playlists allow players to play with others with no ranking system involved for each playlist, although Experience and overall skill still determines player match-ups. Few of the original achievements work in social matches, but the DLC achievements all are unlockable in social playlists. One can also still earn Experience for the playlists, as well as global and playlist-specific Experience points (EXP). Finally, every weekend, Double Experience Weekend begins that focus on a very specific playstyle or gametype, including Grifball and Infection. The playlists are:RankedLone Wolves-Matches include 6 players and use free-for-all game modes, like Slayer, Swords, Slayer BRs, Crazy King, and Oddball.Team Slayer-Matches are team-based and usually include 6 or 8 players in 3-on-3 or 4-on-4 games. Modes played are Team Slayer, Team BRs, Team Snipers, and Shotty Snipers.Team Doubles- 2-on-2 matches with both Slayer and Objective gametypes, including Team Slayer, Team BRs, Team Snipers, Team Oddball, Team Crazy King, Multi-Flag CTF and One FlagMLG- A playlist using MLG-created maps and MLG versions of Team Slayer, Team Ball, Team Hill and Multi-Flag.Squad battle 6-on-6 matches with slayer and flag variantsSWAT-A hardcore playlist involving the use of no energy shields and no motion trackers, and using only Battle Rifle/Magnum combos, just Magnums, or just Shotguns. Most games are simply SWAT, SWAT Magnums, or ShWATguns, but as of an update, SWATball and 2-flag CTF are also used as gametypes.Team Snipers-3-on-3 and 4-on-4 games in Slayer-based gametypes such as Team Snipers, Shotty Snipers and Team Splasers.SocialGameplay of multiplayer map, "Avalanche"Rumble Pit-Much like Lone Wolves, but in a social setting. Uses Slayer and "Fiesta" variants such as Slayer, Hammerzeit, Swords, Juggernaut, Oddball, Crazy King, Ninja Ball and Mosh Pit.Social Big Team-Uses 5-on-5 and 8-on-8 matches. Gametypes played include Team Slayer, Multi-Flag CTF, One Bomb, VIP, Territories, Big Splockets, Land Grab, and 2 Flag Heavy CTF.Social Slayer-5-on-5 and solo gametypes, such as Team Slayer/Slayer, Team Rockets/Rockets, Team Duals/Duals, and Team BRs/Slayer BRs.Social Skirmish-4-on-4 and 5-on-5 non-slayer matches. Gametypes are One Flag CTF, Multi-Flag CTF, One Bomb Assault, Neutral Bomb Assault, VIP, Territories, and Land Grab.Multi-Team- Uses four teams of 2 in gametypes like Team Slayer, Team Hammers, Team Swords, VIP, Team Oddball, and Team Crazy King.Action Sack- Random 8 player matches offering 0 EXPTeam Mythic-Much like team slayer but the Halo 3 Mythic disc is required.In custom mode players can play multiplayer matches using custom game modes, settings, and maps. All modes and maps are available to play on and can be changed between matches by the party leader. Players must invite friends to play these games, however.MapsHalo 3 shipped with 11 maps, and subsequently released 5 DLC bundles throughout the games life. The Heroic map pack adds three maps for free, Legendary adds 3 more for $10, Mythic adds an additional 3 for $10, Mythic II adds another 3 for $10 (or free if you bought ODST new), and Cold Storage adds one map for free.ConstructConstructConstruct is a map for 2-8 players (10 after they changed the max player count for Social Slayer) with no vehicles. It is a simple 3 leveled map which uses grav lifts as elevators. The main power weapon on this map is the Energy Sword which is found at the far end of the map on the third level.EpitaphEpitaphEpitaph is probably the smallest map of the original group. This map is never played in Social Slayer because 8 (10 post patch) players is simply too much for this map. The two-levelled map has a Gravity Hammer, Shotgun, and Rocket Launcher for power weapons. Generally used in Team Doubles because 4 players is the right size for this map.GuardianGuardianAnother simple map for Social Slayer game types. This is the most symmetrical of the small maps in the game, making it a common choice for people to use for 1 v 1 matches. A spiritual successor to Halo 2's Lockout, the changes made to it to make it a more compact map with ease of use for melee started a movement of people in the first few months of the games launch to constantly veto it whenever it game up. This happens even more so now with the release of Blackout (a Lockout remake) as part of the Legendary map pack.High GroundHigh GroundThe first map in the game with vehicles, High Ground is a popular choice for One Flag, One Bomb, and other objective types due to the two oppositely balanced sides. The high ground team spawns next to a sniper tower with a Spartan Laser, and a couple of Mongooses for quick transportation. While the low ground spawns at the beach, next to a Ghost and the Sniper Rifle. This is a key map for the "One" objective types because it switches both teams between sides during each round.IsolationIsolationIsolation is a pretty symmetrical map made for Attack and Defend game types and Slayer types. The upper outdoor grassy level features a few Mongooses to get around, along with a Shotgun in the barricade in the center. The underground is where the map starts to really differentiate between other maps. Underground there are two large man cannons on each side to launch players back up the the main level. A Ghost in the middle for main vehicular control of the map. And a Rocket Launcher next to the Ghost.RanksReaching different ranks requires the player to gain certain amounts of EXP and, for officer ranks, reach different skill levels. Skill levels are increased when the player wins ranked games. EXP is gained from simply winning games which can be either ranked or unranked. One EXP is gained from winning a game, zero is gained from losing a game and one EXP is lost for quitting out of a game early. The Ranks in increasing order are:Recruit grade 1Apprentice Grade 1, Apprentice Grade 2Private Grade 1, Private Grade 2Corporal Grade 1, Corporal Grade 2Sergeant Grade 1, Sergeant Grade 2, Sergeant Grade 3Gunnery Sergeant Grade 1, Gunnery Sergeant Grade 2, Master Gunnery SergeantLieutenant Grade 1, Lieutenant Grade 2, Lieutenant Grade 3, First LieutenantCaptain Grade 1, Captain Grade 2, Captain Grade 3, Staff CaptainMajor Grade 1, Major Grade 2, Major Grade 3, Field MajorCommander Grade 1, Commander Grade 2, Commander Grade 3, Strike CommanderColonel Grade 1, Colonel Grade 2, Colonel Grade 3, Force ColonelBrigadier Grade 1, Brigadier Grade 2, Brigadier Grade 3, Brigadier GeneralGeneral Grade 1, General Grade 2, General Grade 3, 5 Star GeneralUser-Generated ContentForgeMain Article: ForgeWith the addition of the new Forge mode, any Halo 3 owner can completely customize every Halo 3 multiplayer map. From vehicle and weapon placement to fusion coils and equipment placement, just about everything the player can use and interact with on a map can be moved, tweaked, and adjusted to the player's liking. Once completed, all forged maps can be put on the player's file share and uploaded to Bungie.net were other players can download, comment, tag, and share their creations over the Internet. The recent maps Foundry (From the Heroic Map Pack) and Sandbox (From the Mythic Map Pack) were made specifically to cater to users of Forge. Many forging communities have arisen in the wake of these two maps releases, creating a massive number of user-generated maps. Bungie has recently taken notice of this user-generated content and has incorporated several Forge maps created in Foundry and Sandbox into both Ranked and Social matchmaking. Bungie has also regularly featured maps created by the community in their weekly updates and included interviews with their creators. A few special features of the Forge have been included in recent map packs as well, from different color affects to the Killball.TheaterThe Theater is a powerful tool allowing the viewing and saving of previously played campaign missions and multiplayer matches. The system used to create the video allows the video to maintain a size of mere kilobytes. The Theater can be used to take screenshots, save film clips, and save whole films. The camera in the Theater is not limited to a body either. The camera can be moved to any player or free-floated anywhere in the map, allowing for interesting angles and screenshots.ScreenshotsA User Created ScreenshotWith the use of theater mode, users can take screenshots of their favorite moments and upload them to Bungie.net. There, players can also comment, rate, and download other users' screenshots. Bungie has used screenshots uploaded to Bungie.net in their Weekly updates.Saved FilmsWhile watching a match in Theater, people can save entire custom and matchmaking games or cut out specific parts to make video clips. These videos can then be watched through Theater by anyone who has downloaded the file from the user's File Share. Plus, as the Theater records gameplay information and not video, matches can be viewed from any angle. Unfortunately, for the same reason, the Theater clips cannot be viewed online (although the Bungie Pro Video feature alleviates this problem, see below), although you can set a video to download the next time you play Halo 3.File ShareThe File Share is available for every Halo 3 user and allows them to upload their files for others to view and download at no cost. These slots can include Films, Film Clips, Screenshots, Map Variants, Gametypes or any combination. The standard capacity for the File Share is six slots and/or 25MB, although this can be upgraded to 24 slots and 250MB via the pay service called Bungie Pro (see below).Bungie ProBungie Pro enables a number of premium features to the Halo 3 user, including an expansion of storage for your Halo 3 File Share (see above) and the ability to use Bungie Pro Video (see below). A 12-Month Bungie Pro subscription can be purchased over Xbox Live for 750 MS Points. At the end of the subscription, you'll be asked to whether you want to renew or your subscription or not. For a limited time, a trial of Bungie Pro was given as a gift to people who downloaded the Legendary Map Pack or Mythic Map Pack. The trial lasted roughly 4 months.Bungie Pro VideoAs of now Bungie Pro comes bundled with Bungie Pro Video. Bungie Pro Video allows you take your game film clips (which, as they are purely game data, require Halo 3 to be viewed) and turn them into videos you can watch on your computer using the .wmv format. Users are allowed 5 render minutes a month, which expire at the end of the month. Bungie has stated that users will soon be able to buy render minutes using the File Share menu at 10 minutes for 100 MSP ($1.25).SkullsA Halo 3 SkullHuman skulls can be found tucked away in odd corners of the Halo 3 campaign. Each one has some kind of effect on the game that can be turned on or off at the beginning of a play session. In doing so, Bungie has expanded the original skulls "Easter Egg" from Halo 2. In Halo 3, when you find a skull you can turn it on and off at will, as opposed to having to start a new save to turn it off. There are four "silver skulls" which don't give an achievement but go towards unlocking the Hayabusa armor, and nine "gold skulls" which each have their own achievement and go towards unlocking the Hayabusa armor.Silver SkullsCowbell Skull - Makes explosions larger.Grunt Birthday Party Skull - When Grunts are shot in the head, their head explodes and confetti flies out. There is also the sound of children cheering.IWHBYD Skull - Activates new, often humorous dialogue in the game.Blind Skull - Removes your reticule, shield bar, ammo count, etc. from your HUD.Gold SkullsCatch Skull - Makes enemies use grenades more often and also drop more when you kill them. Friendly units will also throw grenades more often.Iron Skull - If playing the campaign singleplayer, death will send the player back to the beginning of the level. In co-op, the death of a single player takes all players back to the last checkpoint, similarly to playing Halo 2 on the Legendary difficulty.Black Eye Skull - Your shields don't recharge unless you melee attack enemies.Tough Luck Skull - Enemies are better at dodging explosions and vehicles.Fog Skull - Removes your motion sensor.Famine Skull - Makes dropped weapons supply you with less ammo. This does not include weapons on weapon racks or certain weapons "planted" by Bungie for the player to use.Thunderstorm Skull - Enemies' ranks are higher. Higher ranked enemies take more damage.Tilt Skull - Enemies are more resistant to certain weapons. Even ordinarily, plasma weapons deal more damage to energy shields than to flesh, while the opposite is true for bullet-based weapons. With the skull on, shielded enemies will take dramatically less damage from bullet weapons and unshielded enemies will take dramatically less damage from plasma weapons. This includes vehicle weapons, such that a Plasma Rifle can take down a Brute's shields before a Warthog LAAG turret can, but this is much less noticeable in a tank.Mythic Skull - Enemies have double health.Guides are available on Giant Bomb to aid in locating each skull. Additionally, six more skulls were can be found in each multiplayer map added in the downloadable Mythic Map Pack, and also in the three maps be packed in with Halo 3: ODST, with one skull per map. These skulls do not have any effects, and their only benefit is the Vidmaster achievement for finding all of them (meaning they are therefore required to achieve the coveted Recon armor).Multiplayer Map SkullsAssembly Skull - This skull is located in the center of the map, up top, in between the big purple arm and the middle post. As with all the Mythic skulls, you must be in Forge to obtain it.Orbital Skull - This skull is located above the pit in the middle of the map, it is a few floors up and hidden under and overhang. As with all the Mythic skulls, you must be in Forge to obtain it.Sandbox Skull - This skull is located at the back of the dunes, in between the guardians towers. There are many custom maps you can download with the towers shut off so you can just fly out and grab it. As with all the Mythic skulls, you must be in Forge to obtain it.Citadel SkullHeretic SkullLongshore SkullDownloadable ContentHalo 3 has seen four Map Packs released for the game since its September 2007 launch, which are the Heroic Map Pack (initially 600 MS points, now free), Legendary Map Pack (600 MS Points), the standalone map Cold Storage (free), and the first and second half of the Mythic Map Pack (800 MS Points).Heroic Map PackThe Heroic Map Pack was released on December 11th, 2007 and included the three new maps:FoundryFoundryA medium-sized map with a focus on team-based gametypes, made from the ground-up for Forge Mode; every single object in the level can be deleted and rearranged in an innumerable number of combinations.Rat's NestRat's Nest Based on Crow's Nest, the second level in Halo 3's campaign, Rat's Nest is a medium-sized symmetrical map with a focus on vehicular combat and large-scale objective game types. In a nod to the name, actual rats were placed around the level, but they were found to be distracting during gameplay because they triggered players' motion sensors. In the final version of the map, rats are still present, but all of them are dead, and therefore immobile.StandoffStandoffA medium-large map, set near a Satellite Base in New Mombasa, ideal for medium-sized objective games.Legendary Map PackThe Legendary Map Pack was released on April 15th, 2008 and included the three new maps:AvalancheAvalancheA large, vehicle-focused map inspired by Halo: Combat Evolved's Sidewinder, Avalanche is set on a snowy shelf of the partially completed spare Halo seen at the end of Halo 3's campaign. Each of the vehicles was given a new wintery look for the map.BlackoutBlackoutA small, asymmetrical map that is a remake of Halo 2's Lockout. Made, like Lockout, specifically for FFA and small team-based gametypes. Bungie took great efforts to make Blackout an exact recreation of the Halo 2 map, even going as far as to recreate the "ability" to launch the Sniper Rifle across the map via shooting the nearby fusion coil. Referred to in updates by the deliberately silly name "John Carpenter's Prince of Dorkness".Ghost TownGhost TownA medium-sized base assault map, set in the jungle of Sierra-117, the first level in Halo 3's campaign.Cold Storage Map PackThe Cold Storage Map Pack was released on July 7th, 2008 and included a single map. It was a "gift" from Bungie to its fans for Bungie Day '08 (July 7, 2008). Cold Storage is technically considered Legendary tier, meaning that to play it in matchmaking you must have the Legendary map pack as well.Cold StorageCold StorageA faithful remake of Halo: Combat Evolved's Chill Out, Cold Storage is a small, claustrophobic map used primarily for Slayer and Oddball gametypes.Mythic Map Pack (First Half)First alluded to in the achievements Title Update 2 added, the Mythic Map Pack consists of six maps, with three bundled in with the Halo Wars Limited Edition and released onto Xbox Live Marketplace April 9th, 2009, and 3 to be bundled with Halo 3: ODST, along with every other map. Unlike with all other multiplayer maps, the Mythic Map Pack will contain six hidden skulls, with one per map. The skulls go toward unlocking the "Vidmaster" achievement. Bungie has said that once all the Vidmaster achievements are unlocked, Recon Armor will be unlocked. The last Vidmaster Achievement will be achievable when the other three maps of the "Mythic" Map Pack release with Halo 3: ODST.The first half of the Mythic Map Pack, which first shipped with the Limited Edition version of Halo Wars and came to Marketplace April 9th, 2009 consists of:AssemblyAssemblyFirst shown off at PAX '08, Assembly is a small, symmetrical arena-style map made to cater to small, team-based gametypes and FFA. Previously known as "Purple Reign" internally, Assembly has been one of the longest referred-to maps by Bungie, via their Bungie Weekly Updates.OrbitalOrbitalA close-quarters, asymmetrical map, tailored for eight player, one-sided gametypes. The map takes place aboard the Quito Space Tether, an orbital docking station used as an Earth-based space port. First referenced as " Moonbase Alpha", Orbital, along with Assembly, it has been the longest referred-to DLC maps by Bungie.SandboxSandboxA map, similar to Foundry, made from the ground-up with Forge in mind. Sandbox is unique as it features three separate "planes" of play: the ground level, made completely from Forge objects and using a floor of sand, the "sky bubble", a free-floating level hundreds of feet above the ground, and the "crypt," an underground room, accessible via the ground level, made to accommodate Grifball matches, though it, like the ground level, can be completely customized via the level's almost endless array of Forge objects.Mythic Map Pack (Second Half)First referenced to in the achievements Title Update 2 added to the game, the Mythic Map Pack's latter three maps were bundled in with Halo 3: ODST as maps exclusive to that package. Along with Halo 3: ODST itself, they are the last DLC content added to Halo 3 before its follow-up game, Halo: Reach. On Bungie Day '09, Bungie revealed the first screenshots and descriptions of Citadel, Longshore, and Heretic. Since February 2nd, 2010, the maps have been available to download off the Xbox Live Marketplace under the name Mythic II Map Pack.CitadelCitadelLongshoreLongshoreHereticHereticSoundtrackThe original soundtrack to Halo 3 was composed by Martin O'Donnell and Michael Salvatori and was released a few months after the game in a two disc set.Tracklist:Disc 1Soundtrack Box ArtLuck (3:25)Released (5:20)Infiltrate (3:49)Honorable Intentions (2:46)Last of the Brave (3:57)Brutes (5:07)Out of Shadow (4:37)To Kill a Demon (3:44)This is Our Land (4:00)This is the Hour (2:08)Dread Intrusion (5:25)Follow Our Brothers (3:25)Farthest Outpost (5:14)Behold a Pale Horse (5:38)Edge Closer (3:03)Disc 2Three Gates (4:34)Black Tower (6:03)One Final Effort (3:08)Gravemind (5:21)No More Dead Heroes (5:01)Keep What You Steal (2:36)Halo Reborn (3:59)Greatest Journey (4:52)Tribute (2:52)Roll Call (5:58)Wake Me When You Need Me (2:19)Legend (0:40)Choose Wisely (1:18)Movement (0:27)Never Forget (3:07)Finish the Fight (2:27)Title Update 1MeleeIn Bungie's first mandatory Title Update, they fixed what many players were complaining about at the time, the melee system. Previously, if two players melee'd each other at the same time, the player with more shielding would die and there was a two second window that the system considered "same time." Due to the high level of complaints, Bungie came up with a new Melee system. The "same time" window was closed to about a second and the kill would often go to would hit first, but if the game determined that both players hit at the same time, both players would die, ending in a somewhat humorous death as both players flopped backwards.Title Update 2RankingIn their online Weekly Update for August 1st, 2008, Bungie unveiled a new addition to the online ranking system to be implemented in the second mandatory Title Update for Halo 3. The post included a chart illustrating EXP progression in various matchmaking playlists. The update offers players another visual representation of their progress in the online game, and serves to display precisely how many victories they have earned in any given matchmaking playlist.This is achieved by adding a new layer of specificity to the tracking of player EXP (EXP is a value that serves to illustrate how seasoned a player is in matchmade games). While a player's online Service Record still reflects their total EXP value, under the new ranking system, the player also has a visual EXP value (in the form of the same military ranks that previously existed in the online game) for each individual playlist. To clarify, this means that as a player wins more games in a particular playlist their overall EXP value responds as it normally would, but they also progress through the Halo 3 military ranks specific to that playlist. An example: A player may fancy the Team Slayer hopper over all others, and after some time and enough wins, obtain an EXP rank of General in the playlist -- however, if said player has only been competing in the Team Slayer playlist, they will have a playlist military rank of Recruit in the other playlists that they've been ignoring.A common misconception among Halo fans after the announcement of this news was that the hard-fought rankings that they had toiled away for since first setting foot online would be made meaningless after the release of the update, because now any player who invested enough time in a certain playlist would reach the esteemed upper ranks in a much easier fashion. This concern was later proven to be immaterial, because no aspect of the previous ranking system was being modified, and the individual playlist rankings were not to be reflected in a player's Service Record.Map VariantsThe Title Update also introduced four new variants of existing maps, out of Epitaph came Epilogue, and out of Snowbound came Boundless. While Epilogue is entirely without shield doors, Boundless still has those in High and Low base middle entrances (to counter the possibility of grenade spamming). These new maps will replace the existing ones; they will appear in matchmaking simultaneously, however in the long run Bungie hopes to have these maps become the dominant set. In addition to these two, Sand Tarp is now a version of Sand Trap without the Elephant vehicle and with new flag capture spaces. Pit Stop is a new version of The Pit with the upper spawn areas now inaccessible. These same matchmaking policies apply to these two as well. These maps are treated as Forge variants by the game, and can therefore be played normally and saved to an Xbox 360 Hard Drive.Xbox 360 Game InstallationHalo 3 requires 5.7 GB of HDD space to be installed. However, Bungie has recommended players to not install the game, saying that due to optimizations made to the game (so that it can be played on Xbox 360 consoles with no HDD attached), playing an installed copy (either through the installation process or through Games on Demand) causes longer loading times when playing multiplayer.</description><genres><genre id="1">Action</genre><genre id="32">First-Person Shooter</genre></genres><similar_games><game id="20601">Killzone 2</game><game id="20699">Resistance 2</game><game id="19654">Frontlines: Fuel of War</game><game id="18569">BlackSite: Area 51</game><game id="7547">Warhammer 40,000: Fire Warrior</game><game id="1539">Half-Life 2</game><game id="772">Outwars</game><game id="20232">Marathon</game><game id="32620">Section 8: Prejudice</game><game id="29021">Resistance 3</game><game id="33360">Warsoup</game><game id="39691">Killzone Trilogy</game><game id="38740">N.O.V.A. 3: Near Orbit Vanguard Alliance</game><game id="29510">N.O.V.A.</game><game id="36067">Destiny</game></similar_games><image>http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/scale_avatar/8/87790/2079826-box_halo3.png</image></root>